<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 04:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 04:00:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>Non-Cloistered Religious Women and Rome at the Aftermath of the Council of Trent. Journey in Archives (ISHWRA)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11813088/non-cloistered-religious-women-and-rome-aftermath-council</link>
						<dc:creator>Sarah Barthélemy</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Seminar</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-25T00:00:00-05:00">November 25, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Belgium</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Early Modern History and Period Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Cultural History / Studies, Italian History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>This coming Friday, 25 November at 4pm, we’ll be hosting in Brussels (Université Saint-Louis Bruxelles - room P30) this month’s ISHWRA seminar, when we’ll be joined by Dr Isabel Harvey (UCLouvain / GEMCA).</p><p>Recent historiography about non-cloistered religious women is based above all on the punctual luck of archives, as the wealth of an Inquisition trial or an autobiography, or on notarial institutional documentation of mainly economic nature. This documentation allows to reconstruct interesting cases, to contextualize them, but it is difficult to move away from the exceptionality of a person, a situation, or an institution rich enough to accumulate a number of notarial archives. I propose to look at another archive, the voluminous documentation of the Congregation of Bishops and Regulars, which will allow us to identify and hear the voices of others, those non-cloistered religious women who are considered neither saints nor heretics, and who did not live in a wealthy community in a large urban center. This presentation will detail the archival and methodological path to identify them and to gather information about their singular existences and experiences.</p><p>D﻿r Isabel Harvey is FNRS postdoctoral fellow at the Université catholique de Louvain.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><strong>T﻿his hybrid event will take place online and at Université Saint-Louis Bruxelles, 43 Boulevard du Jardin Botanique, Bruxelles, 1000 (room P30).</strong></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:sarah.barthelemy@durham.co.uk">sarah.barthelemy@durham.co.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/ishwra-seminar-november-2022-tickets-438918977477" target="_blank">https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/ishwra-seminar-november-2022-tickets-438918977477</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1669185431787870</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
