<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 12:21:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 12:21:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>CFP: Religions in Ritual, Spectacle, and Drama in the Medieval &amp; Early Modern World</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12155016/cfp-religions-ritual-spectacle-and-drama-medieval-early-modern</link>
						<dc:creator>Kristin Bezio</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-01T00:00:00-05:00">March 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology, World History / Studies, Theatre &amp; Performance History / Studies, Early Modern History and Period Studies, Medieval and Byzantine History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The journal <em>Religions </em>is hosting a Special Issue entitled “Religions in Ritual, Spectacle, and Drama in the Medieval &amp; Early Modern World,” co-edited by Drs. Kristin M.S. Bezio (University of Richmond) and Samantha Dressel (Chapman University).</p><p> The issue have proposed a final deadline of fall 2023 for publication, and we are asking for abstract proposals by March 1, 2023. Assuming all proposed abstracts fit the theme, we are hoping for initial drafted chapters by 1 July 2023 to allow time for revisions and editing before entering the production process. Final chapters will be due to Religions for peer review, etc., by 15 October 2023.</p><p> We are inviting essays that pertain, broadly speaking, to the ideas of spectacle, ritual, and drama as it relates to questions or practice of religion. We are particularly interested in essays that include global, non-white (or not only white), and non-Anglocentric (or not only Anglocentric) perspectives. </p><p>Spectacle lies at the heart of both ritual and drama, and religion is often similarly to be found at the core of both. Whether a spectacle is tied to ritualized praxis, to celebration or mourning, or to the production of a dramatic performance, elements of religious culture are often foregrounded, particularly in the medieval and early modern world.</p><p>This Special Issue aims to showcase essays that discuss the impact and depictions of religious belief and conflict in public ritual and drama throughout the medieval and early modern periods. Specifically, the issue seeks essays that cross multiple boundaries, whether religious, cultural, social, or geographical in terms of their depictions of public spectacle, whether religious, dramatic, or both. Essays in this volume should also consider the importance of their argument’s focus to larger questions of inclusion, equity, and diversity, either within the period or relative to more contemporary discussions, whether in the classroom or in the wider world. </p><p> In this Special Issue, original research articles and reviews are welcome. Research areas may include (but are not limited to) the following: religious studies, theology, literature and drama, history, art history, musicology, archaeology, or another relevant field. We ask for articles that focus on the middle ages through the early modern period (understood as flexible based on the region(s) under consideration) and specifically pertain to the focal topic of the special issue (religions in ritual, spectacle, and drama).</p><p>Please submit abstracts directly to Drs. Bezio &amp; Dressel (<a href="mailto:kbezio@richmond.edu">kbezio@richmond.edu</a> and <a href="mailto:sdressel@chapman.edu">sdressel@chapman.edu</a>) before March 1, 2023. The editors will evaluate abstracts and respond promptly with an invitation to submit chapters within two weeks of the deadline.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:kbezio@richmond.edu">kbezio@richmond.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 21:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1672987028409807</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sacred Journeys 10th Global Conference</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12154888/sacred-journeys-10th-global-conference</link>
						<dc:creator>Ian McIntosh</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-07-04T00:00:00-04:00">July 4, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-07-07T00:00:00-04:00">July 7, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Malta</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Anthropology, Cultural History / Studies, Humanities, Religious Studies and Theology, Social Sciences</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><b><span><span>Call for Papers </span></span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>More than 400 million people embark annually on pilgrimages with numbers steadily increasing. Pilgrimage is one of the most ancient practices of humankind and is associated with a great variety of religious and spiritual traditions, beliefs and sacred geographies. As</span></span><span> a global phenomenon, pilgrimage facilitates interaction between and among diverse peoples from countless cultures, occupations, and walks of life. In the 10<sup>th</sup> Global Conference, we will continue to explore pilgrimage’s personal, interpersonal, intercultural, and international dimensions. This includes s<span>imilarities and differences in the practice in Islam, Hinduism, Buddhism, Christianity, Judaism, Taoism, and other traditions, as well as secular pilgrimage. The impact of the internet and globalization, pilgrimage as protest, and pilgrimage and peace building, among others, are all topics of interest, as are the concepts of the internal pilgrimage and the journey of self-discovery.</span> Other potential topics include: (1) pilgrimage and the marketplace (2) the metaphor of the journey as explored by writers, artists, performers, and singers, including humanists and agnostics (3) pilgrimage and ‘miracles’ and the related topic of thanksgiving, and (4) ‘dark’ pilgrimages to sites of remembrance and commemoration.</span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:imcintos@iupui.edu">imcintos@iupui.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="http://www.thecn.com/SJ2014" target="_blank">http://www.theCN.com/SJ2014</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 21:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1672987028409806</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP: Swarthmore College Special Collections's Moore Research Fellowship (2023-2024)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12154655/cfp-swarthmore-college-special-collectionss-moore-research</link>
						<dc:creator>Rachel Mattson</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Fellowship</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-04-01T00:00:00-04:00">April 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Pennsylvania</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>American History / Studies, Social History / Studies, Peace History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Humanities</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Calling all scholars of Quaker history, Peace history, and allied topics! Swarthmore College Special Collections is now accepting applications for our Moore Research Fellowship for the 2023-2024 cycle.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The Margaret W. Moore and John M. Moore Research Fellowship promotes research during the academic year or summer months using the resources of the Friends Historical Library and/or the Swarthmore College Peace Collection, providing a stipend of $1,400-$5,600 to support such research. Applications are due April 1, 2023.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Please share this announcement with all who might be interested. More details and application instructions are here:  </span></span></span></span></span></span><a href="https://www.swarthmore.edu/friends-historical-library/moore-research-fellowship" rel="nofollow"><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>https://www.swarthmore.edu/friends-historical-library/moore-research-fellowship</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Questions about the application process may be directed to Celia Caust-Ellenbogen, <a href="mailto:ccauste1@swarthmore.edu">ccauste1@swarthmore.edu</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ccauste1@swarthmore.edu">ccauste1@swarthmore.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.swarthmore.edu/friends-historical-library/moore-research-fellowship" target="_blank">https://www.swarthmore.edu/friends-historical-library/moore-research-fellowship</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 21:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1672987028409805</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Avar: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Life and Society in the Ancient Near East - Open CFP for Avar 3.1</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12143401/avar%C2%A0-interdisciplinary-journal-life-and-society-ancient-near</link>
						<dc:creator>Eric M.  Trinka</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-01-03T00:00:00-05:00">January 3, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-08-01T00:00:00-04:00">August 1, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Ancient History, Middle East History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, World History / Studies, Humanities</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><strong>Call for Papers</strong></p><p><em>Avar: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Life and Society in the Ancient Near East</em></p><p> </p><p><strong>CFP Closes August 1, 2023</strong><br/><strong>Submissions: </strong><a href="https://avarjournal.com/avar/about/submissions" rel="nofollow">https://avarjournal.com/avar/about/submissions</a><br/><strong>Abstracts: </strong>The editors are glad to review an abstract to see if your paper or idea is a good fit for Avar. Feel free to send an abstract to <a href="mailto:avar@tplondon.com">avar@tplondon.com</a>.</p><p> </p><p>The editors of Avar: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Life and Society in the Ancient Near East are excited to call for submissions to an open issue (Avar 3.1).</p><p>We seek submissions with interdisciplinary approaches that explicitly adopt, adapt, or integrate theories and methodologies from within the traditional fields of ancient Near Eastern studies (i.e., archaeology, Assyriology, biblical studies, Egyptology, Hittitology, etc.), as well as from socio-anthropological and scientific disciplines.</p><p>Avar is dedicated to publishing open-access, peer-reviewed scholarship on Anatolia, Egypt, the Levant, and Mesopotamia from the third through first millennia BCE that crosses and disrupts disciplinary boundaries.</p><p>Avar accepts short notes (2,000-4,000 words) and articles (6,000-12,000 words) in English, French, German, Italian, and Spanish.</p><p>Submissions will only be accepted through <a href="https://avarjournal.com/avar/about/submissions" rel="nofollow">the submission platform</a>. Inquiries and abstracts can be sent to the editors at <a href="mailto:avar@tplondon.com">avar@tplondon.com</a>.</p><p> </p><p>To view CFPs and announcements, or to learn more about Avar, its future projects, and its editors, please visit <a href="http://avarjournal.com/" rel="nofollow">our website</a> or follow us on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/Avar_TNP" rel="nofollow">@Avar_TNP</a>.</p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><strong>Avar Editors:</strong></p><p><a href="https://cua.academia.edu/IsaacAlderman" rel="nofollow">Isaac <strong>Alderman</strong>,</a> Baruch College, USA</p><p><a href="https://brown.academia.edu/SThompson" rel="nofollow">Shane M. <strong>Thompson</strong></a>, North Carolina Wesleyan University, USA</p><p><a href="https://jmu.academia.edu/EricTrinka" rel="nofollow">Eric M. <strong>Trinka</strong></a>, Colby College, USA</p><p> </p><p><strong>ISSN</strong>: 2752-3527 (Print) <strong>ISSN</strong>: 2752-3535 (Online) | <em>Avar</em> is published twice a year in January and July.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:avar@tplondon.com">avar@tplondon.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="http://www.avarjournal.com/" target="_blank">http://www.avarjournal.com</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 20:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1672987028409804</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP: Drew University, Dean Hopper, 24 March 2023 -- &quot;Modes of Belonging: Kinships, Exile, and Translation&quot;</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12143400/cfp-drew-university-dean-hopper-24-march-2023-modes-belonging</link>
						<dc:creator>Michael Anderson</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-24T00:00:00-04:00">March 24, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>New Jersey</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Race / Ethnic Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies, Philosophy, Political Science</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Modes of Belonging: Kinship, Exile, and Translation </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>In a time of constant fatigue and anxiety caused by economic, political, and climatic catastrophic events, we are faced by dilemmas that are at their core about belonging. Take, for instance, the current focus on Ukrainian refugees and how they have been received differently than Syrian refugees. While in the latter case, we are told of a “refugee crisis,” the former is perceived as a duty Europe owes to Ukrainians because they are Europeans. In other words, Ukrainians “belong” in Europe.The present moment, therefore, calls for a historization and reimagination of major concepts in our debates about belonging. </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>To complicate this concept, we turn to interdisciplinary work that employs ideas of translation, kinship, exile, and diaspora to expose the elasticity of “belonging.” For instance, we ask what understandings of belonging have contributed to the hostile discourse we witness regarding immigration? How might politicians have shaped this discourse? Some scholars, such as Keguro Macharia, have named how political leaders rely on biological kinship and other “genealogical models to generate social and cultural legibility,” to gird up national collective identity and sympathies. Yet, in doing so, they often perniciously privilege “reproductive heteronormativity” at the expense of other forms of belonging or relationality. </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>We may also think of exile and diaspora as an alternative site that complicates our theorizing of belonging. In </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Reflections on Exile and Other Essays</span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>, Edward Said writes, “Exile is… the unbearable rift forced between a human being and a native place, between the self and its true home: its essential sadness can never be surmounted.” One interpretation of this statement might suggest that Said is reinforcing an idea that one only belongs to their place of birth or their “native place.” What might be a way to think about exile beyond this notion of “insurmountable uprootedness”? Following Mary Jacobus, we consider whether belonging must be intimately bound up with a notion of a past home. Her use of “translation” as a mode of analysis highlights how, far from simply being an instance of moving “from one language to another,” translation is also moving “from one place to another–translocation.” Translation enables the experience of “becoming foreign” that gestures toward a cosmopolitan vision of a world without borders. Thus, rather than exploring a melancholic return to the past home, what might be produced when we take, as Nadia Ellis suggests, an utopian diasporic horizon as our imaginary for belonging? </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The 10th annual Dean Hopper Conference of Spring 2023 (March 24) will examine these and related questions, seeking interdisciplinary engagements with the notion of “belonging” in cultural, historical, political, and theoretical contexts. We invite papers engaging with the intellectual and cultural history of belonging, and related topics like home, kinships, translation, exile, migration, both from historians and other scholars and from activists working in the field. Submissions from graduate students, postdocs, and early-career faculty are encouraged. This year’s conference will be hybrid in its modality; as such, we also welcome submissions from individuals to present via Zoom as well as in-person. </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Please send abstracts to </span></span></span></span></span></span><a href="mailto:Hopper@drew.edu"><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Hopper@drew.edu</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></a><span><span><span><span><span><span> by 11 January 2023:</span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span> The conference organizers welcome abstracts of no more than 250 words, and panel proposals of not more than 750 words. We especially welcome reflections on the following themes:</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Immigration studies</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Borders and borderlands</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Translation and translocality</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Models of kinship (genealogical, biological, ancestral, fictive, etc.)</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Exilic and postexilic writings (communal, autobiographical, etc.)</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Struggles of belonging posed by climate change and climate crises</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Refugees and the challenge of multiculturalism</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Intellectual and cultural histories of “belonging”</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Religious belonging</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Exodus: The book, its themes, and its afterlives</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Diaspora and the nation-state</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Postcolonial melancholy and utopianism</span></span></span></span></span></span></li></ul></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:hopper@drew.edu">hopper@drew.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 20:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1672987028409803</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Thinking about Thinking: Modes and Developments of Second Order Thinking in Ancient Israel</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12139454/thinking-about-thinking-modes-and-developments-second-order</link>
						<dc:creator>Sara Ben-Isaac</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-15T00:00:00-04:00">March 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Ancient History, Archaeology, Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><div> </div><div>We are looking forward to welcoming Professor Konrad Schmid of Zurich to London in March 2023 for two events.</div><div> </div><div>On <strong>Wednesday 15 March</strong> Konrad Schmid will deliver the annual <strong>Ethel M. Wood Lecture</strong>, at 5 pm in the Council Room of the King’s Building in the Strand, followed by a drinks reception. He will speak on the theme ‘Thinking about Thinking: Modes and Developments of Second Order Thinking in Ancient Israel’.</div><div> </div><div><strong>On Thursday 16 </strong>March the annual<strong> KCL/UCL Hebrew Bible workshop </strong>will take place. Konrad Schmid will give the keynote lecture, addressing the question ‘How Divine Laws Became Divine: The Case of the Covenant Code (Exodus 20-23)’. The workshop will be in the River Room of the King’s Building in the Strand, from 1.30 pm to 5.30 pm, followed by a drinks reception. <strong>Proposals of short papers are invited from PhD students and early career researchers on topics within the general area of ‘The Laws in the Pentateuch</strong>’. Short paper proposals should be sent to <a href="mailto:paul.joyce@kcl.ac.uk">paul.joyce@kcl.ac.uk</a>, by the deadline of<strong> Monday 13 February</strong>. While the workshop will be an in-person event, with the networking and other benefits this brings, a hybrid option may allow for the possibility of some of the short papers to be presented remotely. </div><div> </div></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Professor Paul Joyce</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:paul.joyce@kcl.ac.uk">paul.joyce@kcl.ac.uk</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 22:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1672900626466785</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>University of Manchester-Manchester Wesley Research Centre Joint Visiting Research Fellowship</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12123279/university-manchester-manchester-wesley-research-centre-joint</link>
						<dc:creator>Geordan Hammond</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Fellowship</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-01-16T00:00:00-05:00">January 16, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>We're accepting applications for the University of Manchester-Manchester Wesley Research Centre Joint Visiting Research Fellowship. The aim of the fellowship is to promote research in the Methodist and Wesleyan traditions by facilitating scholarly access to the internationally renowned Methodist Archives held at the John Rylands Research Institute and Library in Manchester and the MWRC and Nazarene Theological College library. Applications are due by 16 January 2023. Information about other MWRC Fellowships can be found here: <a href="https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/visiting-fellows.%C2%A0" rel="nofollow">https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/visiting-fellows. </a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ghammond@nazarene.ac.uk">ghammond@nazarene.ac.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/visiting-fellows" target="_blank">https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/visiting-fellows</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 21:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1672900626466784</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Practical Theology Hub - Call for Editors</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12121772/practical-theology-hub-call-editors</link>
						<dc:creator>James Morris</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Volunteers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-31T00:00:00-04:00">March 31, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Islamic History / Studies, Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Philosophy</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>We are looking for new editors to join our editorial team!<br/><br/>At Practical Theology Hub topic editors take charge of a topic related to practical theology and within their area of expertise. Over the course of a year (January-December), topic editors are expected to source between 3-5 articles from people (academics, practitioners and students) in the field, review those articles (offering suggestions for improvement), and help to promote Practical Theology Hub on social media.</p><p>The role of a topic editor is voluntary, but it is a great way to enhance one's resume and participate in an expanding international publication and team.<br/><br/>Please send emails of interest or queries to Dr. James Harry Morris at the address provided below.<br/><br/> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr. James Harry Morris</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:editor@biapt.org">editor@biapt.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://practicaltheologyhub.com/" target="_blank">https://practicaltheologyhub.com/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 21:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1672900626466783</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CfP - EASR 2023: Practices, tools, and ecology of magic-shamanic traditions across pre-modern and modern Monsoon Asia</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12099033/cfp-easr-2023-practices-tools-and-ecology-magic-shamanic</link>
						<dc:creator>Paolo E. Rosati</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-12-27T00:00:00-05:00">December 27, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-01-31T00:00:00-05:00">January 31, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Lithuania</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Anthropology, Asian History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, South Asian History / Studies, Southeast Asian History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><div><div><div><span><span>Dear all, if you would like to present a paper during the <span><b>European Association for the Study of Religion 2023 conference </b></span>in Vilnius (4th to 8th September), and it feets with the panel</span></span></div><div><span><span><span><b>Practices, tools, and ecology of magic-shamanic traditions across pre-modern and modern Monsoon Asia</b></span></span></span></div><div><span><span>please upload your proposal thorugh EASR 20223 website <span><a href="https://www.easr2023.org/call-for-papers/?fbclid=IwAR1LnLm0ahIhzdVOE2lhusU_nbjvc0luEbwavGOCPZvkiPeC7P7SLeefvik" rel="nofollow">https://www.easr2023.org/call-for-papers/</a></span></span></span><div><div> </div></div></div><div><span><span>deadline is on 31st January 2023</span></span></div><div><span><span>or fell free to contact me at <a href="mailto:paoloe.rosati@gmail.com">paoloe.rosati@gmail.com</a> (2-3 days before the deadline)</span></span></div><div> </div><div><div><strong><span>Paper proposals must consist of:</span></strong></div><ul><li><div><span>a paper title</span></div></li><li><div><span>the name/s and email address/es of author/s</span></div></li><li><div><span>a short abstract of fewer than 300 characters</span></div></li><li><div><span>a long abstract of fewer than 300 words</span></div></li></ul></div><div> </div><div><span><span><span><b>Short abstract:</b></span> This panel aims to shed light on tools, environments and ecology of magic-shamanic contexts in mainstream Indic, tantric, vernacular, and tribal religions across Monsoon Asia. Perspective authors are expected to focus on that practices often labelled as phenomena outside the mainstream religiosity.</span></span></div><div> </div><div><span><span><span><b>Abstract: </b></span>This panel considers Monsoon Asia as a geographical area—which includes the Indian subcontinent, Tibet, mainland and maritime Southeast Asia, and Southern China—where several religious practices are shared, hence, a socio-cultural unity of the region is marked. In fact, Indic mainstream (e.g. Buddhism, Hinduism, Jainism), tantric, vernacular, and tribal religions, share several socio-religious traits whose origin could be traced back to an ancient common, and complex substratum. The resilience of magic-shamanic elements is among these common traits.</span></span></div><div><span><span>This panel aims to shed light on that (material or intangible) instruments, which have been used as ritual, magic, or shamanic tools since pre-modern history of Monsoon Asia. Indeed, usually mastering magic and shamanic powers is closely related to meditation, yogic practices, severe penances, manipulation of bodily fluids, the consumption of intoxicating substances, the use of bones and skulls as talismans, the use of ashes, mantras, spells and spell-books, geometric diagrams (such as <span><i>maṇḍala</i></span>s and <span><i>yantra</i></span>s), music instruments (particularly drums and other percussions), etc. Panel’s papers discuss in depth the role of these and other tools in magic-shamanic contexts and how they affected practices such as ecstatic possession, shapeshifting, trance and other altered states of consciousness, healing and/or harmful capacities, alchemy, divination (such as scapulimancy and plastromancy) in mainstream, tantric, folk, and tribal traditions across pre-modern and modern Monsoon Asia. Furthermore, this panel invites to analyze the ecology of magic-shamanic contexts in order to better understand the role of the <span><i>locus sacer</i></span> as a sacred space where the practitioners can cross the borders with the supra-human world or may reach the enlightenment or other transcendental states.</span></span></div><div><span><span>Perspective authors are expected to use both empirical and theoretical methodology and to engage the subject with a multidisciplinary approach, considering disciplines such as textual studies, history, art history, archaeology, ethnography, anthropology, folkloric studies, religious studies, etc.</span></span></div></div></div></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Paolo E. Rosati, PhD</p><p><a href="mailto:paoloe.rosati@gmail.com">paoloe.rosati@gmail.com</a></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:paoloe.rosati@gmail.com">paoloe.rosati@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.easr2023.org/" target="_blank">https://www.easr2023.org/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 20:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1672814227157068</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
