<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 04:14:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 04:14:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ September 27, 2022] CFP for conference or similar: The Driving Ideas of the German Enlightenment</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/102690</link>
						<description><p>Invited speakers: Andrew Chignell (Princeton University); Sebastiano Ghisu (University of Sassari); Christian Leduc (University of Montreal); Laura Anna Macor (University of Verona); Charlotte Morel (CNRS, Paris); Udo Thiel (University of Graz, TBC); Anna Tomaszewska (University of Krakow); Michael Walshots (Martin-Luther University, Halle-Wittenberg).</p>
<p>Enlightenment has been labelled in various ways: the ‘century of philosophy’, the ‘century of taste’, the ‘age of criticism’, etc. Undoubtedly, the breakup of the traditional orders of knowledge and the new demands for rationality spawned a remarkable number of ideas and disciplines, either completely new (e.g. the idea of aesthetics or of phenomenology) or profoundly revised (e.g. the idea of "critique" in Kant's system) in the light of novel discursive and social interpretations of the world. An illuminating guide through the complex conceptual geography of this era up to Kant is undoubtedly Norbert Hinske’s ground-breaking essay “Die tragenden Grundideen der deutschen Aufklärung”[1]. Hinske identifies three types of basic ideas (<em>Grundideen</em>) that characterize and drive the philosophy of the German Enlightenment: 1. programmatic ideas (<em>Programmideen</em>), expressing the goals of the <em>Aufklärung</em>, such as ‘thinking for oneself’ (<em>Sebstdenken</em>) and ‘perfectibility’; 2. combat-ideas (<em>Kampfideen</em>), such as ‘confused representations’, ‘prejudice’, and ‘enthusiasm’ (<em>Schwärmerei</em>), against which German enlightened thinkers fight; 3. foundational ideas (<em>Basisideen</em>), expressing the fundamental anthropological convictions which ground their thought, such as the ‘determination’ or ‘destination of the human being’ (<em>Bestimmung des Menschen</em>) and ‘universal human reason’ (<em>allgemeine</em> <em>Menschenvernunft</em>).</p>
<p>This conference aims to build on Norbert Hinske’s typology and promote a critical discussion of his theses, including but not limited to the following topics:</p>
<p>- discuss/develop/revise/reject one or more of the basic ideas Hinske advances;</p>
<p>- advance and analyze other ideas as decisive for the philosophy of the Enlightenment, with or without reference to Hinske’s theses;</p>
<p>- challenge Hinske’s interpretation of the German Enlightenment in this essay (e.g.  the unifying pattern of a small number of fundamental ideas; the specificity of the <em>German</em> Enlightenment; Kant's <em>Mündigkeit</em> as belonging to the same programmatic idea as <em>Eklektik</em> and <em>Selbstdenken</em>).</p>
<p>This call is intended to complement the conference program; about 4 papers will be selected by the conference committee. The language of the conference is English. </p>
<p>Abstracts of original contributions (no more than 400 words), prepared for blind review, should be sent in word format, as attachment to alessandro.nannini@icub.unibuc.ro by 27 September 2022. The author’s name and affiliation should be included in the body of the e-mail. The conference papers might be considered for publication. We cannot cover travel and accommodation expenses.</p>
<p>We aim for an in-person conference, the sanitary context permitting. </p>
<p>Notification of acceptance shall be given by 2 October 2022. </p>
<p>[1]Norbert Hinske, “Die tragenden Grundideen der deutschen Aufklärung”, in: <em>Aufklärung und Haskalah in jüdischer und nichtjüdischer Sicht</em>, ed. Karlfried Gründer and Natan Rotenstreich, Heidelberg: Schneider, 1990; as well as in: <em>Die Philosophie der deutschen Aufklärung. </em><em>Texte und Darstellung</em>, ed. R. Ciafardone, Ditzingen: Reclam, 1998 – expanded).</p>
<p>The conference is organized within the research project “Between Truth and Freedom: Enlightenment Answers to 'Thinking for Oneself’” (funded by UEFISCDI; code PN-III-P4-ID-PCE-2020-2579).</p></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 05:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1662356228462218</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ November 10, 2022 -  November 11, 2022] Conference or similar: The Driving Ideas of the German Enlightenment</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/102686</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p>Invited speakers: Andrew Chignell (Princeton University); Sebastiano Ghisu (University of Sassari); Christian Leduc (University of Montreal); Laura Anna Macor (University of Verona); Charlotte Morel (CNRS, Paris); Udo Thiel (University of Graz, TBC); Anna Tomaszewska (University of Krakow); Michael Walshots (Martin-Luther University, Halle-Wittenberg).</p>

<p>Enlightenment has been labelled in various ways: the ‘century of philosophy’, the ‘century of taste’, the ‘age of criticism’, etc. Undoubtedly, the breakup of the traditional orders of knowledge and the new demands for rationality spawned a remarkable number of ideas and disciplines, either completely new (e.g. the idea of aesthetics or of phenomenology) or profoundly revised (e.g. the idea of "critique" in Kant's system) in the light of novel discursive and social interpretations of the world. An illuminating guide through the complex conceptual geography of this era up to Kant is undoubtedly Norbert Hinske’s ground-breaking essay “Die tragenden Grundideen der deutschen Aufklärung”[1]. Hinske identifies three types of basic ideas (<em>Grundideen</em>) that characterize and drive the philosophy of the German Enlightenment: 1. programmatic ideas (<em>Programmideen</em>), expressing the goals of the <em>Aufklärung</em>, such as ‘thinking for oneself’ (<em>Sebstdenken</em>) and ‘perfectibility’; 2. combat-ideas (<em>Kampfideen</em>), such as ‘confused representations’, ‘prejudice’, and ‘enthusiasm’ (<em>Schwärmerei</em>), against which German enlightened thinkers fight; 3. foundational ideas (<em>Basisideen</em>), expressing the fundamental anthropological convictions which ground their thought, such as the ‘determination’ or ‘destination of the human being’ (<em>Bestimmung des Menschen</em>) and ‘universal human reason’ (<em>allgemeine</em> <em>Menschenvernunft</em>).</p>
<p>This conference aims to build on Norbert Hinske’s typology and promote a critical discussion of his theses, including but not limited to the following topics:</p>
<p>- discuss/develop/revise/reject one or more of the basic ideas Hinske advances;</p>
<p>- advance and analyze other ideas as decisive for the philosophy of the Enlightenment, with or without reference to Hinske’s theses;</p>
<p>- challenge Hinske’s interpretation of the German Enlightenment in this essay (e.g.  the unifying pattern of a small number of fundamental ideas; the specificity of the <em>German</em> Enlightenment; Kant's <em>Mündigkeit</em> as belonging to the same programmatic idea as <em>Eklektik</em> and <em>Selbstdenken</em>).</p>
<p>[1]Norbert Hinske, “Die tragenden Grundideen der deutschen Aufklärung”, in: <em>Aufklärung und Haskalah in jüdischer und nichtjüdischer Sicht</em>, ed. Karlfried Gründer and Natan Rotenstreich, Heidelberg: Schneider, 1990; as well as in: <em>Die Philosophie der deutschen Aufklärung. </em><em>Texte und Darstellung</em>, ed. R. Ciafardone, Ditzingen: Reclam, 1998 – expanded).</p>
<p>The conference is organized within the research project “Between Truth and Freedom: Enlightenment Answers to 'Thinking for Oneself’” (funded by UEFISCDI; code PN-III-P4-ID-PCE-2020-2579).</p></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 05:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1662356228462217</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ February 18, 2023] Conference or similar: Recent and Forthcoming:  Holloway, Parker, Vereb</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/102682</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p>In this virtual workshop, three authors will discuss their current book projects in various stages of the process.  The first part of the program will involve an interview-led open discussion among the authors.  After a short break, we will return for an open discussion among all participants.</p>
<p>In alphabetical order, the authors and projects are:</p>
<p>*</p>
<p><em>Travis Holloway</em></p>
<p><em>SUNY Farmingdale</em></p>
<p><strong>How to Live at the End of the World: Philosophy and Democracy for the Anthropocene</strong></p>
<p>Our historical moment is marked by growing environmental catastrophes, rising populisms and populations, and the throes of neoliberalism’s <em>worldlessness</em>—technocratic governments that continue to subsidize private enterprise and petrocapitalism at the expense of the public good and the planet. How might philosophers propose another way to live at “the end of the world” that resists neoliberalism, ethnonationalism, and colonialism? How could a people or <em>dēmos</em> organize themselves more equally alongside other forms of life in an Anthropocene, or construct a democracy that is no longer distinctly human? Finally, could the specter of shared catastrophe in this century compel a new political project in ways that were unrealizable historically in prior decades? This talk will consider these questions from my new book, <em>How to Live at the End of the World: Theory, Art, and Politics for the Anthropocene</em> (Stanford, 2022). Along with the other panelists, I would like to workshop how to extend Part III of the book, "Democracy at the End of the World," into a new book project called <em>How to Assemble with All of the Living</em>.   </p>
<p>*</p>
<p><em>Emily Anne Parker</em></p>
<p><em>Towson University</em></p>
<p><strong>The Democracy of the Polis</strong></p>
<p>Democracies are under attack in numerous countries around the world. Many argue that what is needed is a recommitment to democracy. This book will argue that what is needed is a reconsideration of democracy and its historical development. In a previous work I argued that the polis is a concept according to which one body is taken to be both the universal body of humankind as well as the rightful earthly agent. The polis is most clearly articulated in the work of Aristotle, and political philosophers for millennia have reached back to Aristotle for re-clarification of the polis. Aristotle was famously opposed to democracy as a concept, as were virtually all political philosophers in the polis tradition until a couple of centuries ago. However, thinkers of the turn to democracy were inspired by the polis tradition.  When democracy began to be redefined, the polis remained. This book argues that what is needed is a disambiguation of the polis tradition from the tradition of democracy. They have so far been synonymous, precisely because democracy was initially defined by the polis. Insofar as it means an identification with the polis, democracy tends toward a denial of elemental difference. I argue that while democracy would seem to be under attack, what is in fact happening is a resurgence of the democracy of the polis. Is another democracy possible? Is the concept of democracy broader than its definition according to the polis? </p>
<p>*</p>
<p><em>Zachary Vereb</em></p>
<p><em>University of Mississippi</em></p>
<p><strong>The Green Kant: Kant, Sustainability, and the Climate Crisis</strong></p>
<p>Kant’s philosophy continues to be a dominant one today, especially for those interested in applications to existing global problems. These include refugee crises, global poverty and exploitation, war, indigenous rights, and public health. However, little research discusses the specific contribution that Kant’s philosophy can make for environmental problems such as climate change. In climate ethics, much research takes as its point of departure consequentialist and economic, cost-benefit analytical methods, while the newer works in Kant scholarship focus primarily on the promise of Kant’s juridical philosophy. I hope to build upon these works to show that, among other things, Kant’s progressive account of societal development and political change have much to contribute for thinking about how to transition to a sustainable and just world. Besides exploring his political and juridical philosophy, I also consider the extent to which Kant’s pre-critical ontological works, physical geography, critical aesthetics, critical ethics, philosophy of education, and philosophy of history provide conceptual resources for thinking about sustainability and the climate crisis from both individual and collective perspectives.</p>
<p>Organized by:  Jeremy Bendik-Keymer, Case Western Reserve University</p>
<p>(outgoing) Member-at-large, IAEP EXCOM</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 05:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1662183434772686</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP: Edited Volume on African American Religious History</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10773560/cfp-edited-volume-african-american-religious-history</link>
						<dc:creator>Ahmad Greene-Hayes</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-09-01T00:00:00-04:00">September 1, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-31T00:00:00-04:00">October 31, 2022</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>African American History / Studies, Atlantic History / Studies, Black History / Studies, Race / Ethnic Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>African American religious history is a vibrant field with a historiographical lineage dating back to the late nineteenth century and its genealogy transcends the geographical borders of the United States of America. From W.E.B. Du Bois’s and Carter G. Woodson’s reflections on “the Negro church” to Zora Neale Hurston’s ethnographic fieldwork on Southern and Caribbean Black religions to Katherine Dunham’s capturing of Vodou and Orisa communities and their diasporic religious performances and aesthetics, scholars in the field have long employed interdisciplinary and transatlantic methods to chronicle the plethora of Black religions and Black religious experiences in the Americas. This volume seeks papers that contribute to the field’s scholarly legacy and contend with its future. </p><p>Equally important, African American religious history is a field of study shaped by the historical experiences and preoccupations of African-descended people in the United States, but not arbitrarily limited by the ideological confines and geographical borders of the U.S. nation-state as a colonial empire. Consequently, the editors seek essays that trouble the multiple, complex, and shifting meanings of “African American” “religious” “history,” through innovative and critical approaches to the study of the religions of Black people in and from the United States, its colonial territories, and within the African Atlantic world. Taking seriously Black religious diversity, the editors welcome essays that analyze the spectrum of religious innovations, practices, beliefs, theologies, performances, politics, and institutions among Africans and their American descendants from the 15<sup>th</sup> century to the contemporary period.  The project’s emphasis on interrogating the boundaries of African American religious history as a scholarly field and historical phenomenon also yields a particular interest in work that models or posits new or creative theories and methods of study.  </p><p>Relatedly, the editors invite historical, interdisciplinary, and theoretical essays, written with an inclusive focus on women, queer, transgender, gender non-conforming, working class, poor, non-Christian, and other historically or historiographically marginalized religious actors. Essays may revisit established areas of study in the field, such as Black Protestant denominational histories and do so by engaging with critical analyses of race, gender, sexuality, class, and empire, or they may expand into new areas of study.   </p><p>The editors envision that this volume will highlight the diverse material and immaterial realities of religious life among people of African descent in and from the United States and the Americas more broadly, and that it will also provide a diagnostic account of the state of the field of African American religious history by paying homage to intellectual ancestors and exploring new directions. In this vein, the editors welcome papers that will hopefully engage the evolution of African American religions, locate places and spaces to find where Black religions have taken form, identify structures that nuance religious thought and practice, and highlight social roles where alternative forms of religious authority can occur. We encourage potential contributors to submit proposals for essays that explore topics that include but are certainly not limited to the following:  </p><p><strong>Categories</strong>: </p><ul><li>Defining “African American” “religious” “history” </li><li>Problematizing Keywords and Concepts in the field (i.e., syncretism, “the Black church,” joy, resistance, liberation, respectability, piety, religious affiliation/belonging, etc.) </li></ul><p><strong>Geographies</strong>: </p><ul><li>African American, Caribbean, Latin American, and African religious convergences </li><li>Hemispheric, comparative, and/or regional approaches </li><li>Migration/Emigration/Immigration </li><li>Empire and Colonialism </li></ul><p><strong>Histories and Temporalities:</strong></p><ul><li>African American religious studies and its founders </li><li>Unsung and understudied African American religious thinkers </li><li>Periodization in the study of African American religion  </li><li>African American religion and slavery  </li><li>African American religion and Antebellum freedom </li></ul><p><strong>Methods and Approaches: </strong> </p><ul><li>Sources for the study of African American religious history </li><li>African American religious history and interdisciplinarity </li><li>African American religion and the digital </li><li>African American religion and the archive </li><li>African American religion and politics </li><li>The secular and secularism </li><li>Pessimism and/or futurism and/or utopianism </li></ul><p><strong>Materialities and Embodiment:</strong> </p><ul><li>Architecture, space, and place </li><li>Health (mental health, public health, HIV/AIDS, Cancer, etc.) </li><li>Gender and/or sexuality </li><li>Labor, Capitalism, and economics </li><li>Climate Change/Environmentalism/Nature </li><li>Incarceration and Policing </li><li>Life Cycles (adolescence, aging, adulthood, parenting, elders) </li><li>Violence (interpersonal, structural, state, social, political, sexual, etc.) </li><li>Performance, entertainment, music, arts, literature, culture, fashion, food, etc. </li></ul><p><strong>Spiritualities and Lived Religion:</strong> </p><ul><li>Ancestral veneration </li><li>Witchcraft </li><li>“Cults” and “sects”  </li><li>The erotics of African American religion  </li><li>Bireligiosity/Multiple Religious Belonging/Theological “Openness”  </li><li>African American religion and “the illicit” (i.e., pornography, sex work, psychedelics, entheogens, alcohol, etc.) </li><li>African American queer, transgender, and gender nonconforming religious histories</li><li>Professional careers (e.g., midwifery, the military, journalism, the sciences, broadcasting, corporate America, religious therapy/counseling, spiritual “gurus”) </li></ul><hr/><p><strong>Co-Editors:</strong></p><ul><li>Vaughn A. Booker (Dartmouth College)</li><li>Ahmad Greene-Hayes (Harvard University)</li><li>Judith Weisenfeld (Princeton University)</li><li>Alexis Wells-Oghoghomeh (Stanford University)</li></ul></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><ul><li>Please send an abstract of no more than 500 words to <a href="mailto:AARH.Anthology@gmail.com">AARH.Anthology@gmail.com</a> by <strong>October 31, 2022</strong>, along with an abridged CV.</li><li>Authors will be notified of decisions by December 2022.</li><li>If accepted, the due date for completed drafts (of no more than 35 typed, double-spaced pages, including footnotes) will be December 30, 2023.</li><li>Accepted authors will also be expected to participate in an in-person collaborative revision workshop to be scheduled later.</li></ul><p>Please do not hesitate to contact us at the above email address with preliminary inquiries. </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:AARH.Anthology@gmail.com">AARH.Anthology@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://crossroads.princeton.edu/cfp-edited-volume-african-american-religious-history" target="_blank">https://crossroads.princeton.edu/cfp-edited-volume-african-american-religious-history</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 19:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1662183434772685</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for papers: Margins and Peripheries in East Asian Cultures</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10776083/call-papers-margins-and-peripheries-east-asian-cultures</link>
						<dc:creator>Luying Zhao</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-17T00:00:00-04:00">October 17, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Arizona</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>East Asian History / Studies, Literature, Religious Studies and Theology, Cultural History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span>Margins and Peripheries in East Asian Cultures</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Call for Papers</span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span>Arizona State University East Asian Studies Graduate Student Conference</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>January 13–14, 2023</span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span>Margins and peripheries in East Asian cultures have long been an underlying motif downplayed by conventional social and cultural discourses. While the concepts of margins and peripheries are often perceived in terms of geography, their extended denotations are ubiquitous in social, economic, cultural, and political contexts.</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>In the 2022–23 ASU East Asian Studies Graduate Student Conference, we encourage innovative ways of <b>conceptualizing East Asian margins and peripheries</b> through history, whether they are defined by political borders, religious and cultural identities, gender and sexuality, ethnicity, social class, disability, technology, life cycle, generative energy, porousness, among others. The keynote speakers are <b>Prof. Kang Xiaofei</b> (Associate Professor of Chinese at the Department of Religion at the George Washington University) and <b>Prof. Oh Young Kyun</b> (Associate Professor of Chinese at the School of International Letters and Cultures at Arizona State University). We invite papers from humanistic fields that address these issues from different perspectives, including but not limited to ethical studies, feminism, critical race theories, social studies, religious studies, art history, linguistics, selfhood, textual editorial intent and transmission, diasporic identities, comparative studies, and media studies. In the spirit of inclusivity, we also welcome any interpretations of margins and peripheries. Travel awards may be available to graduate student presenters.</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Graduate student presenters will receive feedback from their panel’s respondents, who will read and comment on the papers. Each presenter will have 20 minutes to present their work, followed by a 20-minute response for papers presented in the panel and a Q&amp;A session. Each panel will consist of three papers. The conference itself will take place over two days.</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>For those interested in participating, please submit an abstract (max. 250 words) by <b>Oct. 17, 2022</b>. Please also state your intention to apply for a travel award along with abstract submission. Successful applicants will be notified on <b>Nov. 2, 2022</b>. Please direct any questions as well as submissions to the conference organizers from the East Asian Studies Graduate Student Association at <b><a href="mailto:easgradconference@asu.edu">easgradconference@asu.edu</a></b>.</span></span></span></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><strong>President and Vice President of ASU EASGrad Association:</strong></p><p>Pui See Wong: <a href="mailto:puisee.wong@asu.edu">puisee.wong@asu.edu</a></p><p>Francesco Papani: <a href="mailto:fpapani@asu.edu">fpapani@asu.edu</a></p><p><strong>Connect with us on social media:</strong></p><p>Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/AEasgrad" rel="nofollow">https://twitter.com/AEasgrad</a></p><p>Facebook: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/ASUEASGrad/" rel="nofollow">https://www.facebook.com/ASUEASGrad/</a></p></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 19:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1662183434772684</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>EVELYN G. ETHERIDGE CONFERENCE  ON THE HARLEM RENAISSANCE</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/09/01/evelyn-g-etheridge-conference-on-the-harlem-renaissance</link>
						<dc:creator>helziebair@paine.edu</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, September 1, 2022 - 11:22pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Paine College</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:nbookhart@paine.edu">nbookhart@paine.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/african-american">african-american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/renaissance">renaissance</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/theatre">theatre</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>September 9, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>CALL FOR PAPERS</strong></p>
<p><strong>EVELYN G. ETHERIDGE CONFERENCE </strong></p>
<p><strong>ON THE HARLEM RENAISSANCE </strong></p>
<p><strong>PAINE COLLEGE</strong></p>
<p><strong>AUGUSTA, GEORGIA</strong></p>
<p><strong>OCTOBER 26-28, 2022</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Paine College</p>
<p>1235 Fifteenth Street</p>
<p>Augusta, GA 30901</p>
<p>Contact: Dr. Nancy Wellington Bookhart, Conference Chair (<a href="mailto:nbookhart@paine.edu">nbookhart@paine.edu</a>), or Professor Jeffrey Jones, Conference co-chair (<a href="mailto:jjones3@paine.edu">jjones3@paine.edu</a>)</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The Department of Humanities at Paine College in Augusta, Georgia is excited to host the Silver Anniversary of the Evelyn G. Etheridge Conference on the Harlem Renaissance. The Conference is critical to the rich legacy of art and education and its transformative power for the African American community. The Harlem Renaissance is one of the most important artistic and cultural movements in history that spanned from 1919 to 1940 and produced notable writers, critics, and artists such as Claude McKay, James Weldon Johnson, Augusta Savage, Gwendolyn Bennett, Bessie Smith, and Alain Locke.  Paine College is located centrally to beautiful downtown Augusta in the heart of the Central Savannah River Area (CSRA). Augusta is the host of the prestigious Masters Golf Tournament at the Augusta National Golf Course and is the home of James Brown, the Godfather of Soul, internationally renowned opera star, Jessye Norman, and internationally acclaimed author and Paine College alumnus, Frank G. Yerby. This year’s conference and celebration is a blended conference with both virtual and on-campus events. Further information will be posted on the Paine College website, <a href="http://www.paine.edu/">www.paine.edu</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Call for Papers Now Open</strong></p>
<p>The Department of Humanities currently requests abstracts and proposals for panel sessions and individual papers that examine this year’s conference theme, <strong><em>Art Matters: Historicizing Emancipation through the Arts</em></strong><strong>.</strong>Presentations will analyze literature, history, religion philosophy, sociology, psychology, anthropology, business, economics, STEM, art, politics, and music to provide inter-and cross-disciplinary analyses of the Harlem Renaissance and its impact.  Possible areas of inquiry include but are not limited to:</p>
<p> </p>
<ul>
<li>Black Art and Politics in the Harlem Renaissance</li>
<li>Emancipation and Citizenship</li>
<li>Black Music, Protest, and Emancipation</li>
<li>Religious Expressions in Black Art</li>
<li>The Arts and Political Strategies of Equality</li>
<li>The Arts and Black Subjectivity</li>
<li>Negritude and Nationalism in Black Art</li>
<li>Emancipation in Harlem Renaissance Literature</li>
<li>Social and Racial Transgression in Art, Music, and Literature</li>
<li>Deconstructing Stereotypes of History vis-à-vis the Arts</li>
<li>The Primal Scene, Trauma, and Healing Arts</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p>The Department also requests sessions that invite alternate presentation formats such as performances, workshops, visual art exhibitions, roundtables, and multimedia presentations. Please submit by email abstracts and session proposals that do not exceed 200 words to Professor Jeffrey Jones, Conference, co-chair at <a href="mailto:jjones3@paine.edu">jjones3@paine.edu</a>., by September 9, 2022.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 13:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1662183434772683</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
