<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 12:24:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 12:24:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>Dying with the Buddha: The Twenty-four Buddhist Talismans in Chosŏn Korea</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12185264/dying-buddha-twenty-four-buddhist-talismans-chos%C5%8Fn-korea</link>
						<dc:creator>LaGretia Copp</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-09T00:00:00-05:00">February 9, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Kansas</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Asian History / Studies, East Asian History / Studies, Korean History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><h2>Dying with the Buddha: The Twenty-four Buddhist Talismans in Chos<span><span>ŏ</span></span>n Korea</h2><h3>Dr. Sujung Kim, Associate Professor of Religious Studies (DePauw University)</h3><h3>February 9, 2023  /  7 PM CT  /  Zoom</h3><h3><span><span><a href="https://kansas.zoom.us/meeting/register/tJcpf-isqzMvGdwMI9sRI3NOgFRM6NrTkE7y" rel="nofollow">REGISTER HERE</a> (bit.ly/DyingwiththeBuddha)</span></span></h3><p> </p><p><span><span>As a state-of-the-art “wearable technology” of the time, talismans provided protection, perquisites, and prescriptions for the devotees of premodern Korean Buddhism. Among the varied array of talismans discovered from tombs, stupas, and ritual manuals, this talk focuses on a collage of the 24 Buddhist talismans to illustrate how these talismans provided vocabulary and structure to transform believers’ soteriological concerns and cosmological views in the Buddhist mortuary setting. Each talisman in the group was introduced from China and circulated independently from the early Koryŏ period (935–1392). But once combined in the Chosŏn period (1392–1910), the 24 talismans functioned as one giant talisman communicating a complex vision and comprehensive benefits. My findings ultimately suggest that multiple layers of ambiguities built around talismans, such as tensions between text and image, legibility and illegibility, as well as accessibility and inaccessibility, played a key role in enacting the efficacy and potency of talismans, and that the twenty-four talismans occupied a central place in sustaining Chosŏn Buddhist devotionalism.</span></span></p><h3>About the Speaker</h3><p><span><span>Sujung  Kim is Associate professor of Religious Studies at DePauw University. Sujung is specialized in Japanese and Korean Buddhism, interested in tracing the interaction between Buddhist cultures using textual and material sources in East Asian context. Her first book, <em>Shinra Myojin and Buddhist Networks of the East Asian “Mediterranean”</em> (University of Hawai‘i Press, 2019) focuses on a deity called Shinra Myōjin. The book explains that Shinra Myojin is not only an influential protector god of the Onjōji temple in Japan, but also part of the transnational network of people, ideas, and gods, spanning China, Korea, and Japan. Currently, Sujung is working on her second book project tentatively titled, <em>Korean Magical Medicine: Buddhist Healing Talismans in Chosŏn Korea</em>, which she investigates the religious, historical, and iconographic dimensions of healing talismans produced in Buddhist settings during the Chosŏn period. Although its primary focus is Korean talismans, the book also locates itself in the broader East Asian context, aiming at showing the complex web of talismanic culture in East Asia. This book project is supported by ACLS/Robert H.N. Ho Family Foundation (AY 2021–2022), and she is also the recipient of the 1st KABS (Korean Association of Buddhist Studies) Mujin Writing Award (2021).</span></span></p><h4><span><span>Sponsored by the KU Center for East Asian Studies and the Department of East Asian Languages and Cultures.</span></span></h4></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>LaGretia Copp</p><p>Program Assistant</p><p>Center for East Asian Studies</p><p>University of Kansas</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ceas@ku.edu">ceas@ku.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="http://ceas.ku.edu/" target="_blank">http://ceas.ku.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 19:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673505429966189</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Syncretic Spread of Indian Traditions</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12096518/syncretic-spread-indian-traditions</link>
						<dc:creator>Arvind Kaushik</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-04-30T00:00:00-04:00">April 30, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>India</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>South Asian History / Studies, Social Sciences, Humanities, Religious Studies and Theology, Anthropology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span>Foreigners who come to India are often astounded by the diversity of the Indic traditions. As has been repeated often, we have crores of <i>devatas</i>, one for each individual. Each<i> jati</i> within each locality have their own unique set of practices and traditions. Equally fascinating as the diversity of the Indic traditions is their breadth of spread. The Buddhist traditions, for example, are to be found across the length and breadth of Asia, from Northern Mongolia to China to Japan and all the way down to Southeast Asia. </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Given that the Indic traditions did not expand through proselytization, what was the mechanism through which these traditions spread and established themselves in other regions? How did they do so without some centralized institution driving the process?</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Articles will be accepted in Word Format only in English submitted to <a href="mailto:editor@indictoday.com">editor@indictoday.com</a></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span>The articles may be submitted as either quick reads (around 1000-1200 words) or as long reads (2000-4000 words). Selected articles from long reads will be published as a part of an anthology: ‘The Mechanism of the Spread of Indic Traditions’. The deadline for submission of the article is March 30, 2023</span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:editor@indictoday.com">editor@indictoday.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.indica.today/announcements/call-for-papers-the-mechanism-of-the-spread-of-indic-traditions/" target="_blank">https://www.indica.today/announcements/call-for-papers-the-mechanism-of-the-spread-of-indic-traditions/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 19:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673505429966188</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ph.D. Research Grant Announcement 2023/24 Orient-Institut Istanbul</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12184098/phd-research-grant-announcement-202324-orient-institut</link>
						<dc:creator>Gottfried Plagemann</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Grant</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-01-22T00:00:00-05:00">January 22, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Turkey</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Middle East History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Anthropology, History of Science, Medicine, and Technology, Humanities</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>Ph.D. Research Grant Announcement 2023/24</span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>-- <i>Call for Applications</i> --</span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The <b>Orient-Institut Istanbul</b> is pleased to invite applications for Ph.D. research grants for 2023/24. </span></span><span><span>The purpose of the grant is to provide support for research in Turkey to Ph.D. candidates not living in Turkey. </span></span><span><span>If the fellowship is not, or only partially</span></span><span><span>,</span></span><span><span> spent in Istanbul, a close connection to the institute is required. Upon consultation this may also be arranged through supervision by members of the Orient-Institut's Scientific Advisory Board or other scholars associated with the institute. Grants are preferably available to support research in one of the institute’s research areas (</span></span><span><a href="https://www.oiist.org/en/forschungsprofil/" rel="nofollow"><span><span>https://www.oiist.org/en/forschungsprofil/</span></span></a></span><span><span>), namely </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ol><li><span><span><span><span><b><span>Musicological research on the Ottoman Empire and Turkey</span></b></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><b><span>Narrative sources on Istanbul and the Ottoman Empire</span></b></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><b><span>Past and contemporary forms of religious expression in Anatolia since the 11<sup>th</sup> century</span></b></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><b><span>Linguistic Turkology</span></b></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><b><span>Science, Technology and Society in Turkey </span></b></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><b><span>Iran </span></b></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><b><span>Entanglements between Turkish or Ottoman society, culture and literatures on the one, and Southeast Europe, the Mediterranean, Iran, The Caucasus and Eastern Europe on the other side. The migration of academics and artists is part of this field.</span></b></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><b><span>Ottoman modernities.</span></b></span></span></span></span></li></ol><p><span><span><span><span>The research grant consists of a monthly stipend of <b>€ 1,100</b> for the duration of <b>usually ten to twelve months</b>. Short term grants of up to 90 days may also be made available. Travel expenses of a journey to and from Turkey will be reimbursed. Start of the scholarship should be at the earliest <b>April 15th, 2023 </b>and at latest <b>September 15th, 2023</b>.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Prospective applicants are expected to hold an M.A. degree in a related academic discipline. As a rule, a complete application is to demonstrate the necessity of conducting research in Istanbul or Turkey at large. Good command of Turkish or another source language necessary for the proposed project is obligatory. As the Orient-Institut Istanbul aims at creating an open and supportive academic environment, grant holders are expected to attend colloquia and conferences organised by the institute and to give a public presentation of their own research. Research stays outside Istanbul must be cleared with the institute's director.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Applications to</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Prof. Dr. Christoph K. Neumann<br/>Director of the Orient-Institut Istanbul</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>must be submitted </span><span>via our </span><a href="https://www.oiist.org/en/ausschreibungen" rel="nofollow"><b><span>online application portal</span></b></a><span> by</span><span> <b>January 22<sup>nd</sup>, 2023</b>. For the reference letter, please share the link </span><a href="https://www.oiist.org/en/referenzschreiben/" rel="nofollow">https://www.oiist.org/en/referenzschreiben/</a><span> with the academic supervisor you have asked for a reference letter to upload the reference letter there.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span>Complete applications</span></b><span> must include the following:</span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span>Cover letter with indication of the desired period of the fellowship</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>CV</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Outline of the Ph.D./ research project</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Explanatory statement and research schedule for the stay in Istanbul/Turkey </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Letter of recommendation written and uploaded by an academic supervisor</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Copy of M.A. diploma</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Documentation of proficiency in Turkish or another relevant source language</span></span></span></span></span></li></ul></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.oiist.org/en/scholarship/" target="_blank">https://www.oiist.org/en/scholarship/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 19:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673505429966187</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>#MeToo, the Talmud, and the Ethics of Accountability, Prof. Mira Beth Wasserman (Rabbinical College in Philadelphia)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12179288/metoo-talmud-and-ethics-accountability-prof-mira-beth</link>
						<dc:creator>Manuel Lopez</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-01-17T00:00:00-05:00">January 17, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Florida</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Ancient History, Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><strong>PUBLIC LECTURE (In person and live stream): #MeToo, the Talmud, and the Ethics of Accountability, Prof. Mira Beth Wasserman (Rabbinical College in Philadelphia)<br/>When</strong>: TUESDAY, JANUARY 17, 2023<br/><strong>Time</strong>: 5:30 – 7:00 PM (EST)<br/><strong>Where</strong>: NEW COLLEGE OF FLORIDA, SAINER AUDITORIUM (located at NCF's Caple Campus, 5313 Bay Shore Rd)<br/><strong>Live Streaming</strong>: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkBFuIfa1OFGv7XrgMomkpw" rel="nofollow">New College of Florida Religious Studies YouTube Channel</a>.</p><p><strong>#MeToo, the Talmud, and the Ethics of Accountability</strong><br/>Prof. Mira Beth Wasserman<br/>Director of the Center for Jewish Ethics and Associate Professor of Rabbinic Literature at the Reconstructionist Rabbinical College in Philadelphia.</p><p>With the rise of the #MeToo movement, Jewish activists invoked the Jewish ethical tradition to support principles of accountability, dignity, and gender justice. The Talmud seemed to offer a perfect precedent for #MeToo in the story of a rabbinic leader who was chastened and dismissed for sexual violations. But is this an accurate reading of Moed Katan 17a? In this talk, I take a second look at the talmudic text I at first celebrated and discover a more complicated and disturbing story. I offer my reading and re-reading as a case study in how the Talmud can--and can't--advance contemporary ethics.</p><p>Professor Wasserman’s research focuses on the art of the Babylonian Talmud and on how the Talmud can be deployed to support contemporary Jewish ethics. Her book, Jews, Gentiles, and Other Animals: The Talmud after the Humanities (Penn Press), was awarded the Baron Prize for the best first book in Jewish studies published in 2017. Her current projects include a history of the idea of aggadah, and the direction of NEH-funded public scholarship on race, religion, and American Judaism.</p><p>Read more here: <a href="https://www.ncf.edu/ncf-events/klingenstein-lecture-series/" rel="nofollow">https://www.ncf.edu/ncf-events/klingenstein-lecture-series/</a><br/>About Prof. Mira Beth Wasserman: <a href="https://www.reconstructingjudaism.org/profile/rabbi-mira-beth-wasserman-phd/%C2%A0" rel="nofollow">https://www.reconstructingjudaism.org/profile/rabbi-mira-beth-wasserman-phd/ </a></p><p>With Best Wishes,<br/>Prof. Susan Marks<br/> </p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Susan Marks<br/>Professor of Judaic Studies /Klingenstein Chair<br/>New College of Florida<br/>Division of Humanities<br/>5800 Bay Shore Road<br/>Sarasota, Florida 34243-2109<br/><a>smarks@ncf.edu</a><br/>941.487.4271 Fax 941.487.4479<br/>She/Her/Herself</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:smarks@ncf.edu">smarks@ncf.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.ncf.edu/ncf-events/klingenstein-lecture-series/" target="_blank">https://www.ncf.edu/ncf-events/klingenstein-lecture-series/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673505429966186</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – January 11, 2023</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-january-11-2023/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find 3 jobs, 4 fellowships, 3 grants, and 8 Call For Papers.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 30!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Lecturer in Theology, Race, and Ethnicity (Full-Time with continuous renewal, non-Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Leeds University, UK</p>



<p>Deadline: January 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://jobs.leeds.ac.uk/vacancy.aspx?ref=AHCPR1053">https://jobs.leeds.ac.uk/vacancy.aspx?ref=AHCPR1053</a></p>



<h4>Lecturer in Anthropology (Full-time, fixed term until December 31, 2023)</h4>



<p>University of Melbourne, Australia</p>



<p>Deadline: January 22, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://jobs.unimelb.edu.au/en/job/911216/lecturer-in-anthropology">https://jobs.unimelb.edu.au/en/job/911216/lecturer-in-anthropology</a></p>



<h4>Bhagvan Vimalnath Endowed Chair in Jain Studies and South Asian Studies</h4>



<p>UC Santa Barbara, US</p>



<p>Deadline: June 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://recruit.ap.ucsb.edu/JPF02315">https://recruit.ap.ucsb.edu/JPF02315</a></p>



<h4>AAR/SBL Job Forum</h4>



<p><a href="https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search">https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search</a></p>



<h2>Fellowships:</h2>



<h4>Psychology Ph.D. Studentship in Conspiracy Theories (Covered fees, stipend, research funding, conference, and travel funding)</h4>



<p>University of Kent, UK</p>



<p>Deadline: February 28, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.kent.ac.uk/psychology/news/4990/erc-funded-phd-studentship-opportunity-consequences-of-conspiracy-theories">https://www.kent.ac.uk/psychology/news/4990/erc-funded-phd-studentship-opportunity-consequences-of-conspiracy-theories</a></p>



<h4>Swarthmore College Special Collections’ Moore Research Fellowship (2023-2024)</h4>



<p>Swarthmore College, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: April 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12154655/cfp-swarthmore-college-special-collectionss-moore-research">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12154655/cfp-swarthmore-college-special-collectionss-moore-research</a></p>



<h4>New Graduate School Fellowships in Islamic Studies</h4>



<p>Sweden</p>



<p>Deadline: Varies on which institutions you fit best</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://lnu.se/en/research/PhD-studies/religion/graduate-school-in-islamic-studies/">https://lnu.se/en/research/PhD-studies/religion/graduate-school-in-islamic-studies/</a></p>



<h4>Ph.D. funding through Open University, Oxford, and Cambridge</h4>



<p>Deadline: January 11, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.oocdtp.ac.uk/how-to-apply">https://www.oocdtp.ac.uk/how-to-apply</a></p>



<h2>Grants:</h2>



<h4>2023 Frist Book Grant for Scholars of Color (assisting early career, non-tenured religion scholars of color with grants up to $40,000)</h4>



<p>Deadline: January 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://louisville-institute.org/programs-grants-and-fellowships/grants/first-book-grant-for-scholars-of-color/">https://louisville-institute.org/programs-grants-and-fellowships/grants/first-book-grant-for-scholars-of-color/</a></p>



<h4>AAR – Eastern International Region Conference Travel Grants</h4>



<p>Deadline: February 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://eiraar.org/index.php/regional-news/regional-meeting-travel-grants">https://eiraar.org/index.php/regional-news/regional-meeting-travel-grants</a></p>



<h4>Luce – AAR Advancing Public Scholarship Grant</h4>



<p>Deadline: January 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/QS90yCp9Pn">https://t.co/QS90yCp9Pn</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>American Catholic Historical Association 2023 Annual Meeting</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://twitter.com/achahistory/status/1612072394880958464?s=12&amp;t=033LBhhevenzNwJoZ2P4og">American Catholic Historical Association on Twitter: “And just like that, the ACHA 2023 Annual Meeting is over! The call for papers is already out for next year’s meeting. Our deadline is March 15, 2023! https://t.co/S73VsLob2b” / Twitter</a></p>



<h4>Fordham States’ Catholic Studies in the Americas “New Scholar Essay Prize” – $1500 prize</h4>



<p>Deadline: February 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/FKodXblosV">https://t.co/FKodXblosV</a></p>



<h4>Yale Journal of Music &amp; Religion</h4>



<p>Deadline: January 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://elischolar.library.yale.edu/yjmr/">https://elischolar.library.yale.edu/yjmr/</a></p>



<h4>Sacred Journeys 10<sup>th</sup> Global Conference</h4>



<p>Deadline: Conference July 4 – 7, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12154888/sacred-journeys-10th-global-conference">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12154888/sacred-journeys-10th-global-conference</a></p>



<h4>Avar: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Life and Society in the Ancient Near East</h4>



<p>Deadline: August 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12143401/avar%C2%A0-interdisciplinary-journal-life-and-society-ancient-near">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12143401/avar%C2%A0-interdisciplinary-journal-life-and-society-ancient-near</a></p>



<h4>Religion and Spirituality as Sites of Learning Conference</h4>



<p>Deadline: January 17, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://blogs2.abo.fi/religionlearning/?fbclid=IwAR2-Kz85Nu74LFTOuQnTl5rXup_u8m2cRsLi0q6jSemoOlQXLI6BZT6oM0w">https://blogs2.abo.fi/religionlearning/?fbclid=IwAR2-Kz85Nu74LFTOuQnTl5rXup_u8m2cRsLi0q6jSemoOlQXLI6BZT6oM0w</a></p>



<h4>The Other, Persecution and Response</h4>



<p>Deadline: February 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://relcfp.com/blog/2023/01/01/cfp-eir-aar-queens/">https://relcfp.com/blog/2023/01/01/cfp-eir-aar-queens/</a></p>



<h4>Ecclesiology &amp; Ethnography Network</h4>



<p>Deadline: January 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/KYJXgOAwLc">https://t.co/KYJXgOAwLc</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673505429966185</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Materiality of Lived Religion on the Atlantic Edge</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/01/10/the-materiality-of-lived-religion-on-the-atlantic-edge</link>
						<dc:creator>avner.goldstein</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Wednesday, January 11, 2023 - 4:40pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Avner Goldstein (Boston College, USA) and Eleanor March (University of Exeter, UK)</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:avner.goldstein@bc.edu">avner.goldstein@bc.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/classical-studies">classical studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/ecocriticism-and-environmental-studies">ecocriticism and environmental studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/medieval">medieval</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>February 9, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>CALL FOR PAPERS -- EAA 2023 -- BELFAST</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Avner Goldstein and Eleanor March invite abstract submission to session #107 ("The Materiality of Religion on the Atlantic Edge") at the 2023 annual meeting of the European Association of Archaeologists in Belfast. Please see the text below for further details. Any questions may be addressed to the main session organiser at <a href="mailto:avner.goldstein@bc.edu">avner.goldstein@bc.edu</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Session Title and Number:<br/></strong>#107. The Materiality of Religion on the Atlantic Edge</p>
<p><strong>Organizers:</strong><br/>Avner Goldstein (Boston College, USA)<br/>Eleanor March (University of Exeter, UK)</p>
<p><strong>Deadline:</strong><br/>9 February 2023</p>
<p><strong>Submissions:</strong><br/><a href="https://eaa.klinkhamergroup.com/eaa2023/">https://eaa.klinkhamergroup.com/eaa2023/</a></p>
<p><strong>Abstract:</strong><br/>Papers in this session explore the material culture of lived religion on the edge of the European Atlantic, from the Iron Age through the end of the Middle Ages. Following the successful EAA 2022 session “The Materiality of Lived Religion Under and After Rome,” we wish to continue discussions exploring the opportunities and interpretative challenges of using material culture for understanding ritual and religion. This year, particular attention is given to the materials, practices, performances, and experiences of religion in regions that lie along the European Atlantic, including Ireland, Great Britain, the North Sea, France, and Iberia. As well as introducing listeners to the particular materials of religion that are the focus of the paper, presenters should also address at least one of the following issues: the impact that Atlantic environments and landscapes had on ritual practices and understandings, or how lived religion’s material expressions were impacted depending on whether they were found at the centre or on the margins of empires, kingdoms, territories, communities, or societies. This session provides a space for serious discussion between practitioners working in different time periods, places, and disciplines about how to think about and use material evidence to reconstruct the lived experience of religion along the Atlantic’s edge.</p>
<p><strong>Keywords:</strong><br/>religion, history, environment, Iron Age, Roman, medieval</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 20:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673505429966184</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ February 25, 2023] Conference or similar: Marx and the Frankfurt School: An Afternoon Workshop</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/106577</link>
						<description>Venue: UCL Institute of Education<br/><br/><p><strong>Marx and the Frankfurt School: An Afternoon Workshop</strong></p>
<p>UCL Institute of Education, London (with online participation)</p>
<p>2:00-6:00pm, Saturday 25th February 2023</p>
<p>Speakers:</p>
<ul>
<li>Jacob McNulty (UCL), "Historical Materialism as Idealism in Marcuse"</li>
<li>Charlotte Baumann (Sussex), "Adorno's critique of Marx: The Capitalist System and the Non-identical"</li>
</ul>
<p>All are welcome.</p>
<p>To register (whether for in-person or online participation) please use this link: <a target="_blank" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.eventbrite.com/e/marx-and-the-frankfurt-school-an-afternoon-workshop-tickets-510076471457&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1673363267576000&amp;usg=AOvVaw30KnlL_tDVsU6TifX7O6ee">https://www.eventbrite.com/e/marx-and-the-frankfurt-school-an-afternoon-workshop-tickets-510076471457</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 06:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673332629620612</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[Today] Talk or similar: Two Types of the Critique of Religion - Dieter Birnbacher</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/106585</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/>Speakers at this event: <br/>Dieter Birnbacher (Heinrich Heine University Düsseldorf)<br/><br/><p>Dear Colleague,<br/><br/>You are invited to participate in the next session of the Logic and Religion Webinar Series which will be held on <strong>January 12, 2023</strong>, at <strong>4pm CET</strong> with the topic:</p>
<p><strong>TWO TYPES OF CRITIQUE OF RELIGION</strong></p>
<p><strong>Speaker</strong>: Dieter Birnbacher (University of Düsseldorf, Germany)</p>
<p><strong>Chair</strong>: Jens Lemanski (University of Hagen, Germany)</p>
<p>Please, register in advance to receive the zoom link:<br/>https://www.logicandreligion.com/webinars</p>
<p> <br/>Abstract: The talk distinguishes three main directions in the philosophical criticism of religion and  exemplifies them by the critique of religion contained in Schopenhauer’s Dialogue on religion: the inherent inability of religions to reveal the mythical nature of the objects of religious worship; the authoritarian nature of observing religious prescriptions; the allegation that religion produces more evil than good. On the last point, however, Schopenhauer is ambivalent: religion, to him, is the “philosophy of the masses” containing more than a grain of truth but in a form adapted to their seemingly limited intellectual capacities.</p>
<p>Join us 5 minutes prior to the beginning of the session!<br/> <br/>With best wishes,</p>
<p>-- </p>
<p>Francisco de Assis Mariano <br/>The University of Missouri-Columbia<br/>LARA Secretary<br/>lara@logicandreligion.com</p></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 06:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673332629620611</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>PANEL: The Dynamics of Modern Pilgrimages from the Inside #EUARE2023</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12159549/panel-dynamics-modern-pilgrimages-inside-euare2023</link>
						<dc:creator>Pawel Plichta</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-19T00:00:00-04:00">June 19, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-22T00:00:00-04:00">June 22, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology, Cultural History / Studies, Humanities, Literature, Anthropology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>PANEL: <strong>The Dynamics of Modern Pilgrimages from the Inside</strong></p><p>The aim of this panel is to present modern studies related to traveling, especially to religious tourism, as seen from the perspective of pilgrims. Just as the forms of religious and spiritual activity change, the concept of a pilgrimage can be defined in different ways. Often this term is used to describe an exceptional travel to dedicated places of cultural and religious heritage, also without the presence of religious motivation. In this sense, a good example might be e.g. Camino de Santiago or the Holy Land. Sometimes a pilgrimage can be a travel to places related to famous people or cultural icons, like Memphis. We invite all researchers to submit talks and participate in the panel for studying the narrations of modern pilgrims, travel literature about places important (not only) for various religious traditions, as well as different aspects of experience learnt by pilgrims or religious tourists, analyses of their memories and travel reports, and finally cultural tourism that can be considered as religious pilgrimages.</p><p>We are looking for additional panelists interested in modern pilgrimage, cultural and religious tourism.</p><p>Submit your paper: <a href="mailto:pabloplichta@gmail.com">pabloplichta@gmail.com</a></p><p><span><span><span><span>Abstracts of no more than 300 words should be submitted no later than <strong>25 January, 2023</strong></span></span></span></span></p><p>Our panel takes place as part of the 6th Annual Conference of the European Academy of Religion in St Andrews, Scotland, UK, 19-23 Jun 2023.</p><p>The theme for this year’s gathering is Religion from the Inside, with keynote lectures planned by Prof. Jean-Luc Marion, Dr Avivah Gottlieb Zornberg, Prof. Diwakar Acharya, Dr John Makransky, and Prof. Lejla Demiri. As in previous years, the conference programme will be composed of working sessions including: open panels; closed panels; book presentations; and keynote lectures focusing on the overarching topic, Religion from the Inside.</p><p>Religions join people in common endeavours, offer fulfilment and purpose to their adherents, and bind together the material and the immaterial. They can be described propositionally, but are whole ways of life. As such, religions have characteristics which may be clear to those within, but which are difficult to grasp for those without: inhabiting a building is different to looking over its blueprints. The examination of what is added (and what is lost) by taking the inside view is the theme of this year's annual meeting.</p><p>Religion from the Inside looks different in different religious traditions. Within some, the inside view is engaged mainly with questions of theology: the contemplation of the divine and all things in relation thereto. Within others, it is preoccupied with the conforming of human action to a more-than-human law. In yet other, an emic perspective focuses on the practice and experience of ritual. Reflection on sacred texts is common to many traditions, and often differs from external consideration of the same documents. Acknowledging the existence of emic knowledge can be an invitation to exploration and relationship rather than a method of isolation.</p><p>​Panel participating in the theme may choose to explore whether and how emic insights can be articulated in propositional form accessible to etic readers. They may engage with distinctively emic epistemologies, such as narrative traditions or second-person knowledge, which cast religious belief less as an intellectual acceptance of propositions than as an entry into a relationship. They may also discuss empirical questions of the differences religious faith or practice makes to perception, psychology, or individual and communal life. Equally, panels may examine the risks of insulated perspectives, including the exclusionary thrust of strong distinctions between insider and outsider, and the repudiation of common standards of truth.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Pawel Plichta: <a href="mailto:pabloplichta@gmail.com">pabloplichta@gmail.com</a></p><p>Barbara Wezgowiec: <a href="mailto:chopinka@poczta.fm">chopinka@poczta.fm</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:pabloplichta@gmail.com">pabloplichta@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.europeanacademyofreligion.org/conference-schedule" target="_blank">https://www.europeanacademyofreligion.org/conference-schedule</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 18:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673332629620610</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>MESA 2023 CFF: Religious Allusions and Expressions in Arabic Literature in English Translation</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/01/08/mesa-2023-cff-religious-allusions-and-expressions-in-arabic-literature-in-english</link>
						<dc:creator>aidrissi4@yahoo.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Monday, January 9, 2023 - 11:08am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>MESA November 2-5, 2023 - Montréal, Canada</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:aatapanel@gmail.com">aatapanel@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/classical-studies">classical studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/translation-studies">translation studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/world-literatures-and-indigenous-studies">world literatures and indigenous studies</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>February 10, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p> <strong>Religious Allusions and Expressions in Arabic Literature in English Translation</strong></p>
<p>Call for Submissions Deadline: February 10, 2023</p>
<p>One of the challenges faced by translators of Arabic literary texts into English concerns the approaches used in rendering embedded religious content and allusions. In this panel, we invite presentations that focus on the strategies used by translators to convey the meaning of religious expressions, allusions, and symbols in a manner that takes into consideration the compatibility between the linguistic and conceptual planes. We would also like to address the strategies that translators of Arabic literature use to find equivalence and substitutes for particular Qur’anic connotations and implications in the source language and culture and their counterparts in the target language and culture.</p>
<p>In this AATA panel held in conjunction with MESA’s 57th annual meeting on November 2-5, 2023, in Montréal, Canada, we would like to focus on the rhetorical strategies and linguistic choices used in translating religious allusions and expressions in Arabic literature in English in relation to the following topics:</p>
<ul>
<li>• Strategies of semantic and syntactic approximations</li>
<li>• Adaptation and naturalization of culturally specific expressions</li>
<li>• Cultural, pragmatic and text specific problems</li>
<li>• Idiomatic expressions with religious allusions</li>
<li>• Functional equivalents and cultural substitutes.</li>
</ul>
<p>We invite presenters interested in presenting on any of these or similar issues relevant to the panel topic to send a 300-word abstract and a short bio by <strong>Friday, February 10, 2023</strong>, to <strong><a href="mailto:aatapanel@gmail.com">aatapanel@gmail.com</a></strong></p>
<p>Accepted presentations should be delivered in Arabic.</p>
<p>For more information on the American Association of Teachers of Arabic, its publications, and activities, please visit: <a href="https://www.aataweb.org/">https://www.aataweb.org</a> </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 02:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673332629620609</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Experience of Stone: Materiality, Landscape, Expression</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/01/06/the-experience-of-stone-materiality-landscape-expression</link>
						<dc:creator>alexanderD</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Monday, January 9, 2023 - 11:02am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Alexander D'Alisera (Boston College, USA) and Christina Cowart-Smith (Durham University, UK)</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:alexander.dalisera@bc.edu">alexander.dalisera@bc.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/ecocriticism-and-environmental-studies">ecocriticism and environmental studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/medieval">medieval</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>February 9, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>CALL FOR PAPERS -- EAA 2023 -- BELFAST</strong></p>
<p>Alexander D'Alisera and Christina Cowart-Smith invite abstract submission to session #331 ("The Experience of Stone: Materiality, Landscape, Expression") at the 2023 annual meeting of the European Association of Archaeologists in Belfast. Please see the text below for further details. Any questions may be addressed to the organizers at <a href="mailto:alexander.dalisera@bc.edu">alexander.dalisera@bc.edu</a> and <a href="mailto:christina.e.smith@durham.ac.uk">christina.e.smith@durham.ac.uk</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Session Title and Number:<br/></strong>#331. The Experience of Stone: Materiality, Landscape, Expression</p>
<p><strong>Organizers:</strong><br/>Alexander D'Alisera (Boston College, USA)<br/>Christina Cowart-Smith (Durham University, UK)</p>
<p><strong>Deadline: </strong><br/>9 February 2023</p>
<p><strong>Submissions: </strong><br/><a href="https://eaa.klinkhamergroup.com/eaa2023/">https://eaa.klinkhamergroup.com/eaa2023/</a></p>
<p><strong>Abstract:</strong><br/>Stone is a durable, lasting medium. Even in its fragmentation, it exudes permanence, solidity, and symbolism. For millennia, humans have shaped stone, fashioning it into architectural wonders, sculptured monuments, objects of lived religion, and things of everyday use. At the same time, natural stonescapes, from caves and mountains to canyons and valleys, have played indisputable roles in the shaping of human experience and expression. Natural and hewn stone has long been used, reused, repurposed, and recycled in myriad contexts, at local, regional, and global levels. To this end, this session explores human relationships to stone from both historical and archaeological perspectives. It invites scholars of all time periods and geographies, but especially those working from the prehistoric to the medieval periods, to contribute papers exploring the experience of stone. Possible subjects include, but are not limited to: stone and the landscape; a phenomenology of stone; agentive stone; stone and lived religion; the theology of stone; the materiality of stone; the reuse of hewn or sculptured stone; the relationship of stone artifacts to ecofacts; stone and memory; or, shaping stone into space. Above all else, this session seeks to open a dialogue between eras, disciplines, methodologies, and geographies, with the particular aim of bringing archaeologists and historians into further conversation with one another.</p>
<p><strong>Keywords:</strong><br/>stone, phenomenology, sculpture and architecture, landscape archaeology, material culture, monumentality</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 21:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673332629620608</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Edited Collection: Mormonism in Romantic and Victorian Print Culture</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/01/06/edited-collection-mormonism-in-romantic-and-victorian-print-culture</link>
						<dc:creator>Abby Clayton</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, January 10, 2023 - 9:30am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Abby Clayton &amp; Colby Townsend, Indiana University Bloomington</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:aclayto@iu.edu">aclayto@iu.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/bibliography-and-history-of-the-book">bibliography and history of the book</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/romantic">romantic</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/victorian">victorian</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>April 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>Call for Abstracts for Edited Volume - <em>Mormonism in Romantic and Victorian Print Culture</em></strong></p>
<p><strong>Type: </strong>Call for Papers</p>
<p><strong>Deadline for Submissions: </strong>April 1, 2023</p>
<p><strong>Subject Fields: </strong>History of the Book / History of Literature and Culture / Print Culture / Religious Studies/ Gender Studies / Transatlanticism / Romanticism / Victorian Studies</p>
<p><em>Mormonism in Romantic and Victorian Print Culture</em></p>
<p>(Edited by Abby Clayton and Colby Townsend)</p>
<p>Coming on the heels of what is traditionally viewed as the Romantic period and bleeding into the Victorian, Mormonism serves as a lens through which to understand the diverse innovations in print culture during the long nineteenth century. Mormonism—not only a religious, but also a cultural and textual phenomenon—utilized a transatlantic print network almost from its moment of inception. Paradoxically, the same network exponentially multiplied the movement’s growth by reacting to and against its existence. These print systems became embodied as they moved people from the United Kingdom and continental Europe to the American West. The migration of bodies and texts through Mormonism staged key transatlantic nineteenth-century debates including questions about empire, indigenous peoples, gender and sexuality, authorship and composition, forms of prophecy, and religious canons.  </p>
<p>The editors seek essays that re-envision transatlantic Romantic and Victorian print networks through a consideration of Mormon or Mormon-inspired texts and culture. We invite contributors to analyze this period through a variety of literary, historical, and cultural methodologies. We aim to be inclusive in this volume through readings of lesser-known authors of the long nineteenth century, new readings of canonical texts, and treatments of religious movements as sites of political inquiry. This volume re-conceives literature as not just books and novels, but newspapers, tracts, pamphlets, and other print ephemera that are grounded in their materiality and their use in everyday situations by diverse readers and listeners. We invite interdisciplinary, transnational, and intersectional approaches to the question of religion and literature. </p>
<p>Topics include, but are not limited to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Materiality of print and book history</li>
<li>Print ephemera, including railway yellow-backs, looseleaf and magazine extras</li>
<li>History of the novel, including satires, gothic, historical romances, and the “Oriental” tale</li>
<li>Reprinting and pirating culture</li>
<li>Myth of the author</li>
<li>Politics, French Revolution, Anti-Jacobinism, Democracy, Imperialism, and the Subaltern</li>
<li>Representations of Mormonism in print media and Anti-Mormon literature</li>
<li>Lost manuscripts found, ghosts and guardian spirits</li>
<li>The fantastic and the sublime in Romantic, Victorian, and Mormon texts</li>
<li>Form, genre, and narrative theory in 18C and 19C print culture</li>
<li>Gender, minorities, and the “Other” in 18C and 19C texts, including voice and literacy</li>
<li>The problems of scripture and canon in literary criticism</li>
<li>Disability in 18C and 19C print culture</li>
<li>The challenges of locating disability in already contested archives (e.g. slavery, colonialism, etc.)</li>
<li>Oratory, eloquence, and sermon culture</li>
<li>Time and Critical Geographies</li>
<li>Text, image, and credulity in the long nineteenth century</li>
<li>Digital archives and Romantic, Victorian, and Mormon manuscripts</li>
<li>Romantic, Victorian, and Mormon poetry</li>
<li>Portrayals of polygamy in history</li>
</ul>
<p>We welcome submissions from professors, adjunct or contingent faculty, independent scholars, post-docs, and graduate students working in a variety of fields, including history, religion, literature, and others in the humanities. Please submit abstracts (300–500 words), an abbreviated CV, and a short bio to editors Abby Clayton (<a href="mailto:aclayto@iu.edu">aclayto@iu.edu</a>) and Colby Townsend (<a href="mailto:colbtown@iu.edu">colbtown@iu.edu</a>) by April 1, 2023. The University of Illinois Press has expressed interest in reviewing the proposal.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 19:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673332629620607</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Journal Special Issue: Religions in Ritual, Spectacle, and Drama in the Medieval &amp; Early Modern World</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/01/05/journal-special-issue-religions-in-ritual-spectacle-and-drama-in-the-medieval-early</link>
						<dc:creator>kbezio@richmond.edu</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Monday, January 9, 2023 - 11:00am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Religions</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:kbezio@richmond.edu">kbezio@richmond.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/medieval">medieval</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/renaissance">renaissance</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>March 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>The journal <em>Religions</em> is hosting a Special Issue entitled “Religions in Ritual, Spectacle, and Drama in the Medieval &amp; Early Modern World,” co-edited by Drs. Kristin M.S. Bezio (University of Richmond) and Samantha Dressel (Chapman University).</p>
<p> The issue have proposed a final deadline of fall 2023 for publication, and we are asking for abstract proposals by March 1, 2023. Assuming all proposed abstracts fit the theme, we are hoping for initial drafted chapters by 1 July 2023 to allow time for revisions and editing before entering the production process. Final chapters will be due to Religions for peer review, etc., by 15 October 2023.</p>
<p> We are inviting essays that pertain, broadly speaking, to the ideas of spectacle, ritual, and drama as it relates to questions or practice of religion. We are particularly interested in essays that include global, non-white (or not only white), and non-Anglocentric (or not only Anglocentric) perspectives. </p>
<p>Spectacle lies at the heart of both ritual and drama, and religion is often similarly to be found at the core of both. Whether a spectacle is tied to ritualized praxis, to celebration or mourning, or to the production of a dramatic performance, elements of religious culture are often foregrounded, particularly in the medieval and early modern world.</p>
<p> This Special Issue aims to showcase essays that discuss the impact and depictions of religious belief and conflict in public ritual and drama throughout the medieval and early modern periods. Specifically, the issue seeks essays that cross multiple boundaries, whether religious, cultural, social, or geographical in terms of their depictions of public spectacle, whether religious, dramatic, or both. Essays in this volume should also consider the importance of their argument’s focus to larger questions of inclusion, equity, and diversity, either within the period or relative to more contemporary discussions, whether in the classroom or in the wider world. </p>
<p> In this Special Issue, original research articles and reviews are welcome. Research areas may include (but are not limited to) the following: religious studies, theology, literature and drama, history, art history, musicology, archaeology, or another relevant field. We ask for articles that focus on the middle ages through the early modern period (understood as flexible based on the region(s) under consideration) and specifically pertain to the focal topic of the special issue (religions in ritual, spectacle, and drama).</p>
<p>Please submit abstracts directly to Drs. Bezio &amp; Dressel (<a href="mailto:kbezio@richmond.edu">kbezio@richmond.edu</a> and <a href="mailto:sdressel@chapman.edu">sdressel@chapman.edu</a>) before March 1, 2023. The editors will evaluate abstracts and respond promptly with an invitation to submit chapters within two weeks of the deadline.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 20:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673332629620606</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Muslim Queer Imaginaries in South Asian Literatures</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/01/05/muslim-queer-imaginaries-in-south-asian-literatures</link>
						<dc:creator>msnbajwa@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Monday, January 9, 2023 - 11:11am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Routledge (Taylor &amp; Francis, UK)</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:msnbajwa@gmail.com">msnbajwa@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/gender-studies-and-sexuality">gender studies and sexuality</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/postcolonial">postcolonial</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/theory">theory</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>January 31, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>Edited volume titled “Muslim Queer Imaginaries in South Asian Literatures” </strong>(To be published as a part of the Routledge Book Series South Asian Literature in Focus)</p>
<p>Editors: Muhammad Safdar</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>BOOK SERIES:</strong> South Asian Literature in Focus (Routledge, Global Edition) </p>
<p><strong>Series Editors:</strong> Goutam Karmakar, Puspa Damai, Payel Pal, Deimantas Valančiūnas</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Muslims were tolerant of queer genders and were condemned by Medieval Western intellectuals for it. However, modern secular Western polemics of individual human rights and autonomy condemn them for being oppressive. South Asia is home to the world’s largest Muslim population with a variety of religious schools of thought. South Asian Muslimness and their behaviors to <em>khawaja sira </em>and<em> hijra</em> genders/sex have been an interesting case to study intersectionality of Muslimness and queer gender tendencies/practices in a subject because of an intriguing diversity in the behaviors over time and space from being highly regarding, accommodative, moderate, conservative and oppressive. Literatures produced by South Asian Muslims in different languages have engaged with non-normative genders and intimacies including <em>khawaja</em> <em>sira</em> and <em>hijra</em> subjects depicting an enriched variety of their social status/places and ‘lived’ experiences over a history of hundreds of years of the presence and practices of <em>interpretations</em> of Islam in the region. Especially, recently, Pakistani and Bangladeshi Anglophone literatures have attracted international critical scholarly attention for being growingly transgressive in engaging with non-normative genders in the contexts of reignited grappling between secular and religious discourses, charged religiosity, intense cross-(b)orders mobility, compressing/fraying spatial and cultural distinctions, globalization, neoliberalism and resurgent far-right popular masculinist religio-nationalist politics in the region.</p>
<p>Muslim queerness cannot be homogenized into the category of ‘queer of color’ and, further, South Asian Muslim queernesses cannot be reduced and homogenized into Muslim queerness. There are subtle and nuanced institutional, geopolitical, temporal, spatial, individual, affective and humanist distinctions intersected by religious interpretations and nationalisms which require scholarly attention to be explored and examined to foreground Muslim queer imaginaries and underline the struggles, resistance and negotiations of Muslim queers in their historical specificities in South Asia. While reading the intersectionality of Muslimness and queer gender/sexual subjectivity as depicted in South Asian literatures, the aim of this edited book volume is to bring into the limelight Muslim queer marginalities from within queerness of color in South Asia which is in itself on margins in the Western canonical polemics of queerness. Its objectives are to explore 1) Muslim concepts about and Muslimness of queer gender/sex. 2) Muslim queer subjects, subjectivation and subjectivities. 3) Temporal, spatial, social and political shifts in the imaginaries and subjectivities of/about queers intersected by shifts in religious interpretations/understandings or politico-religious praxis to define gender and sexual moralities.</p>
<p>It intends to read South Asian literary inscriptions of Muslim queer imaginaries, temporalities and subjects from a decolonial perspective which critiques the epistemological violence of Euro-America-centric universalism along with underlining the violence of local heteronormative gender/sexual moralities defined by shifts in religious thoughts.</p>
<p>Though all South Asian religions have had an important role in defining gender moralities, this book focuses on how Muslimness has particularly been implicated in an essential intersecting role to define and shape the lives of trans, <em>khawaja sira</em> and <em>hijra</em>.</p>
<p>It invites original contributions in English in the form of critical essays which explore the complexities of South Asian Muslim queer imaginaries and subjects as depicted in literatures written by Muslim or non-Muslim writers of South Asian origin in English or any other regional language. It particularly wants its essays to critically engage in a dialogue with Euro-American universalist and local heteronormative theoretical frames to point out their reductiveness and limits, and to foreground distinctive decolonial and resistive epistemological subtlety(ies) to read South Asian Muslim queer imaginaries and subjects by examining their distinctive complexities and situatedness in which religion is an essential defining element amongst other intersecting factors. It wants its essays to examine how religious trajectories have recognized/derecognized, oppressed/emancipated/rescued, neglected, tolerated, accepted, turned a blind eye to, enabled/disabled and empowered Muslim queers. It also wants its contributors to be self-reflexive and conscious of their researcher positionality while reading the queer.</p>
<p>The essays may focus on either of (but not limited to) the following thematic areas reflected in South Asian literatures:</p>
<p>Typology of Muslim queer imaginary</p>
<p>Transitions in the constructions of Muslim queer imaginary and subjects</p>
<p>Subjectivation and subjectivities of Muslim queers</p>
<p>Social and political status of <em>khawaja sira</em>, <em>hijra</em> and trans</p>
<p>Political erasure and rendering non-subjects of certain queer desires and subjective groundings</p>
<p>Selective acceptance and tolerance of queer experiences</p>
<p>Groundings of Muslims’ behaviors towards queers</p>
<p>Elevation of <em>khawaja sira</em> and <em>hijra</em> to high social and political posts and perspectives behind it</p>
<p>Contemporary Muslim queer politics</p>
<p>Strategic potential and limitations of religious/secular approaches to ensure rights of queers</p>
<p>Diasporic Muslim queer subjects</p>
<p>Narratives and perspectives of queers towards religion regarding their queer subjectivities</p>
<p>Intersectionality or mutual exclusiveness of religion and non-heteronormative intimacies/desires in a queer subject</p>
<p>We are inviting abstracts (350 words along with a bionote of 50 words in a single MS Word file) by January 31, 2023. Kindly send your abstract to <a href="mailto:msnbajwa@gmail.com">msnbajwa@gmail.com</a></p>
<p><strong>About Editors</strong></p>
<p><strong>Muhammad Safdar</strong> is a senior lecturer at the Department of English and Literary Studies (DELS), Institute of Liberal Arts, University of Management and Technology, Pakistan. He earned PhD in English (South Asian Literature) from University of Gujrat, Pakistan. He also got education and trainings from universities in the UK and the USA. His research articles and book chapters on gender, sexuality, Muslim subjectivities and identity have been published in international peer-reviewed journals and books published by Routledge, Wiley, Palgrave Macmillan and IGI Global. He is a member of the Editorial Board (with special responsibilities of South Asia) of the journal <em>Intersections: Gender and Sexuality in Asia and the Pacific</em> published by Australian National University.</p>
<p>Email: <a href="mailto:msnbajwa@gmail.com">msnbajwa@gmail.com</a></p>
<p>ORCID <a href="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-3927-3781" target="_blank"><strong>https://orcid.org/0000-0002-3927-3781</strong></a></p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 11:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673332629620605</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>EuARe-2023 Pilgrimages 2023 : The Dynamics of Modern Pilgrimages from the Inside - EuARe2023</title>
			<link>http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=171047&amp;copyownerid=179034</link>
						<description>The Dynamics of Modern Pilgrimages from the Inside - EuARe2023 [St Andrews] [Jun 19, 2023 - Jun 22, 2023]</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 06:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673159828519650</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP &gt; Deadline Extended 29th Jan &gt; UK Association for Buddhist Studies Conference 2023</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12158703/cfp-deadline-extended-29th-jan-uk-association-buddhist-studies</link>
						<dc:creator>Nicholas Newton</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-01-29T00:00:00-05:00">January 29, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Asian History / Studies, Anthropology, Area Studies, Humanities, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The deadline for paper and panel proposals for the United Kingdom Association for Buddhist Studies Conference 2023 has been extended until the <strong>29th of January 2023</strong>.</p><p>Full details of the CFP can be found here: <a href="https://ukabs.org.uk/2023-conference/" rel="nofollow">https://ukabs.org.uk/2023-conference/</a></p><p>Many thanks,</p><p>Nic Newton, on behalf of the UKABS 2023 Organising Committee</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Please use the contact email address for correspondence.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:negotiatingboundaries@gmail.com">negotiatingboundaries@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://ukabs.org.uk/2023-conference/" target="_blank">https://ukabs.org.uk/2023-conference/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 19:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673073429172040</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP: Religions in Ritual, Spectacle, and Drama in the Medieval &amp; Early Modern World</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12155016/cfp-religions-ritual-spectacle-and-drama-medieval-early-modern</link>
						<dc:creator>Kristin Bezio</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-01T00:00:00-05:00">March 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology, World History / Studies, Theatre &amp; Performance History / Studies, Early Modern History and Period Studies, Medieval and Byzantine History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The journal <em>Religions </em>is hosting a Special Issue entitled “Religions in Ritual, Spectacle, and Drama in the Medieval &amp; Early Modern World,” co-edited by Drs. Kristin M.S. Bezio (University of Richmond) and Samantha Dressel (Chapman University).</p><p> The issue have proposed a final deadline of fall 2023 for publication, and we are asking for abstract proposals by March 1, 2023. Assuming all proposed abstracts fit the theme, we are hoping for initial drafted chapters by 1 July 2023 to allow time for revisions and editing before entering the production process. Final chapters will be due to Religions for peer review, etc., by 15 October 2023.</p><p> We are inviting essays that pertain, broadly speaking, to the ideas of spectacle, ritual, and drama as it relates to questions or practice of religion. We are particularly interested in essays that include global, non-white (or not only white), and non-Anglocentric (or not only Anglocentric) perspectives. </p><p>Spectacle lies at the heart of both ritual and drama, and religion is often similarly to be found at the core of both. Whether a spectacle is tied to ritualized praxis, to celebration or mourning, or to the production of a dramatic performance, elements of religious culture are often foregrounded, particularly in the medieval and early modern world.</p><p>This Special Issue aims to showcase essays that discuss the impact and depictions of religious belief and conflict in public ritual and drama throughout the medieval and early modern periods. Specifically, the issue seeks essays that cross multiple boundaries, whether religious, cultural, social, or geographical in terms of their depictions of public spectacle, whether religious, dramatic, or both. Essays in this volume should also consider the importance of their argument’s focus to larger questions of inclusion, equity, and diversity, either within the period or relative to more contemporary discussions, whether in the classroom or in the wider world. </p><p> In this Special Issue, original research articles and reviews are welcome. Research areas may include (but are not limited to) the following: religious studies, theology, literature and drama, history, art history, musicology, archaeology, or another relevant field. We ask for articles that focus on the middle ages through the early modern period (understood as flexible based on the region(s) under consideration) and specifically pertain to the focal topic of the special issue (religions in ritual, spectacle, and drama).</p><p>Please submit abstracts directly to Drs. Bezio &amp; Dressel (<a href="mailto:kbezio@richmond.edu">kbezio@richmond.edu</a> and <a href="mailto:sdressel@chapman.edu">sdressel@chapman.edu</a>) before March 1, 2023. The editors will evaluate abstracts and respond promptly with an invitation to submit chapters within two weeks of the deadline.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:kbezio@richmond.edu">kbezio@richmond.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 21:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1672987028409807</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sacred Journeys 10th Global Conference</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12154888/sacred-journeys-10th-global-conference</link>
						<dc:creator>Ian McIntosh</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-07-04T00:00:00-04:00">July 4, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-07-07T00:00:00-04:00">July 7, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Malta</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Anthropology, Cultural History / Studies, Humanities, Religious Studies and Theology, Social Sciences</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><b><span><span>Call for Papers </span></span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>More than 400 million people embark annually on pilgrimages with numbers steadily increasing. Pilgrimage is one of the most ancient practices of humankind and is associated with a great variety of religious and spiritual traditions, beliefs and sacred geographies. As</span></span><span> a global phenomenon, pilgrimage facilitates interaction between and among diverse peoples from countless cultures, occupations, and walks of life. In the 10<sup>th</sup> Global Conference, we will continue to explore pilgrimage’s personal, interpersonal, intercultural, and international dimensions. This includes s<span>imilarities and differences in the practice in Islam, Hinduism, Buddhism, Christianity, Judaism, Taoism, and other traditions, as well as secular pilgrimage. The impact of the internet and globalization, pilgrimage as protest, and pilgrimage and peace building, among others, are all topics of interest, as are the concepts of the internal pilgrimage and the journey of self-discovery.</span> Other potential topics include: (1) pilgrimage and the marketplace (2) the metaphor of the journey as explored by writers, artists, performers, and singers, including humanists and agnostics (3) pilgrimage and ‘miracles’ and the related topic of thanksgiving, and (4) ‘dark’ pilgrimages to sites of remembrance and commemoration.</span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:imcintos@iupui.edu">imcintos@iupui.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="http://www.thecn.com/SJ2014" target="_blank">http://www.theCN.com/SJ2014</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 21:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1672987028409806</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP: Swarthmore College Special Collections's Moore Research Fellowship (2023-2024)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12154655/cfp-swarthmore-college-special-collectionss-moore-research</link>
						<dc:creator>Rachel Mattson</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Fellowship</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-04-01T00:00:00-04:00">April 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Pennsylvania</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>American History / Studies, Social History / Studies, Peace History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Humanities</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Calling all scholars of Quaker history, Peace history, and allied topics! Swarthmore College Special Collections is now accepting applications for our Moore Research Fellowship for the 2023-2024 cycle.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The Margaret W. Moore and John M. Moore Research Fellowship promotes research during the academic year or summer months using the resources of the Friends Historical Library and/or the Swarthmore College Peace Collection, providing a stipend of $1,400-$5,600 to support such research. Applications are due April 1, 2023.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Please share this announcement with all who might be interested. More details and application instructions are here:  </span></span></span></span></span></span><a href="https://www.swarthmore.edu/friends-historical-library/moore-research-fellowship" rel="nofollow"><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>https://www.swarthmore.edu/friends-historical-library/moore-research-fellowship</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Questions about the application process may be directed to Celia Caust-Ellenbogen, <a href="mailto:ccauste1@swarthmore.edu">ccauste1@swarthmore.edu</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ccauste1@swarthmore.edu">ccauste1@swarthmore.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.swarthmore.edu/friends-historical-library/moore-research-fellowship" target="_blank">https://www.swarthmore.edu/friends-historical-library/moore-research-fellowship</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 21:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1672987028409805</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Avar: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Life and Society in the Ancient Near East - Open CFP for Avar 3.1</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12143401/avar%C2%A0-interdisciplinary-journal-life-and-society-ancient-near</link>
						<dc:creator>Eric M.  Trinka</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-01-03T00:00:00-05:00">January 3, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-08-01T00:00:00-04:00">August 1, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Ancient History, Middle East History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, World History / Studies, Humanities</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><strong>Call for Papers</strong></p><p><em>Avar: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Life and Society in the Ancient Near East</em></p><p> </p><p><strong>CFP Closes August 1, 2023</strong><br/><strong>Submissions: </strong><a href="https://avarjournal.com/avar/about/submissions" rel="nofollow">https://avarjournal.com/avar/about/submissions</a><br/><strong>Abstracts: </strong>The editors are glad to review an abstract to see if your paper or idea is a good fit for Avar. Feel free to send an abstract to <a href="mailto:avar@tplondon.com">avar@tplondon.com</a>.</p><p> </p><p>The editors of Avar: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Life and Society in the Ancient Near East are excited to call for submissions to an open issue (Avar 3.1).</p><p>We seek submissions with interdisciplinary approaches that explicitly adopt, adapt, or integrate theories and methodologies from within the traditional fields of ancient Near Eastern studies (i.e., archaeology, Assyriology, biblical studies, Egyptology, Hittitology, etc.), as well as from socio-anthropological and scientific disciplines.</p><p>Avar is dedicated to publishing open-access, peer-reviewed scholarship on Anatolia, Egypt, the Levant, and Mesopotamia from the third through first millennia BCE that crosses and disrupts disciplinary boundaries.</p><p>Avar accepts short notes (2,000-4,000 words) and articles (6,000-12,000 words) in English, French, German, Italian, and Spanish.</p><p>Submissions will only be accepted through <a href="https://avarjournal.com/avar/about/submissions" rel="nofollow">the submission platform</a>. Inquiries and abstracts can be sent to the editors at <a href="mailto:avar@tplondon.com">avar@tplondon.com</a>.</p><p> </p><p>To view CFPs and announcements, or to learn more about Avar, its future projects, and its editors, please visit <a href="http://avarjournal.com/" rel="nofollow">our website</a> or follow us on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/Avar_TNP" rel="nofollow">@Avar_TNP</a>.</p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><strong>Avar Editors:</strong></p><p><a href="https://cua.academia.edu/IsaacAlderman" rel="nofollow">Isaac <strong>Alderman</strong>,</a> Baruch College, USA</p><p><a href="https://brown.academia.edu/SThompson" rel="nofollow">Shane M. <strong>Thompson</strong></a>, North Carolina Wesleyan University, USA</p><p><a href="https://jmu.academia.edu/EricTrinka" rel="nofollow">Eric M. <strong>Trinka</strong></a>, Colby College, USA</p><p> </p><p><strong>ISSN</strong>: 2752-3527 (Print) <strong>ISSN</strong>: 2752-3535 (Online) | <em>Avar</em> is published twice a year in January and July.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:avar@tplondon.com">avar@tplondon.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="http://www.avarjournal.com/" target="_blank">http://www.avarjournal.com</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 20:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1672987028409804</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP: Drew University, Dean Hopper, 24 March 2023 -- &quot;Modes of Belonging: Kinships, Exile, and Translation&quot;</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12143400/cfp-drew-university-dean-hopper-24-march-2023-modes-belonging</link>
						<dc:creator>Michael Anderson</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-24T00:00:00-04:00">March 24, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>New Jersey</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Race / Ethnic Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies, Philosophy, Political Science</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Modes of Belonging: Kinship, Exile, and Translation </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>In a time of constant fatigue and anxiety caused by economic, political, and climatic catastrophic events, we are faced by dilemmas that are at their core about belonging. Take, for instance, the current focus on Ukrainian refugees and how they have been received differently than Syrian refugees. While in the latter case, we are told of a “refugee crisis,” the former is perceived as a duty Europe owes to Ukrainians because they are Europeans. In other words, Ukrainians “belong” in Europe.The present moment, therefore, calls for a historization and reimagination of major concepts in our debates about belonging. </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>To complicate this concept, we turn to interdisciplinary work that employs ideas of translation, kinship, exile, and diaspora to expose the elasticity of “belonging.” For instance, we ask what understandings of belonging have contributed to the hostile discourse we witness regarding immigration? How might politicians have shaped this discourse? Some scholars, such as Keguro Macharia, have named how political leaders rely on biological kinship and other “genealogical models to generate social and cultural legibility,” to gird up national collective identity and sympathies. Yet, in doing so, they often perniciously privilege “reproductive heteronormativity” at the expense of other forms of belonging or relationality. </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>We may also think of exile and diaspora as an alternative site that complicates our theorizing of belonging. In </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Reflections on Exile and Other Essays</span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>, Edward Said writes, “Exile is… the unbearable rift forced between a human being and a native place, between the self and its true home: its essential sadness can never be surmounted.” One interpretation of this statement might suggest that Said is reinforcing an idea that one only belongs to their place of birth or their “native place.” What might be a way to think about exile beyond this notion of “insurmountable uprootedness”? Following Mary Jacobus, we consider whether belonging must be intimately bound up with a notion of a past home. Her use of “translation” as a mode of analysis highlights how, far from simply being an instance of moving “from one language to another,” translation is also moving “from one place to another–translocation.” Translation enables the experience of “becoming foreign” that gestures toward a cosmopolitan vision of a world without borders. Thus, rather than exploring a melancholic return to the past home, what might be produced when we take, as Nadia Ellis suggests, an utopian diasporic horizon as our imaginary for belonging? </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The 10th annual Dean Hopper Conference of Spring 2023 (March 24) will examine these and related questions, seeking interdisciplinary engagements with the notion of “belonging” in cultural, historical, political, and theoretical contexts. We invite papers engaging with the intellectual and cultural history of belonging, and related topics like home, kinships, translation, exile, migration, both from historians and other scholars and from activists working in the field. Submissions from graduate students, postdocs, and early-career faculty are encouraged. This year’s conference will be hybrid in its modality; as such, we also welcome submissions from individuals to present via Zoom as well as in-person. </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Please send abstracts to </span></span></span></span></span></span><a href="mailto:Hopper@drew.edu"><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Hopper@drew.edu</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></a><span><span><span><span><span><span> by 11 January 2023:</span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span> The conference organizers welcome abstracts of no more than 250 words, and panel proposals of not more than 750 words. We especially welcome reflections on the following themes:</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Immigration studies</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Borders and borderlands</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Translation and translocality</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Models of kinship (genealogical, biological, ancestral, fictive, etc.)</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Exilic and postexilic writings (communal, autobiographical, etc.)</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Struggles of belonging posed by climate change and climate crises</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Refugees and the challenge of multiculturalism</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Intellectual and cultural histories of “belonging”</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Religious belonging</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Exodus: The book, its themes, and its afterlives</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Diaspora and the nation-state</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Postcolonial melancholy and utopianism</span></span></span></span></span></span></li></ul></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:hopper@drew.edu">hopper@drew.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 20:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1672987028409803</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
