<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 12:21:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 12:21:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>Methodist Studies Seminar (in person and online)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12640999/methodist-studies-seminar-person-and-online</link>
						<dc:creator>Geordan Hammond</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-05-12T00:00:00-04:00">May 12, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Methodist Studies Seminars provide an opportunity for established and emerging scholars of Methodist Studies to present the findings of their research. We conceive of Methodist Studies broadly and aim to provide opportunities for students of history, theology, literature, art, material culture and other fields related to Methodism.</p><p>The next seminar will be hosted by the Manchester Wesley Research Centre and Cliff College at Nazarene Theological College in Manchester and online on Friday 12 May 2023. There is no cost to attend, but registration is required. The registration link and seminar schedule can be found at: <a href="https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/methodist-studies-seminars" rel="nofollow">https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/methodist-studies-seminars</a>. </p><p>The conference will be on Friday 12 May from 10:00am to 4pm BST</p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Nazarene Theological College</p><p>Dene Road, Didsbury</p><p>Manchester M20 2GU</p><p>UK</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ghammond@nazarene.ac.uk">ghammond@nazarene.ac.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/methodist-studies-seminars" target="_blank">https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/methodist-studies-seminars</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 17:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680154627898615</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CfP: Baltic Orthodoxy: People, Practices, Places</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12639618/cfp-baltic-orthodoxy-people-practices-places</link>
						<dc:creator>James White</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Area Studies, Humanities, Religious Studies and Theology, Russian or Soviet History / Studies, Eastern Europe History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span>From the nineteenth century, Orthodox practices, identities, and institutions in the Baltic region have continually been rewoven to form a truly intriguing tapestry reflecting the particular perspectives and interests of a dazzling number of weavers. Initially the religion of Russian settlers, Orthodoxy attracted indigenous lower-class adherents during complex social manoeuvring between local elites and the imperial authorities. In the process, both rural and urban locales were transformed by the presence of Orthodox clergy, churches, charities, schools, and sacred narratives, some imposed from above, others created by agents on the ground. Following the devastation unleashed by the First World War and revolution, Baltic Orthodox churches and believers faced not only the formidable task of creating new institutions embodying both late imperial reform movements and new democratic trends, but also negotiating their position as minorities within avowedly secular republics. Following yet another round of destructive conflict in the Second World War, Orthodoxy in parts of the Baltic region had to confront yet another challenge, that of the militantly atheistic Soviet state, which shuttered churches, persecuted clergy and believers, and imposed strict regulations on religious activities. Today, Orthodoxy and its adherents continue to play an important role in the multicultural landscape of the modern Baltic region, adapting their faith and practices to a world thoroughly changed by digital revolution. </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Throughout this period, the Baltic region has been at the avant-garde of the changes associated with modernity. The population enjoyed levels of literacy that were impressively high compared to many countries of the time. Its transport and communication systems rapidly developed, as did the sciences, arts, and culture</span></span>: <span><span>Orthodoxy in the Baltic region has interacted with and reflected these developments. At the same time, Orthodoxy in the Baltic region was diverse, including representatives not only from ‘official Orthodoxy', but also varied Old Believer groups. </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>The study of Orthodoxy in the Baltic region has typically focused on the religion’s place within overarching political narratives – within imperial russification, as a minority faith in secular states, or as a target of Soviet persecution. Such a focus is certainly justified, but it has often led to the neglect of the everyday religious experiences of Orthodox parishioners, communities, and institutions within this multiconfessional, multiethnic, and multilinguistic region in the throes of modernization. Equally, it has led to a neglect of the agency of a variety of local groups and peoples, as such actors tend to be viewed as the recipients of projects and policies rather than active participants in them. </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Taking as its starting point a microhistorical perspective/Geertzian deep description, this proposed volume will decentralise narratives of Orthodoxy in the Baltic region and restore agency to local Orthodox actors, demonstrating how believers and communities, although not in isolation, have experienced and transformed Orthodoxy in the context of a variety of political regimes (empire, republic, Soviet federal unit, post-Soviet state) and in a period marked by modernization. <b>Contributing authors representing a variety of academic disciplines and national backgrounds will be asked to provide micro examinations of Orthodoxy in the Baltic region (Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, and Finland), choosing as their case studies individual people, communities, and practices from the nineteenth century to the present day</b>. </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>In presenting this research, this book will, for the first time in English, demonstrate the dizzying array of Orthodox experiences from a bottom-up perspective, understanding Orthodox identities as, at least in part, generated not only by central institutions but also by believers, clergymen, and communities. Orthodoxy in this volume will not be understood within a vacuum: the authors will be expected to demonstrate how individuals, communities, and practices influenced and were influenced by broader social, cultural, political, and economic trends, and how Orthodoxy affected and was affected by actors and institutions from other groups. Finally, the volume will also stress the fluid and penetrable nature of both state borders and various imagined communities, emphasising links not only between the Orthodox communities of four Baltic countries, but also connections with groups, people, and institutions in other parts of the globe. These links had and continue to have transformative potential, changing perspectives, attitudes, and the allocation of resources. </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>The contributions should consider the following questions:</span></span></b></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span>How have Baltic Orthodox actors and institutions (individuals, parish communities, schools, ecclesiastical institutions, etc.) developed (and continue to develop) in the context of religious and ethnic diversity? </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>How did/do aspects of modernity affect Orthodox communities and identities?</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>What was/is the impact of central policy (for instance, nationalizing imperial practices or Soviet anti-religious policy) on Orthodox individual and collective identities?</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>What role did/does women and gender issues play in Orthodox communities?  </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>What role has/does monasticism play in the image, identity, and attractiveness of Orthodoxy in the region?</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>How did/do connections with communities (Orthodox or otherwise) across the world transform Baltic Orthodox identities and practices?   </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>How did/do local environmental conditions affect the development of Baltic Orthodox communities? </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>How did/do Orthodox practices of conciliarity, such as the rituals and practices of self-government, develop on the level of the parish, deanery, and diocese? What conflicts did/do they provoke? </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>How did Orthodox theology change and develop in the Baltic context? How did such thought influence Baltic Orthodox praxis? </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>How did music and musical practices reflect developments in Baltic Orthodoxy?</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>In what distinctive ways did Old Believer communities, practices, and institutions develop from the nineteenth to the twenty-first centuries? How did Old Belief’s relationship with ‘official Orthodoxy’ change over this period? </span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>These questions could be studied through the following lenses: </span></span></b></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span>Biographical approaches to individuals, be they clergy or laity, Orthodox or connected with Orthodoxy; </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Focusing on an individual parish or group of parishes from a historical or anthropological/sociological perspective; </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Historical or sociological case studies examining religious institutions, including schools, parish institutions, missions, monasteries, archives, bureaucratic organs, and jurisdictions; </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Historical, ethnographic/anthropological, theological, and musicological approaches to the study of religious practices, including singing, pilgrimage, charity, cross processions, naming practices, etc. </span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span><span>This book is expected to appeal to specialists in the history and politics of states in the Baltic region, specialists in the history and contemporaneity of European religions, specialists in the lives of minority groups, interested members of the general public, and university students. </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>English-language editorial assistance will be provided to non-native speakers. </span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>Timetable for contributors</span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>1 June 2023 – Deadline for proposals (title, author details, abstracts of no more than 500 words, keywords)</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>1 July 2023 – Editorial decisions on contributors and contributions</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>30 January 2024 – Submission of draft articles</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Spring 2024 – Workshop for contributors to be held at the University of Tartu</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>1 April 2024 – Requests for revisions</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>1 September 2024 – Submission of second drafts</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>1 January 2025 – Submission of the book to the press</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>Please submit your proposal to the editors at </span></span></b><a href="mailto:irina.paert@ut.ee"><b><span><span>irina.paert@ut.ee</span></span></b></a><b><span><span>, </span></span></b><a href="mailto:liina.eek@ut.ee"><b><span><span>liina.eek@ut.ee</span></span></b></a><b><span><span>, and </span></span></b><a href="https:///C:/Users/James/Downloads/james.matthew.white@ut.ee"><b><span><span>james.matthew.white@ut.ee</span></span></b></a></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>Irina Paert (general)</span></span></b><i> </i><span><span>is an associate professor at the School of Theology and Religious Studies, University of Tartu. She has two books: <i>Old Believers, Religious Dissent and Gender in Russia, 1760-1850</i> (Manchester, 2003) and <i>Spiritual Elders: Charisma, Tradition and Orthodoxy in Imperial Russia</i> (DeKalb, 2010). She edited the collective monograph (in Russian) <i>Orthodoxy in the Baltic: Religion, Politics, Education 1840-1930 </i>(Tartu, 2018). She is PI in the research project “Orthodoxy as Solidarity: Conciliar and Popular Orthodoxy in Estonia”, funded by the Estonian Research Council. Email address: <a href="mailto:irina.paert@ut.ee">irina.paert@ut.ee</a>. </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>Liina Eek (sociology) </span></span></b><span><span>is a programme manager in Estonian Research Council and part-time researcher at the University of Tartu, School of Theology and Religious Studies, where she also defended her PhD in 2017 (“Catechesis and Beliefs among Contemporary Estonian-Speaking Orthodox”). Her research focus is contemporary Estonian-speaking Orthodox, their beliefs and views on Orthodoxy and Orthodox theology. She has edited a collection of articles about Orthodoxy in Estonia, <i>Mitut usku Eesti IV. Õigeusu eri</i>. Email address: <a href="mailto:liina.eek@ut.ee">liina.eek@ut.ee</a></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>James M. White (history)</span></span></b><i> </i><span><span>is a research fellow in church history at the University of Tartu. He published his first book,<i> Unity in Faith? Edinoverie, Russian Orthodoxy, and Old Belief, 1800-1918</i>, with Indiana University Press in 2020. His article "Russian Orthodox Monasticism in Riga Diocese, 1881-1917" won the Canadian Association of Slavists Article of the Year Award in 2020. He is the creator and runner of <a href="https:///C:/Users/James/Downloads/www.balticorthodoxy.com">www.balticorthodoxy.com</a>. Contact email address: <a href="mailto:james.matthew.white@ut.ee">james.matthew.white@ut.ee</a></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:james.matthew.white@ut.ee">james.matthew.white@ut.ee</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 17:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680154627898614</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Opportunities Digest – March 29, 2023</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-opportunities-digest-march-29-2023/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find 6 new job opportunities, 2 fellowships, 1 training, 3 awards, 3 grants, 9 Call for Papers, and 9 upcoming conferences/speakers.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 33!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Head of School: School of Humanities and Languages (Full-time,  5 yr. appointment)</h4>



<p>University of New South Wales, Australia</p>



<p>Deadline: April 11, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://external-careers.jobs.unsw.edu.au/cw/en/job/514826/head-of-school-school-of-humanities-and-languages">https://external-careers.jobs.unsw.edu.au/cw/en/job/514826/head-of-school-school-of-humanities-and-languages</a></p>



<h4>Teaching Specialist (Experiential Learning)</h4>



<p>University of Melbourne, Australia (Full-time)</p>



<p>Deadline: April 4, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=8f52a2c49f&amp;e=ea2dc4a949">https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=8f52a2c49f&amp;e=ea2dc4a949</a></p>



<h4>Union Organizer</h4>



<p>Melbourne, Australia</p>



<p>Deadline: April 4, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=57fcd63efc&amp;e=ea2dc4a949">https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=57fcd63efc&amp;e=ea2dc4a949</a></p>



<h4>University Assistant (Prae-doc) (1.5-year commitment, can be extended to 3 years)</h4>



<p>University of Vienna, Austria</p>



<p>Deadline: April 9, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://vdtr.univie.ac.at/en/admission/open-positions/">https://vdtr.univie.ac.at/en/admission/open-positions/</a></p>



<h4>Postdoctoral Research Associate (1-year term, possibility of renewal)</h4>



<p>Princeton University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: April 10, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://csr.princeton.edu/news/2023/apply-postdoc">https://csr.princeton.edu/news/2023/apply-postdoc</a></p>



<h4>Teaching Associate in Islamic Studies (Fixed term, part-time)</h4>



<p>University of Nottingham, UK</p>



<p>Deadline: April 28, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://jobs.nottingham.ac.uk/vacancy.aspx?ref=ARTS103323&amp;fbclid=IwAR18Cqj_AyOSJ2SLKhSkKV6F98RhSNpzbMUe2NGAd05QRkBwngUIRyjoJwU">https://jobs.nottingham.ac.uk/vacancy.aspx?ref=ARTS103323&amp;fbclid=IwAR18Cqj_AyOSJ2SLKhSkKV6F98RhSNpzbMUe2NGAd05QRkBwngUIRyjoJwU</a></p>



<p></p>



<h4>AAR/SBL Job Forum</h4>



<p><a href="https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search">https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search</a></p>



<h2>Fellowships:</h2>



<h4>Feinstein Center for American Jewish History</h4>



<p>Temple University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: March 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12553828/summer-fellowship-feinstein-center-american-jewish-history">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12553828/summer-fellowship-feinstein-center-american-jewish-history</a></p>



<h4>E. H Boundy Ph.D. Fellowship</h4>



<p>University of Exeter, UK</p>



<p>Deadline: June 5<sup>th</sup>, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.jobs.ac.uk/job/CYF535/eh-boundy-phd-studentship-theology-and-religion">https://www.jobs.ac.uk/job/CYF535/eh-boundy-phd-studentship-theology-and-religion</a></p>



<h2>Trainings:</h2>



<h4>Sacred Writes Summer Training Cohort (Online)</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 17, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/8Db5pa1taL">https://t.co/8Db5pa1taL</a></p>



<h2>Grants:</h2>



<h4>Outstanding Applied Research Award</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://rraweb.us10.list-manage.com/track/click?u=55bb1644f88e9457d182915ac&amp;id=a20d9da844&amp;e=c7b3861607">https://rraweb.us10.list-manage.com/track/click?u=55bb1644f88e9457d182915ac&amp;id=a20d9da844&amp;e=c7b3861607</a></p>



<h4>Constant H. Jacquet Research Awards</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://rraweb.us10.list-manage.com/track/click?u=55bb1644f88e9457d182915ac&amp;id=cbd632370a&amp;e=c7b3861607">https://rraweb.us10.list-manage.com/track/click?u=55bb1644f88e9457d182915ac&amp;id=cbd632370a&amp;e=c7b3861607</a></p>



<h4>RRA/SSSR Annual Meeting Travel</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://rraweb.us10.list-manage.com/track/click?u=55bb1644f88e9457d182915ac&amp;id=8c7664e1af&amp;e=c7b3861607">https://rraweb.us10.list-manage.com/track/click?u=55bb1644f88e9457d182915ac&amp;id=8c7664e1af&amp;e=c7b3861607</a></p>



<h2>Awards:</h2>



<h4>Excellence in the Study of Religion</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 12, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/ByvUjmGQ5r">https://t.co/ByvUjmGQ5r</a></p>



<h4>Best First Book in the History of Religions</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 12, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/ByvUjmGQ5r">https://t.co/ByvUjmGQ5r</a></p>



<h4>Religion and the Arts Book Award</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 12, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/ByvUjmGQ5r">https://t.co/ByvUjmGQ5r</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>The Afterlife in Popular Culture: <em>The Ausralasian Journal of Popular Culture</em></h4>



<p>Deadline: October 13, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12556769/cfp-afterlife-popular-culture-special-issue-australasian">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12556769/cfp-afterlife-popular-culture-special-issue-australasian</a></p>



<h4>Emerging Religious Geography of Australia</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="mailto:miriamdb@blanquerna.url.edu">miriamdb@blanquerna.url.edu</a></p>



<h4>Situating Religious Cognition</h4>



<p>Deadline: October 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/journal/religions/special_issues/7Q488424D1">https://www.mdpi.com/journal/religions/special_issues/7Q488424D1</a></p>



<h4>Society for Reformation Research: “Intercultural Reformations”</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 17, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12604235/society-reformation-research-intercultural-reformations">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12604235/society-reformation-research-intercultural-reformations</a></p>



<h4>Open Success!? Research and Publishing in Religion, Film, and Media</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://open-success.uni-graz.at/de/welcome/">https://open-success.uni-graz.at/de/welcome/</a></p>



<h4>Religion in Motion: Between Borders and Belonging</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/CfP-Religion-in-motion-NGG-conference-1.pdf</p>



<h4>New Moderate Narratives in Times of Extremism</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/109329">https://philevents.org/event/show/109329</a></p>



<h4>International Conference on the Middle Ages: Religion in Medieval Urban Europe</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12535058/international-conference-middle-ages-2023-religions-medieval">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12535058/international-conference-middle-ages-2023-religions-medieval</a></p>



<h4>Environmental Endings and Religious Futures</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 19, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://basr.ac.uk/2023/03/03/basr-annual-conference-2023-2/">BASR Annual Conference 2023</a></p>



<h2>Conferences:</h2>



<h4>Caught in the Current: British and Canadian Evangelicals in an Age of Self-Spirituality</h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>Date: April 18, 2023, 3 pm EST</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSc69xZ740Njz1g3y1_K4GljB3GMdfAHeHRpCqVX458Zi0j0cQ/viewform">“Caught in the Current: British and Canadian Evangelicals in an Age of Self-Spirituality” CSSR/CCSR Webinar Registration – Inscription pour le webinaire de la SCÉR/CCSR (google.com)</a></p>



<h4>Beyond the Black/White binary: Research on Race &amp; Congregations</h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>Date: April 13, 2023, 3 pm EST</p>



<h4>Shaping the Anthropos: Cosmologies, Mythologies, and Logics of Subjecthood</h4>



<p>Zoom or Columbia University USA</p>



<p>Date: April 7, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/0Rhvs3vfzl">https://t.co/0Rhvs3vfzl</a></p>



<h4>Colloquium on “Interreligious Interactions in South Asia”</h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>Date: April 3-12 10-11: EST</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Program_Interreligious-Interactions-in-South-Asia-1.pdf">https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Program_Interreligious-Interactions-in-South-Asia-1.pdf</a></p>



<h4>Learning Islam and Craft: Muslim Artisans’ Embodied &amp; Textual Knowledge in Colonial India</h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>Date: April 11, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/sKRb7buMtG">https://t.co/sKRb7buMtG</a></p>



<h4>Postsecular Studies, Literature, and Care</h4>



<p>University of Granada, Spain</p>



<p>Date: May 25-26, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/109513">https://philevents.org/event/show/109513</a></p>



<h4>Open Success!? Research and Publishing in Religion, Film, and Media</h4>



<p>University of Graz, Austria</p>



<p>Date: September 14-15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://open-success.uni-graz.at/de/welcome/">https://open-success.uni-graz.at/de/welcome/</a></p>



<h4>Unsettling Normality</h4>



<p>University Heidelberg, Germany</p>



<p>Deadline: September 20-22, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/109141">https://philevents.org/event/show/109141</a></p>



<h4>2023 Silber-Obrecht Lecture in Interreligious and Interfaith Studies with Francis X. Clooney, S.J.</h4>



<p>Loyola University Maryland, USA</p>



<p>Date: April 25-26, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12553960/2023-silber-obrecht-lecture-interreligious-and-interfaith">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12553960/2023-silber-obrecht-lecture-interreligious-and-interfaith</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680154627898613</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CALL FOR PAPERS | Asian Catholic Materialities</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12635051/call-papers-asian-catholic-materialities</link>
						<dc:creator>Minghua Tay</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-05-02T00:00:00-04:00">May 2, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Singapore</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology, Southeast Asian History / Studies, Anthropology, Urban Design and Planning, East Asian History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><strong>DATE OF EVENT : 30 August - 1 September 2023<br/>VENUE : Hybrid (National University of Singapore &amp; Online via Zoom)<br/>WEBSITE : <a href="https://ari.nus.edu.sg/events/catholic-materialities/" rel="nofollow">https://ari.nus.edu.sg/events/catholic-materialities/</a></strong></p><p><br/><span><strong>CALL FOR PAPERS DEADLINE: 2 MAY 2023</strong></span></p><p>This conference investigates the material forms through which Asian Catholics manifest their liturgical concerns, ecological commitment, and institutional presence, and how these material translations and negotiations participate in the making of contemporary Asia.</p><p>Historically, Asian Catholics have built outstanding hospitals, schools, and churches which have reshaped the visual landscape and material flows of Asian social spaces (Arimura 2014, Coomans 2018, Hudd 2019). Often, Asian Catholics and their objects have questioned the ways in which their surrounding society related to and conceptualized the material world. During the multi-secular Chinese rite controversy (1582-1936), Catholics have challenged the ways East Asian authorities materially perform a wide range of ritual practices which structured their political order (Mungello 1994).</p><p>But under different circumstances, Asian Catholics have also integrated and preserved indigenous understandings of the material world and its agency (Bovensiepen 2018). In parallel, Catholic networks and institutions have played a major role in introducing and circulating new knowledge and techniques about physics, botanic, agriculture, chemistry and medicine which have questioned the ways Asian societies relate to the material environment (Galipeau 2021).</p><p>Today, Asian Catholics continue to materially translate their social presence, ecological concerns, economic efforts, and religious commitments. Through the erection of new sites of devotions, cemeteries, and public institutions, Asian Catholics mobilize particular materials and designs to make their priorities tangible. Echoing to Global Catholicism conversations and elaborating on their own locally-informed cultural resources, Asian Catholics join actions to prevent climate change and preserve the environment (Palmer 2015). And the material experience, concerns, and sensibilities of Asian Catholics have far reaching influences – they participate in the contemporary production of Asian societies and Global Catholicism.</p><p>In dialogue with the material turn in religious studies and the <a href="https://www.isac-research.org/" rel="nofollow">Initiative for the Study of Asian Catholics</a>, this hybrid conference probes conceptions of Catholic materialities in contemporary Asia (Fleming 2014; Reinhardt 2016). While considering the relevance of geography, history, politics, and economy in the study of the material ideologies of Asian Catholics (Chambon 2020), the conference seeks to question the ways in which Asian Catholics participate in the material production of contemporary Asia and world Catholicism. Without essentializing and homogenizing Asian Catholic beliefs and practices, the conference will investigate ways to conceptualize Catholic cultural productions and materialities and their relations with other Asian religious traditions, economic flows, and political ideologies.</p><p>Selected papers should address one or more of the following questions:</p><ul><li>What are the materially informed practices and discourses that Asian Catholics promote today? Which worldviews about the material environment, the body, and human sociability do they encourage?</li><li>How are the architectural features of Asian Catholic hospitals, schools, cemeteries, and churches, producing various forms of Asian Catholicism and inter-religious coexistences?</li><li>Who are the individual and institutional actors involved in the production and circulations of Asian Catholic objects? How are the material translation of Asian Catholicism intersecting with on-going negotiations of gender ideologies, class, and racial identities?</li><li>How are Asian Catholics taking parts in economic flows as well as in responses to ecological crisis and climate change?</li><li>How are digital tools impacting the ways in which Asian Catholics relate to the material world and the body? How are online technologies mobilized to spread Catholic understandings of the nature?</li><li>To what extent does the flow of material objects participate in and shape the worldwide integration of Asian Catholics into global economy and world Catholicism? What are the objects circulating in and out of Asian Catholic networks? How do they shape economic flows and religious aesthetics beyond Asian Catholicism?</li></ul><p><br/>BIBLIOGRAPHY</p><p>Arimura, Rie. 2014. “The Catholic Architecture of Early Modern Japan: Between Adaptation and Christian Identity.” Japan Review 27 (27): 53–76.<br/>Judith M. 2018. <a href="https://anchor.fm/isac06/episodes/Episode---7---Judith-Bovensiepen-on-her-book---The-Land-of-Gold-Post-Conflict-Recovery-and-Cultural-Revival-in-Independent-Timor-Leste-e19094q" rel="nofollow">The Land of Gold.</a> Cornell University Press.<br/>Chambon, Michel. 2020. Making Christ Present in China: Actor-Network Theory and the Anthropology of Christianity. Cham: Palgrave Macmillan.<br/>Coomans, Thomas. 2018. “East Meets West on the Construction Site. Churches in China, 1840s-1930s.” Construction History: Journal of the Construction History Group 33 (2): 63–84.<br/>Fleming, Benjamin J. 2014. Material Culture and Asian Religions: Text, Image, Object. New York: Routledge, Taylor &amp; Francis Group.<br/>Galipeau, Brendan A. 2021. “Free in the Mountains or Home in the Vineyard: Institutional Changes in Agriculture and Negotiating Between Contract Farm Labour and Valuable Fungi Collection in Tibet.” Journal of Agrarian Change 21 (1): 143–59.<br/>Hudd, Sandra. 2019. “Revisiting Christian Missionaries in the Straits Settlements: Blurring the Boundaries Between Empire, Mission and Development.” Journal of the Malaysian Branch of the Royal Asiatic Society 92 (1): 21–39.<br/>Mungello, D. E. 1994. The Chinese Rites Controversy: Its History and Meaning. Nettetal: Steyler Verlag.<br/>Palmer, Lisa. Water Politics and Spiritual Ecology Custom, Environmental Governance and Development. New York: Routledge, 2015.<br/>Reinhardt, Bruno. “‘Don’t Make It a Doctrine’: Material Religion, Transcendence, Critique.” Anthropological Theory 16, no. 1 (2016): 75-97.</p><p><br/><strong>SUBMISSION OF PROPOSALS</strong></p><p>Paper proposals should include a title, an abstract (300 words maximum), and a brief personal biography of 150 words for submission by <strong>2 May 2023</strong>. Please also include a statement confirming that your paper has not been published or committed elsewhere, and that you are willing to revise your paper for potential inclusion in an edited book publication (in collaboration with the workshop organizers and other participants).</p><p>Please submit your proposal using the provided <a href="https://ari.nus.edu.sg/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/CFP-Proposal-Form-Catholic-Materialities-4.docx" rel="nofollow">template</a> to <a href="mailto:minghua.tay@nus.edu.sg">minghua.tay@nus.edu.sg</a>. Successful applicants will be notified by the <strong>end of May</strong>. Panel presenters will be required to submit drafts of papers (4,000-6,000) words by <strong>15 August 2023</strong>. These drafts will be circulated to fellow panelists and discussants in advance. Drafts need not be fully polished. Indeed, we expect that presenters will be open to feedback from fellow participants.</p><p>This hybrid conference will accommodate both in-person and online participants, as needed. If possible, the Asia Research Institute will provide overseas participants with full or partial airfare as well as three nights of accommodation. Please indicate in the proposal form if you require funding support.</p><p><br/><strong>CONFERENCE CONVENOR</strong></p><p><strong>Dr Michel Chambon </strong><br/>Asia Research Institute, National University of Singapore</p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><strong>Ms Minghua TAY</strong><br/>Asia Research Institute, National University of Singapore<br/>AS8 Level 7, 10 Kent Ridge Crescent, Singapore 119260<br/>Email: <a href="mailto:minghua.tay@nus.edu.sg">minghua.tay@nus.edu.sg</a><br/>Tel: (65) 6516 4224<br/>Fax: (65) 6779 1428</p><p>URL: <a href="https://ari.nus.edu.sg/upcoming-events/" rel="nofollow">https://ari.nus.edu.sg/upcoming-events/</a></p></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 20:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680068236384637</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Confraternities in the Early Modern World - CFP for sessions at 16th Century Studies Conference (Baltimore - 26-29 October 2023)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12615031/confraternities-early-modern-world-cfp-sessions-16th-century</link>
						<dc:creator>Nicholas Terpstra</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-04-10T00:00:00-04:00">April 10, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Maryland</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Early Modern History and Period Studies, Cultural History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Social History / Studies, World History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The <b>Society for Confraternity Studies </b>(SCS) invites proposals for individual papers or sessions at the 2023 annual meeting of the Sixteenth Century Society and Conference (SCSC), <b>26-29 October 2023</b> at the <b>Renaissance Baltimore Harborplace Hotel</b>.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>We are particularly interested in papers and panels that deal with the following themes: </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><i><span><span>Confraternities in the Development of Global Catholicism </span></span></i><span><span>(e.g., confraternal sociability, ritual, charity, and spirituality in Asian, African, and American settings)</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><i><span><span>Confraternities as Brokers of Collective Identities</span></span></i><span><span> (including occupational, gendered, and ‘national’ confraternities, indigenous confraternities, confraternities of the enslaved, etc.)</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><i><span><span>Artistic, Musical, or Theatrical Patronage in Confraternities</span></span></i></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><i><span><span>Open Topics</span></span></i></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Papers are limited to 20 minutes and should not have been previously published or presented at a different scholarly meeting.  Panels normally include 3 presenters.  All presenters must register for the conference if accepted.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>If you would like to submit a paper or panel or need additional information, please contact:  Nicholas Terpstra (<a href="mailto:nicholas.terpstra@utoronto.ca"><span>nicholas.terpstra@utoronto.ca</span></a>);  we’re happy to work with you as you refine your proposal.  The deadline for submission (via email) of paper and panel proposals is <b>10 April 2023</b>.  The SCS will then review papers and panels and inform applicants of its decisions before the SCSC deadline (17 April 2023).</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><i><span><span>Paper </span></span></i><span><span>proposals should include:</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span>Paper Title</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Abstract (150 words maximum)</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Presenter’s name, affiliation, and email address</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Presenter’s biography or brief CV (3-4 sentences, maximum 150 words, including rank and most important publications or evidence of scholarship)</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Whether audiovisual equipment is needed and what kind</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Whether you wish to have your paper considered for the Carl Meyer prize</span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><i><span><span>Panel</span></span></i><span><span> proposals should include:</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span>Panel title</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Abstract of the panel (300 words maximum)</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Organizer’s name, affiliation, and email address</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Chair / commentator’s name, affiliation, and email address</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>List of papers / presenters with relevant paper proposals, including all of the information noted above for each individual paper in the panel.</span></span></span></span></span></li></ul></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Nicholas Terpstra, Professor of History, University of Toronto</p><p>President, Society for Confraternity Studies</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:nicholas.terpstra@utoronto.ca">nicholas.terpstra@utoronto.ca</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 19:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680068236384636</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>35th  Annual Symposium on Jewish Civilization:    The Jewish Diaspora and  the  Promised Land</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12626824/35th-annual-symposium-jewish-civilization-jewish-diaspora-and</link>
						<dc:creator>Leonard Greenspoon</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-05-01T00:00:00-04:00">May 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The Klutznick Chair (Creighton University), the  Kripke Center (Creighton University), the  Harris  Center  (University  of  Nebraska-Lincoln), and  the Schwalb  Center (University  of  Nebraska at Omaha) announce  their 35th  Annual Symposium  on Jewish Civlization, October  22-23, 2023,  in Omaha, Nebraska.   The  title is "The  Jewish Diaspora and the  Promised Land: Origins, Developments,  Future Prospects."</p><p>Taken together, accepted  presentations will cover many time periods from  the  biblical  era to  the modern world and a range of media,  genres,  and approaches.</p><p>Support for presenters'  transportation  and accommodation will  be  provided.  Presenters  will also submit a written version  of  their presentation for  an  edited, thematic volume as part  of  the  Studies in Jewish Civilization Series  (Purdue  University  Press).</p><p>Proposals should contain a 250-word  abstract and  a CV  and be submitted by  May 1 to  Leonard  Greenspoon,  Klutznick Chair, at  <a href="mailto:ljgrn@creighton.edu">ljgrn@creighton.edu</a>.</p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Leonard  Greenspoon</p><p>Klutznick Chair  in  Jewish Civilization</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ljgrn@creighton.edu">ljgrn@creighton.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 19:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680068236384635</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ July 6, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: The International Conference on Theology of Pilgrimage</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/109685</link>
						<description><p><strong>CFP</strong></p>
<p><strong>The International Conference on “Theology of Pilgrimage”</strong></p>
<p>The Iranian Association for Philosophy of Religion (IAPR) and Astan Quds Razavi’s Foundation of Islamic Researches will hold the international conference on “Theology of Pilgrimage” on November 2023 in collaboration with various Iranian and international academic centers. This conference aims to clarify the various aspects of the theology of pilgrimage, to expand interdisciplinary studies in this field, to create an opportunity for the dialogue between Islam and other religions, and also the dialogue between Imamiyyah and other Islamic sects regarding the pilgrimage, and generally to investigate the capacities, opportunities, and threats in the field of theology of pilgrimage. Laying the groundwork for the conference, the scientific secretariat has planned to hold about 20 virtual/in-person pre-con meetings in Persian, Arabic, and English.</p>
<p>Scientific Secretary: Reza Akbari (Professor, Imam Sadiq University, Iran)</p>
<p>Executive Secretary: Roohollah Fadaei (Ph. D Graduate, Tarbiat Modares University, Iran)</p>
<p>Venue: Mashhad, Iran</p>
<p>Conference issues:</p>
<p>•                  Pilgrimage &amp; Religious Concepts (Faith, Belief, Religious Experience, Practice, etc.)<br/>•                  Theology of Pilgrimage &amp; Interdisciplinary Studies (Psychology, Ethics, Media, Economics, Politics, Anthropology, Sociology, Education, etc.)<br/>•                  Practical Theology of Pilgrimage (Family, The Women, The Elderly, The Disabled, The Sick, Charities, etc.)<br/>•                  Different Approaches to the Theology of Pilgrimage (Historical, Phenomenological, Narrative, etc.)<br/>•                  Pilgrimage in Different Religions and Cultures<br/>•                  Pathology of Pilgrimage<br/>•                  Pilgrimage and Intercultural Relationships<br/>•                  Pilgrimage &amp; Theological Anthropology<br/>•                  Topology of Pilgrimage<br/>•                  Contemporary Challenges of Pilgrimage<br/>•                  Comparative Theology of Pilgrimage</p>
<p>We are honored to host some of well-known scholars in the field of theology of pilgrimage in the scientific board:</p>
<p>·       Kathryn Barush (Graduate Theological Union/Santa Clara University)<br/>·       Joshua Hollmann (Concordia University, St. Paul)<br/>·       Andrew Petersen (University of Wales Trinity Saint David)<br/>·       Kurt Andres Richardson (University of Toronto)<br/>·       Sajjad Rizvi (University of Exeter)<br/>·       Piotr Roszak (Nicolaus Copernicus University)</p>
<p>Important Dates</p>
<p>·       Abstract submission deadline: July 6, 2023</p>
<p>·       Notification of acceptance: July 11, 2023</p>
<p>·       Paper submission deadline: September 21, 2023</p>
<p>·       Announcement of the selected papers and presentations’ schedule: October 7, 2023</p>
<p>·       Conference date: November 11-13, 2023</p>
<p>Only Ph. D holders and postgraduate students may submit abstracts and papers.</p>
<p>Abstract Features:</p>
<p>·       Abstracts should be no less than 250 words in length and no more than 300.</p>
<p>·        Abstracts should be followed by 3 to 5 keywords.</p>
<p>Paper Features:</p>
<p>·       Papers should be no less than 1500 words in length and no more than 2000 (the abstract and bibliography are not counted).</p>
<p>·       Whole text should be typed in Times New Roman font (font size: 11 for body and 9 for endnotes and bibliography).</p>
<p>·       All titles and subtitles in the paper should be arranged numerically (English numbers not Roman).</p>
<p>·       All marginal but useful and important notes should be mentioned as endnotes not footnotes.</p>
<p>·       All references (in-text and reference list) should follow the 16th edition of Chicago citation style.</p>
<p>The conference will be held both virtually and in person.</p>
<p>The conference registration and participation are free of charge. Nevertheless, Participants are responsible for organizing and paying their own travel costs to the venue of the conference as well as for their accommodation. For any further information about the conference and traveling to Iran, contact us: pilgrimagetheology@gmail.com</p>
<p>Conference website, submissions, and registration:  <a href="https://inttheopilgconf.ir/">https://inttheopilgconf.ir/</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 05:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679981838861901</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ November 11, 2023 -  November 13, 2023] Conference or similar: The International Conference on Theology of Pilgrimage</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/109681</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p><strong>CFP</strong></p>
<p><strong>The International Conference on “Theology of Pilgrimage”</strong></p>
<p>The Iranian Association for Philosophy of Religion (IAPR) and Astan Quds Razavi’s Foundation of Islamic Researches will hold the international conference on “Theology of Pilgrimage” on November 2023 in collaboration with various Iranian and international academic centers. This conference aims to clarify the various aspects of the theology of pilgrimage, to expand interdisciplinary studies in this field, to create an opportunity for the dialogue between Islam and other religions, and also the dialogue between Imamiyyah and other Islamic sects regarding the pilgrimage, and generally to investigate the capacities, opportunities, and threats in the field of theology of pilgrimage. Laying the groundwork for the conference, the scientific secretariat has planned to hold about 20 virtual/in-person pre-con meetings in Persian, Arabic, and English.</p>
<p>Scientific Secretary: Reza Akbari (Professor, Imam Sadiq University, Iran)</p>
<p>Executive Secretary: Roohollah Fadaei (Ph. D Graduate, Tarbiat Modares University, Iran)</p>
<p>Venue: Mashhad, Iran</p>
<p>Conference issues:</p>
<p>•                  Pilgrimage &amp; Religious Concepts (Faith, Belief, Religious Experience, Practice, etc.)<br/>•                  Theology of Pilgrimage &amp; Interdisciplinary Studies (Psychology, Ethics, Media, Economics, Politics, Anthropology, Sociology, Education, etc.)<br/>•                  Practical Theology of Pilgrimage (Family, The Women, The Elderly, The Disabled, The Sick, Charities, etc.)<br/>•                  Different Approaches to the Theology of Pilgrimage (Historical, Phenomenological, Narrative, etc.)<br/>•                  Pilgrimage in Different Religions and Cultures<br/>•                  Pathology of Pilgrimage<br/>•                  Pilgrimage and Intercultural Relationships<br/>•                  Pilgrimage &amp; Theological Anthropology<br/>•                  Topology of Pilgrimage<br/>•                  Contemporary Challenges of Pilgrimage<br/>•                  Comparative Theology of Pilgrimage</p>
<p>We are honored to host some of well-known scholars in the field of theology of pilgrimage in the scientific board:</p>
<p>·       Kathryn Barush (Graduate Theological Union/Santa Clara University)<br/>·       Joshua Hollmann (Concordia University, St. Paul)<br/>·       Andrew Petersen (University of Wales Trinity Saint David)<br/>·       Kurt Andres Richardson (University of Toronto)<br/>·       Sajjad Rizvi (University of Exeter)<br/>·       Piotr Roszak (Nicolaus Copernicus University)</p>
<p>Important Dates</p>
<p>·       Abstract submission deadline: July 6, 2023</p>
<p>·       Notification of acceptance: July 11, 2023</p>
<p>·       Paper submission deadline: September 21, 2023</p>
<p>·       Announcement of the selected papers and presentations’ schedule: October 7, 2023</p>
<p>·       Conference date: November 11-13, 2023</p>
<p>Only Ph. D holders and postgraduate students may submit abstracts and papers.</p>
<p>Abstract Features:</p>
<p>·       Abstracts should be no less than 250 words in length and no more than 300.</p>
<p>·        Abstracts should be followed by 3 to 5 keywords.</p>
<p>Paper Features:</p>
<p>·       Papers should be no less than 1500 words in length and no more than 2000 (the abstract and bibliography are not counted).</p>
<p>·       Whole text should be typed in Times New Roman font (font size: 11 for body and 9 for endnotes and bibliography).</p>
<p>·       All titles and subtitles in the paper should be arranged numerically (English numbers not Roman).</p>
<p>·       All marginal but useful and important notes should be mentioned as endnotes not footnotes.</p>
<p>·       All references (in-text and reference list) should follow the 16th edition of Chicago citation style.</p>
<p>The conference will be held both virtually and in person.</p>
<p>The conference registration and participation are free of charge. Nevertheless, Participants are responsible for organizing and paying their own travel costs to the venue of the conference as well as for their accommodation. For any further information about the conference and traveling to Iran, contact us: pilgrimagetheology@gmail.com</p>
<p>Conference website, submissions, and registration:  <a href="https://inttheopilgconf.ir/">https://inttheopilgconf.ir/</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 05:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679981838861900</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Saints and Mystics in Legend and Tradition</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12626038/saints-and-mystics-legend-and-tradition</link>
						<dc:creator>Jeremy Harte</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-09-02T00:00:00-04:00">September 2, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-09-03T00:00:00-04:00">September 3, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Anthropology, Cultural History / Studies, Popular Culture Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Social History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span>Where is the spring that rose where St. Alban’s blood fell? Who cares for Cuddy Ducks? Can we see Enoch and Elijah? When the Virgin fell in labour, was Romani St. Sarah at her side? How did St. Sebastian become a gay icon? Who were the Twin Saints, the Three Pure Ones, the Four Friends and the Five Major Prophets? What goes into a Dumb Cake for St. Agnes’ Eve? Does a wet St. Swithun’s day really foretell forty days of rain? Do girls still appeal to St. Andrew of the fishermen for a good catch in marriage? Can we still hear Old Clem at the hammer and the thunders of St. Barbara? Whether you weave a cross of reeds for Lá Féile Bríde, wear a daff for Dewi Sant, or bear a rose for St. George, come and join our day or we may have to call on St. Jude, patron saint of lost causes.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><i> </i></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>A two-day conference on Saints and Mystics in Legend and Tradition will be held on Saturday 2<sup>nd</sup> (St. Justus of Lyons) and Sunday 3<sup>rd</sup> (St. Gregory the Great) September 2023 at the Chapter House, St. Albans Cathedral. Anyone can join us – scholars, storytellers, hermits and hagiographers. We invite proposals about any saint, mystic, martyr or prophet. Presentations, which should be 20 minutes long, can take the form of talks, performances, or film. For more information, see </span></span></span><a href="https://folklore-society.com/events" rel="nofollow"><span><span><span>https://folklore-society.com/events</span></span></span></a><span><span><span>.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span> </span></span></p><p><span><span><span>The conference fee is £35 for speakers, £70 for others attending. </span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><span><span><span>Jeremy Harte, Bourne Hall, Spring Street, Ewell, Surrey KT17 1UF. Telephone: 020 8394 1734</span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:jrmharte@gmail.com">jrmharte@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://folklore-society.com/events/" target="_blank">https://folklore-society.com/events/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 23:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679981838861899</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>SMLT 2023 : Saints and Mystics in Legend and Tradition</title>
			<link>http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=172801&amp;copyownerid=112085</link>
						<description>Saints and Mystics in Legend and Tradition [St Albans] [Sep 2, 2023 - Sep 3, 2023]</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 05:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679895429109144</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Τ Ε Κ Μ Η Ρ Ι Α, 1  Greeks in the Archaic Age: Institutions, Interactions, Traditions</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/03/17/%CF%84-%CE%B5-%CE%BA-%CE%BC-%CE%B7-%CF%81-%CE%B9-%CE%B1-1-greeks-in-the-archaic-age-institutions-interactions-traditions</link>
						<dc:creator>Carmine Nastri</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Friday, March 24, 2023 - 9:15am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Chair of Greek History of the Department of Humanistic Studies of the University of Salerno (DipSum – Unisa)</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:tekmeria@unisa.it">tekmeria@unisa.it</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/classical-studies">classical studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/international-conferences">international conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>May 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p align="center"><strong><em>Τ</em></strong><strong><em>Ε</em></strong><strong><em>Κ</em></strong><strong><em>Μ</em></strong><strong><em>Η</em></strong><strong><em>Ρ</em></strong><strong><em>Ι</em></strong><strong><em>Α</em></strong><strong>,</strong><strong> 1</strong><strong> </strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>Greeks in the Archaic Age: Institutions, Interactions, Traditions</strong></p>
<p>Τ Ε Κ Μ Η Ρ Ι Α, 1 is a Study Meeting born from the desire of young researchers, associated to the Chair of Greek History of the Department of Humanistic Studies of the University of Salerno (DipSum – Unisa) and coming from <em>Curriculum</em> 1 of the RAMUS Doctoral Program, to create a space for exchange, dialogue, and discussion in the wake of interdisciplinarity. Before included for three years in the Series hitherto called <em>Seminari dei Giovanissimi </em>– as part of the <em>Seminari Salernitani di Storia e Storiografia Greca </em>-, the initiative now takes on an autonomous name and dedicates its first new meeting to the memory of Clara Talamo, who recently passed away. For this reason, the Call proposes the development of themes to which the Scholar was particularly sensitive, and which have connoted the research directions of the Chair. The subject of Τ Ε Κ Μ Η Ρ Ι Α, 1 will therefore be <em>Greeks in the Archaic Age: Institutions, Interactions, Traditions.</em></p>
<p>The topics of the proposals may include:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Archaic institutions of the </em>poleis<em> in the Greek Mediterranean</em></li>
<li><em>Archaic aristocracies and their traditions</em></li>
<li><em>Religiosity and cultic practices in the archaic Greek world</em></li>
<li><em>History and monumentalization in the archaic age</em></li>
<li><em>Relationships among the components of the </em>polis <em>and elaborations on them</em></li>
<li><em>Evolutions in forms of government and their historiographical reception</em></li>
<li><em>Archaic institutions in political and philosophical reflection </em></li>
<li><em>Greeks and forms of interaction in the Mediterranean: traditions and material culture</em></li>
<li><em>Aspects and phenomena of colonial societies in the Archaic age: history, archaeology, historiography from East to West</em></li>
<li><em>Greeks and non-Greeks in land of migration and colony</em></li>
<li><em>Archaic Greekness in the history of European studies</em></li>
<li><em>Compared methodologies and research approaches on the subject</em></li>
</ul>
<p>The Conference will be held, on <strong>October 10, 11, 12, 2023</strong>, in hybrid mode: in presence in the ‘Sala Conferenze del Dipartimento di Studi Umanistici’(building D3, third floor) of the University of Salerno (via Giovanni Paolo II,132, 84084 Fisciano), remotely on the Microsoft Teams platform at the link <a href="https://teams.microsoft.com/l/channel/19%3Aq_ci3pflhBSpQJJKB31-G6qjrJltgWof3eArxZFH5Uk1%40thread.tacv2/Generale?groupId=c121b357-4af3-42c1-af87-170e825bc953&amp;tenantId=c30767db-3dda-4dd4-8a4d-097d22cb99d3">https://teams.microsoft.com/l/channel/19%3aq_ci3pflhBSpQJJKB31-G6qjrJltgWof3eArxZFH5Uk1%40thread.tacv2/Generale?groupId=c121b357-4af3-42c1-af87-170e825bc953&amp;tenantId=c30767db-3dda-4dd4-8a4d-097d22cb99d3</a>.</p>
<p>Those who hold a master's degree in Classics or History or are about to obtain it, PhD students and PhDs are invited to participate.</p>
<p>To participate with a paper, it’s required to send an abstract of up to 500 words, equipped with a title, five keywords, and accompanied by a concise <em>curriculum</em> <em>vitae</em> <em>et</em> <em>studiorum</em>, <strong>by 15 May </strong>to this e-mail address: <a href="mailto:tekmeria@unisa.it">tekmeria@unisa<em>.</em>it</a> . <strong>Abstracts can be sent in Italian, English, French, German, or Spanish</strong>. Attendance in person is free: only for organizational reasons, we invite you to send us an e-mail in which you express your wish to attend; in order to attend remotely, the booking via e-mail is required by the previous day (any request to attend remotely sent during the conference will be equally admitted but may require unforeseeable technical waiting time). No registration fee is required. The Organization Committee will offer participants a courteous sign of welcome, but travel, food, and lodging expenses will be their responsibility.</p>
<p>The Study Meeting will be structured in thematic sessions. Each talk will last 30 minutes; a discussion moderated by the Session Chair will follow at the end of each session to encourage participation and collaboration on all topics. The Conference will start with an opening paper by a keynote speaker and end with a final discussion moderated by a Chair who will draw Conclusions.</p>
<p>Scientific Committee: Elisabetta Bianco (Unito), Maria Paola Castiglioni (Univ. de Grenoble), Elena Franchi (Unitn), Marina Polito (Unisa, Scientific Coordinator of the Meeting), Luigi Vecchio (Unisa).</p>
<p>Organization Committee: Carmine Nastri (Organization Coordinator), Alfredo Novello, Marianna Rago, Annalisa Savino.</p>
<p>If you require any clarification or information, you can contact the Organization Committee ( <a href="mailto:tekmeria@unisa.it">tekmeria@unisa.it</a> ).</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 11:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679722623507719</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ October 26, 2023 -  October 28, 2023] Conference or similar: Between Substance and Subject. The Presence of Spinoza in Hegel</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/109577</link>
						<description>Venue: Aškerčeva cesta 2<br/><br/><p>In the Lectures on the History of Philosophy Hegel notes that Spinoza confronts us with the fundamental alternative: Either Spinozism or no philosophy. In the Science of Logic, he affirms that the only possible refutation of Spinozism consists in first acknowledging its standpoint as essential and necessary and then raising it to a higher level out of its own resources. In philosophy one is accordingly bound to begin as a Spinozist, but it is of equal importance not to remain one. Even Hegel’s programmatic declaration in the Preface to the Phenomenology of Spirit that in his view the true must be comprehended not merely as substance but also as subject, may be read in a double reference to Spinoza: on the one hand, Hegel seems to put the task of philosophy in accepting Spinozist metaphysics and nonetheless in preserving the dimensions of freedom, beauty and life that is usually associated with subjectivity, which Spinozism is supposed to lack; according to the methodological reading, on the other hand, Hegel may be said to call for developing a new conceptual regime that would supersede the mechanistic logic of understanding, exemplified by Spinoza’s mos geometricus, into a truly Hegelian logic of reason. Hegel’s entire philosophical system can thus be understood as a prolonged argument with Spinoza that raised to prominence with the Pantheism Controversy. What is more, not only there was a time when Hegel himself defended metaphysics of one substance, it may be argued that he eventually distanced himself from Spinozist metaphysics under the influence of Spinoza’s own political philosophy. The question is, of course, to what extent Hegel’s understanding of Spinoza was correct (for instance, omnis determinatio negatio, the concept of infinity) and to what extent he read it through Jacobi or Schelling. But it is obvious that, in most various forms, Spinoza is present throughout his philosophy, be it as the ideal to match or the adversary to beat. The aim of the conference is to explore this multifaceted presence of Spinoza in Hegel. We welcome papers on any aspect of the topic and stimulate fruitful exchange between established scholars, junior researchers, and PhD students</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 05:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679636227331736</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ June 15, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Between Substance and Subject. The Presence of Spinoza in Hegel</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/109581</link>
						<description><p>In the Lectures on the History of Philosophy Hegel notes that Spinoza confronts us with the fundamental alternative: Either Spinozism or no philosophy. In the Science of Logic, he affirms that the only possible refutation of Spinozism consists in first acknowledging its standpoint as essential and necessary and then raising it to a higher level out of its own resources. In philosophy one is accordingly bound to begin as a Spinozist, but it is of equal importance not to remain one. Even Hegel’s programmatic declaration in the Preface to the Phenomenology of Spirit that in his view the true must be comprehended not merely as substance but also as subject, may be read in a double reference to Spinoza: on the one hand, Hegel seems to put the task of philosophy in accepting Spinozist metaphysics and nonetheless in preserving the dimensions of freedom, beauty and life that is usually associated with subjectivity, which Spinozism is supposed to lack; according to the methodological reading, on the other hand, Hegel may be said to call for developing a new conceptual regime that would supersede the mechanistic logic of understanding, exemplified by Spinoza’s mos geometricus, into a truly Hegelian logic of reason. Hegel’s entire philosophical system can thus be understood as a prolonged argument with Spinoza that raised to prominence with the Pantheism Controversy. What is more, not only there was a time when Hegel himself defended metaphysics of one substance, it may be argued that he eventually distanced himself from Spinozist metaphysics under the influence of Spinoza’s own political philosophy. The question is, of course, to what extent Hegel’s understanding of Spinoza was correct (for instance, omnis determinatio negatio, the concept of infinity) and to what extent he read it through Jacobi or Schelling. But it is obvious that, in most various forms, Spinoza is present throughout his philosophy, be it as the ideal to match or the adversary to beat. The aim of the conference is to explore this multifaceted presence of Spinoza in Hegel. We welcome papers on any aspect of the topic and stimulate fruitful exchange between established scholars, junior researchers, and PhD students.</p>
<p><strong>Abstracts </strong>(no more than 500 words!) should be sent as attachment to <a href="mailto:luca.illetterati@unipd.it">luca.illetterati@unipd.it</a> and <a href="mailto:zdravko.kobe@ff.uni-lj.si">zdravko.kobe@ff.uni-lj.si</a></p>
<p><strong>Abstracts </strong>should be prepared for double-blind review by removing any identification details. The author’s name, paper title, institutional position and affiliation, as well as contact information and a short CV, should be included in the body of the e-mail, with ‘Submission Hegel Network 2023’ in the subject line.</p>
<p>Information about the conference and the network will be available on <a href="https://www.speculativethought.com/">https://www.speculativethought.com</a> &amp; <a href="https://vu.nl/en/about-vu/more-about/international-network-hegel-s-relevance-in-german">https://vu.nl/en/about-vu/more-about/international-network-hegel-s-relevance-in-german</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 05:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679636227331735</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ May 21, 2023 -  May 22, 2023] Conference or similar: The Conference “In Search of a Hidden Phenomenology”</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/109541</link>
						<description>Venue: Kanonicza 9<br/><br/><p>The Department of the History of Philosophy of the Pontifical University in Kraków is pleased to invite you to The Second Conference “In Search of a Hidden Phenomenology”. The conference will focus on the variety of phenomenological methods and their application in various fields of research. The conference will be held on May 22-23, 2023 in the Senate Room (no. 200) at 9 Kanonicza Street.</p>
<p>“I” and the Other, the world of nature and the world of values, the sacred and God represent only some of the phenomena that the method initiated by Husserl and developed and modified by numerous phenomenologists sought to describe. It strove at its origins to grasp the essence of what transpires, while rejecting earlier presuppositions, theories, and speculations. But is the application of the presuppositionless method still possible in today's world dominated by scientism, and does the obvious ensure the true? Isn't the phenomenology today a method that is receding into the background of other philosophical trends, or is it itself concealed under the veil of scientificness derived from empiricism and positivism? The answers to these questions will be explored in the fields of philosophy, psychology, sociology, medicine, art and literature, and theology. Students, doctoral students, and academics are invited to contribute to this search. We will discuss not only the original understanding of phenomenology as a method and its subsequent development, but also the possibilities of its application today.</p>
<p>Should you be interested in taking part in the conference, please fill in the application form and send your paper outline in Polish or English (between 400 and 600 words) by April 30, 2023. In case of a larger number of submissions, the organizers reserve the right to select the papers. You will receive confirmation of acceptance of your paper within a few days after the submission deadline. Speeches at the conference should not exceed 20 minutes. The application form can be found at: <u>https://forms.gle/BwqV5fZzbPZVNcrf7</u></p>
<p>The conference fee is PLN 100 (lunch on one day) or PLN 200 (lunch on each day of the conference) and will also cover the cost of publication. Deadline and payment information will be provided upon acceptance of the paper to the conference. We also encourage the publication of papers in the form of scientific articles in the university's philosophical journal Logos and Ethos.</p>
<p>The organizers reserve the right to alter the formula of the event and introduce other changes dictated by current sanitary regulations. Any questions about the conference should be emailed to: konferencja.fenomenologiczna@gmail.com</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 05:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679636227331734</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
