<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 12:22:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 12:22:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>Thinking about Thinking: Modes and Developments of Second Order Thinking in Ancient Israel</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12139454/thinking-about-thinking-modes-and-developments-second-order</link>
						<dc:creator>Sara Ben-Isaac</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-15T00:00:00-04:00">March 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Ancient History, Archaeology, Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><div> </div><div>We are looking forward to welcoming Professor Konrad Schmid of Zurich to London in March 2023 for two events.</div><div> </div><div>On <strong>Wednesday 15 March</strong> Konrad Schmid will deliver the annual <strong>Ethel M. Wood Lecture</strong>, at 5 pm in the Council Room of the King’s Building in the Strand, followed by a drinks reception. He will speak on the theme ‘Thinking about Thinking: Modes and Developments of Second Order Thinking in Ancient Israel’.</div><div> </div><div><strong>On Thursday 16 </strong>March the annual<strong> KCL/UCL Hebrew Bible workshop </strong>will take place. Konrad Schmid will give the keynote lecture, addressing the question ‘How Divine Laws Became Divine: The Case of the Covenant Code (Exodus 20-23)’. The workshop will be in the River Room of the King’s Building in the Strand, from 1.30 pm to 5.30 pm, followed by a drinks reception. <strong>Proposals of short papers are invited from PhD students and early career researchers on topics within the general area of ‘The Laws in the Pentateuch</strong>’. Short paper proposals should be sent to <a href="mailto:paul.joyce@kcl.ac.uk">paul.joyce@kcl.ac.uk</a>, by the deadline of<strong> Monday 13 February</strong>. While the workshop will be an in-person event, with the networking and other benefits this brings, a hybrid option may allow for the possibility of some of the short papers to be presented remotely. </div><div> </div></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Professor Paul Joyce</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:paul.joyce@kcl.ac.uk">paul.joyce@kcl.ac.uk</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 22:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1672900626466785</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>University of Manchester-Manchester Wesley Research Centre Joint Visiting Research Fellowship</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12123279/university-manchester-manchester-wesley-research-centre-joint</link>
						<dc:creator>Geordan Hammond</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Fellowship</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-01-16T00:00:00-05:00">January 16, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>We're accepting applications for the University of Manchester-Manchester Wesley Research Centre Joint Visiting Research Fellowship. The aim of the fellowship is to promote research in the Methodist and Wesleyan traditions by facilitating scholarly access to the internationally renowned Methodist Archives held at the John Rylands Research Institute and Library in Manchester and the MWRC and Nazarene Theological College library. Applications are due by 16 January 2023. Information about other MWRC Fellowships can be found here: <a href="https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/visiting-fellows.%C2%A0" rel="nofollow">https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/visiting-fellows. </a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ghammond@nazarene.ac.uk">ghammond@nazarene.ac.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/visiting-fellows" target="_blank">https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/visiting-fellows</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 21:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1672900626466784</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Practical Theology Hub - Call for Editors</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12121772/practical-theology-hub-call-editors</link>
						<dc:creator>James Morris</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Volunteers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-31T00:00:00-04:00">March 31, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Islamic History / Studies, Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Philosophy</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>We are looking for new editors to join our editorial team!<br/><br/>At Practical Theology Hub topic editors take charge of a topic related to practical theology and within their area of expertise. Over the course of a year (January-December), topic editors are expected to source between 3-5 articles from people (academics, practitioners and students) in the field, review those articles (offering suggestions for improvement), and help to promote Practical Theology Hub on social media.</p><p>The role of a topic editor is voluntary, but it is a great way to enhance one's resume and participate in an expanding international publication and team.<br/><br/>Please send emails of interest or queries to Dr. James Harry Morris at the address provided below.<br/><br/> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr. James Harry Morris</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:editor@biapt.org">editor@biapt.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://practicaltheologyhub.com/" target="_blank">https://practicaltheologyhub.com/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 21:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1672900626466783</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CfP - EASR 2023: Practices, tools, and ecology of magic-shamanic traditions across pre-modern and modern Monsoon Asia</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12099033/cfp-easr-2023-practices-tools-and-ecology-magic-shamanic</link>
						<dc:creator>Paolo E. Rosati</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-12-27T00:00:00-05:00">December 27, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-01-31T00:00:00-05:00">January 31, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Lithuania</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Anthropology, Asian History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, South Asian History / Studies, Southeast Asian History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><div><div><div><span><span>Dear all, if you would like to present a paper during the <span><b>European Association for the Study of Religion 2023 conference </b></span>in Vilnius (4th to 8th September), and it feets with the panel</span></span></div><div><span><span><span><b>Practices, tools, and ecology of magic-shamanic traditions across pre-modern and modern Monsoon Asia</b></span></span></span></div><div><span><span>please upload your proposal thorugh EASR 20223 website <span><a href="https://www.easr2023.org/call-for-papers/?fbclid=IwAR1LnLm0ahIhzdVOE2lhusU_nbjvc0luEbwavGOCPZvkiPeC7P7SLeefvik" rel="nofollow">https://www.easr2023.org/call-for-papers/</a></span></span></span><div><div> </div></div></div><div><span><span>deadline is on 31st January 2023</span></span></div><div><span><span>or fell free to contact me at <a href="mailto:paoloe.rosati@gmail.com">paoloe.rosati@gmail.com</a> (2-3 days before the deadline)</span></span></div><div> </div><div><div><strong><span>Paper proposals must consist of:</span></strong></div><ul><li><div><span>a paper title</span></div></li><li><div><span>the name/s and email address/es of author/s</span></div></li><li><div><span>a short abstract of fewer than 300 characters</span></div></li><li><div><span>a long abstract of fewer than 300 words</span></div></li></ul></div><div> </div><div><span><span><span><b>Short abstract:</b></span> This panel aims to shed light on tools, environments and ecology of magic-shamanic contexts in mainstream Indic, tantric, vernacular, and tribal religions across Monsoon Asia. Perspective authors are expected to focus on that practices often labelled as phenomena outside the mainstream religiosity.</span></span></div><div> </div><div><span><span><span><b>Abstract: </b></span>This panel considers Monsoon Asia as a geographical area—which includes the Indian subcontinent, Tibet, mainland and maritime Southeast Asia, and Southern China—where several religious practices are shared, hence, a socio-cultural unity of the region is marked. In fact, Indic mainstream (e.g. Buddhism, Hinduism, Jainism), tantric, vernacular, and tribal religions, share several socio-religious traits whose origin could be traced back to an ancient common, and complex substratum. The resilience of magic-shamanic elements is among these common traits.</span></span></div><div><span><span>This panel aims to shed light on that (material or intangible) instruments, which have been used as ritual, magic, or shamanic tools since pre-modern history of Monsoon Asia. Indeed, usually mastering magic and shamanic powers is closely related to meditation, yogic practices, severe penances, manipulation of bodily fluids, the consumption of intoxicating substances, the use of bones and skulls as talismans, the use of ashes, mantras, spells and spell-books, geometric diagrams (such as <span><i>maṇḍala</i></span>s and <span><i>yantra</i></span>s), music instruments (particularly drums and other percussions), etc. Panel’s papers discuss in depth the role of these and other tools in magic-shamanic contexts and how they affected practices such as ecstatic possession, shapeshifting, trance and other altered states of consciousness, healing and/or harmful capacities, alchemy, divination (such as scapulimancy and plastromancy) in mainstream, tantric, folk, and tribal traditions across pre-modern and modern Monsoon Asia. Furthermore, this panel invites to analyze the ecology of magic-shamanic contexts in order to better understand the role of the <span><i>locus sacer</i></span> as a sacred space where the practitioners can cross the borders with the supra-human world or may reach the enlightenment or other transcendental states.</span></span></div><div><span><span>Perspective authors are expected to use both empirical and theoretical methodology and to engage the subject with a multidisciplinary approach, considering disciplines such as textual studies, history, art history, archaeology, ethnography, anthropology, folkloric studies, religious studies, etc.</span></span></div></div></div></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Paolo E. Rosati, PhD</p><p><a href="mailto:paoloe.rosati@gmail.com">paoloe.rosati@gmail.com</a></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:paoloe.rosati@gmail.com">paoloe.rosati@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.easr2023.org/" target="_blank">https://www.easr2023.org/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 20:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1672814227157068</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
