<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 03:39:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 03:39:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ November 4, 2022] Conference or similar: 18th Murdoch Colloquium: Philosophy, Violence, and Human Rights</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104158</link>
						<description>Venue: 90 South St<br/><br/><p><strong>Keynote speakers</strong>:</p>

<p><strong>Associate Prof Mary Anne Kenny</strong>(Law, Murdoch University)</p>

<p><strong>Prof Toby Miller</strong>(Cultural Studies, Universidad Autónoma Metropolitana, Mexico, and Murdoch University)</p>



<p>This year the Colloquium will have two sections: </p>

<p>·       A <strong>general section</strong> for papers from all areas of philosophy <br/></p>

<p>·       A <strong>special section</strong> of 4 papers on the theme “<strong>Philosophy, Violence, and Human Rights</strong>”. This section explores links between ideas and concepts in philosophy, human rights discourse and practice and violence in the broadest sense. </p>



<p>As always, we encourage contributions from all philosophical traditions, as well as from other disciplines that take into account philosophical questions. Work presented can be polished and close to publication, recently published, or work-in-progress, or non-traditional research outputs (films, etc.).</p>



<p>The Colloquium is a forum for the exchange of ideas in a supportive, collegial atmosphere. It aims to strengthen the ties between academic philosophers in Western Australia, as well as reaching out to colleagues in other disciplines, students and to the wider philosophy community. </p>



<p>The Colloquium is open to academics, undergraduate and postgraduate students. A certificate will be awarded for the best student paper. The Colloquium will be followed by drinks, nibbles and more discussion after the event. We will conclude the evening with a collegial dinner in Fremantle, location tba.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 05:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666071431673719</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Marilynne Robinson, Jesus and John Wayne, and the American Evangelical Tradition</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/10/17/marilynne-robinson-jesus-and-john-wayne-and-the-american-evangelical-tradition</link>
						<dc:creator>hapark1@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Monday, October 17, 2022 - 11:05pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>American Literature Association Conference (ALA); Boston, MA; May 25-28, 2023</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:haein.park@biola.edu">haein.park@biola.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/twentieth-century-and-beyond">twentieth century and beyond</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>November 15, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>The Marilynne Robinson Society and the American Religion and Literature Society (ARLS) will hold a joint panel at the annual American Literature Association Conference (May 25-28, 2022; Boston, MA).  We are seeking papers that examine the author’s relationship to American evangelicalism.  Robinson’s spiritual vision has been shaped by the writings of Jonathan Edwards, who is considered to be the founding father of American evangelicalism.  How does Robinson’s body of work lead us to think critically about the evangelical tradition in the United States?  How do her essays and novels, particularly <em>Gilead</em>, provide a counter-narrative to the discourses found in modern and contemporary American evangelicalism?  In what ways can they respond to the incisive diagnosis presented by Kristen Du Mez’s recent book, <em>Jesus and John Wayne</em>, a text that examines the connection between American evangelicalism, Christian nationalism, rugged masculinity, and political power? How might Robinson’s novels and essays in conversation with Du Mez’s <em>Jesus and John Wayne </em>illuminate our understanding of the evangelical tradition in the United States?  These are some of the questions that the panel seeks to address.
</p><p>Please submit a 350-word paper proposal and short bio to both <a href="mailto:haein.park@biola.edu" target="_blank">haein.park@biola.edu</a> and <a href="mailto:kludwig@bsu.edu" target="_blank">kludwig@bsu.edu</a> by November 15, 2022.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 22:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666071431673718</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FEATURED JOB: Assistant Professor (Religious Studies)- National University of Singapore</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11312765/featured-job-assistant-professor-religious-studies-national</link>
						<dc:creator>Kendra Fuller</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Home Office Notices (Jobs, Reviews)</div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Singapore</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Anthropology, Area Studies, Asian History / Studies, Cultural History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The Department of Southeast Asian Studies at the National University of Singapore invites applications for a <strong>tenure-track position</strong> at the level of <strong>Assistant Professor in Religious Studies</strong>, <strong>beginning January 2024</strong>. We are particularly interested in recruiting a scholar who will enjoy the opportunity of working collaboratively in an area studies department.</p><p>We seek a scholar who specialises in <strong>Buddhism and/or Christianity and has knowledge of other major religions</strong>. The regional focus of the position is<strong> Mainland Southeast Asia (especially Myanmar, Thailand, and/or Cambodia; Myanmar being the priority)</strong>. The disciplinary focus is wide, as we are particularly interested in applicants whose research and teaching are multi- or inter-disciplinary. In particular, we welcome applicants who have a secondary specialisation in one or more of the following fields: <strong>economics, archaeology, media and digital studies, science and technology, urban studies, and gender and sexuality studies.</strong></p><p>Candidates must demonstrate excellence in teaching, as well as strong scholarship or high scholarly potential.</p><p> </p><p>The successful candidate will be expected to:</p><ol><li>be the Convenor of the Minor in Religious Studies;</li><li>teach courses in our undergraduate and graduate programmes in their areas of specialization, and</li><li>engage in an active and innovative research agenda.</li></ol><p> </p><p>Candidates should have <strong>expertise in Southeast Asian languages relevant to their research.</strong> The standard teaching load is three modules (courses) per academic year, with an expectation that the successful candidate will also advise students. </p><p> </p><p><strong>Application Process</strong></p><p>Interested applicants should submit an application dossier consisting of the following:</p><ul><li>Cover letter explaining your interest in the position and how your qualifications and plans fit into the long-term development and enhancement of the Department of Southeast Asian Studies (maximum 2 pages)</li><li>Up to date Curriculum vitae</li><li>Concise statement of your research trajectory thus far and publication plans (1-2 pages)</li><li>Concise statement of your teaching experience and interests, as well as possible courses you are able to offer to raise the profile of the department (1-2 pages)</li><li>Concise statement describing your personal qualities and experience in collaborative and leadership roles in academic projects and community engagements (1-2 pages)</li><li>Evidence of teaching experience (course reviews, sample syllabi, teaching awards)</li><li>A list of three referees (names, contact details and applicant’s relationship to them; only shortlisted applicants will be invited to submit reference letters)  </li></ul><p> </p><p> </p><p><strong>Candidates should submit all application materials online via the <a href="https://careers.nus.edu.sg/job-invite/17642/" rel="nofollow">NUS Careers Portal</a><a href="https://careers.nus.edu.sg/job-invite/17642/" rel="nofollow"> </a>and addressed to:</strong></p><address>Chair, Search Committee</address><address>Department of Southeast Asian Studies</address><address>Faculty of Arts and Social Sciences</address><address>National University of Singapore</address><p> </p><p><strong>Application Timeline</strong></p><p>Candidates should submit all application materials by <strong>31 December 2022</strong>. We will begin evaluating candidates immediately, but the position will remain open until a suitable candidate is found.</p><p> </p><p><strong>Other Information</strong></p><p>Remuneration will be internationally competitive and commensurate with qualifications and experience. The successful candidate may also enjoy housing benefits, relocation allowance, and other benefits depending on the type and duration of appointment and citizenship.</p><hr/><p>To submit YOUR job posting, please visit the H-Net Job Guide:<a href="https://www.h-net.org/jobs" rel="nofollow"> https://www.h-net.org/jobs</a></p><p>Featured jobs receive an added boost on H-Announce and H-Net’s social media channels.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Potential candidates are welcome to get in touch with the Chair of the Search Committee to answer any questions they may have at <a href="mailto:seas.recruitment@nus.edu.sg">seas.recruitment@nus.edu.sg</a>  </p></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php" target="_blank">https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php?id=64337</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 17:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666071431673717</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Literature as Vocation</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/10/14/literature-as-vocation</link>
						<dc:creator>plbrown@apu.edu</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Monday, October 17, 2022 - 10:56pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Patricia Brown/ Western Regional Conference on Christianity and Literature</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:plbrown@apu.edu">plbrown@apu.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/english-education">english-education</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/professional-topics">professional topics</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>December 1, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p> </p>
<p>Why do we do what we do in the field of literary studies? Why does it matter? To whom? What redemptive or transformative work does literature do? When? Where? How? We invite reflection and conversation about the different kinds of work literature does to and through writers, readers, teachers, thinkers, and scholars. Our topic is intentionally broad as we seek to inspire, encourage, and celebrate the creation, interpretation, and appreciation of literature from any historical period and any genre. Our format is inclusive with panels for professors, graduate and undergraduate students, as well as scholars from multiple disciplines including English, Modern Languages, Theology, Education, Psychology, Science, and Humanities.</p>
<p>Suggested topics include but are not limited to the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>the work of <strong>re-enchantment</strong>: magical realism, refreshment, joy, delight</li>
<li>the work of <strong>transformation</strong>: secular/post-secular accounts of religious experience, narratives of conversion and de-conversion, spiritual autobiography</li>
<li>the work of <strong>empathy</strong>: emotion and affect, caregiving, accounts of suffering, grief, and illness</li>
<li>the work of <strong>social justice</strong>: remembrance, rediscovery, lament, protest, reconciliation, peace</li>
<li>the work of <strong>stewardship</strong>: ecology, creation care, apocalypse</li>
</ul>
<p>E-mail a one-paragraph abstract for an individual presentation or a one-paragraph abstract for a group panel session by <strong>December 1, 2022 </strong>to <strong>Dr. Patricia Brown </strong>at <strong><a href="mailto:plbrown@apu.edu">plbrown@apu.edu</a></strong>. Undergraduate students must submit their entire paper for consideration</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666071431673716</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP Western Jewish Studies Association Conference, Las Vegas, March 12-13, 2022</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/10/14/cfp-western-jewish-studies-association-conference-las-vegas-march-12-13-2022</link>
						<dc:creator>Lawrence Baron</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Monday, October 17, 2022 - 10:36pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Western Jewish Studies Association</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:lbaron@sdsu.edu">lbaron@sdsu.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/ethnicity-and-national-identity">ethnicity and national identity</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/film-and-television">film and television</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>November 15, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Call for paper and panel proposals on all areas of Jewish Studies regardless of discipline, geographical focus, or time period.  The WJSA usually includes panels about Jews in the American West, pedagogical aspects in Jewish Studies, and contemporary Jewish issues.  It welcomes panels devoted to the major anniversaries of events in Jewish history or important Jewish individuals in 2023, for example:</p>
<p>1993 US Holocaust Memorial Museum Opens, <em>Schindler’s List</em> Premiers                                                                                              1973 The Yom Kippur War                                                                                                                                                              1948: Israeli War of Independence                                                                                                                                                1923 Birth of Shimon Peres, British Mandate Goes into Effect, 1st Performance of <em>The Dybbuk                                                            </em>1873  Union of American Hebrew Congregations Founded                                                                                                                1848  Jews in the Revolutions of 1848                                                                                                                                            1648  Chmielnicki Pogroms                                                                                                                                           </p>
<p>Paper proposals should be no longer than one double-spaced typed page and should be submitted with a short CV that contains contact information. The submission of panels on a common topic is encouraged.  Organizers of panels should submit a cover sheet with the title of the panel and the titles of each of the papers and contact information for each presenter, followed by the individual paper proposals and brief CVs.  Scholars of Jewish Studies including graduate students are invited to submit proposals for papers/presentations/workshops.  A limited number of modest stipends are available for graduate students and overseas scholars who will be presenting papers.  Individuals wishing to chair a session should submit their CV.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Although it is planning for an in-person conference, the WJSA will feature virtual panels.  If you want to present virtually, you are encouraged to form a panel with other likeminded presenters.  Individual virtual proposals will only be accepted if a thematically coherent virtual panel can be formed with other proposals or if the COVID situation necessitates the holding of the conference virtually.       </p>
<p> </p>
<p>The WJSA annually awards the Baron Award to the best student paper presented at the conference. The winner receives $200.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Although there is no WSJA membership requirement for participation in the conference, a higher registration fee is charged for non-members. </p>
<p> </p>
<p>Proposals should be emailed to Lawrence Baron at: <a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/blank">lbaron@mail.sdsu.edu</a>   The deadline for submission of proposals is <strong>November 15, 2022</strong>.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666071431673715</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ October 31, 2022] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104126</link>
						<description>Publication Name: Call for Papers: The Somatechnics of Violence: Affective, (Im)material and Digital Transformations<br/><br/><p><em><strong>Call for Papers: The Somatechnics of Violence: Affective, (Im)material and Digital Transformations </strong></em></p>
<p><em>Special issue editors: Evelien Geerts (University of Birmingham), Chantelle Gray (North-West University) &amp; Delphi Carstens (University of the Western Cape)</em><br/><br/>A growing number of philosophical studies are arguing for new frameworks from which to theorise and grapple with contemporary forms of violence that escape the overdetermined representations thereof that ensued in the decade or so following 9/11 – which Jeffrey Di Leo and Uppinder Mehan aptly called critical ‘theory’s “ground zero”’ (2012: 16). While it is true that these attacks transformed current-day perceptions and theorisations of violence, the ensuing so-called Wars on Terror led to reductionist treatments thereof, thereby eliding the incredibly complex, multi-layered and lived phenomenon that violence is and which cannot be captured in universal frameworks but must, instead, be situated in its material, immaterial, affective and now digital contexts.<br/><br/>Such situated philosophical analyses of violence require a different vocabulary and world-reimagining methodologies: it is, we hold, no longer sufficient to merely address the impact that violence currently has through, for example, the Foucauldian (1980) idea of the apparatus – a contextual arrangement of discursive-material phenomena diagramming, and thus maintaining societal power relations, while shaping subjects. Neither does the Harawayan (1988: 591) ‘apparatus of bodily production’, which pays more attention to the intersecting lived categories of gender, race/ethnicity, sexuality and so on, suffice as an analytical instrument. Although both Foucault and Haraway accurately theorise the differential mattering of embodied subjects and the violence inflicted during processes of (non-)mattering, today’s societies, together with the myriad ways in which violence manifests itself, are rapidly changing. Driven by neoliberal governmentality, extractive capitalism and contemporary (counter-) terrorism, present-day societies of hyper-control are plagued by violent threats from multiple, often crisscrossing, directions engendered by interlinked macrostructures and microevents that combine the (im)material, discursive, digital and affective. We may think here, for example, of the violent – yet insufficiently emphasised – damage inflicted by white supremacy, institutionalised racism and racist microaggressions; the mob-inciting divisive rhetoric of neo-fascist populists pushing for alt-facts and alt-realities; the increase in affective disorders, driven by what Mark Fisher (2009) calls capitalist realism; material-immaterial infowars engendering algorithmic violence, fittingly described by Mimi Onuoha as ‘violence that an algorithm or automated decision-making system inflicts by preventing people from meeting their basic needs’ (2018: n. p.; also see Noble 2018; Bellanova et al. 2021); or the Anthropogenic-Capitalogenic ecocide unfolding itself and impacting transcorporeally entangled human and more-than-human worlds (see Alaimo 2016).<br/><br/>It would seem, then, that novel analytical perspectives are needed and this, as we would like to propose, can be found in what Joseph Pugliese and Susan Stryker (2009: 2-3), inspired by Foucault, have identified as a ‘somatechnical assemblage’. Initially intimated by Nikki Sullivan (2005), but further developed by Joseph Pugliese and Susan Stryker, and later on also by Sullivan and Samantha Murray (2011: v) and Line Henriksen and Marietta Radomska (2015), somatechnics stands for ‘the materialisation of embodied being[s]’ or how they come to matter through processes of material-discursive-affective meaning-making. Bringing together the corporeal and the technological – which, according to a somatechnical perspective, are always already enmeshed – a somatechnics-focused analytical framework zooms in on the (un)making and (de)humanisation of corporeal beings, all while creating space for a much-needed ethico-political critique of the various types of violence these corporeal beings are forced to endure.<br/><br/>While we are open to a variety of frameworks and methodologies from which to theorise violence, we encourage special issue contributors to think beyond so-called shifts and similar epistemological paradigms that follow a logic of tracing – a way of thinking that fixes phenomena by means of neatly organised structures and representations (see Deleuze and Guattari 2005 for this critique). The reason for this is that we, in somatechnical fashion, would like to emphasise the entangled nature of the corporeal, incorporeal and the technological; the micro and the macro; as well as of humans, the more-than-human and the dehumanised – aspects brought into sharp focus by, for example, critical new materialist, posthumanist and Deleuzoguattarian philosophies (see e.g., Chen 2012; Braidotti 2013; Shotwell 2016). Or as Elizabeth Grosz has put it: When analysing violence, ‘the incorporeal conditions of corporeality, the excesses beyond and within corporeality that frame, orient and direct material things and processes’ need to be examined in relation to corporeality and material (infra)structures (Grosz 2017; Grosz in Grosz and Bell 2017: 5).<br/><br/><strong>Suggested topics:</strong><br/>• The somatechnics of violence (with a focus on the embodied and more-than-bodily lived experience of violence, and that on either a collective or individual level);<br/>• the (im)materiality of violence – political or other (e.g., disposability, dispossession, (neo-) colonialism, extractive capitalism and environmental violence, (bio-/)necropolitics in relation to somatechnics, which bodies come to matter and not matter through violence and its traumas, …);<br/>• (im)material violence, the affective and the hauntological;<br/>• somatechnics-focused, critical new materialist, posthumanist and/or Deleuzoguattarian perspectives on violence;<br/>• somatechnics-focused, critical cartographical and other related methodological takes on violence;<br/>• the somatechnics of violence related to new digital realities;<br/>• the somatechnics of violence in relation to identity politics; populist and (neo-)fascist politics and political ressentiment; infowars, alt-facts and alt-realities; algorithmic violence and/or other manifestations of digital violence – and the concrete impact the latter phenomena have on (individual and/or collective) embodied subjects, groups and entities.<br/><br/><u>1This call for papers is connected to the ERC-sponsored “Urban Terrorism in Europe (2004-19): Remembering, Imagining, and Anticipating Violence” project at the University of Birmingham (ERC-2019-STG 851329) and the November 2021 “(Im)materialities of Violence” conference.</u><br/><br/><br/><strong>Timeline &amp; submission details:</strong><br/><em><u><strong>Abstract submission: October 31st, 2022</strong></u></em><br/><br/>• Abstract acceptance/rejection notification: mid-November 2022<br/>• Manuscript submission: March 31st, 2023<br/>• Peer reviews received: May 31st, 2023<br/>• Revised manuscripts due: August 31st, 2023<br/>• Final manuscript due to EUP: November 30th, 2023<br/><br/>We invite potential contributors to submit an abstract of 500 words by the 31st of October 2022. Please include the contact details and biographies (not included in the word count) of all of the contributors on the abstract document. Abstracts (and manuscripts) must be formatted according to Somatechnics’ author guidelines.<br/><br/>Please note that the initial acceptance of an abstract does not guarantee publication and that all manuscripts will undergo a double-blind review process. We strive toward diversity among our contributors in terms of career-stage, disciplines, self-identification and affiliation. We are happy to accommodate different accessibility needs. Please get in touch with (one of) the guest editors for any of these issues.<br/><br/>The author(s) should email their abstract proposal as a Word file to all of the guest editors: geerts.evelien@gmail.com, gray.chantelle@gmail.com, carstensdelphi@gmail.com. For more information, contact the guest editors.<br/><br/><strong>More about the journal:</strong><br/><em>Somatechnics: Journal of Bodies – Technologies – Power</em> is a journal that provides a forum for research on all things relating to ‘the body’, critically engaging with the technological, ethical and political implications of a wide range of practices, techniques and academic spaces. Articles present innovative debates in topics such as spatialization, race, reproduction, gender, sexuality, medicine, consumption, gaming, film, globalization, ecology, bioscience, family, education, health, visuality and more.<br/><br/><strong>More about the special issue editors:</strong><br/>Evelien Geerts (Ph.D.) is a multidisciplinary philosopher, a Research Fellow at the University of Birmingham and a Posthumanities Hub affiliated researcher. She holds a Ph.D. in Feminist Studies and History of Consciousness from the University of California, Santa Cruz. Her research interests include new materialist, posthumanist and Deleuzoguattarian philosophy, critical epistemologies, political philosophical questions of identity, difference, and violence, and critical and diffractive pedagogies. She previously has published in, amongst others, Philosophy Today, Women’s Studies International Forum, and Rhizomes—publications that can be found at www.eveliengeerts.com.<br/><br/>Chantelle Gray (Ph.D.) is a contemporary Continental philosopher whose interests span critical algorithm studies, queer theory and gender studies, cognitive studies, anarchism and Continental philosophy, especially the work of Deleuze and Guattari. The interdisciplinary nature of her work allows her to ask critical questions about how to take care of humans, technologies and ecologies in the digital age. She is the co-convener of the biennial South African Deleuze &amp; Guattari Studies Conference (www.deleuzeguattari.co.za) and serves on the editorial boards of <em>Somatechnics</em> and <em>Stilet</em>. Her books include <em>Deleuze and Anarchism</em>, co-edited with Aragorn Eloff (2019, Edinburgh University Press) and <em>Anarchism after Deleuze and Guattari</em> (2022, Bloomsbury). <br/><br/>Delphi Carstens (Ph.D.) is a Lecturer at the University of the Western Cape, South Africa. His research interests include the Anthropocene/Capitalocene, Deleuzoguattarian pedagogical interventions, uncanny science fictions and sorcerous new materialisms. His publications include, amongst others, chapters in edited volumes by Palgrave, Sternberg, Bloomsbury and Taylor and Francis as well as journal articles in <em>The South African Journal of Higher Education</em> (SAJHE), <em>Education as Change</em>, <em>Alternation</em>, <em>CriSTal</em>, <em>parallax</em> and <em>Somatechnics</em>.</p>
<p><strong>References used:</strong><br/>Alaimo, Stacy (2016), <em>Exposed: Environmental Politics and Pleasures in Posthuman Times</em>, Minneapolis: University of Minnesota Press.<br/>Bellanova, Rocco, Kristina Irion, Katja Lindskov Jacobsen, Francesco Ragazzi, Rune Saugmann and Lucy Suchman (2021), ‘Toward a Critique of Algorithmic Violence”, <em>International Political Sociology</em>, 15: 1, pp. 121–150. 10.1093/ips/olab003.<br/>Braidotti, Rosi (2013), <em>The Posthuman</em>, Cambridge: Polity Press.<br/>Chen, Mel Y. (2012), <em>Animacies: Biopolitics, Racial Mattering, and Queer Affect</em>, Durham: Duke University Press.<br/>Deleuze, Gilles and Félix Guattari (2005), <em>A Thousand Plateaus: Capitalism and Schizophrenia</em>, Translation and Foreword by Brian Massumi. Minneapolis: University of Minnesota Press.<br/>Di Leo, Jeffrey R. and Uppinder Mehan (eds.) (2012), <em>Terror, Theory and the Humanities</em>, Ann Arbor: Open Humanities Press. An imprint of MPublishing–University of Michigan Library.<br/>Fisher, Mark (2009), <em>Capitalist Realism: Is There No Alternative?</em>, Winchester: Zero Books.<br/>Foucault, Michel (1980), ‘The Confession of the Flesh’, in <em>Power/Knowledge: Selected Interviews and Other Writings,</em> 1972–1977. Translated by Colin Gordon. Brighton: Harvester, pp. 194–228.<br/>Grosz, Elizabeth (2017), <em>Incorporeal: Ontology, Ethics, and the Limits of Materialism</em>, New York: Columbia University Press.<br/>Grosz, Elizabeth, and Vikki Bell (2017), ‘An Interview with Elizabeth Grosz: ‘“The Incorporeal”’, <em>Theory, Culture &amp; Society</em>, 34: 7–8, pp. 237–243. 10.1177/0263276417736814.<br/>Haraway, Donna J. (1988), ‘Situated Knowledges: The Science Question in Feminism and the Privilege of Partial Perspective,’ <em>Feminist Studies</em>, 14: 3, pp. 575–599. 10.2307/3178066.<br/>Henriksen, Line and Marietta Radomska (2015), ‘Missing Links and Non/Human Queerings: An Introduction,’ <em>Somatechnics</em>, 5: 2, pp. 113–119. 10.3366/soma.2015.0156.<br/>Noble, Safiya U. (2018), <em>Algorithms of Oppression: How Search Engines Reinforce Racism</em>, New York: NYU Press.<br/>Onuoha, Mimi (2018, February 22), ‘On Algorithmic Violence’, GitHub. https://github.com/MimiOnuoha/On-Algorithmic-Violence.<br/>Pugliese, Joseph and Susan Stryker (2009). ‘The Somatechnics of Race and Whiteness,’ <em>Social Semiotics</em>, 19: 1, pp. 1–8. 10.1080/10350330802632741.<br/>Shotwell, Alexis (2016), <em>Against Purity: Living Ethically in Compromised Times</em>, Minneapolis: The University of Minnesota Press.<br/>Sullivan, Nikki (2005), ‘Somatechnics, or, the Social Inscription of bodies and Selves,’ <em>Australian Feminist Studies</em>, 20: 48, pp. 363–366. 10.1080/08164640500280274.<br/>Sullivan, Nikki and Samantha Murray (2011), ‘Editorial,’ <em>Somatechnics</em>, 1: 1, pp. v–vii.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 05:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1665898633218707</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ June 2, 2023 -  June 4, 2023] Conference or similar: Intuition, Creation, Duration, and Relativity</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104130</link>
						<description>Venue: 5998 Alcala Park<br/><br/><p>The North American Society for Early Phenomenology invites abstracts for papers on phenomenological work related to intuition, creation, duration, and relativity for our annual conference.</p>
<p>In the phenomenological rejection of both rationalism and empiricism, the concepts of intuition, creation, duration and relativity pervade the work of early phenomenologists. For this conference, we invite work on these concepts, with special attention to Henri Bergson’s influence on phenomenology, along with contemporary work related to these concepts. Scholarly papers on the history of phenomenology are welcomed alongside work developed with an awareness of the method of reductions common to early phenomenologists. For example, intuition and how Husserl adapted it to the reception of the <em>eidos</em> his developing exegesis of the phenomenological method of reductions, creation and its attendant metaphysics, freedom and determinism, open and closed morality, static and dynamic religion, order and chaos, time and its relation to consciousness, and relativity in conversation with scientific pursuits, change, movement, unity and multiplicity—all of these phenomenological concepts bespeak a metaphysics (or perhaps epistemology) that diverges from more well-known analytic counterparts.  </p>
<p>As always, we encourage submissions dealing with the thought of the full spectrum of early phenomenologists (including Edmund Husserl, Franz Brentano, Carl Stumpf, Theodor Lipps, Alexander Pfänder, Max Scheler, Moritz Geiger, Hedwig Conrad-Martius, Eugen Fink, Roman Ingarden, Edith Stein, Dietrich Von Hildebrand, Adolf Reinach, Maximilian Beck, Jean Hering, Henri Bergson, Emmanuel Levinas, et al.) as well as figures who were in conversation with or influenced the early phenomenological movement (Ravaisson, Kierkegaard, Nietzsche, etc).</p>
<p>We especially encourage submissions from individuals who identify as members of groups currently underrepresented in philosophy and academia more generally.</p>
<p><strong>Abstracts</strong> should be <strong>400-600 words</strong> and include a short bibliography. Abstracts must be prepared for blind review and sent to Charlene Elsby (<u>celsby@ingarden.org</u>).</p>
<p><strong>Deadline</strong> for submissions is <strong>February 1th, 2023.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Decisions</strong> will be sent out no later than <strong>March 1st, 2023.</strong></p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 05:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1665898633218706</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ February 1, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Intuition, Creation, Duration, and Relativity</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104134</link>
						<description><p>The North American Society for Early Phenomenology invites abstracts for papers on phenomenological work related to intuition, creation, duration, and relativity for our annual conference.</p>
<p>In the phenomenological rejection of both rationalism and empiricism, the concepts of intuition, creation, duration and relativity pervade the work of early phenomenologists. For this conference, we invite work on these concepts, with special attention to Henri Bergson’s influence on phenomenology, along with contemporary work related to these concepts. Scholarly papers on the history of phenomenology are welcomed alongside work developed with an awareness of the method of reductions common to early phenomenologists. For example, intuition and how Husserl adapted it to the reception of the <em>eidos</em> his developing exegesis of the phenomenological method of reductions, creation and its attendant metaphysics, freedom and determinism, open and closed morality, static and dynamic religion, order and chaos, time and its relation to consciousness, and relativity in conversation with scientific pursuits, change, movement, unity and multiplicity—all of these phenomenological concepts bespeak a metaphysics (or perhaps epistemology) that diverges from more well-known analytic counterparts.  </p>
<p>As always, we encourage submissions dealing with the thought of the full spectrum of early phenomenologists (including Edmund Husserl, Franz Brentano, Carl Stumpf, Theodor Lipps, Alexander Pfänder, Max Scheler, Moritz Geiger, Hedwig Conrad-Martius, Eugen Fink, Roman Ingarden, Edith Stein, Dietrich Von Hildebrand, Adolf Reinach, Maximilian Beck, Jean Hering, Henri Bergson, Emmanuel Levinas, et al.) as well as figures who were in conversation with or influenced the early phenomenological movement (Ravaisson, Kierkegaard, Nietzsche, etc).</p>
<p>We especially encourage submissions from individuals who identify as members of groups currently underrepresented in philosophy and academia more generally.</p>
<p><strong>Abstracts</strong> should be <strong>400-600 words</strong> and include a short bibliography. Abstracts must be prepared for blind review and sent to Charlene Elsby (<u>celsby@ingarden.org</u>).</p>
<p><strong>Deadline</strong> for submissions is <strong>February 1th, 2023.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Decisions</strong> will be sent out no later than <strong>March 1st, 2023.</strong></p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 05:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1665898633218705</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFA: The Robert H. N. Ho Family Foundation Program in Buddhist Studies</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11277202/cfa-robert-h-n-ho-family-foundation-program-buddhist-studies</link>
						<dc:creator>Ryan Cuthbert</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Fellowship</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-01-11T00:00:00-05:00">January 11, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Asian History / Studies, East Asian History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, South Asian History / Studies, Southeast Asian History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><table><tr><td><h2><strong>The Robert H. N. Ho Family Foundation </strong><br/><b><strong>Program in Buddhist Studies</strong><br/><br/><em>Now Accepting Applications for 2022-23 </em><br/><i><em>Fellowship and Grant Competitions</em></i></b></h2></td></tr><tr><td><p>The American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS) invites applications for <a href="https://www.acls.org/programs/robert-h-n-ho-family-foundation-in-buddhist-studies/" rel="nofollow">The Robert H. N. Ho Family Foundation Program in Buddhist Studies</a> 2022-23 competitions. In cooperation with the Foundation, ACLS awards fellowships and grants supporting work that will expand the understanding and interpretation of Buddhist thought in scholarship and society, strengthen international networks of Buddhist scholars, and increase the visibility of new knowledge and research on Buddhist traditions.  </p><table><tr><td><p><strong>Worldwide Scope</strong><br/>These are global competitions.  All scholars – anywhere in the world – who are engaged in the study of any aspect of Buddhist traditions are welcome to apply. There are no restrictions as to the location of work proposed or the citizenship of applicants. </p><p> </p><p><b>Eligible scholars at Asian universities and monastic institutions are especially encouraged to apply.</b><br/><br/>Applications must be submitted in English, but the written work produced by the fellow or grantee can be in any language. Work proposed must be in <a href="https://www.acls.org/faqs/acls-faq/" rel="nofollow">the humanities and interpretive social sciences</a> and must employ humanistic approaches and methods.<br/><br/><strong>Awards</strong> </p><ul><li><a href="https://www.acls.org/competitions/the-robert-h-n-ho-family-foundation-dissertation-fellowships-in-buddhist-studies/" rel="nofollow"><strong>Dissertation Fellowships</strong></a>: One-year stipends to PhD candidates for full-time preparation of dissertations.</li><li><a href="https://www.acls.org/competitions/robert-h-n-ho-early-career/" rel="nofollow"><strong>Early Career Research Fellowships</strong></a>: One-year stipends to pre-tenure scholars for research and writing.</li><li><a href="https://www.acls.org/competitions/the-robert-h-n-ho-family-foundation-translation-grants-in-buddhist-studies/" rel="nofollow"><strong>Translation Grants in Buddhist Studies</strong></a>: One-year awards supporting collaborative or individual projects for translations of important texts in order to make them available to communities of scholarship and Buddhist practice.</li><li><a href="https://www.acls.org/competitions/the-robert-h-n-ho-family-foundation-new-professorships-in-buddhist-studies/" rel="nofollow"><strong>New Professorships</strong></a>: Multiyear grants to colleges and universities to establish new teaching positions in Buddhist studies.</li><li><strong><a href="https://www.acls.org/competitions/the-robert-h-n-ho-family-foundation-buddhism-public-scholars/" rel="nofollow">Buddhism Public Scholars</a></strong><b>:</b> Awards of up to two years to place early career scholars in positions at museums and publishers. These positions are initially one-year placements that are renewable for a second year. Host institutions will be announced in the fall.</li></ul><p><strong>Deadlines</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Fellowships and Grants - November 16, 2022</strong></li><li><strong>New Professorships Awards to Institutions and Buddhism Public Scholars - January 11, 2023</strong></li></ul><p><br/><i>The Robert H. N. Ho Family Foundation Program in Buddhist Studies, administered by ACLS, is committed to inclusion, equity, and diversity as integral components of merit that enhance the scholarly enterprise. It is a</i> <i>priority of this program that cohorts of fellows and grantees be broadly inclusive of different backgrounds and cultures, as well as in languages of study, topics, Buddhist traditions, and locations of research.</i><br/><strong> </strong><br/><strong>Questions?  Contact us at </strong><a href="mailto:BuddhistStudies@acls.org?subject=Questions%20About%20the%20Buddhist%20Studies%20Program">BuddhistStudies@acls.org</a><strong>.</strong></p></td></tr></table></td></tr></table></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><strong>Questions?  Contact us at </strong><a href="mailto:BuddhistStudies@acls.org?subject=Questions%20About%20the%20Buddhist%20Studies%20Program">BuddhistStudies@acls.org</a><strong>.</strong></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:BuddhistStudies@acls.org">BuddhistStudies@acls.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.acls.org/programs/robert-h-n-ho-family-foundation-in-buddhist-studies/" target="_blank">https://www.acls.org/programs/robert-h-n-ho-family-foundation-in-buddhist-studies/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 17:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1665812232263379</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Theophron Spring 2023: Vice, Virtue, &amp; Disagreement</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11253053/theophron-spring-2023-vice-virtue-disagreement</link>
						<dc:creator>Cameron  Hurta</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-12T00:00:00-05:00">February 12, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Ancient History, Intellectual History, Philosophy, Religious Studies and Theology, Sociology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><em>Theophron</em> <em>Journal of Christian Studies </em>is a multidisciplinary, double-blind peer reviewed journal based in Princeton, NJ. Below is our spring 2023 call: Vice, Virtue, &amp; Disagreement </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Taken narrowly, vice and virtue comprise both central considerations of virtue ethical theories and peripheral considerations of any sophisticated normative ethics—that is, all plausible normative ethics will comment on vice and virtue in some manner. Taken broadly, the terms relate to goodness and badness, righteousness and evil, morality and depravity, inculcation and elimination. In each of these conjunctions, conflict stands at the forefront. Similar tensions manifest across theory and lived experience, from disagreement and wars to schisms and debates on the very existence of God. The interplay of vice, virtue, and conflict, then, occasions inquiry into the facets of life in a broken world and faith in the One who alone is perfect. </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>With this topic in mind, we</span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span> </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>invite undergraduate and graduate students, as well as early-career post-docs, to submit to </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Theophron</span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>’s spring 2023 issue. Scholarship from all fields, particularly philosophy, theology, history, and biblical studies, is welcome. </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Possible topics include but are certainly not limited to:  </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Epistemology of Religious or Moral Disagreement </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Historical Christian Responses to Global Strife </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Virtue’s Role in Christian Discipleship across Traditions </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Prophetic &amp; Apostolic Responses to Political-Religious Tensions</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Moral Arguments for God’s Existence</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Just War Theory &amp; Pacifism in World War II </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Early Church Understandings of Spiritual Conflict</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Metaethics and Theories of Sin</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Protestant, Catholic, &amp; Orthodox Views of Vice </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Historical Case Studies on Christian Moral Disagreement </span></span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Submission Instructions</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Submissions should be between </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>4,000–6,500 words </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>(not including abstract), conform to the </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Chicago Manual of Style </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>(17</span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span><sup>th</sup></span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span> edition), and be original, unpublished works prepared for double-blind peer review. Please include an abstract of no more than 250 words, uploading the entire manuscript in both PDF and .docx formats at </span></span></span></span></span></span><a href="http://www.theophron.org/submissions" rel="nofollow"><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>www.theophron.org/submissions</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></a><span><span><span><span><span><span>. </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Do not place your name or any identifying information on the submitted manuscript</span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>—author identities will remain anonymous to reviewers and editors until after final acceptance/rejection decisions.  </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Submissions received by </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>February 12, 2023</span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>,</span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span> </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>will be considered for publication. </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Direct all questions to </span></span></span></span></span></span><a><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>submissions@theophron.org</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></a><span><span><span><span><span><span>.</span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span>Visit </span></span></span></span></span></span><a href="http://www.theophron.org/" rel="nofollow"><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>theophron.org</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></a><span><span><span><span><span><span> for all live calls for papers, including our annual open-topic summer call. </span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:submissions@theophron.org">submissions@theophron.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.theophron.org/spring2023call" target="_blank">https://www.theophron.org/spring2023call</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 17:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1665725834156789</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Ph.D. applications</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11236017/call-phd-applications</link>
						<dc:creator>Benjamin Brose</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Fellowship</div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Michigan</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>East Asian History / Studies, Philosophy, Religious Studies and Theology, South Asian History / Studies, Southeast Asian History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span>The <a href="https://sites.lsa.umich.edu/buddhiststudies/" rel="nofollow">Group in Buddhist Studies</a> at the University of Michigan’s Department of Asian Languages and Cultures invites applications to its Ph.D. program. The University of Michigan has one of the largest Asian language libraries in North America and several active and endowed <a href="https://ii.umich.edu/ii/about-us/centers-programs.html" rel="nofollow">Asia Centers</a>. The Department has five (soon to be six) faculty with overlapping specializations in the Buddhist traditions of Tibet, India, Mongolia, Korea, Japan, and China. Ph.D. students are fully funded for the first five years of study, with multiple additional opportunities for fellowships and grants. More information can be found on the <a href="https://lsa.umich.edu/asian/graduates/prospective-students.html" rel="nofollow">department website</a>.</span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Benjamin Brose<br/>Professor of Buddhism and Chinese Studies<br/>Chair, Department of Asian Languages &amp; Cultures<br/>University of Michigan <br/> </p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:bbrose@umich.edu">bbrose@umich.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 17:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1665725834156788</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Special Issue of Religions: Something Bigger than Ourselves: Religion in the Lives of African Americans</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/10/09/special-issue-of-religions-something-bigger-than-ourselves-religion-in-the-lives-of</link>
						<dc:creator>EUceh2024</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, October 13, 2022 - 9:05am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Special Issue Editor: Dr. Carol E Henderson/Emory University, Office of the Provost</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:Carol.e.henderson@emory.edu">Carol.e.henderson@emory.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/african-american">african-american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/ethnicity-and-national-identity">ethnicity and national identity</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>March 30, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Special Issue Information</p>
<p>Religions invites submissions for a special journal issue that will examine the contemporary function and presence of religion in the lives of African Americans. Taking its cue from the journal title itself—religions—this special issue welcomes contributions with multidisciplinary approaches that consider “religion” as both a literal set of practices and value systems that anchor various spiritual, philosophical and cultural beliefs, and as an organizational tool that mobilizes communities for political and social change. As the gospel according to Common states, “the movement is a rhythm to us/freedom is like religion to us.”  Given the wide-range of topics and time-periods that could be discussed under this heading, specific attention will be given to papers that examine:</p>
<ul>
<li>The sermon as social catalyst</li>
<li>Religion as wellness</li>
<li>Faith and the African American community</li>
<li>Gender and sexuality and African American religion</li>
<li>Religion as theme in African American literature</li>
<li>Sacred and secular in African American music</li>
<li>Political movements and African American religion</li>
<li>Religion and African American Film</li>
</ul>
<p>Abstracts of 500 words should be submitted to special issue editor, Dr. Carol E. Henderson at <a href="mailto:carol.e.henderson@emory.edu">carol.e.henderson@emory.edu</a> by December 1, 2022. Completed and accepted papers of 7,500 to 15,000 words (excluding notes) should be submitted using the journal’s submission system by March 30, 2023.</p>
<p>All submissions must contain original unpublished work not being considered for publication elsewhere. All essays are peer-reviewed.</p>
<p>For more information, please see <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/journal/religions/special_issues/2US4YUDLG0">https://www.mdpi.com/journal/religions/special_issues/2US4YUDLG0</a></p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 02:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1665725834156787</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ July 5, 2023 -  July 7, 2023] Conference or similar: Tyndale Fellowship's Study Group in Philosophy of Religion</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103978</link>
						<description>Venue: High Leigh Conference Centre, Lord Street<br/><br/></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 05:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1665639430588658</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ November 23, 2022] CFP for conference or similar: Tyndale Fellowship's Study Group in Philosophy of Religion</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103982</link>
						<description><p>The Tyndale Fellowship plans to meet (in person) Wednesday 5th July 14:00 – Friday 7 July 2023 14:00 at <strong>High Leigh Conference Centre, Hoddesdon (</strong><a href="https://www.cct.org.uk/high-leigh/high-leigh-conference-centre">https://www.cct.org.uk/high-leigh/high-leigh-conference-centre</a>).</p>
<p>We are very pleased that Dr Paul Gould (<a href="https://www.paul-gould.com/about/">https://www.paul-gould.com/about/</a>) of Palm-Beach University, Florida, has agreed to be our Tyndale Lecturer; title and topic to be confirmed. </p>
<p>Booking is not open yet, but we hope that it will open on <strong>2nd December</strong>. Early-bird booking is expected to finish on<strong> 31st January</strong>. We expect that bursaries will be available, on the basis of need, for those struggling to raise the funds to travel to Hoddesdon.</p>
<p>If you'd like to give us a paper, please send an <strong>abstract</strong> (no precise word limit: aim for 250 words or so) to <a href="mailto:djhill1972@gmail.com">djhill1972@gmail.com</a> by <strong>23rd November</strong>. (The paper itself should be aimed to last for about <strong>30 minutes</strong>.) The abstract can be on any area of philosophy of religion, broadly construed. We are happy to receive submissions from any stream of philosophy (analytical, continental, historical, feminist...) and from people of any faith or none. If you do not expect to be able to be present in person please feel free to submit an abstract <em>making it clear that you are able to present only on-line</em>. Equally, it'd be helpful if you can confirm that you expect to be in person, if that is the case. We intend to give preference for in-person talks, but may, as this year, be able to accommodate a couple of on-line talks.</p>
<p>Any queries, please contact Daniel Hill at djhill1972@gmail.com. </p></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 05:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1665639430588657</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP: Tenth Annual Symposium on Medieval and Renaissance Studies, June 12-14, 2023</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11240449/cfp-tenth-annual-symposium-medieval-and-renaissance-studies</link>
						<dc:creator>D.R.F. Knackstedt</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-12T00:00:00-04:00">June 12, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-14T00:00:00-04:00">June 14, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Medieval and Byzantine History / Studies, Early Modern History and Period Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Law and Legal History, Military History</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span>The Tenth Annual Symposium on Medieval and Renaissance Studies is happening June 12-14, 2023 and submissions are now open!</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>You can submit and/or read our complete Call for Papers on our website here: <a href="https://www.smrs-slu.org/" rel="nofollow">https://www.smrs-slu.org/</a></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>We invite proposals on all topics and in all disciplines of medieval and early modern studies, whether individual papers, complete sessions, roundtables, or an entire mini-conference for your group.  Our guiding principle throughout is a programmatic flexibility that puts excellence in scholarship ahead of all other concerns.  The Ninth Annual Symposium hosted a total of 86 sessions and we're planning to make this one our largest yet!</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>The <strong>deadline </strong>is <strong>December 31st</strong>.</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>The Symposium is held annually on the beautiful midtown St. Louis campus of Saint Louis University. On campus housing options include affordable, air-conditioned apartments as well as a more luxurious hotel. Inexpensive meal plans are also available, although there is a wealth of restaurants, bars, and cultural venues within easy walking distance of campus.  The <b>plenary speakers</b> for this year will be </span></span><b><span>Uta-Renate Blumenthal</span></b><span><span>, of</span></span><span> the Catholic University of America<span>, and </span><b>Lia Markey</b><span>, of </span>the Newberry Library, Chicago<span>.</span></span></span></span></p><p><br/> </p></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 17:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1665639430588656</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – October 12, 2022</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-october-12-2022/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find full-time job listings, long-term research positions, a journal editor position, two conferences, and two call-for-papers.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 36!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Cluster Hire in American Indian and Indigenous Studies (3 Assistant Professor Positions, 1 Full Professor Position)</h4>



<p>University of North Carolina Chapel Hill, US</p>



<p>Deadline: Late October</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://college.unc.edu/cluster-hire-in-american-indian-and-indigenous-studies/">https://college.unc.edu/cluster-hire-in-american-indian-and-indigenous-studies/</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor Religious Studies (Tenure-Track)</h4>



<p>Saratoga Springs, NY, US</p>



<p>Deadline: October 21, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://eodq.fa.us6.oraclecloud.com/hcmUI/CandidateExperience/en/sites/CX/requisitions/preview/865/">https://eodq.fa.us6.oraclecloud.com/hcmUI/CandidateExperience/en/sites/CX/requisitions/preview/865/</a></p>



<h4>Full-Time Postdoctoral Researcher for “Digital Islam across Europe: Understanding Muslims’ Participation in Online Islamic Environments” (5-year funded research project)</h4>



<p>University of Wales Trinity Saint David’s Lampeter Campus UK, or remotely</p>



<p>Deadline: October 10<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://jobs.uwtsd.ac.uk/JobDescription/9q162YnH2h8">https://jobs.uwtsd.ac.uk/JobDescription/9q162YnH2h8</a></p>



<h4>Postdoctoral Researcher for PENTACTORS (Ph.D. earned no later than 7 years ago, 5-year placement)</h4>



<p>Ethnographic research in Poland focused on Pentecostalism, migration, others, and activism. Knowledge of Ukrainian or Russian REQUIRED, knowledge of English REQUIRED, knowledge of Polish preferred but not necessary.</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://sway.office.com/4EO3FMJ2ivnfqlsn?ref=Link">https://sway.office.com/4EO3FMJ2ivnfqlsn?ref=Link</a></p>



<h4>Reviews Editor of Fieldwork in Religion Journal with Equinox Publishing</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://journal.equinoxpub.com/FIR">https://journal.equinoxpub.com/FIR</a></p>



<p>Contact: <a href="mailto:GDChryssides@religion21.com">GDChryssides@religion21.com</a>, or <a href="mailto:carole.cusack@sydney.edu.au">carole.cusack@sydney.edu.au</a></p>



<h2>Conferences:</h2>



<h4>Demons: Good and Bad</h4>



<p>Trinity College Dublin, IE</p>



<p>October 27<sup>th</sup> and 28<sup>th</sup> 2022</p>



<p><a href="https://www.tcd.ie/religion/conference-seminars/demons22/index.php">https://www.tcd.ie/religion/conference-seminars/demons22/index.php</a></p>



<h4>Digital Religion Research Award Lecture: Dr. Giulia Evolvi – Religion and the Internet: Digital religion, (hyper)mediated spaces, and materiality</h4>



<p>Date: November 3<sup>rd</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://digitalreligion.tamu.edu/blog/thu-10062022-1121/press-release-2022-digital-religion-research-award-winner-dr-giulia-evolvi">https://digitalreligion.tamu.edu/blog/thu-10062022-1121/press-release-2022-digital-religion-research-award-winner-dr-giulia-evolvi</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>Authority, Lineage, &amp; Schism: 48<sup>th</sup> Spalding Symposium on Indian Religions</h4>



<p>Kings College London, UK</p>



<p>Deadline: December 22<sup>nd</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information and Submission: https://forms.gle/C9Q7G4NvWiBjkiEP6</p>



<h4>2023 European Association for the Study of Religion Conference “Religions and Technologies”</h4>



<p>Vilnius, Lithuania, September 4th-8th, 2023</p>



<p>Deadline: November 15<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.easr2023.org/">https://www.easr2023.org/</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1665639430588655</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Medieval Melting Pot? Group Formation and Maintenance in the Abbasid Caliphate, 750-1000</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11232164/medieval-melting-pot-group-formation-and-maintenance-abbasid</link>
						<dc:creator>Layal Mohammad</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-29T00:00:00-05:00">November 29, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Arabic History / Studies, Islamic History / Studies, Middle East History / Studies, Medieval and Byzantine History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>In this inaugural lecture for the Tejpar Professorship, Philip Wood sets out his plan for his new research project on <em>Group Formation in the Abbasid Caliphate</em>. His earlier work has engaged with how Christian groups in the Middle East have enforced boundaries with other populations, both other Christians and with pagans, Jews and Muslims. In particular, he has examined the way that history writing has functioned as an identitarian discourse, which legitimated social boundaries in the present by referring to an idealised representation of the past.</p><p>The <em>Group Formation </em>project seeks to understand how ethnic and religious communities have maintained their distinctiveness over time, or failed to do so. It aims to compare Jewish, Christian and Muslim populations across Iraq and the Levant to isolate the factors that allowed some groups to survive and flourish while others did not. Previous literature on this subject has tended to approach these issues through the rate of conversion to Islam. While this is an important viewpoint, this project focusses instead on the factors that allowed a group to retain coherence in a multicultural society, on how its leaders could maintain separation from outsiders while still gaining trust and acceptance from the Abbasid state.</p><p><strong>Speaker</strong><br/>Philip Wood is the inaugural Tejpar Professor of Inter-Religious Studies at the Aga Khan University's Institute for the Study of Muslim Civilisations (AKU-ISMC), London, and a historian of Christians in the medieval Middle East, c.500-1000. He is also interested in issues of contemporary social integration and religious education. He is the author of <em>Imam of the Christians: The World of Dionysius of Tel-mahre, 750-850 </em>(Princeton 2021) and co-editor with Leif Stenberg of<em> What is Islamic Studies? European and North American Approaches to a Contested Field</em> (Edinburgh, 2022).</p><p><strong>Date and Time</strong><br/>Tuesday 29 November 2022, 18:00 - 19:00  (London).</p><p><strong>Venue</strong><br/>Aga Khan Centre (Atrium Conference Room),<br/>10 Handyside Street,<br/>London N1C 4DN</p><p><strong>Booking</strong><br/>The event is free, but booking is essential:<br/>To attend in person, <a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/group-formation-and-maintenance-in-the-abbasid-caliphate-750-1000-tickets-438909448977" rel="nofollow">register via Eventbrite</a>.<br/>To attend online, <a href="https://aku-edu.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_P5BWVkjoTByW8MyEOTOK-Q" rel="nofollow">register via Zoom</a>.</p><p><strong>Organiser</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.aku.edu/ismc/Pages/home.aspx" rel="nofollow">The Aga Khan University's Institute for the Study of Muslim Civilisations (AKU-ISMC)</a>, London.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Layal Mohammad<br/>Manager, Marketing and Communications<br/>The Aga Khan University (International) in the United Kingdom<br/>Aga Khan Centre, 10 Handyside Street, London N1C 4DN</p><p>Phone: +44 [0] 20 7380 3839<br/>Website: <a href="https://www.aku.edu/ismc/Pages/home.aspx" rel="nofollow">www.aku.edu/ismc</a></p><p>Incorporated in England as a company limited by guarantee no. 4448389 Registered Charity Number 1179136</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:layal.n.mohammad@aku.edu">layal.n.mohammad@aku.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.aku.edu/events/pages/event-detail.aspx" target="_blank">https://www.aku.edu/events/pages/event-detail.aspx?EventID=2219&amp;Title=Group%20Formation%20and%20Maintenance%20in%20the%2…</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 17:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1665553032218328</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
