<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 03:31:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 03:31:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ February 1, 2023] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104304</link>
						<description>Publication Name: Cross-Training in Psychological Science at Baylor University<br/><br/><p>Thanks to a generous grant from the John Templeton Foundation, we are pleased to announce a Request for Proposals for cross-training opportunities with the psychological sciences, run by Dr. Devan Stahl (PI), Dr. Natalie Carnes, Dr. Anne Jeffrey, Dr. Sarah Schnitker, Dr. JoAnn Tsang. Those working in any discipline that engages theological inquiry are welcome to apply (moral theology, philosophy, aesthetics, etc.). This program will help successful applicants build supportive and collaborative interpersonal relationships with other scholars interested in the psychological sciences interested in working on research of interest to theologians. </p>
<p><br/> In addition to one funded year of cross training, successful applicants will then have the opportunity to apply for an additional $45,000 of salary funding for additional training and $5,000-40,000 for a collaborative empirical study with a psychology lab in subsequent years.   </p>
<p>If you or a colleague is interested in exploring issues relevant to Christian theology and philosophy, especially virtue, suffering and vulnerability, and religious aesthetics please consider applying.   </p>
<p>Applications are due February 1, 2023.</p>
<p>For more information on this project, and for the details of the funding request, please visit our website: https://www.baylor.edu/ethics/index.php?id=986085  </p>
<p>Questions should be directed to crosstraining@baylor.edu.  </p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666417028529899</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CONFERENCE: Amsterdam as Haven for Religious Refugees in the Early Modern Period (10, 11, 12 November, Amsterdam, hybrid)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11378515/conference-amsterdam-haven-religious-refugees-early-modern</link>
						<dc:creator>Kyra Gerber</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-10T00:00:00-05:00">November 10, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-12T00:00:00-05:00">November 12, 2022</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Netherlands</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Early Modern History and Period Studies, European History / Studies, Intellectual History, Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>In the 17th century Amsterdam became a hotbed of religious exchange, as religious exiles from all over the continent flocked to the Netherlands and especially its capital city because of relatively lax laws on religious expression and publishing. One center of such exchange was the so-called House with the Heads on Keizersgracht, the home of Louis de Geer and later his son Laurens. Both men acted as patrons to a variety of religious free thinkers and reformers. Figures such as Jan Comenius, Friedrich Breckling and Christian Hoburg gathered in the de Geer home to discuss their ideas. Today, the House with the Heads is home to the Bibliotheca Philosophica Hermetica and its associated museum, the Embassy of the Free Mind. We are currently preparing an exhibition on the history of the House with the Heads. As part of these preparations, we are hosting a conference 11-12 November 2022 on the role of Amsterdam as a haven for religious refugees.</p><p>Over two days, a group of international experts will explore different groups’ or individuals’ experiences (Jews, Radical Pietists, Huguenots, etc.), the role of publishing in the city, patronage, conflicts between groups, urban versus rural strategies for survival, the role of war in the era and other related topics. The conference will take place on-site, but will also accommodate speakers from afar through digital connection. Likewise, the public can attend in person or remotely. A conference publication is planned.</p><p>The complete conference program can be viewed <a href="https://embassyofthefreemind.com/en/library/271-amsterdam-as-haven" rel="nofollow">here</a>.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Those who wish to attend in person should contact the Director of the Ritman Research Institute, Lucinda Martin: <span><a href="mailto:lmartin@efm.amsterdam">lmartin@efm.amsterdam</a></span></p><p>Those who wish to view lectures remotely by zoom should request a link from Junior Researcher Kyra Gerber: <span><a href="mailto:kgerber@efm.amsterdam">kgerber@efm.amsterdam</a></span></p><p>Tickets to attend the evening lecture by Emil Schrijver will be sold separately. Tickets can be bought <a href="https://tickets.embassyofthefreemind.com/en/events/tickets" rel="nofollow">here</a>.</p><p>Learn more about the Ritman Research Institute <a href="https://embassyofthefreemind.com/en/library/269-ritman-research-institute" rel="nofollow">here</a>.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:lmartin@efm.amsterdam">lmartin@efm.amsterdam</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://embassyofthefreemind.com/en/library/271-amsterdam-as-haven" target="_blank">https://embassyofthefreemind.com/en/library/271-amsterdam-as-haven</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 17:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666417028529898</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ March 22, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Husserl-Arbeitstage 2023. Reason and Relativity</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104284</link>
						<description><p><strong>Husserl-Arbeitstage 2023,</strong> <strong>REASON AND RELATIVITY</strong></p>
<p>From Husserl’s early critique of psychologism in the <em>Prolegomena,</em> to his criticism of both naturalism and historicism in the <em>Logos</em> article, and his later diagnosis of the inner fragmentation of science and philosophy in the <em>Crisis</em>, phenomenology has confronted  diverse forms of relativism and skepticism. As one strategy for facing this challenge, Husserl elaborated a phenomenology of reason embracing the theoretical sphere of being and truth, the axiological sphere of value and genuine evaluation, and the practical sphere of authentic ethical action. He thereby placed the rational ideals of autonomy and self-responsibility at the heart of his project of philosophy as a rigorous science. Moreover, he advanced investigations of social and cultural realities by developing a phenomenological science of what is often considered ‘merely’ relative: Culture, history, and community. For the 2023 <em>Husserl-Arbeitstage</em>, the Husserl-Archives Leuven are inviting contributions concerning “Reason and Relativity”. Papers on a wide range of thematic issues are welcome, including, but not limited to, <em>experience and rational justification, moral and epistemic responsibility, normativity and rationality, cultural relativism and scientific universalism, essentialism and marginalization, scientific and philosophical thinking, foundations of social science</em>, etc.</p>
<p>Please send a two-page abstract or full paper before December 11th, 2022 to husserl2023@kuleuven.be. All submissions should be anonymized. Notifications of acceptance will be issued on December 20th, 2022. The conference will be held in English.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 05:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666330630467876</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ March 22, 2023 -  March 24, 2023] Conference or similar: Husserl-Arbeitstage 2023. Reason and Relativity</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104280</link>
						<description>Venue: Kardinaal Mercierplein 2<br/><br/><p><strong>Husserl-Arbeitstage 2023,</strong> <strong>REASON AND RELATIVITY</strong></p>
<p>From Husserl’s early critique of psychologism in the <em>Prolegomena,</em> to his criticism of both naturalism and historicism in the <em>Logos</em> article, and his later diagnosis of the inner fragmentation of science and philosophy in the <em>Crisis</em>, phenomenology has confronted  diverse forms of relativism and skepticism. As one strategy for facing this challenge, Husserl elaborated a phenomenology of reason embracing the theoretical sphere of being and truth, the axiological sphere of value and genuine evaluation, and the practical sphere of authentic ethical action. He thereby placed the rational ideals of autonomy and self-responsibility at the heart of his project of philosophy as a rigorous science. Moreover, he advanced investigations of social and cultural realities by developing a phenomenological science of what is often considered ‘merely’ relative: Culture, history, and community. For the 2023 <em>Husserl-Arbeitstage</em>, the Husserl-Archives Leuven are inviting contributions concerning “Reason and Relativity”. Papers on a wide range of thematic issues are welcome, including, but not limited to, <em>experience and rational justification, moral and epistemic responsibility, normativity and rationality, cultural relativism and scientific universalism, essentialism and marginalization, scientific and philosophical thinking, foundations of social science</em>, etc.</p>
<p>Please send a two-page abstract or full paper before December 11th, 2022 to husserl2023@kuleuven.be. All submissions should be anonymized. Notifications of acceptance will be issued on December 20th, 2022. The conference will be held in English.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 05:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666330630467875</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Conference programme 3-4 November: Editing, Translating and Interpreting the Greek Fathers in the French-Speaking Regions of Europe (1450-1650)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11365962/conference-programme-3-4-november-editing-translating-and</link>
						<dc:creator>Paolo Sachet</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-03T00:00:00-04:00">November 3, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-04T00:00:00-04:00">November 4, 2022</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Switzerland</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Classical Studies, Early Modern History and Period Studies, French History / Studies, Humanities, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><b>Editing, Translating and Interpreting the Greek Fathers in the French-Speaking Regions of Europe (1450-1650)  / </b></p><p><b>Éditer, traduire et interpréter les Pères grecs  dans l’espace francophone européen (1450-1650)</b></p><p> </p><p>Geneva, Institut d'histoire de la Réformation, UNIGE</p><p><b>3-4 November</b></p><p> </p><p>Further information can be found <a href="https://www.unige.ch/ihr/fr/accueil/journees-detude-ihr-3-4-novembre-2022/" rel="nofollow">here</a>, including full <b>programme</b> and the Zoom link for <b>attending online</b>.</p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr Paolo Sachet, Institut d'histoire de la Réformation, UNIGE</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:paolo.sachet@unige.ch">paolo.sachet@unige.ch</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="http://www.unige.ch/ihr/fr/accueil/journees-detude-ihr-3-4-novembre-2022/" target="_blank">http://www.unige.ch/ihr/fr/accueil/journees-detude-ihr-3-4-novembre-2022/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 17:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666330630467874</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Papers: Religion and James Bond</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11360067/call-papers-religion-and-james-bond</link>
						<dc:creator>George Tsakiridis</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-19T00:00:00-04:00">October 19, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-12-31T00:00:00-05:00">December 31, 2022</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Film and Film History, Humanities, Philosophy, Popular Culture Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><strong>Call for Papers: <em>Religion and James Bond</em></strong></p><p> </p><p>Volume Editor: George Tsakiridis, PhD</p><p> </p><p>Abstract and CV Due: November 30, 2022</p><p> </p><p>Initial Final Paper Due: June 1, 2023</p><p> </p><p>Click <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U9FzgsF2T-s%3E" rel="nofollow">this link</a>, and close your eyes…wait a few seconds and start reading…</p><p> </p><p>It’s hard to imagine a more iconic action hero from the past 60 years than James Bond. He encapsulates the Western ideal in a spy hero from the Cold War Era till today. Though much has changed, this figure has been the focus of twenty-five (plus) films. He embodies popular culture for two generations of British and American viewers, and helps us to see the development of pop culture through film, social mores, and sexuality over time. He is a perfect topic for the <a href="https://rowman.com/Action/SERIES/_/LFATPC/Theology,-Religion,-and-Pop-Culture" rel="nofollow">Theology, Religion, and Pop Culture series</a>.</p><p>           </p><p>Having started in novels, and made more famous through film, Bond has spanned multiple generations of viewers, helping us to see the evolution of the character and the culture though the technology, sexual norms, and politics of several decades. He is a lens through which we can view religion and how religion has been portrayed over time. The accepted behavior of a character like Bond, as well as the accepted visuals of the series changed slowly, then rapidly over the course of the films. Having been played by six actors (not counting an outlier or two), he also has been interpreted and reinterpreted many times. As scholars, this gives us an opportunity to see how popular culture lenses have changed over time so that meaning, morals, and aesthetics can be central to this study. This is not meant to be a hit piece on Bond, as some scholars have done in recent years, but a critical study of a character that many of us enjoy, looking at the good while not ignoring the less than good. There’s a reason he is so beloved, despite his flaws; he taps into something underlying all of us – our very human nature.</p><p>           </p><p>The volume will focus on a number of themes, including, but not limited to: sin/redemption, sexuality, political theology, and religious plurality. Because of both its political and multicultural emphases, Bond gives us a glimpse at a British agent’s Cold War development as he engages multiple cultures and peoples. This is seen both in his own journey of redemption and his redemption of others. It is seen in his mistreatment of women and culture as well as his embrace of it. In Bond’s spycraft, we see both the good and the bad sides of human nature, sometimes at the same time. As can be inferred from the multitude of themes, this volume will engage both religious studies scholars and theologians, having some of both already signed on in the pre-seeding of this volume. Scholars of all types are welcome: religious studies, theology, philosophy, and other areas of the humanities.</p><p> </p><p>Though the volume will focus predominately on the films, I also hope to see proposals on Ian Fleming’s novels, the history and development of Bond, and perhaps even the video games and collectibles. We will have to see what the call for papers brings in, but there is a lot of fertile ground in the world of 007.</p><p> </p><p><strong>Some potential categories that are priorities for this volume are as follows (though other ideas are welcome!):</strong></p><p> </p><p>-World Religions in James Bond (and the accurate or inaccurate portrayal of them). This might be exploring the use of one religion, such as Hinduism or Buddhism throughout the Bond corpus, or examining a broader theme. (this topic is high priority)</p><p>-Redemption/Sacrifice/Salvation</p><p>-Sexual Ethics in Bond and Bond Girls</p><p>-Morality and Sin in the Context of Technology</p><p>-Ethics of Spycraft in the Cold War</p><p>-Good and Evil during the Cold War</p><p>-The Music of James Bond – Can either be a song or two, or the use of music throughout the series. (this topic is high priority)</p><p>-Political Theology in James Bond Films</p><p>-Religion in Ian Fleming’s James Bond Novels</p><p>-Religion/Theology in James Bond Comic Books (I know it will be tough to get this one, but if anyone is interested, I am listening!)</p><p>-M, Q, and Moneypenny – How do the supporting characters make for a robust theology in Bond?</p><p>-Bond by Actor: Looking for pieces that specifically will look at the individual film corpus of Connery, Lazenby, Moore, Dalton, Brosnan, and Craig (this topic is high priority – especially a piece on Lazenby/OHMSS)</p><p>-Bond by Film – Looking at the presentation of religion within individual films – implicit here is the cultural appropriation/interpretation of religion and culture in Bond films</p><p>-James Bond Collectables – the iconography of James Bond</p><p>-James Bond in Video Games (Goldeneye was groundbreaking in its development of first-person shooter games) – Exploring the philosophy of Bond on the small screen</p><p>Feel free to get creative. This volume looks to highlight creative, diverse, and well-researched chapters.</p><p>Abstracts should be approximately 300-500 words and should present a basic outline of your potential contribution to the volume and potential methodology. If you make the initial cut, you will be contacted by Dr. Tsakiridis to discuss and finalize your contribution to the volume. Send an abstract and a CV to <a href="mailto:religionandjamesbond@gmail.com">religionandjamesbond@gmail.com</a>. Final drafts will be approximately 6,000 to 7,000 words, but exact word counts for each article will be discussed at the time of acceptance. You are welcome to contact Dr. Tsakiridis in advance of the proposal deadline to float a potential topic if you are unsure. Early submissions are strongly encouraged.</p><p> </p><p>The tentative schedule for production is:</p><p> </p><p>November 30, 2022 – Call for Papers Ends</p><p>June 1, 2023 – First Drafts Due</p><p>July 1, 2023 – Drafts Reviewed and Returned</p><p>September 1, 2023 – Final Drafts Due</p><p>October 1, 2023 – Final Edits Made Before Peer Review</p><p>November 1, 2023 – Drafts to Peer Review</p><p>January 15, 2024 – Final Revisions Due</p><p>February 29, 2024 – Submission to Publisher</p><p>Summer/Fall 2024 – Publication</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr. George Tsakiridis</p><p>South Dakota State University</p><p><a href="mailto:george.tsakiridis@sdstate.edu">george.tsakiridis@sdstate.edu</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:george.tsakiridis@sdstate.edu">george.tsakiridis@sdstate.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://popularcultureandtheology.com/2022/08/31/call-for-papers-religion-and-james-bond/" target="_blank">https://popularcultureandtheology.com/2022/08/31/call-for-papers-religion-and-james-bond/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666330630467873</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Fourteenth International Conference on Religion &amp; Spirituality in Society (A Blended Conference)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11355161/fourteenth-international-conference-religion-spirituality</link>
						<dc:creator>Tamsyn Gilbert</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2024-05-23T00:00:00-04:00">May 23, 2024</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2024-05-24T00:00:00-04:00">May 24, 2024</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Spain</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology, Sociology, Cultural History / Studies, Human Rights, Anthropology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Fourteenth International Conference on Religion &amp; Spirituality in Society, Institute of Religious Studies, Complutense University of Madrid, Spain (23-24 May 2024) <br/>A Blended Conference <br/> </p><p>Founded in 2011, the <strong>Religion in Society Research Network</strong> explores the relationship between religion in society and the changing nature of spirituality. We seek to build an epistemic community where we can make linkages across disciplinary, geographic, and cultural boundaries. As a Research Network, we are defined by our scope and concerns and motivated to build strategies for action framed by our shared themes and tensions.<br/> <br/>The <strong>Fourteenth International Conference on Religion &amp; Spirituality in Society</strong> calls for research addressing the following annual themes and special focus:</p><ul><li><em>2024 Special Focus—Spaces, Movement, Time: Religions at Rest and in Movement</em></li><li><em>Theme 1: Interdisciplinary Approaches</em></li><li><em>Theme 2: Human Rights and Policy</em></li><li><em>Theme 3: Narratives and Identity</em></li><li><em>Theme 4: Culture and Education</em><br/> </li></ul></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:support@cgnetworks.org">support@cgnetworks.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://religioninsociety.com/2024-conference" target="_blank">https://religioninsociety.com/2024-conference</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 17:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666330630467872</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – October 19th, 2022</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-october-19th-2022/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find full-time job listings, an early scholar workshop, a conference, and a call for papers.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 36!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Sociology of Religion (Tenure-Track)</h4>



<p>University of Toronto Scarborough, Canada</p>



<p>Deadline: November 28, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.utsc.utoronto.ca/sociology/sites/utsc.utoronto.ca.sociology/files/docs/02%2026546%20Sociology%20of%20Religion%20External%20posting.pdf">https://www.utsc.utoronto.ca/sociology/sites/utsc.utoronto.ca.sociology/files/docs/02 26546 Sociology of Religion External posting.pdf</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor in the Department of Near Eastern and South Asian Languages and Cultures (Tenure-Track)</h4>



<p>Ohio State University, US</p>



<p>Deadline: November 15<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://academicjobsonline.org/ajo/jobs/22406">https://academicjobsonline.org/ajo/jobs/22406</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor in Spirituality and Religious Ethics (Tenure-Track)</h4>



<p>University of Montreal, Canada</p>



<p>Deadline: November 6<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information:  <a href="https://twitter.com/NAASReligion/status/1580975963428753408/photo/1">https://twitter.com/NAASReligion/status/1580975963428753408/photo/1</a> (PDF, English)</p>



<p><a href="https://etudes-religieuses.umontreal.ca/notre-institut/presentation/">https://etudes-religieuses.umontreal.ca/notre-institut/presentation/</a> (University website, French)</p>



<h2>Workshops:</h2>



<h4>2023 American Examples</h4>



<p>University of Alabama, US</p>



<p>Deadline: November 7<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://americanexamples.ua.edu/2023-call-for-participants/">https://americanexamples.ua.edu/2023-call-for-participants/</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>Critical Muslim Studies Online Colloquium II</h4>



<p>Online Colloquium</p>



<p>Deadline: 31 October 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://cers.leeds.ac.uk/2022/10/17/critical-muslim-studies-cms-online-colloquium-ii/">https://cers.leeds.ac.uk/2022/10/17/critical-muslim-studies-cms-online-colloquium-ii/</a></p>



<h2>Conferences:</h2>



<h4>Second Annual Black Feminist Theory Summer Institute</h4>



<p>Duke University, US</p>



<p>Deadline: December 15, 2022</p>



<p>More Information:  <a href="https://gendersexualityfeminist.duke.edu/black-feminist-theory-summer-institute">https://gendersexualityfeminist.duke.edu/black-feminist-theory-summer-institute</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666244227512150</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ August 31, 2023 -  September 2, 2023] Conference or similar: Love, Religion, and God</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104198</link>
						<description>Venue: Lady Margaret Hall<br/><br/><p><strong>Keynote Speakers:</strong></p>
<p>Fiona Ellis (University of Roehampton)</p>
<p>Talbot Brewer (University of Virginia)</p>
<p>Judith Wolfe (University of St Andrews)</p>
<p>Paul Fiddes (University of Oxford)</p>
<p>The question of the relation between love, religion, and God is a central concern for both atheists and theists; and philosophers, theologians, and scientists have drawn interesting and sometimes conflicting conclusions about the nature of this relation and of the things related in this context. Can love be understood in the absence of God? Is love one thing or many things? And what is the relation between love and desire, or love and redemption? How are we to assess Nietzsche’s critique of Christian love? What is the role and value of love in non-theistic religious traditions? And in what sense, if any, should we accept that love is deeply mysterious?</p>
<p>These questions are attracting attention in recent scholarship, and the conference organisers are keen to examine the relevant issues from the vantage point of philosophy of religion as broadly conceived. We welcome papers taking a philosophical and/or theological approach to all aspects of love, religion, and God, including secular and diverse religious perspectives. We also encourage submissions from scholars who seek to make connections with other disciplines, such as religious studies, psychology, literature, and cognitive science. Members of under-represented groups are particularly encouraged to submit an abstract.</p>
<p>Those interested in presenting a short paper should send a proposal of no more than 250 words in a Word document to Dr David Worsley (<a target="_blank">david.worsley@york.ac.uk</a>) <strong>no earlier than 3rd January 2023 and no later than 31st March 2023.</strong> Please include the paper's title, and your name, institutional affiliation, and email address (these are not included in the 250 word word limit). We expect to notify people about whether their proposals have been accepted by 30th April 2023.</p>
<p>Some partial bursaries (including bursaries to cover the cost of childcare) may be available for participants who do not have another source of funding for attending the conference, with preference for these given to those who are presenting a paper. If you anticipate being in need of a bursary, please indicate this in your submission.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 05:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666157833185379</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Grant Applications due at Notre Dame's Cushwa Center by December 31</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11338378/grant-applications-due-notre-dames-cushwa-center-december-31</link>
						<dc:creator>Shane Ulbrich</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Grant</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-12-31T00:00:00-05:00">December 31, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>American History / Studies, Chicana/o History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Social History / Studies, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The University of Notre Dame's Cushwa Center administers the following funding opportunities to support scholarly research in a variety of subject areas. Apply by December 31, 2022, at <a href="https://cushwa.nd.edu/" rel="nofollow">cushwa.nd.edu</a>:</p><p><a href="https://cushwa.nd.edu/grant-opportunities/research-travel-grants/" rel="nofollow">Research Travel Grants</a> assist scholars who wish to visit the University Archives or other collections at the Hesburgh Libraries at Notre Dame for research relating to the study of Catholics in America.</p><p><a href="https://cushwa.nd.edu/grant-opportunities/peter-r-dagostino-research-travel-grant/" rel="nofollow">Peter R. D'Agostino Research Travel Grants</a> Offered in conjunction with Italian Studies at Notre Dame and designed to facilitate the study of the American past from an international perspective, these grants support research in Roman archives for projects on U.S. Catholic history.</p><p><a href="https://cushwa.nd.edu/grant-opportunities/davis/" rel="nofollow">The Cyprian Davis, O.S.B., Prize</a> Established in partnership with the American Catholic Historical Association, this prize recognizes outstanding research on the Black Catholic experience.</p><p><a href="https://cushwa.nd.edu/grant-opportunities/guerin/" rel="nofollow">Mother Theodore Guerin Research Travel Grants</a> This grant program supports scholars whose research projects seek to feature Catholic women more prominently in modern history. Grants are made to scholars seeking to visit any repository in or outside the United States, or traveling to conduct oral history interviews, especially of women religious.</p><p><a href="https://cushwa.nd.edu/grant-opportunities/hibernian-research-award/" rel="nofollow">Hibernian Research Awards</a> Funded by an endowment from the Ancient Order of Hibernians and Ladies Ancient Order of Hibernians, Hibernian Research Awards support the scholarly study of Irish and Irish American history.</p><p>For updates on future opportunities, join the Cushwa Center's mailing list at <a href="https://cushwa.nd.edu/subscribe/" rel="nofollow">cushwa.nd.edu/subscribe</a>.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Cushwa Center for the Study of American Catholicism</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:cushwa@nd.edu">cushwa@nd.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://cushwa.nd.edu/grant-opportunities/" target="_blank">https://cushwa.nd.edu/grant-opportunities/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 18:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666157833185378</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Philosophical Aspects of Byzantine Music</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11324458/philosophical-aspects-byzantine-music</link>
						<dc:creator>Brandie Ratliff</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-31T00:00:00-04:00">October 31, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Medieval and Byzantine History / Studies, Music and Music History, Classical Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Area Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The Mary Jaharis Center for Byzantine Art and Culture is pleased to announce our first lecture of 2022–2023: <strong>Philosophical Aspects of Byzantine Music</strong>. In this lecture, Dr. Achilleas G. Chaldæakes, University of Athens, will discuss the philosophical and symbolic significance of the circle in Byzantine Music.</p><p><strong>October 31, 2022 | Zoom | 12:00–1:30 pm (Eastern Daylight Time, UTC -4)</strong></p><p>This lecture will take place live on Zoom, followed by a question and answer period. Please register to receive the Zoom link.</p><p><strong><a href="https://maryjahariscenter.org/events/philosophical-aspects-of-byzantine-music" rel="nofollow"><strong>REGISTER</strong></a></strong></p><p><em>Part of the Boston Byzantine Music Festival Lecture Series exploring the musical heritage of the Byzantine Empire. The Boston Byzantine Music Festival is a program of the Mary Jaharis Center for Byzantine Art and Culture.</em></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Brandie Ratliff<br/>Director, Mary Jaharis Center for Byzantine Art and Culture</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:mjcbac@hchc.edu">mjcbac@hchc.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://maryjahariscenter.org/events/philosophical-aspects-of-byzantine-music" target="_blank">https://maryjahariscenter.org/events/philosophical-aspects-of-byzantine-music</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 16:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666157833185377</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Race, Missions and Contemporary Missiologies – Theories and Practices / Le Mans &amp; Aix en Provence, France</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11332806/race-missions-and-contemporary-missiologies-%E2%80%93-theories-and</link>
						<dc:creator>Maud Michaud</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-03-23T00:00:00-04:00">March 23, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-03-24T00:00:00-04:00">March 24, 2022</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>France</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Black History / Studies, Colonial and Post-Colonial History / Studies, Race Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Social Sciences</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><b>Call for Papers : Race, Missions and Contemporary Missiologies – Theories and Practices</b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b>Conference 1: Le Mans University, France / 23-24 March 2023 – Race and Contemporary Missiology</b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b>Conference 2 / IREMAM, Aix-en-Provence, France / 8-9 June 2023 – Race, Missions and Missionary Field Practices</b></span></span></p><p><span><span>The ReLRace and IREMAM research programmes wish to explore the ways in which Christian missionary institutions of the contemporary world, among others, have managed – or failed, or refused – to integrate the notion of “race” in their operating methods, in the justification and preparation of their enterprise and in their practices in the field. The 19th and 20th centuries have witnessed the redefinition, in a changing geopolitical context, of the apostolic mission of these Christian organisations; in the field, they have increasingly called upon local clergy whom they themselves had trained, and who thus sometimes had to stand up against the racist discourses and practices of white administrators and clergy.</span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><b>Conference 1 / Le Mans University / 23-24 March 2023 – Race and Contemporary Missiology</b></span></span></p><p><span><span>Through this first two-day conference on “Race and Contemporary Missiology”, the RelRace [ Religions, Lineages, Races] programme wishes to explore the contemporary uses of the concept of “race” in contemporary missiology, as well as all the vocabulary and themes of raciology that may have been developed in the 19th and 20th centuries in the writings of missionaries – both in their published (or unpublished) correspondence, and in their extra-apostolic work (linguistics, anthropology...).</span></span></p><p><span><span>The work of the ReLRace ANR programme argues that racial concepts based on religious foundations do exist and, from the eighteenth century onwards, have even coexisted with the notion of race as it was thought of within the framework of natural history and racial anthropology. Thus, as the new science of missiology developed in European and American Christian missionary circles in the second half of the 19th century, how did it integrate racialist theories into its principles with the various racial-religious traditions, particularly in an effort to scientifically legitimise the missionary enterprise [Dujardin and Prudhomme, 2015]? The Christian imperialism that characterised the Protestant movement of the late Victorian and early 20th centuries, for example, seemed paradoxically to combine the crudest forms and expressions of imperialist arrogance and racist prejudice with the internationalist and “humanist” vocation of the apostolic enterprise. However, how can the initial objective of creating autonomous indigenous churches – theorised by the Anglican Henry Venn as the “three selves principle” that is supposed to lead to the “euthanasia of the mission” –  be achieved when they are planted and developed in a colonial soil marked by violence and inequality between the “races”? Missionary organisations and the churches involved in the apostolic enterprise were subject to tensions on these issues, especially in colonial and post-colonial areas in the 19th and 20th centuries. The tropes associated with the notion of “race” were undoubtedly used by the actors of these debates, and this conference therefore calls on its future participants to shed light on this part of the history of missiology and missions, thanks to case studies from all continents, without necessarily focusing on European Christian missionary organisations alone.</span></span></p><p><span><span>The ReLRace ANR programmes has also wished to highlight the way in which African and Afro-descendant populations have adopted Christian and Muslim religions and challenged or even reversed the racial stigma with which they were associated. Early on, for example, African-American churches, notably the African Methodist Episcopalian Church (AME), launched missionary activity in the Caribbean, first, and then in Africa. Their preachers offered an approach that did not forego racial themes, but presented eminently different narratives that gave black populations pride of place.</span></span></p><p><span><span>Moreover, while a growing number of missionary organisations developed in Africa, Asia, the Pacific and the American continent throughout the 19th century, they also organised themselves in an increasingly systematic way and in a supranational, trans-imperial and interdenominational perspective: after the Edinburgh Conference in 1910, the creation of the World Council of Churches in 1938 reaffirmed mission-oriented churches’ desire to reflect on what missionary activities really meant. The delegates of major missionary organisations, as well as representatives of their agents on the field, were able to exchange views during these major events on topics such as the inclusion of courses in the sociology of religion or anthropology in the training of agents [Stanley, 2009], the use of vocabulary in the translation of sacred texts into vernacular languages, or the difficulties encountered by non-white Christians in colonial societies marked by the rise of anti-colonialism. Later, at the 1968 Uppsala Conference, for instance, the inter-generational as well as inter-racial tensions of a changing world could be felt, as when the YMCA delegates publicly expressed their belief that “imperialism and paternalism continue to be perpetuated in the structure and theology of the World Council of Churches”, even as the reiterated that “racism is a blatant denial of the Christian faith”.</span></span></p><p><span><span>The following lines of questioning could be explored:</span></span></p><p><span><span><b>1/ Missiology in the 19th and 20th centuries: how was “race” used in the science of missions?</b></span></span></p><p><span><span>This ReLRace programme wishes to examine the ways in which missiology, which was built up in part during events such as the International Council of Missions conference (from 1921 onwards), the Commission on World Mission and Evangelism (from 1961 onwards) and the World Council of Churches, as well as missionaries working in the field in various political, scientific and religious publications, were able to take up concepts linked to racialist theories in order to integrate them into their thinking or, on the contrary, to leave them aside or even to contradict them forcefully. Missionary periodicals, targeting a wide range of readerships –  both “enlightened” and not – can be a source of investigation, as well as the proceedings of conferences and meetings of missionary organisations at local and international levels.</span></span></p><p><span><span><b>2/ Translation, linguistics, anthropology: how were racialised biblical narratives be integrated into scientific missionary work and writing?</b></span></span></p><p><span><span>Many missionaries were involved in the debates in American and European scientific societies and universities on monogenism and polygenism or racial anthropology, for example: how, then, did the themes and typologies used in these discussions and publications infuse missionary discourses and practices at a key moment when both the Protestant and Catholic missionary enterprises were beginning to reflect on their practices and objectives? Work on the translation of sacred texts, or on strategies for promoting the missionary enterprise, could be a particularly fertile field for this line of investigation.</span></span></p><p><span><span><b>3/ Missions and race in colonial and post-colonial field: how did missionary organisations and their agents adapt to the mutations of colonial societies that were becoming independent nations in the second half of the 20th century?</b></span></span></p><p><span><span>How did missionary organisations receive the anti-colonial movements that flourished in Africa, Asia or the Pacific, sometimes within their own churches, and that were able to promote (sometimes armed) struggle against white colonisers? One example is the Indian theologian M.M. Thomas (1916-1996) of the Mar Thoma Church, who created the Programme to Combat Racism (1969), which financed armed liberation movements in South Africa and Rhodesia. Earlier, in the early 19th century, Uganda was the theatre of clashes between religious and social factions in which missionaries were involved because of their often controversial proximity to the British colonial administration in the territory.</span></span></p><p><span><span><i>Proposals along with a short CV should be sent to </i><a href="mailto:relrace@univ-lemans.fr"><i>relrace@univ-lemans.fr</i></a><i>, </i><a href="mailto:Maud.Michaud@univ-lemans.fr"><i>Maud.Michaud@univ-lemans.fr</i></a><i>, </i><a href="mailto:norig.neveu@univ-amu.fr"><i>norig.neveu@univ-amu.fr</i></a><i>, and </i><a href="mailto:annalauraturiano@gmail.com"><i>annalauraturiano@gmail.com</i></a><i> </i><i>by 15 January 2023 at the latest. They should not exceed 500 words.</i><i> </i><i>Paper will be given in French or in English and will be given via Zoom for faraway participants. </i></span></span></p><p><span><span><i><span><span><span>The World Missionary Conference, Edinburgh 1910</span></span></span></i><span><span><span>, Brian Stanley, Grand Rapids, MI:  William B. Eerdmans Publishing Co., 2009</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><i><span><span><span>Mission and Science, Missiology Revised/Missiologie revisitée, 1850–1940</span></span></span></i><span><span><span>, Carine Dujardin and Claude Prudhomme (ed.), Leuven University Press, 2015.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><div><span> </span></div><p> </p><p><span><span><b>Conference 2 / Aix-en-Provence, IREMAM / 8-9 June 2023 – Race, Missions and Missionary Field Practices</b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b>Through the “Race, Missions and Missionary Field Practices” conference, the RelRace [Religions, Lineages, Races] research programme, in collaboration with the IREMAM programme, wishes to explore the effects of the indigenisation of local clergy in the Middle East, sub-Saharan Africa and Asia </b>between the 19th and 21st centuries, using case studies. From the second half of the 19th century onwards, the training of a local clergy became an injunction within the framework of the Protestant and Catholic missionary redeployment, which resulted in tremendous changes on local cults. Numerous institutions were created to that end, such as schools, seminaries, congregations. Missions across the globe were called upon to encourage the indigenisation of their male and female staff by nurturing local vocations as much as possible. The rise of nationalist movements, as well as reflections within the pre-Conciliar Catholic Church, accelerated these dynamics.</span></span></p><p><span><span>How did religious institutions respond to the integration of indigenous clergy into their midst, and to complaints about racist behaviour? Is there a gendered dimension to be explored in this racialised understanding of clergy? What kind of policies followed from this phenomenon? How did local clerics, after their training and upon their return to the mission field, become agents of a sometimes racialist missiology, having to implement reforms with such perspectives? How did those institutions move from logics of nationalisation to practices of ethnicisation within the local churches at the end of the 20th century?</span></span></p><p><span><span>These indigenisation policies call for several initial observations that can sometimes appear paradoxical: the training of an indigenous clergy is apprehended and actually set up unequally according to the Churches and regions concerned. For example, in the Ottoman Empire, the seminary of Beit Jala was created in 1852 for Catholic priests of the Latin rite who were dependent on the Patriarchate of Jerusalem, whereas the Orthodox Church, in that region, resisted this Arabisation process, which resulted in protests from lay agents. In general, the indigenisation of missionary personnel occurred unevenly and was highly dependent on missionary hierarchy and surroundings. How churchgoers and political authorities reacted in the face of this indigenisation process should also be examined.</span></span></p><p><span><span>Local clerics became privileged auxiliaries of local governments, sometimes acting as intermediaries for the colonial powers. Apart from such in-between figures, how did religious men and women make demands within their institutions that could question the dynamics of subordination and domination?  This 2-day conference will be an opportunity to explore the interwining of missiology and field practices beyond the Christian churches, in particular in the context of the Muslim missionary deployment carried out by Ottoman authorities in the Middle East and/or the religious authorities in Africa and Asia, among others. </span></span></p><p><span><span>From the end of the Ottoman Empire, Muslim missionary action developed, especially in what was called the Arab provinces of the Empire. These missionaries embodied a reform discourse that played on the supposed backwardness of the targeted populations and the need to standardize their religious practices. How did the question of race fit in these discourses? How did physiology play a part in missionary action in the field? In the same way, the <i>da'wa</i> advocated and practised by the various representatives of Salafism or by different reformist movements such as the <i>Tablighi Jama'at</i> (a society for the “propagation of the faith” founded in India in 1927) is commonly referred to as a missionary enterprise in academic literature. Can this theoretical reflection on <i>da'wa</i>, somehow a Muslim “missiology” itself, be understood in terms of racial issues? How did preaching, apostolic work and racial issues intertwine in the discourses and practices of movements such as the Nation of Islam?  Were specific modes of missionary action employed depending on the targeted audiences? How were these ideas theorised or practised in the field? How can we put these dynamics into perspective with those that run through Christian missiology?</span></span></p><p><span><span>In order to explore these dynamics, participants could take the following three axes into account:</span></span></p><p><span><span><b>1/</b> <b>The training of indigenous clergy in the mission field.</b> How were calls to train indigenous clergy implemented? Which institutions were in charge of such training and how did they imprint, convey and pass on racial ideas? Our focus will be on the processes of training local clergy, through analyzing the training institutions, their functioning and the profiles of the training personnel. Among other things, the opening of “indigenous novitiates” by Christian missions in the Middle East, Africa and Asia will be examined. In addition to practices, this conference could reflect on the discourses and racial perspectives underlying the functioning of formation institutions. For example, how was the concept of race conjured up to justify the formation of “indigenous” religious men and women as intermediaries between foreign missionaries, the churches and local societies?  </span></span></p><p><span><span><b>2/ Interactions, resistance and tensions between missionaries and European clergy / between indigenous clergy and European clergy.</b> What place did the indigenous clergy have in the religious and missionary hierarchy? Could the relationship between them be thought of in terms of domination/subordination? How did gender, race and other differentiating factors intertwine to produce a “grammar of difference” within church and missionary spaces? How did racial perspectives lead to the domestication of bodies and the imposition of new gender norms? This section will look at the interactions and power relations within church and missionary space. It will focus on the question of subalternity and on reactions to racist practices.</span></span></p><p><span><span><b>3/ Indigenous clergy, missionary society and racial dynamics.</b> How did the indigenous clergy internalise the racialist perspectives that could be integral to their training? How did they (re)contextualise these perspectives in preaching and social action in mission societies? How were such perspectives translated into missionary action? What were the specific claims of the indigenous clergy? How did scientific societies, associations or media contribute to the organisation of this local clergy? What racial elaborations were forged and developed out of them? This axis will analyse how the injunctions of reform and modernity made local clerics the agents of racialist policies. It will reflect on the ways in which, in some contexts, once in office and set up in a position of subordination, clerics could stand up against the policies of their religious institutions. Finally, it will reflect on how the implementation of local clergy, their interaction with missionary societies or the laity differed from one denomination to another, according to context and chronology.</span></span></p><p><i><span><span>Proposals along with a short CV should be sent to </span></span></i><span><span><a href="mailto:relrace@univ-lemans.fr"><i>relrace@univ-lemans.fr</i></a></span></span><i><span><span>, </span></span></i><span><span><a href="mailto:Maud.Michaud@univ-lemans.fr"><i>Maud.Michaud@univ-lemans.fr</i></a></span></span><i><span><span>, </span></span></i><span><span><a href="mailto:norig.neveu@univ-amu.fr"><i>norig.neveu@univ-amu.fr</i></a></span></span><i><span><span>, and </span></span></i><span><span><a href="mailto:annalauraturiano@gmail.com"><i>annalauraturiano@gmail.com</i></a></span></span><i> <span><span>by 15 January 2023 at the latest. They should not exceed 500 words.</span></span> <span><span>Paper will be given in French or in English and will be given via Zoom for faraway participants.</span></span></i></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Relrace programme: <span><span><a href="mailto:relrace@univ-lemans.fr">relrace@univ-lemans.fr</a></span></span></p><p>Vincent Vilmain, Le Mans Université, France, <a href="mailto:Vincent.Vilmain@univ-lemans.fr">Vincent.Vilmain@univ-lemans.fr</a></p><p>Maud Michaud, Le Mans Université, France, <a href="mailto:Maud.Michaud@univ-lemans.fr">Maud.Michaud@univ-lemans.fr</a></p><p>Norig Neveu, IREMAM, France, <span><span><a href="mailto:norig.neveu@univ-amu.fr">norig.neveu@univ-amu.fr</a></span></span></p><p>Annalaura Turiano, IREMAM, France, <span><span><a href="mailto:annalauraturiano@gmail.com">annalauraturiano@gmail.com</a></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:Maud.Michaud@univ-lemans.fr">Maud.Michaud@univ-lemans.fr</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://relrace.hypotheses.org/4999" target="_blank">https://relrace.hypotheses.org/4999</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 16:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666157833185376</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ November 4, 2022] Conference or similar: 18th Murdoch Colloquium: Philosophy, Violence, and Human Rights</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104158</link>
						<description>Venue: 90 South St<br/><br/><p><strong>Keynote speakers</strong>:</p>

<p><strong>Associate Prof Mary Anne Kenny</strong>(Law, Murdoch University)</p>

<p><strong>Prof Toby Miller</strong>(Cultural Studies, Universidad Autónoma Metropolitana, Mexico, and Murdoch University)</p>



<p>This year the Colloquium will have two sections: </p>

<p>·       A <strong>general section</strong> for papers from all areas of philosophy <br/></p>

<p>·       A <strong>special section</strong> of 4 papers on the theme “<strong>Philosophy, Violence, and Human Rights</strong>”. This section explores links between ideas and concepts in philosophy, human rights discourse and practice and violence in the broadest sense. </p>



<p>As always, we encourage contributions from all philosophical traditions, as well as from other disciplines that take into account philosophical questions. Work presented can be polished and close to publication, recently published, or work-in-progress, or non-traditional research outputs (films, etc.).</p>



<p>The Colloquium is a forum for the exchange of ideas in a supportive, collegial atmosphere. It aims to strengthen the ties between academic philosophers in Western Australia, as well as reaching out to colleagues in other disciplines, students and to the wider philosophy community. </p>



<p>The Colloquium is open to academics, undergraduate and postgraduate students. A certificate will be awarded for the best student paper. The Colloquium will be followed by drinks, nibbles and more discussion after the event. We will conclude the evening with a collegial dinner in Fremantle, location tba.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 05:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666071431673719</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Marilynne Robinson, Jesus and John Wayne, and the American Evangelical Tradition</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/10/17/marilynne-robinson-jesus-and-john-wayne-and-the-american-evangelical-tradition</link>
						<dc:creator>hapark1@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Monday, October 17, 2022 - 11:05pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>American Literature Association Conference (ALA); Boston, MA; May 25-28, 2023</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:haein.park@biola.edu">haein.park@biola.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/twentieth-century-and-beyond">twentieth century and beyond</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>November 15, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>The Marilynne Robinson Society and the American Religion and Literature Society (ARLS) will hold a joint panel at the annual American Literature Association Conference (May 25-28, 2022; Boston, MA).  We are seeking papers that examine the author’s relationship to American evangelicalism.  Robinson’s spiritual vision has been shaped by the writings of Jonathan Edwards, who is considered to be the founding father of American evangelicalism.  How does Robinson’s body of work lead us to think critically about the evangelical tradition in the United States?  How do her essays and novels, particularly <em>Gilead</em>, provide a counter-narrative to the discourses found in modern and contemporary American evangelicalism?  In what ways can they respond to the incisive diagnosis presented by Kristen Du Mez’s recent book, <em>Jesus and John Wayne</em>, a text that examines the connection between American evangelicalism, Christian nationalism, rugged masculinity, and political power? How might Robinson’s novels and essays in conversation with Du Mez’s <em>Jesus and John Wayne </em>illuminate our understanding of the evangelical tradition in the United States?  These are some of the questions that the panel seeks to address.
</p><p>Please submit a 350-word paper proposal and short bio to both <a href="mailto:haein.park@biola.edu" target="_blank">haein.park@biola.edu</a> and <a href="mailto:kludwig@bsu.edu" target="_blank">kludwig@bsu.edu</a> by November 15, 2022.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 22:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666071431673718</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FEATURED JOB: Assistant Professor (Religious Studies)- National University of Singapore</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11312765/featured-job-assistant-professor-religious-studies-national</link>
						<dc:creator>Kendra Fuller</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Home Office Notices (Jobs, Reviews)</div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Singapore</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Anthropology, Area Studies, Asian History / Studies, Cultural History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The Department of Southeast Asian Studies at the National University of Singapore invites applications for a <strong>tenure-track position</strong> at the level of <strong>Assistant Professor in Religious Studies</strong>, <strong>beginning January 2024</strong>. We are particularly interested in recruiting a scholar who will enjoy the opportunity of working collaboratively in an area studies department.</p><p>We seek a scholar who specialises in <strong>Buddhism and/or Christianity and has knowledge of other major religions</strong>. The regional focus of the position is<strong> Mainland Southeast Asia (especially Myanmar, Thailand, and/or Cambodia; Myanmar being the priority)</strong>. The disciplinary focus is wide, as we are particularly interested in applicants whose research and teaching are multi- or inter-disciplinary. In particular, we welcome applicants who have a secondary specialisation in one or more of the following fields: <strong>economics, archaeology, media and digital studies, science and technology, urban studies, and gender and sexuality studies.</strong></p><p>Candidates must demonstrate excellence in teaching, as well as strong scholarship or high scholarly potential.</p><p> </p><p>The successful candidate will be expected to:</p><ol><li>be the Convenor of the Minor in Religious Studies;</li><li>teach courses in our undergraduate and graduate programmes in their areas of specialization, and</li><li>engage in an active and innovative research agenda.</li></ol><p> </p><p>Candidates should have <strong>expertise in Southeast Asian languages relevant to their research.</strong> The standard teaching load is three modules (courses) per academic year, with an expectation that the successful candidate will also advise students. </p><p> </p><p><strong>Application Process</strong></p><p>Interested applicants should submit an application dossier consisting of the following:</p><ul><li>Cover letter explaining your interest in the position and how your qualifications and plans fit into the long-term development and enhancement of the Department of Southeast Asian Studies (maximum 2 pages)</li><li>Up to date Curriculum vitae</li><li>Concise statement of your research trajectory thus far and publication plans (1-2 pages)</li><li>Concise statement of your teaching experience and interests, as well as possible courses you are able to offer to raise the profile of the department (1-2 pages)</li><li>Concise statement describing your personal qualities and experience in collaborative and leadership roles in academic projects and community engagements (1-2 pages)</li><li>Evidence of teaching experience (course reviews, sample syllabi, teaching awards)</li><li>A list of three referees (names, contact details and applicant’s relationship to them; only shortlisted applicants will be invited to submit reference letters)  </li></ul><p> </p><p> </p><p><strong>Candidates should submit all application materials online via the <a href="https://careers.nus.edu.sg/job-invite/17642/" rel="nofollow">NUS Careers Portal</a><a href="https://careers.nus.edu.sg/job-invite/17642/" rel="nofollow"> </a>and addressed to:</strong></p><address>Chair, Search Committee</address><address>Department of Southeast Asian Studies</address><address>Faculty of Arts and Social Sciences</address><address>National University of Singapore</address><p> </p><p><strong>Application Timeline</strong></p><p>Candidates should submit all application materials by <strong>31 December 2022</strong>. We will begin evaluating candidates immediately, but the position will remain open until a suitable candidate is found.</p><p> </p><p><strong>Other Information</strong></p><p>Remuneration will be internationally competitive and commensurate with qualifications and experience. The successful candidate may also enjoy housing benefits, relocation allowance, and other benefits depending on the type and duration of appointment and citizenship.</p><hr/><p>To submit YOUR job posting, please visit the H-Net Job Guide:<a href="https://www.h-net.org/jobs" rel="nofollow"> https://www.h-net.org/jobs</a></p><p>Featured jobs receive an added boost on H-Announce and H-Net’s social media channels.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Potential candidates are welcome to get in touch with the Chair of the Search Committee to answer any questions they may have at <a href="mailto:seas.recruitment@nus.edu.sg">seas.recruitment@nus.edu.sg</a>  </p></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php" target="_blank">https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php?id=64337</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 17:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666071431673717</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Literature as Vocation</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/10/14/literature-as-vocation</link>
						<dc:creator>plbrown@apu.edu</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Monday, October 17, 2022 - 10:56pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Patricia Brown/ Western Regional Conference on Christianity and Literature</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:plbrown@apu.edu">plbrown@apu.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/english-education">english-education</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/professional-topics">professional topics</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>December 1, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p> </p>
<p>Why do we do what we do in the field of literary studies? Why does it matter? To whom? What redemptive or transformative work does literature do? When? Where? How? We invite reflection and conversation about the different kinds of work literature does to and through writers, readers, teachers, thinkers, and scholars. Our topic is intentionally broad as we seek to inspire, encourage, and celebrate the creation, interpretation, and appreciation of literature from any historical period and any genre. Our format is inclusive with panels for professors, graduate and undergraduate students, as well as scholars from multiple disciplines including English, Modern Languages, Theology, Education, Psychology, Science, and Humanities.</p>
<p>Suggested topics include but are not limited to the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>the work of <strong>re-enchantment</strong>: magical realism, refreshment, joy, delight</li>
<li>the work of <strong>transformation</strong>: secular/post-secular accounts of religious experience, narratives of conversion and de-conversion, spiritual autobiography</li>
<li>the work of <strong>empathy</strong>: emotion and affect, caregiving, accounts of suffering, grief, and illness</li>
<li>the work of <strong>social justice</strong>: remembrance, rediscovery, lament, protest, reconciliation, peace</li>
<li>the work of <strong>stewardship</strong>: ecology, creation care, apocalypse</li>
</ul>
<p>E-mail a one-paragraph abstract for an individual presentation or a one-paragraph abstract for a group panel session by <strong>December 1, 2022 </strong>to <strong>Dr. Patricia Brown </strong>at <strong><a href="mailto:plbrown@apu.edu">plbrown@apu.edu</a></strong>. Undergraduate students must submit their entire paper for consideration</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666071431673716</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP Western Jewish Studies Association Conference, Las Vegas, March 12-13, 2022</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/10/14/cfp-western-jewish-studies-association-conference-las-vegas-march-12-13-2022</link>
						<dc:creator>Lawrence Baron</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Monday, October 17, 2022 - 10:36pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Western Jewish Studies Association</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:lbaron@sdsu.edu">lbaron@sdsu.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/ethnicity-and-national-identity">ethnicity and national identity</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/film-and-television">film and television</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>November 15, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Call for paper and panel proposals on all areas of Jewish Studies regardless of discipline, geographical focus, or time period.  The WJSA usually includes panels about Jews in the American West, pedagogical aspects in Jewish Studies, and contemporary Jewish issues.  It welcomes panels devoted to the major anniversaries of events in Jewish history or important Jewish individuals in 2023, for example:</p>
<p>1993 US Holocaust Memorial Museum Opens, <em>Schindler’s List</em> Premiers                                                                                              1973 The Yom Kippur War                                                                                                                                                              1948: Israeli War of Independence                                                                                                                                                1923 Birth of Shimon Peres, British Mandate Goes into Effect, 1st Performance of <em>The Dybbuk                                                            </em>1873  Union of American Hebrew Congregations Founded                                                                                                                1848  Jews in the Revolutions of 1848                                                                                                                                            1648  Chmielnicki Pogroms                                                                                                                                           </p>
<p>Paper proposals should be no longer than one double-spaced typed page and should be submitted with a short CV that contains contact information. The submission of panels on a common topic is encouraged.  Organizers of panels should submit a cover sheet with the title of the panel and the titles of each of the papers and contact information for each presenter, followed by the individual paper proposals and brief CVs.  Scholars of Jewish Studies including graduate students are invited to submit proposals for papers/presentations/workshops.  A limited number of modest stipends are available for graduate students and overseas scholars who will be presenting papers.  Individuals wishing to chair a session should submit their CV.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Although it is planning for an in-person conference, the WJSA will feature virtual panels.  If you want to present virtually, you are encouraged to form a panel with other likeminded presenters.  Individual virtual proposals will only be accepted if a thematically coherent virtual panel can be formed with other proposals or if the COVID situation necessitates the holding of the conference virtually.       </p>
<p> </p>
<p>The WJSA annually awards the Baron Award to the best student paper presented at the conference. The winner receives $200.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Although there is no WSJA membership requirement for participation in the conference, a higher registration fee is charged for non-members. </p>
<p> </p>
<p>Proposals should be emailed to Lawrence Baron at: <a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/blank">lbaron@mail.sdsu.edu</a>   The deadline for submission of proposals is <strong>November 15, 2022</strong>.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666071431673715</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ October 31, 2022] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104126</link>
						<description>Publication Name: Call for Papers: The Somatechnics of Violence: Affective, (Im)material and Digital Transformations<br/><br/><p><em><strong>Call for Papers: The Somatechnics of Violence: Affective, (Im)material and Digital Transformations </strong></em></p>
<p><em>Special issue editors: Evelien Geerts (University of Birmingham), Chantelle Gray (North-West University) &amp; Delphi Carstens (University of the Western Cape)</em><br/><br/>A growing number of philosophical studies are arguing for new frameworks from which to theorise and grapple with contemporary forms of violence that escape the overdetermined representations thereof that ensued in the decade or so following 9/11 – which Jeffrey Di Leo and Uppinder Mehan aptly called critical ‘theory’s “ground zero”’ (2012: 16). While it is true that these attacks transformed current-day perceptions and theorisations of violence, the ensuing so-called Wars on Terror led to reductionist treatments thereof, thereby eliding the incredibly complex, multi-layered and lived phenomenon that violence is and which cannot be captured in universal frameworks but must, instead, be situated in its material, immaterial, affective and now digital contexts.<br/><br/>Such situated philosophical analyses of violence require a different vocabulary and world-reimagining methodologies: it is, we hold, no longer sufficient to merely address the impact that violence currently has through, for example, the Foucauldian (1980) idea of the apparatus – a contextual arrangement of discursive-material phenomena diagramming, and thus maintaining societal power relations, while shaping subjects. Neither does the Harawayan (1988: 591) ‘apparatus of bodily production’, which pays more attention to the intersecting lived categories of gender, race/ethnicity, sexuality and so on, suffice as an analytical instrument. Although both Foucault and Haraway accurately theorise the differential mattering of embodied subjects and the violence inflicted during processes of (non-)mattering, today’s societies, together with the myriad ways in which violence manifests itself, are rapidly changing. Driven by neoliberal governmentality, extractive capitalism and contemporary (counter-) terrorism, present-day societies of hyper-control are plagued by violent threats from multiple, often crisscrossing, directions engendered by interlinked macrostructures and microevents that combine the (im)material, discursive, digital and affective. We may think here, for example, of the violent – yet insufficiently emphasised – damage inflicted by white supremacy, institutionalised racism and racist microaggressions; the mob-inciting divisive rhetoric of neo-fascist populists pushing for alt-facts and alt-realities; the increase in affective disorders, driven by what Mark Fisher (2009) calls capitalist realism; material-immaterial infowars engendering algorithmic violence, fittingly described by Mimi Onuoha as ‘violence that an algorithm or automated decision-making system inflicts by preventing people from meeting their basic needs’ (2018: n. p.; also see Noble 2018; Bellanova et al. 2021); or the Anthropogenic-Capitalogenic ecocide unfolding itself and impacting transcorporeally entangled human and more-than-human worlds (see Alaimo 2016).<br/><br/>It would seem, then, that novel analytical perspectives are needed and this, as we would like to propose, can be found in what Joseph Pugliese and Susan Stryker (2009: 2-3), inspired by Foucault, have identified as a ‘somatechnical assemblage’. Initially intimated by Nikki Sullivan (2005), but further developed by Joseph Pugliese and Susan Stryker, and later on also by Sullivan and Samantha Murray (2011: v) and Line Henriksen and Marietta Radomska (2015), somatechnics stands for ‘the materialisation of embodied being[s]’ or how they come to matter through processes of material-discursive-affective meaning-making. Bringing together the corporeal and the technological – which, according to a somatechnical perspective, are always already enmeshed – a somatechnics-focused analytical framework zooms in on the (un)making and (de)humanisation of corporeal beings, all while creating space for a much-needed ethico-political critique of the various types of violence these corporeal beings are forced to endure.<br/><br/>While we are open to a variety of frameworks and methodologies from which to theorise violence, we encourage special issue contributors to think beyond so-called shifts and similar epistemological paradigms that follow a logic of tracing – a way of thinking that fixes phenomena by means of neatly organised structures and representations (see Deleuze and Guattari 2005 for this critique). The reason for this is that we, in somatechnical fashion, would like to emphasise the entangled nature of the corporeal, incorporeal and the technological; the micro and the macro; as well as of humans, the more-than-human and the dehumanised – aspects brought into sharp focus by, for example, critical new materialist, posthumanist and Deleuzoguattarian philosophies (see e.g., Chen 2012; Braidotti 2013; Shotwell 2016). Or as Elizabeth Grosz has put it: When analysing violence, ‘the incorporeal conditions of corporeality, the excesses beyond and within corporeality that frame, orient and direct material things and processes’ need to be examined in relation to corporeality and material (infra)structures (Grosz 2017; Grosz in Grosz and Bell 2017: 5).<br/><br/><strong>Suggested topics:</strong><br/>• The somatechnics of violence (with a focus on the embodied and more-than-bodily lived experience of violence, and that on either a collective or individual level);<br/>• the (im)materiality of violence – political or other (e.g., disposability, dispossession, (neo-) colonialism, extractive capitalism and environmental violence, (bio-/)necropolitics in relation to somatechnics, which bodies come to matter and not matter through violence and its traumas, …);<br/>• (im)material violence, the affective and the hauntological;<br/>• somatechnics-focused, critical new materialist, posthumanist and/or Deleuzoguattarian perspectives on violence;<br/>• somatechnics-focused, critical cartographical and other related methodological takes on violence;<br/>• the somatechnics of violence related to new digital realities;<br/>• the somatechnics of violence in relation to identity politics; populist and (neo-)fascist politics and political ressentiment; infowars, alt-facts and alt-realities; algorithmic violence and/or other manifestations of digital violence – and the concrete impact the latter phenomena have on (individual and/or collective) embodied subjects, groups and entities.<br/><br/><u>1This call for papers is connected to the ERC-sponsored “Urban Terrorism in Europe (2004-19): Remembering, Imagining, and Anticipating Violence” project at the University of Birmingham (ERC-2019-STG 851329) and the November 2021 “(Im)materialities of Violence” conference.</u><br/><br/><br/><strong>Timeline &amp; submission details:</strong><br/><em><u><strong>Abstract submission: October 31st, 2022</strong></u></em><br/><br/>• Abstract acceptance/rejection notification: mid-November 2022<br/>• Manuscript submission: March 31st, 2023<br/>• Peer reviews received: May 31st, 2023<br/>• Revised manuscripts due: August 31st, 2023<br/>• Final manuscript due to EUP: November 30th, 2023<br/><br/>We invite potential contributors to submit an abstract of 500 words by the 31st of October 2022. Please include the contact details and biographies (not included in the word count) of all of the contributors on the abstract document. Abstracts (and manuscripts) must be formatted according to Somatechnics’ author guidelines.<br/><br/>Please note that the initial acceptance of an abstract does not guarantee publication and that all manuscripts will undergo a double-blind review process. We strive toward diversity among our contributors in terms of career-stage, disciplines, self-identification and affiliation. We are happy to accommodate different accessibility needs. Please get in touch with (one of) the guest editors for any of these issues.<br/><br/>The author(s) should email their abstract proposal as a Word file to all of the guest editors: geerts.evelien@gmail.com, gray.chantelle@gmail.com, carstensdelphi@gmail.com. For more information, contact the guest editors.<br/><br/><strong>More about the journal:</strong><br/><em>Somatechnics: Journal of Bodies – Technologies – Power</em> is a journal that provides a forum for research on all things relating to ‘the body’, critically engaging with the technological, ethical and political implications of a wide range of practices, techniques and academic spaces. Articles present innovative debates in topics such as spatialization, race, reproduction, gender, sexuality, medicine, consumption, gaming, film, globalization, ecology, bioscience, family, education, health, visuality and more.<br/><br/><strong>More about the special issue editors:</strong><br/>Evelien Geerts (Ph.D.) is a multidisciplinary philosopher, a Research Fellow at the University of Birmingham and a Posthumanities Hub affiliated researcher. She holds a Ph.D. in Feminist Studies and History of Consciousness from the University of California, Santa Cruz. Her research interests include new materialist, posthumanist and Deleuzoguattarian philosophy, critical epistemologies, political philosophical questions of identity, difference, and violence, and critical and diffractive pedagogies. She previously has published in, amongst others, Philosophy Today, Women’s Studies International Forum, and Rhizomes—publications that can be found at www.eveliengeerts.com.<br/><br/>Chantelle Gray (Ph.D.) is a contemporary Continental philosopher whose interests span critical algorithm studies, queer theory and gender studies, cognitive studies, anarchism and Continental philosophy, especially the work of Deleuze and Guattari. The interdisciplinary nature of her work allows her to ask critical questions about how to take care of humans, technologies and ecologies in the digital age. She is the co-convener of the biennial South African Deleuze &amp; Guattari Studies Conference (www.deleuzeguattari.co.za) and serves on the editorial boards of <em>Somatechnics</em> and <em>Stilet</em>. Her books include <em>Deleuze and Anarchism</em>, co-edited with Aragorn Eloff (2019, Edinburgh University Press) and <em>Anarchism after Deleuze and Guattari</em> (2022, Bloomsbury). <br/><br/>Delphi Carstens (Ph.D.) is a Lecturer at the University of the Western Cape, South Africa. His research interests include the Anthropocene/Capitalocene, Deleuzoguattarian pedagogical interventions, uncanny science fictions and sorcerous new materialisms. His publications include, amongst others, chapters in edited volumes by Palgrave, Sternberg, Bloomsbury and Taylor and Francis as well as journal articles in <em>The South African Journal of Higher Education</em> (SAJHE), <em>Education as Change</em>, <em>Alternation</em>, <em>CriSTal</em>, <em>parallax</em> and <em>Somatechnics</em>.</p>
<p><strong>References used:</strong><br/>Alaimo, Stacy (2016), <em>Exposed: Environmental Politics and Pleasures in Posthuman Times</em>, Minneapolis: University of Minnesota Press.<br/>Bellanova, Rocco, Kristina Irion, Katja Lindskov Jacobsen, Francesco Ragazzi, Rune Saugmann and Lucy Suchman (2021), ‘Toward a Critique of Algorithmic Violence”, <em>International Political Sociology</em>, 15: 1, pp. 121–150. 10.1093/ips/olab003.<br/>Braidotti, Rosi (2013), <em>The Posthuman</em>, Cambridge: Polity Press.<br/>Chen, Mel Y. (2012), <em>Animacies: Biopolitics, Racial Mattering, and Queer Affect</em>, Durham: Duke University Press.<br/>Deleuze, Gilles and Félix Guattari (2005), <em>A Thousand Plateaus: Capitalism and Schizophrenia</em>, Translation and Foreword by Brian Massumi. Minneapolis: University of Minnesota Press.<br/>Di Leo, Jeffrey R. and Uppinder Mehan (eds.) (2012), <em>Terror, Theory and the Humanities</em>, Ann Arbor: Open Humanities Press. An imprint of MPublishing–University of Michigan Library.<br/>Fisher, Mark (2009), <em>Capitalist Realism: Is There No Alternative?</em>, Winchester: Zero Books.<br/>Foucault, Michel (1980), ‘The Confession of the Flesh’, in <em>Power/Knowledge: Selected Interviews and Other Writings,</em> 1972–1977. Translated by Colin Gordon. Brighton: Harvester, pp. 194–228.<br/>Grosz, Elizabeth (2017), <em>Incorporeal: Ontology, Ethics, and the Limits of Materialism</em>, New York: Columbia University Press.<br/>Grosz, Elizabeth, and Vikki Bell (2017), ‘An Interview with Elizabeth Grosz: ‘“The Incorporeal”’, <em>Theory, Culture &amp; Society</em>, 34: 7–8, pp. 237–243. 10.1177/0263276417736814.<br/>Haraway, Donna J. (1988), ‘Situated Knowledges: The Science Question in Feminism and the Privilege of Partial Perspective,’ <em>Feminist Studies</em>, 14: 3, pp. 575–599. 10.2307/3178066.<br/>Henriksen, Line and Marietta Radomska (2015), ‘Missing Links and Non/Human Queerings: An Introduction,’ <em>Somatechnics</em>, 5: 2, pp. 113–119. 10.3366/soma.2015.0156.<br/>Noble, Safiya U. (2018), <em>Algorithms of Oppression: How Search Engines Reinforce Racism</em>, New York: NYU Press.<br/>Onuoha, Mimi (2018, February 22), ‘On Algorithmic Violence’, GitHub. https://github.com/MimiOnuoha/On-Algorithmic-Violence.<br/>Pugliese, Joseph and Susan Stryker (2009). ‘The Somatechnics of Race and Whiteness,’ <em>Social Semiotics</em>, 19: 1, pp. 1–8. 10.1080/10350330802632741.<br/>Shotwell, Alexis (2016), <em>Against Purity: Living Ethically in Compromised Times</em>, Minneapolis: The University of Minnesota Press.<br/>Sullivan, Nikki (2005), ‘Somatechnics, or, the Social Inscription of bodies and Selves,’ <em>Australian Feminist Studies</em>, 20: 48, pp. 363–366. 10.1080/08164640500280274.<br/>Sullivan, Nikki and Samantha Murray (2011), ‘Editorial,’ <em>Somatechnics</em>, 1: 1, pp. v–vii.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 05:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1665898633218707</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ June 2, 2023 -  June 4, 2023] Conference or similar: Intuition, Creation, Duration, and Relativity</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104130</link>
						<description>Venue: 5998 Alcala Park<br/><br/><p>The North American Society for Early Phenomenology invites abstracts for papers on phenomenological work related to intuition, creation, duration, and relativity for our annual conference.</p>
<p>In the phenomenological rejection of both rationalism and empiricism, the concepts of intuition, creation, duration and relativity pervade the work of early phenomenologists. For this conference, we invite work on these concepts, with special attention to Henri Bergson’s influence on phenomenology, along with contemporary work related to these concepts. Scholarly papers on the history of phenomenology are welcomed alongside work developed with an awareness of the method of reductions common to early phenomenologists. For example, intuition and how Husserl adapted it to the reception of the <em>eidos</em> his developing exegesis of the phenomenological method of reductions, creation and its attendant metaphysics, freedom and determinism, open and closed morality, static and dynamic religion, order and chaos, time and its relation to consciousness, and relativity in conversation with scientific pursuits, change, movement, unity and multiplicity—all of these phenomenological concepts bespeak a metaphysics (or perhaps epistemology) that diverges from more well-known analytic counterparts.  </p>
<p>As always, we encourage submissions dealing with the thought of the full spectrum of early phenomenologists (including Edmund Husserl, Franz Brentano, Carl Stumpf, Theodor Lipps, Alexander Pfänder, Max Scheler, Moritz Geiger, Hedwig Conrad-Martius, Eugen Fink, Roman Ingarden, Edith Stein, Dietrich Von Hildebrand, Adolf Reinach, Maximilian Beck, Jean Hering, Henri Bergson, Emmanuel Levinas, et al.) as well as figures who were in conversation with or influenced the early phenomenological movement (Ravaisson, Kierkegaard, Nietzsche, etc).</p>
<p>We especially encourage submissions from individuals who identify as members of groups currently underrepresented in philosophy and academia more generally.</p>
<p><strong>Abstracts</strong> should be <strong>400-600 words</strong> and include a short bibliography. Abstracts must be prepared for blind review and sent to Charlene Elsby (<u>celsby@ingarden.org</u>).</p>
<p><strong>Deadline</strong> for submissions is <strong>February 1th, 2023.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Decisions</strong> will be sent out no later than <strong>March 1st, 2023.</strong></p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 05:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1665898633218706</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ February 1, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Intuition, Creation, Duration, and Relativity</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104134</link>
						<description><p>The North American Society for Early Phenomenology invites abstracts for papers on phenomenological work related to intuition, creation, duration, and relativity for our annual conference.</p>
<p>In the phenomenological rejection of both rationalism and empiricism, the concepts of intuition, creation, duration and relativity pervade the work of early phenomenologists. For this conference, we invite work on these concepts, with special attention to Henri Bergson’s influence on phenomenology, along with contemporary work related to these concepts. Scholarly papers on the history of phenomenology are welcomed alongside work developed with an awareness of the method of reductions common to early phenomenologists. For example, intuition and how Husserl adapted it to the reception of the <em>eidos</em> his developing exegesis of the phenomenological method of reductions, creation and its attendant metaphysics, freedom and determinism, open and closed morality, static and dynamic religion, order and chaos, time and its relation to consciousness, and relativity in conversation with scientific pursuits, change, movement, unity and multiplicity—all of these phenomenological concepts bespeak a metaphysics (or perhaps epistemology) that diverges from more well-known analytic counterparts.  </p>
<p>As always, we encourage submissions dealing with the thought of the full spectrum of early phenomenologists (including Edmund Husserl, Franz Brentano, Carl Stumpf, Theodor Lipps, Alexander Pfänder, Max Scheler, Moritz Geiger, Hedwig Conrad-Martius, Eugen Fink, Roman Ingarden, Edith Stein, Dietrich Von Hildebrand, Adolf Reinach, Maximilian Beck, Jean Hering, Henri Bergson, Emmanuel Levinas, et al.) as well as figures who were in conversation with or influenced the early phenomenological movement (Ravaisson, Kierkegaard, Nietzsche, etc).</p>
<p>We especially encourage submissions from individuals who identify as members of groups currently underrepresented in philosophy and academia more generally.</p>
<p><strong>Abstracts</strong> should be <strong>400-600 words</strong> and include a short bibliography. Abstracts must be prepared for blind review and sent to Charlene Elsby (<u>celsby@ingarden.org</u>).</p>
<p><strong>Deadline</strong> for submissions is <strong>February 1th, 2023.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Decisions</strong> will be sent out no later than <strong>March 1st, 2023.</strong></p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 05:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1665898633218705</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
