<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 12:27:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 12:27:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ April 27, 2023] Talk or similar: Book Launch of Anna Tomaszewska's &quot;Kant’s Rational Religion and the Radical Enlightenment</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/109125</link>
						<description>Venue: Grodzka 52<br/><br/>Speakers at this event: <br/>Anna Tomaszewska (Jagiellonian University)<br/>Stephen R. Palmquist (Hong Kong Baptist University)<br/>Diego Lucci (American University in Bulgaria)<br/>Wojciech Kozyra (University of Warsaw)<br/><br/><p>The team of the project "Between Secularization and Reform: Religious Rationalism in the Late 17th Century and in the Enlightenment" are pleased to invite you to a book launch of Anna Tomaszewska's "Kant's Rational Religion and the Radical Enlightenment. From Spinoza to Contemporary Debates" (Bloomsbury, 2022). </p>
<p>Tomaszewska challenges the view of Kant as attempting to merely reconcile faith and reason and reconceptualizes his religious thought along rationalist lines. By doing so, she opens up the possibility of understanding Kant in terms of the radical enlightenment originating with Spinoza rather than, as before, classifying him as a moderate enlightener.</p>
<p>The event consists of a presentation by the author, followed by three commentaries and a discussion. Commentators include Diego Lucci (American University in Bulgaria), Stephen Palmquist (Hong Kong Baptist University), and Wojciech Kozyra (University of Warsaw). </p>
<p>The hybrid event will take place on April 27th at 18:00 CET in Kraków, at Grodzka 52 Street, in room 5 at the Collegium Broscianum at the Institute of Religious Studies (Jagiellonian University). Registration is available online at the project website https://www.religiousrationalism.com/events</p>
<p>For more information concerning the book and the opportunity to purchase it at up to 20 % limited-time discount, visit https://www.bloomsbury.com/uk/kants-rational-religion-and-the-radical-enlightenment-9781350195844/.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 05:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1678772244083044</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>DEADLINE for ABSTRACTS EXTENDED TO  APRIL 15; Conference &quot;The social science of religion - Troeltsch, Weber, Simmel and others&quot; 1-2 June 2023</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12552843/deadline-abstracts-extended-april-15-conference-social-science</link>
						<dc:creator>Michal Warchala</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-01T00:00:00-04:00">June 1, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-02T00:00:00-04:00">June 2, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Poland</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>German History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Social Sciences, Sociology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span>CALL FOR PAPERS </span></span></p><p><span><span><i>The social science of religion: Troeltsch, Weber, Simmel and others</i></span></span></p><p><span><span>International Conference</span></span></p><p><span><span>June 1-2, 2023 Cracow, Poland </span></span></p><p><strong><span><span><span><span>Invited keynote speakers:</span></span></span></span></strong></p><p><span><span>Prof. Hans Joas (Humboldt-Universität)</span></span></p><p><span><span>Prof. Ulrich Schmiedel (Edinburgh University)  </span></span></p><p><span><span>Prof. Dominika Motak (Jagiellonian University)</span></span></p><p><span><span>The year 2023 sees the centenary of Ernst Troeltsch’s death. Finding this a good occasion to re-visit Troeltsch’s work together with its broader context the Chair for Sociology of Religion at the Pedagogical University of Cracow would like to invite for the international conference <i>The (social) science of religion: Troeltsch, Weber, Simmel and others</i>. The main idea of the conference is to acknowledge and re-consider Troeltsch’s (rarely appreciated) role within the “visionary company” of great social scientists dealing with religion in the early 20<sup>th</sup> century. What we attempt is broad and interdisciplinary reflection in which Troeltsch’s theological, philosophical and sociological approach together with the work of his contemporaries constitutes a point of departure. Submissions from sociologists, historians, theologians or philosophers are welcome. Different approaches to the main theme, both appreciative and critical, debates around heritage and questions of possible meanings that the “social science of religion” may have for (and in) our time – all this is of utmost interest to us. The list of possible topics includes:    </span></span></p><p><span><span><span>1) Troeltsch as a theologian and social scientist. Troeltsch has usually been treated as a theologian only while his contributions to social sciences or philosophy of religion have been overlooked or simply forgotten. But this is as much pigeonholing as treating Weber solely as a “classic of sociology”. In fact what both Troeltsch and Weber offer is a broad synthesis of theology, sociology, history and philosophy</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>2) </span></span></span><span><span><span>Troeltsch and his contemporaries – mutual inspirations and influences. Troeltsch has long been in the shadow of Weber and only recently was the importance of his work for social sciences and our reflection on modernity re-discovered. The same more or less can be said of Simmel.       </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>3) Troeltsch’s multidisciplinary “science of religion” among similar projects by Weber, Simmel Durkheim or James </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>4) Visions of modernity and secularization in the writings of Troeltsch, Max Weber, Georg Simmel, Émile Durkheim or William James: parallels and differences.      </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>5) Protestant Reformation in the writings of Troeltsch and Weber. The mutual influence of Troeltsch’s account of the birth of modernity out of the spirit of Protestantism and Weber’s theses about Reformation and capitalism is now indisputable. The question which may be asked today is which of these two accounts seem more relevant and inspiring from today’s perspective.  </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>6) Mutual interactions between theology and social sciences in Troeltsch and other representatives of the “science of religion”.</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>7) Religion, historical consciousness and the question of values in Troeltsch and in the social science of the early 20<sup>th</sup> century. </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>8) The question of “public function” and political responsibilities of both social science and theology according to Troeltsch, Weber, Simmel or James. </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><u>The conference will be held on 1-2 June 2023</u></b><b> </b>at the Pedagogical University of Cracow in Cracow, Poland. The precise venue will be announced later.  </span></span></p><p><span><span><u>Abstracts of max. 300 words</u> together with a short cv should be sent to: </span></span></p><p><span><span><b><a href="mailto:science.of.religion.conference@gmail.com">science.of.religion.conference@gmail.com</a></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><u>The deadline for abstracts is 15 April 2023</u></b><b>. </b>Authors will be notified of the acceptance of their submissions by <b>20</b> <b>April 2023</b>.  </span></span></p><p><span><span>Conference languages are English and Polish.</span></span></p><p><span><span><b><u>Fee options:</u></b></span></span></p><p><span><span>200 PLN/50 EUR – participation on-site </span></span></p><p><span><span>250 PLN/80 EUR – participation + lunches on June 1 and 2</span></span></p><p><span><span>300 PLN/100 EUR – participation + lunches + conference dinner on June 1</span></span></p><p><span><span>Abstract submitters are kindly asked to choose one of the options.  </span></span></p><p><span><span>All other costs, including transport and accommodation, should be covered separately by the participants. Cracow is a typical tourist city so there are plenty of accommodation options – the organizers will be happy to provide all necessary information but cannot make any bookings. </span></span></p><p><span><span>All queries concerning the conference should be addressed to the organizing committee at <b><a href="mailto:science.of.religion.conference@gmail.com">science.of.religion.conference@gmail.com</a></b>.  </span></span></p><p><span><span><u>Organizing committee:</u></span></span></p><p><span><span>Dr. Michał Warchala (chairman)                                                                  </span></span></p><p><span><span>Prof. Piotr Stawiński </span></span></p><p><span><span>Dr. Grzegorz Kubiński (conference secretary)</span></span></p><p><span><span>Dr. Maria Roginska </span></span></p><p><span><span>Dr. Bogdan Więckiewicz </span></span></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr. Michał Warchala </p><p>Pedagogical University of Cracow</p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:science.of.religion.conference@gmail.com">science.of.religion.conference@gmail.com</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 18:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1678772244083043</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Conference announcement: Accessibility, Archives, and Native American Boarding Schools: Pathways for Catholic History, March 24-25, 2023</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12537116/conference-announcement-accessibility-archives-and-native</link>
						<dc:creator>Patrick Hayes</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-24T00:00:00-04:00">March 24, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-25T00:00:00-04:00">March 25, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Arizona</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>American History / Studies, Archival Science, Childhood and Education, Native American History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>This two-day, hybrid conference brings together academic historians and archivists to discuss Native American Boarding Schools and the recorded legacy of the Catholic Church in their operation, roughly from 1819 to 1969. The conference is sponsored by the American Catholic Historical Association and is funded through the ACHA’s SHARP grant—a one-year project designed to place historians, archivists, and members of Native communities in conversation and collaboration.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Attendees at this two-day conference will hear from ten invited participants who were selected to present on their current or past work and the overarching theme of accessibility—to Catholic archival repositories, to new knowledge or understandings, to new issues affecting tribal histories, especially in relation to the Church, and so forth. They will present formal papers of 20 minutes in duration followed by questions and comments from the audience, both on-site and online. Over the course of two days, three contemplated sessions of an hour and a half each, plus another group round table will give closure to our conference. Registration details, along with the full program, may be found here:</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><a href="http://www.achahistory.org/sharp2023" rel="nofollow">www.achahistory.org/sharp2023</a></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Please save the dates: March 24-25, 2023. For further information, please contact the ACHA grant coordinator, Dr. Patrick Hayes (<a href="mailto:pjhayesphd@gmail.com">pjhayesphd@gmail.com</a>).</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Patrick Hayes, Ph.D.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Redemptorist Archives</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Philadelphia, PA</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Patrick Hayes</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:pjhayesphd@gmail.com">pjhayesphd@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="http://www.achahistory.org/sharp2023" target="_blank">http://www.achahistory.org/sharp2023</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 17:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1678772244083042</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP [Extended] - &quot;Apocalyptic Nostalgia: Cold War Imagery in Popular Culture&quot;, Manchester July 13th 2023</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12522205/cfp-extended-apocalyptic-nostalgia-cold-war-imagery-popular</link>
						<dc:creator>Andrew Crome</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-21T00:00:00-04:00">March 21, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>American History / Studies, Art, Art History &amp; Visual Studies, Cultural History / Studies, Popular Culture Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><b>Extended deadline for submissions: Tuesday 21<sup>st</sup> March 2023.</b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Since the end of the Cold War, its imagery, atmosphere, and music have been repeatedly appropriated and reappropriated within contemporary popular culture. More than thirty years after the Berlin Wall fell, these images continue to appeal to generations with no memory of the original tensions of the time. From the early Cold War imagery of games such as the <i>Fallout</i> series, or the mid-1980s backdrop of Soviet infiltration in <i>Stranger Things</i>, visual culture, music, and ideas from the period are constantly recycled in popular culture. These images are often linked to fears of nuclear destruction or disturbing post-apocalyptic settings, while also recalling nostalgic and often patriotic images of a lost world of the West. With the recent Russian invasion of Ukraine and heightened fear of nuclear war, these images are being appropriated and applied in new ways online and in popular entertainment. </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>This conference invites participants to examine this theme and to explore the complexities of encountering Cold War imagery within popular film, television, video and tabletop games, music, graphic novels and social media content. In particular, it aims to examine the way in which this imagery impacts understandings of the apocalyptic and post-apocalyptic within popular culture. Potential topics might include, but are not limited to:</span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span>The role of nostalgia and nuclear destruction on screen.</span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span>The influence of popular culture on historical memory.</span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span>“Alternative histories” of the Cold War in popular culture.</span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span>Live action roleplay.</span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span>“Apocalyptic fandom”.</span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span>Use of Cold War-era music in film, television and gaming.</span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span>The role of Cold War narratives and imagery in Marvel/DC franchises media.</span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span>The use of apocalypticism in historical and popular documentaries.</span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span>Cold War imagery on social media related to the Ukraine War.</span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span>Cold War kitsch and ironic nostalgia.</span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span>Player agency in apocalyptic video games. </span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span>The conference will take place on Thursday 13<sup>th</sup> July 2023 at Imperial War Museum North, Manchester, UK. There is no charge for registration/attendance for those presenting papers.</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>For submissions, email 250-word abstracts with a short biography to Dr. Andrew Crome (<a href="mailto:a.crome@mmu.ac.uk">a.crome@mmu.ac.uk</a>) by Tuesday 21<sup>st</sup> March 2023.</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>See <a href="https://censamm.org/conferences/cold-war-nostalgia" rel="nofollow">www.censamm.org/conferences/cold-war-nostalgia</a> for more information. Organised by Manchester Metropolitan University and the Centre for the Critical Study of Apocalyptic and Millennial Movements.</span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr Andrew Crome, Manchester Metropolitan University</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:a.crome@mmu.ac.uk">a.crome@mmu.ac.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="http://www.censamm.org/conferences/cold-war-nostalgi" target="_blank">http://www.censamm.org/conferences/cold-war-nostalgi</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1678343835329134</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – March 8, 2023</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-march-8-2023/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find 2 new job opportunities, 2 grants, 4 awards, 11 Call for Papers, and 9 upcoming conferences/speakers.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 33!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Open-rank position in Sociology (1-year visiting or rolling-track full-time position, subfield and specialization open)</h4>



<p>The American University of Sharjah, UAE (classes taught in English)</p>



<p>Deadline: March 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="http://www.rraweb.org/sociology-position-american-university-of-sharjah/">http://www.rraweb.org/sociology-position-american-university-of-sharjah/</a></p>



<h4>Visiting Assistant Professor of Religious Studies &amp; Theology (1-year, non-renewable)</h4>



<p>Canisius College, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: Until filled</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.canisius.edu/cw/en-us/job/495012/visiting-assistant-professor-of-religious-studies-theology?fbclid=IwAR3Cg7humnrASqp-kZw2SgXJWKve5j0789H7lsdnKMY0298jvgORQgKG6WQ">https://careers.canisius.edu/cw/en-us/job/495012/visiting-assistant-professor-of-religious-studies-theology?fbclid=IwAR3Cg7humnrASqp-kZw2SgXJWKve5j0789H7lsdnKMY0298jvgORQgKG6WQ</a></p>



<h4>AAR/SBL Job Forum</h4>



<p><a href="https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search">https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search</a></p>



<h2>Grants:</h2>



<h4>Social Science Research Council: Religion, Spirituality, and Democratic Renewal Grants</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 20, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.ssrc.org/programs/religion-and-the-public-sphere/religion-spirituality-and-democratic-renewal-fellowship/">https://www.ssrc.org/programs/religion-and-the-public-sphere/religion-spirituality-and-democratic-renewal-fellowship/</a></p>



<h4>Religious Research Association Annual Meeting Travel Grant</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="http://www.rraweb.org/annual-meeting/rra-travel-grant/">http://www.rraweb.org/annual-meeting/rra-travel-grant/</a></p>



<h2>Awards:</h2>



<h4>AAR Journalism Awards – Best in-depth Newswriting, Best in-depth Multimedia Journalism</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 10, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://aarweb.org/AARMBR/Who-We-Are-/Award-Programs-/Awards/Journalism-Award.aspx">Journalism Award (aarweb.org)</a></p>



<h4>Ruth Alexander Award</h4>



<p>June 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12485457/ruth-alexander-award">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12485457/ruth-alexander-award</a></p>



<h4>Peace History Society Book, Article, and Lifetime Achievements Prizes</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12478627/call-nominations-peace-history-society-book-article-and">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12478627/call-nominations-peace-history-society-book-article-and</a></p>



<h4>AAR Book Award</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 12, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://events.resultsathand.com/aar/1596/speakersubmissions/showform/102-AAR-Book-Award-Nomination-Form">https://events.resultsathand.com/aar/1596/speakersubmissions/showform/102-AAR-Book-Award-Nomination-Form</a></p>



<h4>Outstanding Applied Research Award</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="http://www.rraweb.org/outstanding-applied-research-award/">http://www.rraweb.org/outstanding-applied-research-award/</a></p>



<h4>Constant H. Jacquet Research Awards</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="http://www.rraweb.org/constant-h-jacquet-research-awards/">http://www.rraweb.org/constant-h-jacquet-research-awards/</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>Sons &amp; Daughters of Narnia: Tracing CS Lewis’s Literary Influence into the 21<sup>st</sup> Century.</h4>



<p>Deadline: September 4, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=172294&amp;copyownerid=180112">http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=172294&amp;copyownerid=180112</a></p>



<h4>Weatherford College 5<sup>th</sup> Annual Philosophy of Religion and Politics</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 19, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/108865">https://philevents.org/event/show/108865</a></p>



<h3>Theism in the Language of Humanism: Reincarnations of the Transcendent God in the Secular Subject</h3>



<p>Deadline: April 5, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12509621/special-issue-journal-religions-subject-theism-language">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12509621/special-issue-journal-religions-subject-theism-language</a></p>



<h4>Journal of Lao Studies</h4>



<p>Deadline: June 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12511352/call-papers-journal-lao-studies">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12511352/call-papers-journal-lao-studies</a></p>



<h4>Architectures of the Soul. Religious Heritage: Understanding the Past, Shaping the Future</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12499168/call-abstracts-%E2%80%93-architectures-soul-4-religious-heritage">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12499168/call-abstracts-%E2%80%93-architectures-soul-4-religious-heritage</a></p>



<h4>British Association for the Study of Religions: “Environmental Endings and Religious Futures”</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 19, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/FDUIfPXRHb">https://t.co/FDUIfPXRHb</a></p>



<h4>Minds, Persons, and Cosmos</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/108697">https://philevents.org/event/show/108697</a></p>



<h4>“Putting Our Faith in Institutions:” Religion and Literature Permanent Section</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/03/01/%E2%80%9Cputting-our-faith-in-institutions%E2%80%9D-religion-and-literature-permanent-section">https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/03/01/%E2%80%9Cputting-our-faith-in-institutions%E2%80%9D-religion-and-literature-permanent-section</a></p>



<h4>Situating Religious Cognition</h4>



<p>Deadline: October 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/journal/religions/special_issues/7Q488424D1">https://www.mdpi.com/journal/religions/special_issues/7Q488424D1</a></p>



<h4>Rationality and Spirituality: Retrieving Edwards for Understanding Religion and Spirituality in Human Experience</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 20, 2023</p>



<p>More Information:  <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12325495/global-jonathan-edwards-congress-2023">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12325495/global-jonathan-edwards-congress-2023</a></p>



<h4>The Difficulties of Solidarity</h4>



<p>Deadline: August 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://ctjournal.org/call-for-papers-the-difficulties-of-solidarity/">https://ctjournal.org/call-for-papers-the-difficulties-of-solidarity/</a></p>



<h2>Conferences:</h2>



<h4>Accessibility, Archives, and Native American Boarding Schools: Pathways for Catholic History</h4>



<p>Date: March 24-25, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="http://www.achahistory.org/sharp2023">http://www.achahistory.org/sharp2023</a></p>



<h4>Women and Sermons in the Early Modern Anglo-Atlantic World</h4>



<p>Date: March 22, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12492700/women-and-sermons-early-modern-anglo-atlantic-world">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12492700/women-and-sermons-early-modern-anglo-atlantic-world</a></p>



<h4>Method Madness: A Graduate Student Roundtable</h4>



<p>Date: March 24<sup>th</sup>, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://twitter.com/sohinipillai/status/1632860846752780288?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw">https://twitter.com/sohinipillai/status/1632860846752780288?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw</a></p>



<h4>Material Religion: Objects, Images, Books</h4>



<p>Date: June 25-30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.americanantiquarian.org/material-religion-objects-images-books">https://www.americanantiquarian.org/material-religion-objects-images-books</a></p>



<h4>United Kingdom Association for Buddhist Studies annual conference</h4>



<p>Date: June 21-23, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12484014/conference-ukabs-2023-registration-now-open">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12484014/conference-ukabs-2023-registration-now-open</a></p>



<h4>Research, Personal Growth, and Finding your Significant Original Contribution to Knowledge</h4>



<p>Date: May 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/xkci1kgZYs">https://t.co/xkci1kgZYs</a></p>



<h4>The Significance of the Menorah in Ancient Judaism</h4>



<p>Date: March 8, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.ucl.ac.uk/institute-jewish-studies/">https://www.ucl.ac.uk/institute-jewish-studies/</a></p>



<h4>48<sup>th</sup> Spalding Symposium on Indian Religions</h4>



<p>Date: April 21-23, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/spalding-symposium-on-indian-religions-kings-college-london-tickets-547871387067?utm_campaign=post_publish&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_source=eventbrite&amp;utm_content=shortLinkNewEmail">https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/spalding-symposium-on-indian-religions-kings-college-london-tickets-547871387067?utm_campaign=post_publish&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_source=eventbrite&amp;utm_content=shortLinkNewEmail</a></p>



<h4>British Academy/Welcome Conference: Public Health After COVID – Beliefs, Religion, and Competing Epistemologies</h4>



<p>Date: May 26-27, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.thebritishacademy.ac.uk/events/british-academy-conferences/public-health-after-covid/">https://www.thebritishacademy.ac.uk/events/british-academy-conferences/public-health-after-covid/</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1678343835329133</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sons &amp; Daughters of Narnia: Tracing CS Lewis's Literary Influence into the 21st Century</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/03/05/sons-daughters-of-narnia-tracing-cs-lewiss-literary-influence-into-the-21st-century</link>
						<dc:creator>cwwhite78@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Wednesday, March 8, 2023 - 11:31am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Ulster University </div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:White-C36@ulster.ac.uk">White-C36@ulster.ac.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/childrens-literature">childrens literature</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/international-conferences">international conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/romantic">romantic</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/twentieth-century-and-beyond">twentieth century and beyond</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>September 4, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p align="center"><strong> </strong><strong><strong>                                                                    </strong></strong></p>
<p><strong><strong><strong>This will be the 2nd Annual CS Lewis Symposium at Ulster University</strong></strong></strong> </p>
<p><strong><strong>To be held: 13-14, November 2023 </strong></strong></p>
<p><strong><strong><strong>Location: Ulster University, Coleraine, Northern Ireland (United Kingdom)</strong></strong></strong></p>
<p><strong><strong>*Please Note: this will be an in-person event; at present, we cannot accommodate virtual/remote participation.</strong></strong></p>
<p><strong>Keynote: to be delivered by Dr Malcolm Guite (Cambridge University) and Professor Jerry Root (Wheaton College)</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rationale:</strong></p>
<p>This two-day, public-facing academic symposium aims to examine CS Lewis in the light of his influence upon 20th &amp; 21st century writers— those working in genres as varied as children’s fiction, sci-fi, literary and cultural criticism, popular apologetics, and even poetry. The central organising metaphor for the event is that of genealogy—the passing down to successive generations of the essences, qualities and characteristics which one inherits. Drawing upon this central metaphor, we will examine both the way in which Lewis was shaped by his own set of literary influences, and how he transmitted (and transmuted) these influences, through his own work, to writers throughout the world—in a way which almost recalls T.S. Eliot’s description of literary communion in ‘Tradition and the Individual Talent’. Our hope is that this ‘Janus-like’ approach—looking simultaneously back to Lewis’s ‘forbears’, and forward to his ‘sons and daughters’— will offer scholars working in diverse areas of Lewis research ample opportunity to carve out topics suited to their own interests. </p>
<p><strong>Call for Papers:</strong></p>
<p>We invite proposals of up to 250 words for 20-minute papers on some aspect of our theme. Submissions are welcome from scholars at every career stage, from ECR to well-established. Please include a brief bio with submission. </p>
<p><strong>Email proposals to: </strong><a href="mailto:White-C36@ulster.ac.uk">White-C36@ulster.ac.uk</a> by 5pm 04 September 2023</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 12:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1678343835329132</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Anglican and Episcopal History journal spotlights deaconesses, black women priests and Tudor Dynasty confusion</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12518582/anglican-and-episcopal-history-journal-spotlights-deaconesses</link>
						<dc:creator>Matthew Payne</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Journal</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-01T00:00:00-05:00">March 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><em><a href="https://hsec.us/AEH" rel="nofollow">Anglican and Episcopal History</a></em> (<em>AEH</em>) considers the ministry of two deaconesses, the first five Black women ordained as Episcopal priests, and Tudor Dynasty confusion in the March 2023 issue. Readers also enjoy two church reviews and 22 book reviews.</p><p>Two studies call attention to largely overlooked and poorly documented ministries of deaconesses.</p><p>In the first, <strong>Joan R. Gundersen</strong> examines the life’s work of Deaconess Ruth Byllesby (1865-1959) whose ministry included the dioceses of Pittsburgh, Georgia, Michigan, Wyoming, and Vermont.</p><p>Gundersen, former archivist in the Diocese of Pittsburgh, notes “the training deaconesses received made them pioneers in the field of social work.” Her essay is titled “In Plain Sight, and Yet Visible: The Ministry of Deaconess Ruth Byllesby”</p><p>Readers then learn about the 37-year ministry of Deaconess Emma Britt Drant (d. 1932) in the dioceses of Southern Ohio, Hawaii, and California. Drant’s ministry included the Chinese diaspora in both Hawaii and California as well as work among victims of the 1906 San Francisco earthquake and fire.</p><p>Retired priest <strong>John Rawlinson</strong> describes Drant as typical in being impoverished but “unique in pursuing most of her ministries without being closely supervised by a male priest.” His essay is titled “‘I… have $100 for my burial’: Deaconess Emma Britt Drant”</p><p><strong>Qiana M. Johnson</strong> then examines the unique gifts and experiences of the first five Black women ordained as priests in the Episcopal Church—Pauli Murray, Mary Adebonojo, Barbara C. Harris, Sandye Wilson, and Gayle Harris—describing “a common thread in the lives of these women was work around civil rights and social justice.”</p><p>Deacon Johnson, assoc. dean of libraries at Dartmouth College, calls for further research regarding power with consideration for “what happens when authority is invested in people society has long held as being unworthy of authority, especially Black women.” Johnson’s essay is titled “Being First Two Times Over: The First Five Black Women Episcopal Priests”</p><p><strong>John L. Kater</strong> takes readers to England during the Tudor Dynasty. He contends far-reaching Tudor Dynasty changes in the Church of England were not a “revolution” akin to reformed churches on the European continent. Kater points to the continuation of episcopacy; little structural change to organization of parishes, dioceses, and provinces; and basic rhythm of church life as remaining intact as examples. However, he notes “the theological understanding of many of the church’s services changed”</p><p>Kater is professor emeritus at the Church Divinity School of the Pacific and assoc. professor at Ming Hua Theological College in Hong Kong, China. His essay is “Ministry and the Tudors: Change, Confusion, and Continuity.”</p><p><em>AEH</em> also features two church reviews providing glimpses of Easter services at St. Aidan’s Episcopal Church in Bolinas, part of the Episcopal Diocese of California, and at Rockefeller Memorial Chapel at the University of Chicago.</p><p>The March issue also includes 22 book reviews related to church history and Anglican scholarship. Among them:</p><ul><li><em>Walking Together: Global Anglican Perspectives on Reconciliation</em> edited by Muthuraj Swamy and Stephen Specer | Reviewed by Carla E. Roland Guzmán of General Theological Seminary</li><li><em>Royalist, Religion, and Revolution: Wales 1640-1688</em> by Sarah Ward Clavier | Reviewed by William Gibson of Oxford Brookes University</li><li><em>A Century of Praise: The Monastic Chapel of Saint Augustine</em> edited by Josép Martinez-Cubero et al. | Reviewed by Matthew F. Reese of the Johns Hopkins University</li><li><em>“For the Good of Their Souls”: Performing Christianity in Eighteenth-Century Mohawk Country</em> by William B. Hart | Reviewed by Harvey Hill of St. David’s Episcopal Church in Agawam, Mass.</li><li><em>Christianity in Central Tanzania, A Story of African Encounters and Initiatives in Ugogo and Ukaguru, 1876-1933</em> by Mwita Akiri | Reviewed by John Rawlinson</li></ul></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Matthew P. Payne, Director of Operations, Historical Society of the Episcopal Church (HSEC)<br/>PO Box 1301, Appleton, WI 54912-1301 | ​(920) 383-1910 | Cell (920) 279-6267<br/><a href="http://hsec.us/" rel="nofollow">hsec.us</a> | <a href="https://facebook.com/hsec1910" rel="nofollow">facebook.com/hsec1910</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:administration@hsec.us">administration@hsec.us</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://hsec.us/news/13123185" target="_blank">https://hsec.us/news/13123185</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 01:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1678257429600515</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Anarchists, Communists, and Women: Congregational Missions to Polish Immigrants in 20th Century America</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12518313/anarchists-communists-and-women-congregational-missions-polish</link>
						<dc:creator>Lauren Lemley</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Event</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-31T00:00:00-04:00">March 31, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Massachusetts</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>American History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The history of Congregational Home Missions still awaits its historian. One of their least known fields of work was the outreach to Polish immigrants in US cities. Inspired by both 19th century missionary zeal and social gospel they were surprisingly successful and perhaps because of that quickly forgotten. Join us for lunch at noon on Friday, March 31st to hear Rev. Bem talk about his research into this important topic and his experiences working in the CLA and other libraries.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The event is free to attend, but tickets are limited and registration is required by Tuesday, March 28th via this link: <a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/anarchists-communists-and-women-a-lunch-talk-with-rev-kazimierz-bem-tickets-576348151837" rel="nofollow">https://www.eventbrite.com/e/anarchists-communists-and-women-a-lunch-talk-with-rev-kazimierz-bem-tickets-576348151837</a></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>After registering, you will receive a confirmation email containing information about joining the webinar.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>For more information, please email <a href="mailto:info@14beacon.org?subject=Anarchists%2C%20Communists%2C%20and%20Women">info@14beacon.org</a>.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Lauren Lemley<br/>Congregational Library &amp; Archives</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:info@14beacon.org">info@14beacon.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.congregationallibrary.org/events/bemlunchtalk" target="_blank">https://www.congregationallibrary.org/events/bemlunchtalk</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 01:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1678257429600514</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What Girls Learn in Jewish Families</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12423352/what-girls-learn-jewish-families</link>
						<dc:creator>Elizabeth DiNolfo</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Event</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-15T00:00:00-04:00">March 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Social History / Studies, Teaching and Learning, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><strong>Learning About Learning: A Conversation with Professor Ilana Horwitz | What Girls Learn in Jewish Families</strong><br/>Wednesday, March 15, 2023 1-1:30 ET</span></span></span></span></span><br/>Via Zoom / Free / Register at <a href="https://bit.ly/LAL-IH" rel="nofollow">https://bit.ly/MC-LAL</a><br/><br/><span><span><span><span><span>In the past, Jewish families, like many others, offered girls fewer educational opportunities than boys. But that has not been the case for some time now. In her recent scholarship, Ilana Horwitz has demonstrated the ways that girls raised by Jewish parents complete more years of college and attend more selective schools than girls from comparable socioeconomic backgrounds raised by non-Jewish parents. She argues that this is based on a distinctive “religious subculture” in the home.</span></span></span><br/><br/><a href="https://liberalarts.tulane.edu/departments/jewish-studies/people/ilana-horwitz" rel="nofollow"><span><span><span>Ilana M. Horwitz</span></span></span></a><span><span><span> (PhD, Stanford University) is an assistant professor of Jewish Studies and Sociology and the Fields-Rayant Chair of Contemporary Jewish Life at the </span></span></span><a href="https://liberalarts.tulane.edu/departments/jewish-studies/grant-center" rel="nofollow"><span><span><span>Stuart and Suzanne Grant Center for the American Jewish Experience</span></span></span></a><span><span><span> at Tulane University. She is also the program director for the Mandel Center for Studies in Jewish Education Doctoral Fellows Program. <br/><br/>In her research, Dr. Horwitz takes a sociological approach to examine how people’s religious upbringing, race, ethnicity, social class, and gender shape their life course, especially their educational experiences. Dr. Horwitz’s recent book, <i>God, Grades, and Graduation: Religion’s Surprising Impact on Academic Success</i>, introduces readers to the concept of religious restraint, a new type of childrearing logic that cuts across social class groups and accounts for the role of religion.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><a href="https://www.brandeis.edu/mandel/events/learning-about-learning.html" rel="nofollow"><strong><span><span><span><span><span>Learning About Learning: Conversation with Scholars of Jewish Education</span></span></span></span></span></strong></a></p><p>A series of conversations hosted by Mandel Center Director Jon A. Levisohn (Brandeis University), in which leading scholars of Jewish education discuss what they have learned from their investigations of various aspects of jewish education and why it matters.<br/><br/>Videos and podcast of past events can be found at <a href="https://www.brandeis.edu/mandel/events/videos.html" rel="nofollow">https://www.brandeis.edu/mandel/events/videos.html</a>.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Mandel Center for Studies in Jewish Education | Brandeis University</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:mandelcenter@brandeis.edu">mandelcenter@brandeis.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.brandeis.edu/mandel/index.html" target="_blank">https://www.brandeis.edu/mandel/index.html</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 01:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1678257429600513</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CALL for Papers and Proposals: Religious Communication Association</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12512019/call-papers-and-proposals-religious-communication-association</link>
						<dc:creator>Andre E. Johnson</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Tennessee</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>African American History / Studies, Black History / Studies, Communication, Composition &amp; Rhetoric, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>CALL for Papers and Proposals: Religious Communication Association, an affiliated organization of NCA</span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>2023 NCA Convention, National Harbor, Maryland</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>Deadline for Submissions: Wednesday, March 29, 2023, 11:59 p.m. Pacific</span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>RCA Program Planner: Andre E. Johnson, <a href="mailto:ajohnsn6@memphis.edu">ajohnsn6@memphis.edu</a></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>The Religious Communication Association (RCA) welcomes submissions for the 2023 National Communication Association Convention, November 16-19, 2023, in National Harbor, Maryland. <b>RCA opens its portion of the National Harbor meeting on Wednesday, November 15, 2023, one day before the NCA meeting officially begins on Thursday</b>.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>RCA is an interfaith 501 (c) (3) independent from NCA. As an affiliate organization, RCA proudly showcases religious communication scholarship during the NCA meeting and its separate one-day program before the NCA convention begins. <b>Submissions to Convention Central will be considered simultaneously for NCA panels and inclusion in RCA Conference’s programming on November 15, 2023.</b> <b>Submission to the NCA review process for programming indicates your agreement to attend the preceding RCA Conference should your paper be programmed there.</b></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>The standards for acceptance for NCA and RCA are equally stringent. NCA allots multiple program sessions to RCA. This relationship and arrangement allow RCA to strengthen scholarly inquiry and foster meaningful dialogue among colleagues with increased presentation opportunities.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>The 109th Annual Convention theme of the National Communication Association is “Freedom.” Our NCA First Vice President, Marnel Niles Goins,</span></span><span><span> suggests that as “communication scholars, our voices must continue to address and parse out the nuances of what freedom was, is, and can be. Further, she writes that “engaging with the concept of freedom allows us to challenge assumptions of what freedom means and offer solutions for individuals, groups, organizations, and societies to attain freedom.</span></span><span><span>” Inspired by this call, she encourages us to ask:</span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span>What does it mean to be free? </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Is freedom simply the state of not being imprisoned or enslaved? </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Where do we find freedom, and how do we get there? </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Are we free now? </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Has freedom been reached in the past? </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Is freedom a goal of the future? </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Who is free?</span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>RCA celebrates and embraces the Convention theme. As religious communication scholars, the theme “Freedom” </span></span></span><span><span><span>inspires us to not only wrestle with those questions but also inspires</span></span></span><span><span><span> us to think about and (re) examine ways in which “freedom” exists within religious discourses. For instance, while we are interested in submissions examining the role of religious freedom in the public square, we are also interested in how religion shapes our notions and understanding of freedom. This would also mean examining our concepts of “freedom of religion” and “freedom from religion.” </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Moreover, while we invite submissions on a wide variety of topics related to the convention’s theme, we are especially interested in proposals that challenge us to “free” ourselves by expanding our understanding of religious communication and how religious discourses function in society. We especially welcome submissions incorporating how race/racism functions in our convention theme and our knowledge of religious communication. </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span><span>RCA is also particularly interested in cross-sponsoring with other NCA units and affiliates. In your submission, please indicate if your paper/session/panel proposal involves potential inter-divisional cooperation within RCA or between RCA and other NCA divisions or affiliate groups.</span></span></i></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>The Religious Communication Association accepts submissions in various formats: competitive individual papers, paper sessions, and panel discussions. </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>Individual Papers</span></span></b><span><span>: Individual papers should include an uploaded abstract and are limited to 25 double-spaced pages, excluding notes. <b>Only completed papers will be considered</b>. Individual paper uploads should not contain identifying information (author name, university affiliation, etc.). Note that the same paper may not be submitted to more than one division or planning unit, but there are no limits on the number of unique papers one individual may submit to NCA.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Student Papers should be marked as such to be eligible for the RCA Student Paper of the Year Award and the Donald P. Cushman Award for the top student paper at the NCA convention. For multi-authored works to be eligible for these awards, all authors must be students. INDICATE if the paper is a STUDENT PAPER (undergraduate or graduate) by checking the appropriate box on the NCA Convention Central form.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Review the “Scholar-to-Scholar” description below and indicate your willingness to present your paper as part of this Scholar-to-Scholar exchange if you think this is an appropriate venue for your scholarship. Choosing this option does not exclude your paper from consideration as a competitive paper. <b>This option is an ADDITIONAL consideration and increases your chances for presentation acceptance at NCA</b>.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>Paper Sessions:</span></span></b><span><span> These theme-based submissions should include (1) a session title, (2) a list of presenters with their institutional affiliations (multiple institutions must be represented), (3) titles and full abstracts for each individual presentation, (4) a detailed session description for the online convention program, and (5) a thoroughly developed rationale arguing for the significance and relevance of the session. <b>A session chair is required and should not present a paper during the session</b>. A respondent is optional. <i>In your rationale, please indicate if your paper/session/panel proposal involves potential inter-divisional cooperation within RCA or between RCA and other NCA divisions or affiliate groups.</i></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>Panel Discussions:</span></span></b><span><span> Panel discussions should include (1) a panel title, (2) a list of presenters and their institutional affiliations (multiple institutions must be represented), (3) a detailed session description for the online convention program, and (4) a thoroughly developed rationale describing the format of the discussion and arguing for the significance and relevance of the panel. Proposals for panel discussions are encouraged to demonstrate creative adaptation of the discussion format. <b>A session chair is required</b>. <i>In your rationale, please indicate if your paper/session/panel proposal involves potential inter-divisional cooperation within RCA or between RCA and other NCA divisions or affiliate groups</i>.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>Scholar-to-Scholar Sessions: </span></span></b><span><span>A one-on-one interactive format for communication and discussion will be employed. Individual papers are submitted for public display in dedicated sessions with engagement by selected “wandering scholars” (experts in the field). This format is appropriate for presentations such as videos, interactive media, slide shows, experiential activities, and posters. Please check the appropriate approval box on the electronic submission form to be considered for Scholar-to-Scholar. <b>Choosing this option does not exclude your paper from consideration as a competitive paper. Selecting this option is an ADDITIONAL consideration and increases your chances for presentation acceptance at NCA.</b></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Submit ALL papers/sessions/panels to RCA online via <a href="https://www.natcom.org/nca-109th-annual-convention-freedom" rel="nofollow">NCA’s Convention Central</a> site. Audio-visual requests must be made at the time of submission. Due to the excessive number of requests, late requests WILL NOT be accommodated. All participants should review the “Professional Standards for Convention Participants,” which will further clarify expectations. The “Professional Standards for Convention Participants” site includes live and recorded step-by-step instructions on submitting and is available in the NCA Convention Library (<u><a href="http://www.natcom.org/conventionresources" rel="nofollow">www.natcom.org/conventionresources</a> )</u>.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>If you have any questions, please contact the RCA program planner, Andre E. Johnson, at </span></span><a href="mailto:ajohnsn6@memphis.edu"><span><span>ajohnsn6@memphis.edu</span></span></a><span><span>. </span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Andre E. Johnson</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ajohnsn6@memphis.edu">ajohnsn6@memphis.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 00:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1678257429600512</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
