<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 12:18:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 12:18:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ May 4, 2023 -  August 24, 2023] Conference or similar: Realismus und Idealismus heute III</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/110849</link>
						<description>Venue: Poppelsdorfer Allee 28<br/><br/><p>Das "Realismus und Idealismus heute" Kolloquium ist eine Reihe von Vorlesungen und Workshops im Themenbereich des Realismus und Idealismus, in welchen sowohl historische als auch systematische Forschung aus diesem Themenbereich vorgestellt wird. Das Kolloquium ist öffentlich und alle Interessierten sind, unabhangig von ihrem akademischen Hintergrund, dazu eingeladen am Kolloquium teilzunehmen.</p>
<p>The "Realismus und Idealismus heute" colloquium is a series of lectures and workshops in the field of realism and idealism, in which both historical and systematic research in this field is presented. The colloquium is open to the public and all interested parties are invited to participate in the colloquium, regardless of their academic background.</p>
<p>04.05.23 | Zachary Hall (Stanford)<br/>Transzendentale Metaphysik des Denkens bei Kant und Wittgenstein</p>
<p>11.05.23 | Alexandros Duskos (Berlin)<br/>»Seele ist dort, wo Leiblichkeit ist.« Zur Aufhebung des Leib-Seele-Dualismus in Hegels Anthropologie.</p>
<p>01.06.23 | Alexander Schubert (Bonn)<br/>Emergenz und Schellings spekulative Physik.</p>
<p>15.06.23 | Merlin Krzemien (Bonn)<br/>Die Welt sehen, wie sie ist. Erscheinungen und Naiver Realismus</p>
<p>29.06.23 | Ana Guzmán (Aachen/Bonn)<br/>Objektive Subjekte. Objektivität in Hegels Logik und die Möglichkeit einer Naturphilosophie.</p>
<p>13.07.23 |  Dacian Bugnar (Köln)<br/>Die Intelligibilität alles Seienden. Spinozas explanatorischer Realismus.</p>
<p>20.07.23 | Giuliano Infantino (Stuttgart)  <br/>Notwendigkeit und Zufall in Hegels Naturphilosophie</p>
<p>17.08.23 (14 – 18 Uhr c.t.) | Gregory Moss (Hongkong). <br/>Workshop: Mythologizing the World: Idealism and Realism in the Philosophy of Religion     </p>
<p>24.08.23 (14 – 18 Uhr c.t.) | Sebastian Stein (Stuttgart)<br/>Workshop: Absolute Freiheit: Die Einheit von Idealismus und Substanzrealismus                            </p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 05:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1682660234261296</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Jessica Zu, “Karma and Structural (In)justice: Buddhist Social Philosophy in Modern Asia,” May 9/10, online</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12773779/jessica-zu-%E2%80%9Ckarma-and-structural-injustice-buddhist-social</link>
						<dc:creator>Jessica (Xiaomin) Zu</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>California</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Asian History / Studies, Chinese History / Studies, Philosophy, Religious Studies and Theology, Social Sciences</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Friends and colleagues, please join me for my online lecture, “Karma and Structural (In)Justice: Buddhist Social Philosophy in Modern Asia” at <a href="https://www.facebook.com/mahidol/" rel="nofollow">Mahidol University</a>, May 10.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Join here: </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Webex Meeting ID: <b>585 424 904</b> or here <a href="https://mahidol.webex.com/meet/sermwit.mee" rel="nofollow">https://mahidol.webex.com/meet/sermwit.mee</a></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>May 9 (Tue), 6:00 pm Hawaii Time</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>May 9 (Tue), 9:00 pm Pacific Time</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>May 9 (Tue), 10:00 pm Mountain Time</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>May 9 (Tue), 12midnight East Coast</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>May 10 (Wed), 6:00 am EU Time </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>May 10 (Wed), 11:00 am Thai Time</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>May 10 (Wed), 9:30 am Indian Standard Time</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>May 10 (Wed), 12noon Beijing Time </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Jessica Zu</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>University of Southern California </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Jessica Zu</p><p>University of Southern California</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:xzu@usc.edu">xzu@usc.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://mahidol.webex.com/meet/sermwit.mee" target="_blank">https://mahidol.webex.com/meet/sermwit.mee</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1682660234261295</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>After Disaster: Southeast Regional Conference on Christianity and Literature</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/04/25/after-disaster-southeast-regional-conference-on-christianity-and-literature</link>
						<dc:creator>csmith@csuniv.edu</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, April 27, 2023 - 4:53am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Southeast Conference on Christianity and Literature</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:csmith@csuniv.edu">csmith@csuniv.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/general-announcements">general announcements</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>August 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>Southeast Regional Conference on Christianity and Literature</strong></p>
<p>Theme: After Disaster</p>
<p>Charleston Southern University Charleston, SC</p>
<p>October 26-28, 2023</p>
<p>Keynote Speaker: Dr. Susan Felch, Professor Emerita, Calvin University</p>
<p>My [kitchen, syllabus] is a disaster. [Higher ed, the planet] faces impending disaster. [The responsible party of your choice] bungled the disaster response. We frequently invoke the word “disaster” to convey a sense of magnitude but also to imply events beyond our control. Questions of agency lie embedded in the word’s etymology—maybe it’s the stars’ fault—and yet we seem to believe that human response is possible and perhaps even imperative. Among the many possible responses to various disasters over the millennia, the literary offers the opportunity to slow down, to examine what has happened and what may be salvaged—and to develop and practice Christian virtues.</p>
<p>Conference participants will ponder these themes with keynote speaker Dr. Susan Felch (Renaissance and Reformation scholar and co-author of Teaching and the Christian Imagination). We invite papers that consider literary responses to disasters past, present, and future (the “after” in the conference title is mostly there for assonance). Possible topics include but are not limited to:</p>
<p>•            Lament and other biblical genres depicting and responding to disaster</p>
<p>•            Plague, famine, and fire in literature</p>
<p>•            Cli-fi (climate fiction)</p>
<p>•            Ethical and aesthetic limitations of depicting disaster, whether personal or public</p>
<p>•            Interpreting and/or memorializing disaster in its aftermath</p>
<p>•            Theodicy and other theological responses to disaster</p>
<p>•            Agency in disaster prevention, experience, or response</p>
<p>Other proposals concerning the relationship of Christianity and literature, including panel proposals and creative works, are welcome. Presenters should be members of the Conference on Christianity and Literature by the time of the conference.</p>
<p>Submit abstracts of 250-300 words by August 1, 2023, to Dr. Carissa Turner Smith, <a href="mailto:csmith@csuniv.edu" target="_blank">csmith@csuniv.edu</a>. Undergraduate students must submit their entire paper for consideration; eligible undergraduate papers will be entered into the national CCL Undergraduate Writing Contest for a cash prize. Graduate students accepted to the conference are encouraged to apply for the CCL Conference Travel Grant.</p>
<p>Schedule information: Participants who arrive early on October 26 are welcome to attend an afternoon pedagogy workshop led by Dr. Felch and to explore Charleston sites in the evening. Conference panels will run in the morning and afternoon on October 27 and 28. Dr. Felch’s keynote address will be in the late afternoon on October 27, followed by a dinner at which the Conference on Christianity and Literature’s 2022 <a href="https://www.christianityandliterature.com/" target="_blank">Lifetime Achievement Award</a> will be presented to Dr. Jewel Spears Brooker, T. S. Eliot scholar and Professor Emerita of Literature at Eckerd College.</p>
<p> </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 16:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1682660234261294</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Southeastern Medieval Association 2023</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/04/20/southeastern-medieval-association-2023</link>
						<dc:creator>Jo Koster</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, April 27, 2023 - 4:48am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Southeastern Medieval Association</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:sema2023@winthrop.edu">sema2023@winthrop.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/general-announcements">general announcements</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/medieval">medieval</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>June 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p align="center">SEMA 2023: <br/> Construction and (Re)Construction<br/> Winthrop University, October 12-14, 2023</p>
<p align="center"><strong>CALL FOR PAPERS: ABSTRACTS DUE JUNE 15, 2023</strong></p>
<p>As we watch the new silhouette of Notre Dame rising from the burned ruins of its past, participate in vigorous debates about how the study of the Middle Ages will be pursued now and in the future, and plan to meet on a campus where medieval buildings have literally been rebuilt, we invite proposals for individual papers, whole sessions, or round tables on the conference theme of “construction and (re)construction.” Papers might consider the notions of</p>
<ul>
<li>How identities and places have been constructed in various periods of medieval history, literature, politics, art, and culture;</li>
<li>The ways in which medieval systems of belief, value, and thought have been constructed, deconstructed, appropriated, and/or reconstructed;</li>
<li>The relationships between form and construction (whether they be verse, literary, political, musical, architectural, artistic, ideologic, etc.);</li>
<li>Ways in which modern society, countries, organizations, and/or individuals have re-made the medieval in their modern images;</li>
<li>The ongoing debates about how we conceptualize, pursue, and further the study of the Middle Ages in the 21st century.</li>
</ul>
<p>Abstracts on any aspect of medieval studies are welcome, but we will give preference to submissions related to the conference theme.</p>
<p>The organizers are extremely proud that Rock Hill was home to one of the earliest of the “sit-in” lunch counter protests that sparked the Civil Rights movement in the 1960s. The conference will be held only a few blocks where the Friendship Nine were arrested for their lunch counter sit-in in February 1960, and a short drive from the tribal lands of the Catawba Indian Nation. In respect of these important historical and cultural contexts, we particularly invite papers and panels that focus on the ways in which diverse and/or indigenous religious, social, physical, political, legal, and/or economic identities have been constructed and reconstructed in the Middle Ages and beyond.</p>
<ul>
<li>Proposals for individual papers should be limited to 300 words.</li>
<li>Session proposals or roundtables should include an overview and abstracts for the three papers for a session, or 5-6 abstracts for a roundtable, as well as the contact information for all presenters.</li>
<li>When considering sending an abstract, applicants should be aware that SEMA 2023 will be a fully in-person conference with no options for remote presentation and attendance.</li>
<li><strong>On your submission, please indicate any Audio/Visual needs!!!</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Please submit proposals using the forms at <a href="https://semarockhill2023.com/">https://semarockhill2023.com/</a> no later than <strong>June 15, 2023</strong>. If you have questions, please reach out to us at <a href="mailto:sema2023@winthrop.edu">sema2023@winthrop.edu</a>. </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 12:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1682660234261293</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Shifting Perspectives on Muslimness and Islam in Contemporary Fiction</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/04/20/shifting-perspectives-on-muslimness-and-islam-in-contemporary-fiction</link>
						<dc:creator>mmothes@uni-koblenz.de</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, April 27, 2023 - 4:48am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Maria Mothes/Pacific Ancient and Modern Language Association (PAMLA)</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:mmothes@uni-koblenz.de">mmothes@uni-koblenz.de</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/postcolonial">postcolonial</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/world-literatures-and-indigenous-studies">world literatures and indigenous studies</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>May 31, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Special Session</p>
<p>Presiding Officer/Panel Chair: Maria Mothes (University of Koblenz, Germany)</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Abstract:</p>
<p>The panel invites papers discussing texts that shape the perception and representation of Muslimness and/or Islam in contemporary literature. Global, transnational, and comparative perspectives are welcome.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Description:</p>
<p>This panel seeks to contextualize the current position of Muslims in Western societies as either marginalized or made hypervisible. More often than not, portrayals of Muslims in the media or popular culture focus on the adherents of the imagined category of ‘Islam,’ rendering the people behind this category invisible. In light of the all-to-common binary distinctions (secular/religious, moderns/traditional, etc.), this panel seeks to contemplate ways toward “a religious literacy that does not overdetermine the role of religion” (Rashid 61). Instead of the either/or trap, an epistemological approach allowing us to trace ‘both/and’ is sought out “since the most common Muslim life is lived amidst a congeries of various laws and norms” (Reinhart 8). The panel seeks to create a space for dialogue about how contemporary literature negotiates holistic but also nuanced identities and how Muslimness is depicted as part of the spectrum of the human experience. Moreover, the panel invites papers investigating the role of literature in shaping the perception and representation of religion and how literature thus contributes to shifting perspectives on Islam and Muslimness.</p>
<p>Please submit abstract proposals using the PAMLA online submission form (you will have to go to <a href="https://pamla.ballastacademic.com/">https://pamla.ballastacademic.com</a> to login or create an account first). Please note: PAMLA is an entirely in-person conference.</p>
<p>If you have questions or encounter problems submitting your abstract, please contact: Maria Mothes (University of Koblenz, Germany) at: <a href="mailto:mmothes@uni-koblenz.de">mmothes@uni-koblenz.de</a>.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 11:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1682660234261292</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Papers for the Midwest Jewish Studies Association Annual Conference</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12769491/call-papers-midwest-jewish-studies-association-annual</link>
						<dc:creator>Mara Cohen Ioannides</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-15T00:00:00-04:00">June 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Holocaust, Genocide, and Memory Studies, Jewish History / Studies, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies, World History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><b><span>THE 35<sup>rd</sup> ANNUAL CONFERENCE</span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span>Hosted by</span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The Israel and Golda Koschitzky Centre for Jewish Studies</span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>, York University, Toronto</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Call for Papers</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span>The thirty-fifth annual conference of the Midwest Jewish Studies Association (MJSA) will be held October 29-30, 2023 in-person only and in English. </span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span>The conference welcomes proposals in all areas of Jewish Studies: from any discipline (history, philosophy, literature, religion, sociology, music, etc.) and from any time period (ancient to contemporary) from scholars and advanced graduate students anywhere in the world.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>All interested scholars and professionals of Jewish Studies, including advanced graduate students, are cordially invited to submit proposals for papers, presentations, and workshops. Proposals may be for complete panels or for individual papers. Proposals must include a 200-word abstract defining the primary themes, conclusions, and sources utilized in the research, as well as a one-page CV. Panel proposals must include abstracts for 3 to 4 papers, CVs for all participants, a general explanation of how the papers are related and what the general significance of the panel is, as well as the name of the chair of the proposed session. Roundtables are also welcome with an abstract and CV of all participants. Only one submission per participant, please. </span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>All graduate students (full or part-time) are eligible to compete for the Graduate Student Paper Award. Only publishable papers, some portion of which will be presented at the conference, are welcome. The winning paper will be recognized on our website and the winner awarded a check. Once the paper has been accepted to the conference, it needs to be submitted by September 1<sup>st</sup>, 2023 to Professor Laura Wiseman (<a href="mailto:lwiseman@edu.yorku.ca">lwiseman@edu.yorku.ca</a>) for judging by the committee.</span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><b><span>The deadline for the submission of proposals for individual papers or complete panels is June 15<sup>th</sup>, 2023. Please direct all inquiries and submissions to: Dr. Mara W. Cohen Ioannides (</span></b><a href="mailto:maraioannides@missouristate.edu"><span>maraioannides@missouristate.edu</span></a><b><span>).</span></b></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:maraioannides@missouristate.edu">maraioannides@missouristate.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 20:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1682573829165193</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The British &amp; Irish Association for Practical Theology Annual Conference 2023 (Registration Open)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12769143/british-irish-association-practical-theology-annual-conference</link>
						<dc:creator>James Morris</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-07-11T00:00:00-04:00">July 11, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-07-13T00:00:00-04:00">July 13, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Humanities, Philosophy, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Our conference title, <em>Take Off Your Shoes – Hospitality and Practical Theology</em>, allows us to explore a theme that has come under increasing theological scrutiny in recent years. Hospitality is a universal virtue, one that is claimed by every culture, but what does it mean to welcome another into our country, home, space or personal narrative?</p><p>“Take off your shoes” was chosen as the title for this conference because it communicates very well the ambiguities, complexities and contradictions of the act of hospitality. On the one hand, it does not hide the power imbalance of the relationship between host and guest that will surely be explored during the conference<span> </span>but, on the other, it is an instruction that is redolent of sacred spaces in the Abrahamic religions. Receiving hospitality as well as the giving of hospitality becomes a sacred act. On the one hand it is an invitation for the guest to leave the cares of the outside world at the door and on the other it is an instruction not to bring the dirt – physical and spiritual – of the outside into the house.</p><p>During our conference this theme will be explored from numerous perspectives. Our keynote sessions will examine the hospitality offered or withheld to immigrants and refugees, the welcoming that exists within the interfaith dialogue and reflect theologically upon the theme in relation to disability. The inaugural Practical Theology Hub Event will be an interfaith conversation about hospitality. In addition to all of this there will be many short papers, workshops and informal gatherings throughout the three days. We will have stories of hospitality before each keynote that will encourage reflection in the theme and, through our very own art gallery, there will be an opportunity for delegates to tell their own hospitality story and to illustrate it through an image of a pair of shoes.</p><p>Our conference is once again online. There will, however, be opportunities for delegates to meet at various locations around the country and share hospitality and the conference experience for the duration of the three days.</p><p>Using the Whova platform, our conference is <em><strong>an online experience which will be flexible across different time-zones and as varied and creative as possible</strong></em>. Building on our successful online conferences in 2021 &amp; 2022, this platform enables <em><strong>many different kinds of engagement</strong></em> over the course of our conference, from informal chats between colleagues and friends, keynote sessions, workshops, papers and online gallery space, plus the opportunity to access conference content in the forms of recorded sessions and shared resources for six months after the event.</p><p>Whether online or in person, we look forward to giving you a very warm welcome!</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Contact our team at either: <a href="mailto:admin@biapt.org">admin@biapt.org</a> or <a href="mailto:conference@biapt.org">conference@biapt.org</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:conference@biapt.org">conference@biapt.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.biapt.org/event/2023-annual-conference-take-off-your-shoes-hospitality-practical-theology/" target="_blank">https://www.biapt.org/event/2023-annual-conference-take-off-your-shoes-hospitality-practical-theology/?doing_wp_cron=168…</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 20:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1682573829165192</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest-April 26, 2023</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-april-26-2023/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find 3 new job opportunities, 2 Fellowships, 1 Call for Papers, and 2 upcoming conferences/speakers.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 33!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Senior Lecture/Associate Professor of History (Full-time)</h4>



<p>Australian National University, Australia</p>



<p>Deadline: May 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=9eb7aa4ea6&amp;e=ea2dc4a949">https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=9eb7aa4ea6&amp;e=ea2dc4a949</a></p>



<h4>Director Indo-Pacific Research Center (Full-time, 5 years)</h4>



<p>Murdoch University, Australia</p>



<p>Deadline: May 5, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=a73ee870ae&amp;e=ea2dc4a949">https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=a73ee870ae&amp;e=ea2dc4a949</a></p>



<h4>Lecturer in Social Work (Full-time, fixed term)</h4>



<p>University of Tasmania, Australia</p>



<p>Deadline: May 13, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=968aa09c64&amp;e=ea2dc4a949">https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=968aa09c64&amp;e=ea2dc4a949</a></p>



<h4>Minerva Recruitment Job Listings Cite (with areas specifically tailored for Ph.D.)</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://minerva-recruitment.com/">Minerva Recruitment – Higher Education Graduate Jobs, UK &amp; Worldwide (minerva-recruitment.com)</a></p>



<h4>AAR/SBL Job Forum</h4>



<p><a href="https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search">https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search</a></p>



<h2>Fellowships:</h2>



<h4>Marie-Curie Fellowship</h4>



<p>Deadline: September 13, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=cf02b505ca&amp;e=ea2dc4a949">https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=cf02b505ca&amp;e=ea2dc4a949</a></p>



<h4>Indigenous and Contemplative Practices</h4>



<p>University of Melbourne, Australia</p>



<p>Deadline: May 12, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=180b440a27&amp;e=ea2dc4a949">https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=180b440a27&amp;e=ea2dc4a949</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>Pathways and Passages: Faith and Migration in the Indian Ocean Region</h4>



<p>Deadline: August 20<sup>th</sup>, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=23e435fe86&amp;e=ea2dc4a949">https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=23e435fe86&amp;e=ea2dc4a949</a></p>



<h2>Conferences:</h2>



<h4>Religion, Culture, and Society Annual Lecture</h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>Date: June 16<sup>th</sup>, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.notredame.edu.au/research/institute-for-ethics-and-society/events">https://www.notredame.edu.au/research/institute-for-ethics-and-society/events</a></p>



<h4>Research on Religious and Spiritual Communities: Insiders, Outsiders, and Other Useful Fictions</h4>



<p>University of Notre Dame, Australia</p>



<p>Date: June 16<sup>th</sup>, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=7ec0300047&amp;e=ea2dc4a949">https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=7ec0300047&amp;e=ea2dc4a949</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1682573829165191</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ June 12, 2023] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/110765</link>
						<description>Publication Name: Deleuze and the Schizoanalysis of Performance<br/><br/><p><strong>Call for submissions:</strong></p>

<p><strong><em>Deleuze and the Schizoanalysis of Performance</em></strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Schizoanalytic Applications Series, Bloomsbury Press.</p>

<p>Since the publication of <em>Deleuze and Performance </em>(2009), Deleuze’s philosophy has inspired a number of vital interventions in the fields of performance and theatre studies. Deleuze’s thought has also played an important role in the emergence of Performance Philosophy and continues to energise theory and practice across a range of disciplinary and vocational boundaries. </p>

<p>However, relatively little research has taken an explicitly schizoanalytic approach to performance. While many of the key conceptual tools of schizoanalysis recur across the literature (the assemblage; the BwO; the abstract machine etc.), the question of whether schizoanalysis might provide a framework for analysing and creating performance has only been infrequently asked. Given the difficulty of trying to extract a schizoanalytic method from Deleuze and Guattari’s writing – and the continuing need for schizoanalysis to be more carefully addressed in the field of Deleuze studies – this is not surprising. But it does point towards two possibilities: that schizoanalysis might provide resources for creating new ways of thinking, feeling, and doing performance; and that performance might contribute to the development of new schizoanalytic methods and practices.  </p>

<p>This volume aims to pursue these possibilities. Bringing together research in Deleuze and Guattari studies, performance and theatre studies, Performance Philosophy and beyond, scholars are invited to explore a range of questions. What does a schizoanalytic theatre or performance criticism look like? Could the materialist psychiatry of <em>Anti-Oedipus</em> – and particularly an understanding of desiring-production as a ‘universal primary process’ – reshape our understanding of performance as a social and historical practice? And how do problems that are central to performance – such as ‘liveness’, participation, presence, the performing body etc. – test the schizoanalytic categories that Deleuze and Guattari most frequently deploy with reference to literary examples? How might a schizoanalytic framework operate in an applied theatre setting and what can applied theatre practices contribute to our understanding of schizoanalysis, particularly given its involvement in questions of mental health and wellbeing? In what ways can performance make legible and resist the fascism of the present? How can contemporary work in new materialism, affect theory, theatre ecologies and Performance Philosophy contribute to the emergence of a performance schizoanalysis? And what concepts will invent themselves once schizoanalysis and performance are brought together? </p>

<p><strong>Submissions:</strong></p>

<p>Scholars and practitioners are invited to propose chapters that respond to these questions (but should not feel limited by them). Abstracts should be between 400-700 words, accompanied by a short bio and affiliation, and sent to <a href="mailto:daniel.koczy@newcastle.ac.uk">daniel.koczy@newcastle.ac.uk</a> before 12/6/23. Final articles will be between 7000-10000 words, including footnotes and citations. </p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 05:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1682401025830846</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>ICSP 2024 : 9th International Conference on Spirituality and Psychology</title>
			<link>http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=173351&amp;copyownerid=31491</link>
						<description>9th International Conference on Spirituality and Psychology [Bangkok, Thailand] [Mar 13, 2024 - Mar 15, 2024]</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 05:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1682401025830845</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Living Islam in Nigeria: Muslim Experiences in a Postcolonial State. Essays in Memory of Prof. Ismail Ayinla Babatunde Balogun</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12760612/living-islam-nigeria-muslim-experiences-postcolonial-state</link>
						<dc:creator>'Yemi Balogun</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-04-25T00:00:00-04:00">April 25, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-09-30T00:00:00-04:00">September 30, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Nigeria</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>African History / Studies, Cultural History / Studies, Islamic History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Social History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span>During the colonial era in Nigeria, colonial administrators built socio-economic and political structures that affected every facet of the life of Muslims. Muslims, however, were not passive to the structural changes, but actively engaged with the colonial system as a whole. At times, colonial administrators bent to Muslims' concerns, but at other times, they failed to yield to their demands. Apart from such engagement, Muslims actively participated, incorporated, and adopted many aspects of colonial life. In addition, they borrowed from Christians and European practices. In the post-colonial period, Muslims lived under different political conditions. However, because Nigeria's self-government did not break the colonial system, Muslim experiences showed continuity and change from colonial to post-colonial times.</span></span></p><p><span><span>By lived religious experiences, we take a cue from the framework of lived religion. This is a framework in which religious experiences are not only understood through the text but also in the context of everyday life. This requires that we focus on how Islam is practiced by ordinary Muslims in settings like the home, community, place of work, and organizations. For this volume, we assume that the postcolonial context has impacted the religious practices and social encounters of the Muslims in Nigeria. The change in the postcolonial period has been stimulated by Muslims' resistance to colonial legacies, Islamic reform, and globalization. Evidence of this change varies but is visible in all aspects of Muslims' lived experiences. Thus, we are interested in studies examining the Muslim lived experiences in Nigeria's postcolonial context. Specifically, we welcome studies that discuss Muslims' experiences in relation to areas such as their religious practices, education, associational life, civic society, gender interreligious encounters, Muslim faith-based organizations (FBOs), clerical life, Muslim-state relations, social media, and popular culture. We seek empirical and theoretical contributions from various disciplines in the humanities and social sciences.</span></span></p><p><span><span>The volume is in memory of Ismail Ayinla Babatunde Balogun, a professor of Islamic Studies whose works focused on Muslims' social life in postcolonial Nigeria and religion in general. We encourage contributors to this volume to also investigate some of his works on Muslim experiences in Nigeria.</span></span></p><p><span><span>Editors of the volume are Prof. Ishaq Olanrewaju Oloyede (<a href="mailto:ioloyede@yahoo.co.uk">ioloyede@yahoo.co.uk</a>); Prof. Siyan Oyeweso (<a href="mailto:gafoye@gmail.com">gafoye@gmail.com</a>); Dr. Gbemisola Abdul-Jelili Animasawun (<a href="mailto:aganimasawun@gmail.com">aganimasawun@gmail.com</a>); Dr. Adeyemi Balogun. The volume will be published by a university press, to be announced later.</span></span></p><p><span><span>The word count for each article should be about 5000-7000 including references. Each article should include the following: Title of the paper and an abstract of up to 250 words, the name of the author(s), institutional affiliation, Email address, and Five keywords.</span></span></p><p><span><span>The deadline for abstract submission is May 30, 2023. Authors whose abstracts are accepted will be notified by June 12, 2023. The deadline for full papers is October 31, 2023. Abstracts and full papers should be sent to <u><a href="mailto:balogunbookproject@gmail.com">balogunbookproject@gmail.com</a></u>. All submissions should follow the Chicago Citation Style (17th Edition<u>)</u> in the endnotes.</span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Prof. Ishaq Olanrewaju Oloyede (<a href="mailto:ioloyede@yahoo.co.uk">ioloyede@yahoo.co.uk</a>);</p><p>Prof. Siyan Oyeweso (<a href="mailto:gafoye@gmail.com">gafoye@gmail.com</a>), Osun State University;</p><p>Dr. Gbemisola Abdul-Jelili Animasawun (<a href="mailto:aganimasawun@gmail.com">aganimasawun@gmail.com</a>), University of Ilorin;</p><p>Dr. Adeyemi Balogun, (<a href="mailto:yemi2ulama@gmail.com">yemi2ulama@gmail.com</a>) Osun State University.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:yemi2ulama@gmail.com">yemi2ulama@gmail.com</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1682401025830844</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Women in Judaism: Call for Book Reviewers</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12754504/women-judaism-call-book-reviewers</link>
						<dc:creator>Dina Ripsman Eylon</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Jewish History / Studies, Literature, Religious Studies and Theology, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><b>Call for Book Reviewers</b></span></span></p><p><span><span><i>Women in Judaism: A Multidisciplinary Journal</i> is seeking book reviewers for its forthcoming issues. </span></span></p><p><span><span>The Journal is published exclusively on the Internet as a forum for scholarly debate on gender-related issues in Judaism. It is particularly intended to promote critical analysis of gender inequalities within Jewish religion, culture, and society, both ancient and modern. The journal does not promote a fixed ideology, and welcomes a variety of approaches. </span></span></p><p><span><span>To access the list of the new review copies [PDFs], click on the Books Received button on the journal's homepage, or visit <a href="https://wjudaism.library.utoronto.ca/index.php/wjudaism/about/#reviewbooks" rel="nofollow">https://wjudaism.library.utoronto.ca/index.php/wjudaism/about/#reviewbooks</a></span></span></p><p><span><span>The list can also be obtained by emailing the editor-in-chief.</span></span></p><p><span><span>All reviews are min. 750 words and due 30 days from receipt of the book [PDF]. They may be formal or informal, as long as they are fair and engaging. </span></span></p><p><span><span>Queries, along with a short bio and a writing sample, should be made by e-mail to: <a href="mailto:dina.eylon@alum.utoronto.ca">dina.eylon@alum.utoronto.ca</a></span></span></p><p><span><span>Dr. Dina Ripsman Eylon, Editor-in-Chief<br/>Email: <a href="mailto:dina.eylon@alum.utoronto.ca">dina.eylon@alum.utoronto.ca</a><br/>Women in Judaism: A Multidisciplinary Journal<br/><a href="http://www.womeninjudaism.org/" rel="nofollow">www.womeninjudaism.org</a></span></span></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><span><span>Dr. Dina Ripsman Eylon, Editor-in-Chief<br/>Email: <a href="mailto:dina.eylon@alum.utoronto.ca">dina.eylon@alum.utoronto.ca</a><br/>Women in Judaism: A Multidisciplinary Journal<br/><a href="http://www.womeninjudaism.org/" rel="nofollow">www.womeninjudaism.org</a></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:dina.eylon@alum.utoronto.ca">dina.eylon@alum.utoronto.ca</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="http://www.womeninjudaism.org/" target="_blank">http://www.womeninjudaism.org</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 17:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1682401025830843</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ May 15, 2023 -  May 16, 2023] Conference or similar: Politiques de la traduction - Politiken der Übersetzung</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/110729</link>
						<description>Venue: Friedrichstraße 191<br/><br/><p>We are pleased to share with you the program of the Franco-German conference "Politiques de la traduction: appropriation, critique, hospitalité -  Politiken der Übersetzung: Aneignung, Kritik, Gastfreundschaft" (link: https://cmb.hu-berlin.de/fileadmin/user_upload/Politiken_der_Uebersetzung_Programm_def.pdf). The event will begin on Monday, May 15 at 9:30 am at the Centre Marc Bloch (Berlin) and end on Tuesday, May 16 at 1:00 pm. Admission to the entire colloquium is free.<br/>There will also be the opportunity to take part to the conference online. Please contact us at uebersetzungsseminar@gmail.com if you would like to receive the link to log in.  <br/><br/>Best regards,<br/><br/>The organizers,<br/>Alessandro Colleoni<br/>Elise Huchet<br/>Silvia Pieroni<br/>Lilja Walliser</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 05:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1682228225468455</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ May 1, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: 2023 Annual Meeting Canadian Society of Christian Philosophers</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/110689</link>
						<description><p>The Canadian Society of Christian Philosophers will hold its annual meeting the morning of <strong>June 1, 2023</strong> as part of the Annual Congress of the Canadian Philosophical Association. This year’s conference is in-person and will be held at York University. We invite submissions in any field of philosophy, that, by virtue of its topic, may be of particular interest to Christian philosophers. <strong>Please submit an abstract (prepared for blind review) of no more than 500 words.</strong> Please use a Word, pdf, or rtf document and send abstracts to Paul Franks (pfranks@tyndale.ca). </p>
<p><strong>Deadline: May 1st, 2023.   </strong></p>
<p>Our main event will be a keynote lecture by Professor Klaas Kraay from Toronto Metropolitan University. For updates and for information on the society, visit our website: www.cscp-scpc.ca.   Please note that current membership in the CSCP is required to present. Details regarding membership can be found here: https://cscp-scpc.ca/?page_id=13. </p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 05:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1682141829031981</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>4th  Graduate Colloquium in Middle Eastern and Ottoman Studies</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12747560/4th-graduate-colloquium-middle-eastern-and-ottoman-studies</link>
						<dc:creator>Didar Ayşe Akbulut</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-08-11T00:00:00-04:00">August 11, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-08-12T00:00:00-04:00">August 12, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Turkey</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Arabic History / Studies, Immigration &amp; Migration History / Studies, Islamic History / Studies, Middle East History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><hr/><hr/><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><b><span><span>4<sup>th</sup>  Graduate Colloquium in Middle Eastern and Ottoman Studies</span></span></b></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The Institute of Middle East and Islamic Countries Studies at Marmara University, in collaboration with the AbuSulayman Center for Global Islamic Studies at George Mason University, invites proposals for the third meeting of the Annual Graduate Colloquium in Middle Eastern and Ottoman Studies to be held on August 11-12, 2023 in Istanbul. The Colloquium welcomes papers related to the Middle East Islamic Studies in historical and contemporary contexts, including Ottoman Studies. The Colloquium is open to all disciplines as well as multidisciplinary and cross-disciplinary fields, including, but not limited to history, history of arts and architecture, <span><span>literature</span></span>, <span><span>religious studies</span></span>, cultural studies, political science, sociology, and anthropology. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Middle Eastern, Islamic, and Ottoman studies have been rapidly expanding in recent decades, in theme, scope, specialty, and researcher demographics. Expansion and specialization at once make it increasingly more difficult to have broad-based conversations on common themes. The Colloquium will bring together advanced Ph.D. students </span></span><span><span><span>who have already passed their doctoral examinations at the time of application and scholars whose expertise closely aligns with topics of accepted papers. </span></span></span><span><span>The Colloquium will host graduate students to present their ongoing research to a peer audience with diverse specialties and disciplinary expertise, exchange views and perspectives, and engage in constructive discussion in a multidisciplinary intellectual setting. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Please submit proposals that include approx. 250-word abstract with a tentative title, short CV, and the name of the proposed discussant. Proposals may be submitted for individual papers or pre-organized panels. All submissions will be evaluated by a blind peer review process. The organizing committee will make an effort to match presenters of accepted papers with the most suitable discussants. It is advised, therefore, that presenters contact their preferred discussants in advance. Papers on ongoing research are welcome. Papers in the form of thesis proposals alone will not be considered. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p>For further information please visit<u> istanbulcolloquium.com</u></p><p> </p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><b><span><span>Timeline</span></span></b></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Application Deadline: May 20, 2023</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Notification of acceptance: June 3, 2023</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Full Paper Submission: August 3, 2023</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Colloquium date: August 11-12, 2023</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:istanbulcolloquium@gmail.com">istanbulcolloquium@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://istanbulcolloquium.com/" target="_blank">https://istanbulcolloquium.com</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 17:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1682141829031980</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
