<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 12:18:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 12:18:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ January 12, 2024 -  January 14, 2024] Conference or similar: West-Coast Heidegger Workshop</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/113842</link>
						<description>Venue: 1 University Circle<br/><br/><p>See Flyer for information and CFP</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 05:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1692423429878682</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ September 30, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: West-Coast Heidegger Workshop</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/113846</link>
						<description><p>See flyer for info.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 05:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1692423429878681</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Gender, Sexuality and Islam in Muslim Women’s English Literature</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/08/16/gender-sexuality-and-islam-in-muslim-women%E2%80%99s-english-literature</link>
						<dc:creator>msnbajwa@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Friday, August 18, 2023 - 7:16am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Intersections (Australia)</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:msnbajwa@gmail.com">msnbajwa@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/gender-studies-and-sexuality">gender studies and sexuality</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/postcolonial">postcolonial</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/theory">theory</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>November 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>Gender, Sexuality and Islam in Muslim Women’s English Literature</strong>
</p><p> </p>
<p>Gender, sexuality and Islam are generally perceived as incompatible because discussion on gender and sexuality and the rights of women or LGBTQ+ people is viewed as not having any place in Islam. This general perception ignores the fact that Islam was once accused of being feminine and tolerant of non-heterosexual sensibilities. Islamophobic discourse and many Muslims also consider that the contemporary discourses on gender and sexuality do not have compatibility with Islam. Islamophobia perpetuates the notion that Islam is inherently patriarchal and heterosexual. This perspective blames the religion for its perceived lack of inclusivity towards women and LGBTQ+ individuals. On the other hand, some Muslims view discussions on gender and sexuality as western cultural imports aimed at promoting westernisation, vulgarity and anti-Islamism. These viewpoints contribute to a complex challenge faced by Muslim-majority societies when addressing the connection between gender, sexuality and Islam.</p>
<p>As a result of this complex challenge from both external and internal sources, discourse on gender, sexuality and Islam in Muslim-majority contexts has remained subdued. This silence has had detrimental effects on marginalised communities within Muslim societies who could otherwise have been granted equal rights. Muslim women and LGBTQ+ people of colour find themselves doubly marginalised within marginalities. It is, therefore, crucial to critically evaluate the prevailing perceptions surrounding gender, sexuality and Islam. Recognising the historical diversity within Islamic thought regarding these topics can help dispel misconceptions about their incompatibility. Additionally, fostering an open dialogue that respects diverse perspectives can contribute to a more nuanced understanding of the intersectionality between gender, sexualit, and Islam.</p>
<p>English literature, especially by Muslim women, has problematised the general perception of incompatibility and responded to the inside and the outside through such characters who negotiate between their gender, sexuality and Islam. While the terms 'gender' and 'sexuality' are modern constructs, Islam predates them and may not employ contemporary linguistic tools to address these concepts in a nuanced manner. However, literary works have explored the intricate interplay between them by presenting their female and non-heterosexual characters who confront patriarchal cultural/nationalist imaginaries within their own communities while also responding to western Islamophobic narratives. These characters engage in a constant struggle, fighting against societal norms and negotiating an intermediate space between western secularism and local religious traditions. This special issue aims to examine such inclusive and non-binary characters in English literature written by Muslim women. Its primary focus is to explore the compatibility of gender, sexuality and Islam within women's experiences as well as non-heteronormative subjectivities depicted in literature. Its primary focus is to explore the compatibility of gender, sexuality and Islam within women's experiences as well as non-heteronormative subjectivities depicted in literature. Its scope includes but is not restricted to the following themes:</p>
<ol>
<ol>In/compatibility of gender, sexuality, and Islam</ol>
</ol>
<p> </p>
<ol>
<ol>Muslim women’s and non-normative or LGBTQ+ people’s battles for their gender and sexual rights</ol>
</ol>
<p> </p>
<ol>
<ol>Suppression of discourse and struggle for gender and sexuality by Muslims</ol>
</ol>
<p> </p>
<ol>
<ol>Reduction of Islam as a gender- and sexuality-biased religion by Islamophobic frames</ol>
</ol>
<p> </p>
<ol>
<ol>Negotiated Muslim women and non-heterosexual subjectivities</ol>
</ol>
<p> </p>
<ol>
<ol>Embedding agency in religion</ol>
</ol>
<p> </p>
<ol>
<ol>Narratives of resistance and liberation</ol>
</ol>
<p> </p>
<ol>
<ol>Negotiating modernity and tradition</ol>
</ol>
<p> </p>
<ol>
<ol>Feminist and queer theoretical approaches in literature</ol>
</ol>
<p> </p>
<ol>
<ol>Voices of LGBTQ+ Muslim women</ol>
</ol>
<p> </p>
<ol>
<ol>The role of Muslim women writers in shaping discourse</ol>
</ol>
<p> </p>
<ol>
<ol>Challenging Islamophobia and misconceptions</ol>
</ol>
<p> </p>
<ol>Intersectionality and Muslim women's experiences</ol>
<p>Please, submit your abstract of 200 words along with your bio in 50 words to <a href="mailto:msnbajwa@gmail.com">Muhammad Safdar</a> (<a href="mailto:msnbajwa@gmail.com">msnbajwa@gmail.com</a>) by 15 Nov. 2023. The submitted abstracts will be reviewed and responses will be sent by 10 Dec. 2023. The full paper submission date is 30 Apr. 2024. The special issue will be published in the journal Intersections: Gender and Sexuality in Asia and the Pacific. The journal is also known as Intersections (Australia). Its ISSN is 1440-9151. It is published by The Australian National University and has a long and rich history of publishing scholarship on gender and sexuality as an open-access journal without charging any APC.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 11:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1692423429878680</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religion 2024 : Fourteenth International Conference on Religion &amp; Spirituality in Society</title>
			<link>http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=175805&amp;copyownerid=47287</link>
						<description>Fourteenth International Conference on Religion &amp; Spirituality in Society [Madrid, Spain] [May 23, 2024 - May 24, 2024]</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 05:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1692077828012696</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
