<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 12:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 12:19:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ March 7, 2024 -  March 8, 2024] Conference or similar: Between Power and Authority: Arendt on the Constitution and the Courts</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/115142</link>
						<description>Venue: 1448 Annadale Road<br/><br/><p>The U.S. Supreme Court today faces a crisis of legitimacy. More than half of Americans have an unfavorable view of the Court—the lowest in over three decades. Following a slate of rulings on abortion, affirmative action, student debt, and freedom of religion, an increasing number of Americans no longer believe the Court is impartial, viewing it as simply another partisan institution. As a result, many are calling for various reforms of the Court, including term limits and packing the court. At the same time, the Court has, even at this moment, has struck down racially motivated gerrymandering in Alabama and has refused to accept the Independent State Legislature Theory that would allow states to overturn the will of their voters. There is little doubt that politics is at play in the Supreme Court; at the same time, the Court still gives credence to the idea of the rule of law and not men. </p>
<p>In <em>On Revolution</em>, Hannah Arendt places the American constitutional tradition at the center of her inquiry into the founding and preserving of political freedom. The success of the American Revolution, for her, consisted in two things: its unleashing of citizen power through the principle of  federalist dispersion of power and its institutionalization of authority in the Supreme Court and the United States Constitution. Regarding the former, Arendt argues that the embrace of federalism allowed for the multiplication and flourishing of power within a stable system. Regarding the latter, Arendt offers an original reading of the Supreme Court as the successor of the Roman Senate. The Court's authority combined with the surprising fact that the Constitution came to be worshiped allowed the United States to achieve authority for its laws absent religious sanction. This authority tied together permanence and change, permitting the country to develop and grow while also maintaining order and stability. In short, the combination of power and authority that emerged from  the worship of the United States Constitution became the modern condition for the possibility of founding free government.</p>

<p>This conference aims to bring together scholars of Arendt’s constitutional thought and those working in political and legal theory more broadly to pursue the following questions: Is the Supreme Court still a legal institution, one that wields and deserves the authority imbued by the rule of law? Is the Supreme Court simply an undemocratic institution of power? If the latter, should we abandon the charade that the Supreme Court is above politics?  Or, should we work to uphold the reality and the illusion that the Court is a legal and not simply a political institution? Any answers to these questions request that we face what is lost if and when the Supreme Court is no longer recognized as a seat of authority. We are especially interested in papers that address: Arendt’s conception of power and/or authority, Arendt’s constitutional and/or legal theory, and the relevance of all of this for current discussions of the Supreme Court and constitutional politics.</p>
<p><br/></p>
<p><strong>Submission guidelines</strong></p>
<p>We invite submissions of paper proposals in the form of an extended abstract (500-1,000 words). Papers should be suitable for a 20 to 25 minute presentation, to be followed by a 15 minute Q&amp;A.</p>
<p>Please send anonymized submissions to <a href="mailto:hacpowerandauthority@gmail.com">hacpowerandauthority@gmail.com</a> by 1 December 2023; personal information (author name and affiliation) should be included in the body of the email. Decisions will be communicated by 1 January 2024. </p>
<p><strong>Registration and Format</strong></p>
<p>The event will take place in-person and will be free and open to the public. Please direct any questions to Nicholas Dunn (<a href="mailto:ndunn@bard.edu">ndunn@bard.edu</a>).</p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 05:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1696311426374612</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ December 1, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Between Power and Authority: Arendt on the Constitution and the Courts</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/115146</link>
						<description><p>The U.S. Supreme Court today faces a crisis of legitimacy. More than half of Americans have an unfavorable view of the Court—the lowest in over three decades. Following a slate of rulings on abortion, affirmative action, student debt, and freedom of religion, an increasing number of Americans no longer believe the Court is impartial, viewing it as simply another partisan institution. As a result, many are calling for various reforms of the Court, including term limits and packing the court. At the same time, the Court has, even at this moment, has struck down racially motivated gerrymandering in Alabama and has refused to accept the Independent State Legislature Theory that would allow states to overturn the will of their voters. There is little doubt that politics is at play in the Supreme Court; at the same time, the Court still gives credence to the idea of the rule of law and not men. </p>
<p>In <em>On Revolution</em>, Hannah Arendt places the American constitutional tradition at the center of her inquiry into the founding and preserving of political freedom. The success of the American Revolution, for her, consisted in two things: its unleashing of citizen power through the principle of  federalist dispersion of power and its institutionalization of authority in the Supreme Court and the United States Constitution. Regarding the former, Arendt argues that the embrace of federalism allowed for the multiplication and flourishing of power within a stable system. Regarding the latter, Arendt offers an original reading of the Supreme Court as the successor of the Roman Senate. The Court's authority combined with the surprising fact that the Constitution came to be worshiped allowed the United States to achieve authority for its laws absent religious sanction. This authority tied together permanence and change, permitting the country to develop and grow while also maintaining order and stability. In short, the combination of power and authority that emerged from  the worship of the United States Constitution became the modern condition for the possibility of founding free government.</p>

<p>This conference aims to bring together scholars of Arendt’s constitutional thought and those working in political and legal theory more broadly to pursue the following questions: Is the Supreme Court still a legal institution, one that wields and deserves the authority imbued by the rule of law? Is the Supreme Court simply an undemocratic institution of power? If the latter, should we abandon the charade that the Supreme Court is above politics?  Or, should we work to uphold the reality and the illusion that the Court is a legal and not simply a political institution? Any answers to these questions request that we face what is lost if and when the Supreme Court is no longer recognized as a seat of authority. We are especially interested in papers that address: Arendt’s conception of power and/or authority, Arendt’s constitutional and/or legal theory, and the relevance of all of this for current discussions of the Supreme Court and constitutional politics.</p>
<p><br/></p>
<p><strong>Submission guidelines</strong></p>
<p>We invite submissions of paper proposals in the form of an extended abstract (500-1,000 words). Papers should be suitable for a 20 to 25 minute presentation, to be followed by a 15 minute Q&amp;A.</p>
<p>Please send anonymized submissions to <a href="mailto:hacpowerandauthority@gmail.com">hacpowerandauthority@gmail.com</a> by 1 December 2023; personal information (author name and affiliation) should be included in the body of the email. Decisions will be communicated by 1 January 2024. </p>
<p><strong>Registration and Format</strong></p>
<p>The event will take place in-person and will be free and open to the public. Please direct any questions to Nicholas Dunn (<a href="mailto:ndunn@bard.edu">ndunn@bard.edu</a>).</p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 05:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1696311426374611</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ February 20, 2024 -  February 22, 2024] Conference or similar: Challenging Concepts Debating Conceptualism and Non-Conceptualism in Epistemology and Metaphysics</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/115110</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p>CALL FOR ABSTRACTS<br/>International Conference<br/><br/><br/><strong>Challenging Concepts</strong><br/><strong>Debating Conceptualism and Non-Conceptualism in Epistemology and Metaphysics</strong><br/><br/>February, 20-21-22, 2024<br/>University of Padua, Italy</p>
<p><br/>  </p>
<p>Keynote Speakers:</p>
<p><strong>Bill Brewer</strong></p>
<p>(King’s College London, UK)</p>
<p><strong>Walter Hopp</strong></p>
<p>(Boston University, USA)<br/> <strong>Denis McManus</strong></p>
<p>(University of Southampton, UK)<br/> <strong>Sonja Rinofner-Kreidl</strong></p>
<p>(University of Graz, Austria)<br/> <strong>Elisabetta Sacchi</strong></p>
<p>(University Vita-Salute San Raffaele, Italy)</p>
<p>Submission Deadline: <strong>15th of December, 2023</strong><strong></strong></p>
<p>The nature of concepts continues to be one of the most fundamental conundrum around which philosophical reflection has converged. Understanding the role of concepts and their intersection with other dimensions of experience is directly related to investigating “human nature” and the structure of world and reality. Inquiries into the functioning of concepts rest at the heart not only of an internal bifurcation in Classical phenomenology (Husserl, Heidegger) but have notably played a pivotal role in analytical debates (Russell, Moore). Especially in the last 30 years, the philosophical discussion about the role of concepts and the nature of conceptual content has been mainly subsumed within the dichotomous debate about conceptualism and non-conceptualism. Scholars have been engaged in classifying concepts (Benoist, Peacocke), determining their relation to perception (Sellars, McDowell, Brewer, Hopp), negating/limiting their cognitive role (Dreyfus) or accounting for a non-conceptual content of perception (Dretske, Travis, Bermúdez). This extremely intricate, yet rich and fruitful debate has attracted scholars from different traditions of thought who have engaged in metaphysical and epistemological analysis in the broadest sense. In order to answer the question regarding the nature of the concept, scholars have employed various strategies, either through an investigation into the history of philosophy – from Aristotle, to Hume, Kant, Hegel, Husserl, and Wittgenstein – or by attempting to approach the question from both the analytical and continental traditions: exploiting pragmatism, phenomenology, and philosophy of language.<br/> <br/> The conference aims to gather diverse perspectives of the topic at hand and enrich critical debate. To that end, the conference will bring together scholars from diverse backgrounds in order to discuss the key problematics concerning the nature of conceptual/non-conceptual content, such as: What are concepts? How shall we understand the relationship between the conceptual and non-conceptual spheres? What is at stake in the conceptual/non-conceptualism debate?</p>
<p>Papers are welcome that try to answer these and related questions. Suitable topics may include, but are not limited to:<br/> -       the nature of concepts<br/> -       the origin of concepts<br/> -       the relationship between concepts and perception<br/> -       the relationship between concepts and knowledge<br/> -       the role of concepts in human experience in general<br/> -       the nature of concepts versus the nature of the world<br/> -       critical analyses of the debate on conceptualism/non-conceptualism</p>
<p><strong>Details of the conference</strong></p>
<p>Date: February, 20-21-22, 2024<br/> Place: University of Padua, Italy<br/> Keynote Speakers: Bill <strong>Brewer</strong> (King’s College London, UK); Walter <strong>Hopp</strong> (Boston University, USA); Denis <strong>McManus</strong> (University of Southampton, UK); Sonja <strong>Rinofner</strong>-<strong>Kreidl</strong> (University of Graz, Austria); Elisabetta <strong>Sacchi</strong> (University Vita-Salute San Raffaele, Italy).</p>
<p><strong>Submission guidelines</strong></p>
<p>The working language of the conference will be English.</p>
<p>Please submit an abstract of 250-400 words (title included) in PDF format by <strong>December 15th, 2023</strong> to the following address: <a target="_blank">giulia.lanzirotti@unipd.it</a><br/> In the <strong>subject of the email</strong>, please write: Challenging Concepts - Abstract Submission.<br/> The submission must include the following two documents in PDF-format:<br/> - Abstract of the presentation, prepared for blind review<br/> - Document which states name, address, institutional affiliation and title of the presentation.</p>
<p><br/> The conference will be held in person.</p>
<p><br/> <br/> If you have any questions, please feel free to contact the organizer using the e-mail address: <a target="_blank">giulia.lanzirotti@unipd.it</a></p>
<p><strong>Organizer</strong>: Giulia Lanzirotti</p>
<p><br/> <strong>Scientific Committee</strong>: Andrea Altobrando, Simone Aurora, Luca Corti, Giulia Lanzirotti, Vittorio Morato</p>
<p>The event is supported by the University of Padua (Italy), within the STARS@UNIPD 2021 Grant-Project “TYPRAX”.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 05:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1696311426374610</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Contemporary Pagans in Public Interaction: Constructing Religion in Central and Eastern Europe</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/09/26/contemporary-pagans-in-public-interaction-constructing-religion-in-central-and</link>
						<dc:creator>Egle Aleknaite</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Friday, September 29, 2023 - 3:18pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Egle Aleknaite</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:egle.aleknaite@vdu.lt">egle.aleknaite@vdu.lt</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/ethnicity-and-national-identity">ethnicity and national identity</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>December 31, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>Call for Papers</strong></p>
<p><strong>Contemporary Pagans in Public Interaction: </strong></p>
<p><strong>Constructing Religion in Central and Eastern Europe </strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>We are seeking papers for a peer-reviewed edited volume, to be published by Bloomsbury Press with the editor Eglė Aleknaitė, Vytautas Magnus University (<a href="mailto:egle.aleknaite@vdu.lt">egle.aleknaite@vdu.lt</a>).</p>
<p>With questioning of secularization thesis and recognizing the unceasing public role of religion in modern societies, scholars have observed and analyzed numerous collaborative public interactions between secular and religious actors. In current academic debates, however, contemporary Pagans are rarely seen as religious actors seeking the public role. The proposed volume aims to present case studies analyzing contemporary Pagans’ engagement in public interactions in Central and Eastern Europe.</p>
<p>Pagans of the region differ in their disposition to seek the public role and interact with secular actors. Some of them, for example, engage in identity and heritage politics and interact with other actors through their work at secular heritage institutions, academia, or public event organizing. The landscape within which Pagans act and the actors which they interact with is historically and regionally specific because of a number of pre-Soviet and pre-socialist, Soviet and socialist, and post-Soviet and post-socialist developments in Eastern and Central Europe. The countries of the region share relatively similar experiences of 19th-century nationalism, Soviet and socialist modernization and anti-religious policies, and post-Soviet and post-socialist processes. Some contemporary Pagan communities of the region are building on imageries and conceptualizations of religion, spirituality, and culture and related practices and institutions that have been developed since the nationalist movements of the 19th-early 20th century, or later Soviet and Socialist periods. Post-Soviet and post-socialist developments related to changes in the politics of religion and culture administration also shaped the landscapes and opportunities of Pagans’ interaction with various secular and religious actors. Finally, sharing concerns over globalization, migration, gender politics, and the like, some Pagans recently got involved in discourses, practices, and events of nationalist populism that has been recently on the rise in the region.</p>
<p>Such interactions demonstrate Pagans’ attitudes towards the surrounding society and the nature of their relationships with it, and, on the other hand, the impact of the state, the majority religion, and other relevant actors. They also serve as situations within which essential categories and ideas are constructed, reified, and performed on variously defined terms that depend on the actors' power relations, ideologies, and goals. Collaborations with public institutions are opportunities for establishing and maintaining relationships, embodying, contesting, and negotiating religious, national, ethnic and local identities, and constructing the very Pagan tradition, a category of religion, and boundaries between the religious and the secular.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>We are looking for papers between 8,000 and 10,000 words from a range of theoretical, methodological, and disciplinary perspectives. Contributors are invited to address such topics as:</p>
<ul>
<li>Interactions with the state and other secular institutions and actors in the context of academia, public culture, identity politics, heritage management, environmental initiatives, and other spheres;</li>
<li>Interactions with other religious actors in the context of academia, public culture, identity politics, heritage management, environmental initiatives, and other spheres;</li>
<li>The interpretation and use of the legacy of pre-Soviet/socialist and Soviet/socialist narratives and practices by Pagans and against Pagans;</li>
<li>Construction of religion, conceptualization, and performance of Paganism as religion and culture, use of secular and religious discourse and authorities in interactions;</li>
<li>Participation in discourses, practices, and events of nationalist populism;</li>
<li>Interactions in the context of gender politics.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p>Please send an abstract (max 200 words) with name and affiliation (if relevant), a proposal (max 1000 words), and an anticipated word count, to Eglė Aleknaitė at <a href="mailto:egle.aleknaite@vdu.lt.">egle.aleknaite@vdu.lt.</a> Please do feel free to contact the editor with any questions.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Proposals Due: December 31st 2023</p>
<p>Acceptance Response: January 31th 2024</p>
<p>Contributors’ Chapters Due: August 31st 2024</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Contact Information</strong></p>
<p>Eglė Aleknaitė, PhD, Vytautas Magnus University</p>
<p><strong>Contact Email</strong></p>
<p><a href="mailto:egle.aleknaite@vdu.lt">egle.aleknaite@vdu.lt</a></p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 18:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1696052222495992</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Digest – September 27, 2023</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-digest-september-27-2023/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find 26 new job opportunities, 1 Award, 8 Calls for Papers, 2 Conferences/Speakers, and 2 other events/submissions.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 31!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Academic:</h4>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Philosophy (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Utah State University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: November 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178550058&amp;utm_source=09_26_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178550058&amp;utm_source=09_26_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>National Association of Baptist Professor of Religion Postdoc Fellowship</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://nabpr.org/nabpr-postdoc-fellowship-annoucement/">https://nabpr.org/nabpr-postdoc-fellowship-annoucement/</a></p>



<h4>Visiting Assistant Professor in Modern Hebrew and Jewish Studies (2-year appointment)</h4>



<p>Muhlenberg College, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: October 16, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178512583&amp;AAEmail=133566&amp;MatchType=0&amp;utm_source=09_23_2023&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=AAEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178512583&amp;AAEmail=133566&amp;MatchType=0&amp;utm_source=09_23_2023&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=AAEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Anthropology (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Texas A&amp;M University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: November 10, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178547554&amp;utm_source=09_23_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178547554&amp;utm_source=09_23_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Sociology (Full-time, non-tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Grove City College, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178546809&amp;utm_source=09_23_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178546809&amp;utm_source=09_23_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Robert H. N. Ho Family Foundation Professor in Buddhist Studies (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>University of Utah, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: October 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178546714&amp;utm_source=09_23_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178546714&amp;utm_source=09_23_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Chair of Department of Biblical and Religious Studies (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Samford University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: December 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178546086&amp;utm_source=09_23_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178546086&amp;utm_source=09_23_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor in Department of Religion (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign</p>



<p>Deadline: October 25, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178544546&amp;AAEmail=133522&amp;MatchType=2&amp;utm_source=09_22_2023&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=AAEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178544546&amp;AAEmail=133522&amp;MatchType=2&amp;utm_source=09_22_2023&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=AAEmail</a></p>



<h4>Visiting Assistant Professor in Cultural Anthropology (2-3 year appointment)</h4>



<p>Duke Kunshan University, China</p>



<p>Deadline: October 27, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178545345&amp;utm_source=09_22_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178545345&amp;utm_source=09_22_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor in Department of Native American Studies (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>University of Montana, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: December 3, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178543987&amp;utm_source=09_21_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178543987&amp;utm_source=09_21_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Religion and Science (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Rice University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: October 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://apply.interfolio.com/131328">https://apply.interfolio.com/131328</a></p>



<h4>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</h4>



<p>Illinois State University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: October 10, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://jobsearch.illinoisstate.edu/cw/en-us/job/517572">https://jobsearch.illinoisstate.edu/cw/en-us/job/517572</a></p>



<h4>Asia Research Postdoctoral Fellowship (2-year appointment)</h4>



<p>National University of Singapore, Singapore</p>



<p>Deadline: October 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://ari.nus.edu.sg/opportunities/postdoctoral-fellowships-fy2024-25/">https://ari.nus.edu.sg/opportunities/postdoctoral-fellowships-fy2024-25/</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor in South Asian Cultural Studies (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Duke University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: January 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://academicjobsonline.org/ajo/jobs/25880">https://academicjobsonline.org/ajo/jobs/25880</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor in Roman History (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>University of Connecticut, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: October 23, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.historians.org/jobs/19194322/assistant-professor-of-roman-history">https://careers.historians.org/jobs/19194322/assistant-professor-of-roman-history</a></p>



<h4>Professor in Modern or Contemporary Global Church History (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Boston College, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: October 27, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.historians.org/jobs/19183683/full-time-position-in-modern-or-contemporary-global-church-history">https://careers.historians.org/jobs/19183683/full-time-position-in-modern-or-contemporary-global-church-history</a></p>



<h4>Minerva Recruitment Job Listings Cite (with areas specifically tailored for Ph.D.)</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://minerva-recruitment.com/">Minerva Recruitment – Higher Education Graduate Jobs, UK &amp; Worldwide (minerva-recruitment.com)</a></p>



<h4>AAR/SBL Job Forum</h4>



<p><a href="https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search">https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search</a></p>



<h4>Non-Academic:</h4>



<h4>Director of Fellowships Advising (Masters Degree required)</h4>



<p>Franklin &amp; Marshall College, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178547622&amp;utm_source=09_23_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178547622&amp;utm_source=09_23_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Head of University Archives Reference Services</h4>



<p>Harvard University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: October 20, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178546337&amp;utm_source=09_23_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178546337&amp;utm_source=09_23_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Court Research Associate (Masters degree or JD required)</h4>



<p>National Center for State Courts, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.indeed.com/viewjob?jk=6ec7536772937e63&amp;q=phd&amp;l=United+States&amp;tk=1haqprbuj3cce000&amp;from=ja&amp;alid=5f1dda7fef3c8f057b077c6e">https://www.indeed.com/viewjob?jk=6ec7536772937e63&amp;q=phd&amp;l=United+States&amp;tk=1haqprbuj3cce000&amp;from=ja&amp;alid=5f1dda7fef3c8f057b077c6e</a></p>



<h4>Black Church Reporter</h4>



<p>Associated Press, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: October 19, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.ap.org/job/Atlanta-Newsperson-%28Black-Church-Reporter%29-GA-30303-2720/1078380000/?fbclid=IwAR3Vy0X3vwN6DTrvo2uNyg-HElzUEeyRaeFBjd9hH9_uJKPwXkFtCFMx0kw">Newsperson (Black Church Reporter) (ap.org)</a></p>



<h4>Staff Cultural Resource Specialist</h4>



<p>ERM, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://erm.wd3.myworkdayjobs.com/ERM_Careers/job/Walnut-Creek-California/Staff-Cultural-Resource-Specialist--Entry-Level-_R00017361">https://erm.wd3.myworkdayjobs.com/ERM_Careers/job/Walnut-Creek-California/Staff-Cultural-Resource-Specialist–Entry-Level-_R00017361</a></p>



<h4>Anthropologist (PhD required)</h4>



<p>Communitology, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/jobs/view/3725111324/">https://www.linkedin.com/jobs/view/3725111324/</a></p>



<h4>Instruction Designer (Masters degree required)</h4>



<p>Penn State University, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://psu.wd1.myworkdayjobs.com/en-US/PSU_Staff/job/Instructional-Designer-3--Filippelli-Institute-for-e-Education-and-Outreach_REQ_0000045512-1">https://psu.wd1.myworkdayjobs.com/en-US/PSU_Staff/job/Instructional-Designer-3–Filippelli-Institute-for-e-Education-and-Outreach_REQ_0000045512-1</a></p>



<h4>Senior Research Writer</h4>



<p>Penn State University, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://psu.wd1.myworkdayjobs.com/PSU_Staff/job/Penn-State-University-Park/Senior-Research-Writer_REQ_0000048831-1">https://psu.wd1.myworkdayjobs.com/PSU_Staff/job/Penn-State-University-Park/Senior-Research-Writer_REQ_0000048831-1</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Historian (PhD required)</h4>



<p>US Senate, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.usajobs.gov/job/750511400">https://www.usajobs.gov/job/750511400</a></p>



<h4>Ethics Program Coordinator</h4>



<p>Cambia Health Solutions, USA (Remote)</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://cambiahealth.wd1.myworkdayjobs.com/External/job/Portland-OR/Ethics-Program-Coordinator_R-4316">https://cambiahealth.wd1.myworkdayjobs.com/External/job/Portland-OR/Ethics-Program-Coordinator_R-4316</a></p>



<h2>Awards:</h2>



<h4>Frantz Fanon Dissertation Award</h4>



<p>Deadline: November 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/Jngx86F5ff">https://t.co/Jngx86F5ff</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>Berkeley Journal of Sociology</h4>



<p>Deadline: December 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://twitter.com/berkeleyjournal/status/1704956033175806192/photo/1">https://twitter.com/berkeleyjournal/status/1704956033175806192/photo/1</a></p>



<h4>Spring Academy 2024 – Interdisciplinary Conference on American Studies</h4>



<p>Deadline: November 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=176333&amp;copyownerid=80601">http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=176333&amp;copyownerid=80601</a></p>



<h4>Gulf Studies Symposium</h4>



<p>Deadline: October 10, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/OGhZ5NsZIG">https://t.co/OGhZ5NsZIG</a></p>



<h4>De/Centering Southeast Asia</h4>



<p>Deadline: November 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://twitter.com/seacsydney/status/1706170413884289350?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw">https://twitter.com/seacsydney/status/1706170413884289350?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw</a></p>



<h4>Caste-ing Academia: The Global Rice of (Critical) Caste Studies</h4>



<p>Deadline: September 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/09/22/caste-ing-academia-the-global-rise-of-critical-caste-studies">https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/09/22/caste-ing-academia-the-global-rise-of-critical-caste-studies</a></p>



<h4>Writing Faith and Place in Early Modern Britain</h4>



<p>Deadline: January 12, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/09/21/writing-faith-and-place-in-early-modern-britain">https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/09/21/writing-faith-and-place-in-early-modern-britain</a></p>



<h4>Competing Chrisitan Identities</h4>



<p>Deadline: November 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/09/22/competing-christian-identities">https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/09/22/competing-christian-identities</a></p>



<h4>Songlines and Lifelines: Women and Muslim Vernacular Cultures on the Malabar Coast</h4>



<p>Deadline: October 20, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/09/25/songlines-and-lifelines-women-and-muslim-vernacular-cultures-on-the-malabar-coast">https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/09/25/songlines-and-lifelines-women-and-muslim-vernacular-cultures-on-the-malabar-coast</a></p>



<h2>Conferences/Speakers:</h2>



<h4>2024 American Catholic Historical Association</h4>



<p>San Francisco, USA</p>



<p>Date: January 4-6, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/0oTAZD9SN3">https://t.co/0oTAZD9SN3</a></p>



<h4>Religion &amp; the Public Intellectual</h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>Date: September 28, 2023, 3:00 – 4:00 pm (EST)</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://twitter.com/csraac/status/1706084318383321280?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw">https://twitter.com/csraac/status/1706084318383321280?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw</a></p>



<h2>Miscellaneous:</h2>



<h4>Oxford Public Philosophy Positions</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.oxfordpublicphilosophy.com/join">join the team — oxford public philosophy</a></p>



<h4>National Humanities Center – Humanities Education Resources</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://nationalhumanitiescenter.org/">https://nationalhumanitiescenter.org/</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1695879426383191</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ March 15, 2024] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/114894</link>
						<description>Publication Name: CALL FOR PAPERS / APPEL A PROPOSITIONS :  Etudes Ricoeuriennes / Ricoeur Studies (ERRS)  / Volume 15, N°1 (2024) :  « Ontology and Metaphysics in Ricoeur’s Philosophy »<br/><br/><p><strong>CALL FOR PAPERS / APPEL A PROPOSITIONS :</strong></p>
<p><strong>Etudes Ricoeuriennes / Ricoeur Studies (ERRS)</strong></p>
<p><strong>Volume 15, N°1 (2024</strong><strong>) :</strong></p>
<p><strong>« </strong><strong>Ontology and Metaphysics in Ricoeur’s Philosophy </strong><strong>»</strong></p>
<p>Ontology and metaphysics are fields of inquiry and disciplines that have structured philosophy since its origins, and have undergone countless developments to the present day. They represent the most general and abstract aims of thinking about being qua being, of systematic knowledge of beings, and of what determines the way in which other fields of philosophical investigation can be elaborated. In the twentieth century, the contributions of phenomenology and analytic philosophy transformed definitions inherited from the tradition, leading to ontology becoming the most general framework for investigating being or, alternatively, to differentiating metaphysics and ontology by ascribing specific regions of being and objects to them according to related analytic or descriptive aims. Whether as a teacher and historian of philosophy or while producing his own work, Ricoeur came back to this diverse heritage. While his approach was derived from the Kantian critique of metaphysics as ontotheology, it has also become more complex by determining itself in relation to a general framework irreducible solely to either the legacy of Kantianism or the post-metaphysical perspectives that result. Here, then, the concern of reformulating ontology based on the phenomenological method or the scientific paradigm is decisive: Ricoeur explicitly sought to maintain the reference to a metaphysical plane and to the legitimacy of this reference as part of his philosophy of human action and hermeneutics of the self.</p>
<p>However, this position needs to be reconsidered in the light of Heidegger’s ontology and post-Heideggerian reformulations of ontology, of a post-metaphysical perspective more specifically derived from a Hegelian lineage, and of an analytic philosophy that affirms anew the connection between ontology and metaphysics as well as their respective purposes. While Heidegger’s idea of destruction of metaphysics and its various legacies rely on a fundamental ontology that precedes all epistemology and ethics, Ricoeur’s philosophy highlights the need to return to the epistemological and ethical plane from the ontological one: here, a well-maintained bond with metaphysics is at play. With regards to a post-metaphysical stance claimed by the critical theory in a Hegelian vein, the relation of Ricoeur’s anthropology to objective spirit, through its self-proclaimed metaphysical connection to human action, necessarily deserves consideration. The way that Ricoeur seeks to escape this reference to a post-metaphysical framework might instead relate to approaches and elaborations stemming from analytic philosophy: hence one finds references to problems in ontology and metaphysics alongside references to analysis in philosophy of language and philosophy of mind. While this reappropriation receives hardly any acknowledgement, and is even strongly criticized, it nonetheless results from the way in which Ricoeur deals with the ties between ontology and metaphysics and then builds up an approach of his own that differentiates itself from usual legacies within the phenomenological vein.</p>
<p>Some of Ricoeur’s work refers to those different legacies, to a greater or lesser degree, while another part continuously develops a hermeneutics of the self from this original affirmation using ontological and metaphysical reflection that claims roots in French reflexive philosophy, phenomenology, and hermeneutics. Although mainly approached within the vein of phenomenology and in the wake of Heidegger’s philosophical provocations, Ricoeur nevertheless defines ontology and metaphysics as the ultimate, always problematic, and unfinished goal of philosophical discourse. But this seemingly unresolved difficulty within Ricoeur’s philosophy, a result of its Kantian and Heideggerian legacy, would be compensated for by the fact that the issue of human action is precisely linked to a metaphysical aim that necessarily relies on Ricoeur’s own conception of ontology. One must thus consider not only the link between metaphysics and morality or ethics, but also the decision to hold metaphysics and ontology together in a way that, after a confrontation with Levinas’s philosophy, explains its difference with the latter and specifies the framework of its hermeneutics of the self with regards to the meta-category of alterity.</p>
<p>Accordingly, issues of ontology and metaphysics can be considered from these approaches. The first approach relates to legacies of the history of philosophy and the multiple ways in which variations of thought on being qua being construct and attempt to deal with the polysemy of being. The second one relates to Ricoeur’s more personal engagement with various philosophical, theoretical, and even theological currents of his time, linking the issue of human action to issues of identity, ipseity and alterity. These two approaches – one that looks at the history of philosophy as a whole, another that tries to elaborate a more personal path – inevitably overlapped at one point or another, bringing to light the most salient leanings of Ricoeur’s approach to ontology and metaphysics. In this respect, <em>Oneself as Another</em><em> </em>represents a kind of peak achievement, as it brings together the various contemporary resources of Ricoeur’s thought and philosophy of human action as anticipated since its inception. It is nevertheless noteworthy that, in <em>Réflexion faite</em>, he looks back in a partly critical way at this last section of <em>Oneself as Another</em>, leaving the final reading of the ontology and metaphysics throughout his work open. <em>The Course of Recognition</em> refers again to this project of generating metaphysics anew, by deepening the questions of human action and attestation by starting out from the recognized-being.</p>
<p>This issue of ERRS aims to gather articles that explore these links between legacies of the history of philosophy and the reappropriations or reformulations that characterize Ricoeur’s philosophy specifically</p>
<p>-- by reviewing the significance of Ricoeur’s references to French reflexive philosophy (Marcel, Nabert etc.), his initial approach to human action and the issue of evil, or the phenomenological, ethical and metaphysical issues involved in his relationship with Levinas’s philosophy;</p>
<p>-- by focusing on Ricoeur’s project for a philosophical anthropology linked to an ontology of action and power, engaging in an in-depth reading of Aristotle or even referring to Spinoza, but from the perspective of a critique of substantialism;</p>
<p>-- by confronting Ricoeur’s ontology and metaphysics with the methodological and epistemological discussion inherited from hermeneutics, phenomenology and analytic philosophy, notably in regard to significant developments within the latter vein; or, more polemically, with regard to post-metaphysical perspectives;</p>
<p>-- connections with the fields of theology and the philosophy of religion can also be taken into account, but preferably as far as they shed light on what Ricoeur tries to implement from a philosophical field considered for its own sake;</p>
<p>-- any study that relates Ricoeur to a theme or author dealing with metaphysics or ontology is welcome.</p>
<p>Closing date for the submission of texts: 15 March 2024. Maximum number of characters (including spaces and notes): 50,000. Articles can be written either in English or in French. Format and style: the journal follows the Chicago Manual of Style. See the rubric ‘Author Guidelines’ on the journal’s website: http://ricoeur.pitt.edu/ojs/index.php/ricoeur/about/submissions#onlineSubmissions The editors cannot consider articles that do not follow these guidelines. Instructions to authors: in order to submit an article, authors need to register on the journal website: http://ricoeur.pitt.edu/ojs/index.php/ricoeur/user/register. There is a quick, five-step procedure to upload articles to the website. As soon as articles are uploaded, authors will receive a confirmation email. All articles will be peer-reviewed by two referees in a ‘double blind’ process.</p>
<p>Guest Editor: Samuel Lelièvre.</p>
<p>Ernst Wolff and Jean-Luc Amalric, co-editors Etudes Ricoeuriennes/Ricoeur Studies Journal -- http://ricoeur.pitt.edu/ </p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 05:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1695793026584502</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[Today] Talk or similar: Sobre la virtud de la responsabilidad. Una tesitura epistémica desde la hermenéutica</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/114910</link>
						<description>Venue: Miñones 2073<br/><br/>Speakers at this event: <br/>Luiz Rohden (Universidade do Vale do Rio dos Sinos)<br/><br/><p>Dear researchers,</p>
<p>We are pleased to announce the upcoming conference "Sobre la virtud de la responsabilidad. Una tesitura epistémica desde la hermenéutica" (in Portuguese and Spanish), presented by Prof. Dr. Luiz Rohden (Unisinos - Brazil). This event is organized by the Institute of Philosophy "Ezequiel de Olaso" (INEO), based at the Centro de Investigaciones Filosóficas (Miñones 2073, Buenos Aires, Argentina).</p>
<p>The conference will be held in a hybrid format (both in-person and virtual) on Friday, September 29th, at 11:00 AM (Argentina/Brazil time). For those interested in attending the Zoom meeting, please find the meeting details below.</p>
<p>Join Zoom Meeting: https://conicet-gov-ar.zoom.us/j/88396457044?pwd=Y0czVDBuaU4wMkNpdlVsWjVTdldHQT09</p>
<p>Meeting ID: 883 9645 7044</p>
<p>Passcode: E20iX^uEcG</p>
<p>Further information is available in https://ineo.conicet.gov.ar/conferencia-sobre-la-virtud-de-la-responsabilidad-una-tesitura-epistemica-desde-la-hermeneutica/</p>
<p>Warm regards,</p>
<p>Instituto de Filosofía “Ezequiel de Olaso”</p>
<p>Centro de Investigaciones Filosóficas</p>
<p>CONICET</p>
<p>-------------------------------------------</p>
<p>Estimadas/os investigadoras/es:</p>
<p>Difundimos la realización de la conferencia “Sobre la virtud de la responsabilidad. Una tesitura epistémica desde la hermenéutica” (en Portugués y Español), a cargo del Prof. Dr. Luiz Rohden (Unisinos - Brasil), organizada por el Instituto de Filosofía “Ezequiel de Olaso”, con sede en el Centro de Investigaciones Filosóficas (Miñones 2073, C. A. B. A.).</p>
<p>La actividad es abierta y se desarrollará de forma híbrida (presencial y virtual) el viernes 29/9 a las 11hs (hora de Argentina/Brasil). Quienes deseen asistir a la reunión por Zoom, les dejamos a continuación los datos de la reunión.</p>
<p>Unirse a la reunión Zoom: https://conicet-gov-ar.zoom.us/j/88396457044?pwd=Y0czVDBuaU4wMkNpdlVsWjVTdldHQT09</p>
<p>ID de reunión: 883 9645 7044</p>
<p>Código de acceso: E20iX^uEcG</p>
<p>Más información en https://ineo.conicet.gov.ar/conferencia-sobre-la-virtud-de-la-responsabilidad-una-tesitura-epistemica-desde-la-hermeneutica/</p>
<p>Saludos cordiales,</p>
<p>Instituto de Filosofía “Ezequiel de Olaso”</p>
<p>Centro de Investigaciones Filosóficas</p>
<p>CONICET</p>
<p>---------------</p>
<p>Prezados/as pesquisadores/as,</p>
<p>Temos o prazer de anunciar a próxima conferência "Sobre a virtude da responsabilidade: Uma tessitura epistêmica a partir da hermenêutica" (em português e espanhol), apresentada pelo Prof. Dr. Luiz Rohden (Unisinos - Brasil). Este evento é organizado pelo Instituto de Filosofia "Ezequiel de Olaso" (INEO), sediado no Centro de Investigaciones Filosóficas (Miñones 2073, Buenos Aires, Argentina).</p>
<p>A conferência será realizada em formato híbrido (presencial e virtual) na sexta-feira, 29 de setembro, às 11:00 (horário da Argentina/Brasil). Para aqueles interessados em participar da reunião pelo Zoom, encontrem os detalhes da reunião abaixo.</p>
<p>Junte-se à Reunião Zoom: https://conicet-gov-ar.zoom.us/j/88396457044?pwd=Y0czVDBuaU4wMkNpdlVsWjVTdldHQT09</p>
<p>ID da Reunião: 883 9645 7044</p>
<p>Código de Acesso: E20iX^uEcG</p>
<p>Mais informações estão disponíveis no https://ineo.conicet.gov.ar/conferencia-sobre-la-virtud-de-la-responsabilidad-una-tesitura-epistemica-desde-la-hermeneutica/</p>
<p>Atenciosamente,</p>
<p>Instituto de Filosofía “Ezequiel de Olaso”</p>
<p>Centro de Investigaciones Filosóficas</p>
<p>CONICET</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 05:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1695793026584501</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
