<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 12:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 12:24:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ May 15, 2023] Conference talk or similar: CFP: Rethinking Racism Through Embodiment and Place (A thematic stream for the 47th  Annual Meeting of the International Merleau-Ponty Circle)</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/109945</link>
						<description>Venue: Deakin Downtown<br/><br/><p>CFP: Rethinking Racism Through Embodiment and Place </p>
<p>A thematic stream for the 47th Annual Meeting of the International Merleau-Ponty Circle </p>
<p>4-6 December 2023 </p>
<p>In-person and virtual (hybrid) </p>
<p>Deakin University, Melbourne / Narrm, Australia </p>
<p>To many critical phenomenologists working on race, racism, and decoloniality, Maurice Merleau-Ponty’s philosophical account of the body as central to all lived experience has been a productive touchstone. Building on the classic phenomenological tradition while advancing critiques of its assumptions, these accounts have drawn attention to the ways in which racism impacts the bodily experience, self-perceptions, lived temporalities, habits, and social worlds of marginalised groups. Critical phenomenologists of race – among whom we might name Frantz Fanon, Sara Ahmed, Alia Al-Saji, Linda Martín Alcoff, George Yancy, Mariana Ortega, and others – have variously examinedthe existential, everyday, and deeply embodied impacts of racist oppression, and how these can affect our experience of place and placemaking. </p>
<p>As part of the 47th annual International Merleau-Ponty Circle (IMPC), we warmly invite submissions for a thematic stream exploring questions of racism, place, and embodiment. Interdisciplinary approaches that engage with these themes through phenomenology – critically or otherwise – are most welcome. We also encourage intersectional analyses that consider multiple systems of oppression (e.g., based on gender, class, disability, sexual orientation) and the differential impacts these may have.</p>
<p>Potential paper topics may include, but are not limited to: </p>
<ul>
<li>interpersonal and structural forms of oppression </li>
<li>settler colonialism and dispossession </li>
<li>home, placemaking, and belonging </li>
<li>social justice, protest, and resistance </li>
<li>migration, mobility, and diaspora </li>
<li>language, gesture, and embodiment </li>
</ul>
<p>We especially encourage submissions from First Nations people, people of colour, and other underrepresented groups in Philosophy and the academy more generally.  </p>
<p>This stream will be curated by Helen Ngo for a research project funded by the Australian Research Council (DE220100329). Anumber of travel bursaries will be available for students and unsalaried/low-waged early career researchers (ECRs) presenting in-person in this stream. (An ECR is defined as being fewer than 5 years out of their PhD, excluding career interruptions.) Participants wishing to be considered for a bursary should indicate on their cover letter: (1) your usual place of residence, and (2) whether you are a student or a low-waged ECR. Please note that submissions which engage directly with Merleau-Ponty’s work are also eligible to be considered for the two student prizes outlined in the conference’s general call for papers.  </p>
<p>Full paper submissions of no more than 3,500 words should be prepared for anonymous review and sent to Helen Ngo (helen.ngo@deakin.edu.au) and Ryan Gustafsson (r.gustafsson@deakin.edu.au) with the subject heading "IMPCRethinking Racism submission." The deadline for submissions is May 15, 2023.   </p>
<p>As this conference will be held as a hybrid event, please indicate whether, upon acceptance, you plan to attend in-person or virtually. In order to host the conference at a physical location, a certain percentage of talks will need to be presented in person, and this will be factored in during the review process. Please also include any anticipated accessibility needs, which will greatly assist in planning.  </p>
<p>Helen Ngo and Jack Reynolds/ IMPC 2023 conference co-convenors </p>
<p>Ryan Gustafsson / Research Assistant  </p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 05:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680673038711653</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Theme: “Life is War”: Social Militarization and the Culture of Prayers in Africa</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12671589/theme-%E2%80%9Clife-war%E2%80%9D-social-militarization-and-culture-prayers</link>
						<dc:creator>Abimbola Adelakun</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-07-24T00:00:00-04:00">July 24, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>African History / Studies, Cultural History / Studies, Humanities, Religious Studies and Theology, Theatre &amp; Performance History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Theme: “Life is War”: Social Militarization and the Culture of Prayers in Africa</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Prayers are a ritual common to all religions, but the intensity of their performance and social application differ from one religion to another. One resonant factor in the rituals of prayer offered in contemporary Africa is how the context of physical insecurity, social instability, and economic precarity have penetrated through and shaped its content and rites. Our responses to the challenges of underdevelopment and weakness of state political apparatuses through the instrumentality of prayer have configured daily life around militarization. Despite the pervasiveness of prayer as a form of warfare against extant reality, this spectacular practice that reverberates through the cultural landscape in Africa and beyond has not received enough scholarly attention. Militarized prayers, aimed at cosmic forces perceived to be militating against social progress, are initiatives toward addressing existential realities. They demonstrate African cosmological insights into the mechanisms of world-ordering and agency of those who want to re-order it. Warfare prayers are thus worth understanding on these terms. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>This conference calls for papers that engage the sort of world Africans build when they employ prayers as a form of warfare. How do these forms of prayers re-order personal, social, and political life? What cultural understanding of the nature of reality drives these prayers? How do these prayers integrate the physical and psychic with the political? What is the nexus between prayer performance, pleasures, and political practices?  This interdisciplinary conference welcomes presentations that engage these questions and many more from scholars, theologians, postgraduate students, and members of faith communities. This study is not limited to any religious traditions. We welcome presentations from across a broad spectrum of faith practices. Please send in abstracts/proposals of not more than 250 words and proposals via email: </span></span></span><a href="mailto:violentprayersconference@gmail.com"><span><span><span>violentprayersconference@gmail.com</span></span></span></a><u><span><span><span>.</span></span></span></u></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Papers are expected from these subthemes but are not limited to:</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ol><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Typologies of prayer practices within and across religious spectrum</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Theoretical conceptions of prayers and social militarization</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Comparative religious perspectives on prayer and social militarization</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Historical study of prayer and social militarization</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Methodological approaches to prayer and social militarization</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Ethical issues in warfare prayer </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Popular culture, prayer, and prayer warfare</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Spaces, places, and prayer as warfare</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Politics, democracy, and notions of power in prayer </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Urban culture and prayer warfare </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Language and poetics of prayer warfare</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Language, literature and creativity in prayer warfare</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Gender issues in prayer warfare</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Technology, medium, and warfare prayers</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Warfare prayers and shaping of social imaginary</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Performance, sacred objects, and rituals of warfare prayers </span></span></span></span></span></span></li></ol><p> </p><p> </p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Date: 24</span><span>th </span><span>– 27</span><span>th </span><span>July, 2023 (Arrival: 24</span><span>th </span><span>July and Opening Ceremony: 25</span><span>th </span><span>July, 2023). </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Venue: The Redeemed Christian Bible College, Redemption Camp, Mowe, Ogun State. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Conference fee: N15,000 (scholars), N5,000 (PG students) and $60 (non-Nigerians) </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Note: This conference has a virtual component for international participants</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span> </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p> </p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:benson.igboin@aaua.edu.ng">benson.igboin@aaua.edu.ng</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 19:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680673038711652</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Esoteric Theology of Philip K. Dick</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/04/03/the-esoteric-theology-of-philip-k-dick</link>
						<dc:creator>mbarros</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, April 4, 2023 - 11:49am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>George Sieg &amp; Michael Barros</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:pkdandtheology@gmail.com">pkdandtheology@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/fan-studies-and-fandom">fan studies and fandom</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/general-announcements">general announcements</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>May 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>Call for Abstracts:</strong> <em>The Esoteric Theology of Philip K. Dick</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Editors:</strong> Dr. George Sieg &amp; Michael Barros</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Philip K. Dick was one of the most influential science fiction authors of the 20th century, and he remains the most adapted.His work has exemplified qualities and features that have become increasingly significant within the science fiction genre, anticipating its exploration of artificial intelligence, alternate and parallel realities, and the problems of identity.  Dick’s work is most popularly known through its adaptation to films such as <em>Blade Runner, Total Recall, A Scanner Darkly, The Adjustment Bureau, </em>and <em>Paycheck</em>, as well as Amazon’s streaming adaptation of <em>The Man in the High Castle</em>, followed by its recent anthology homage to Dick, <em>Philip K. Dick’s Electric Dreams</em>.   His work is pervaded by the uncanny intersection of derealization with the hyper-real, with protagonists and readers embarking on a journey of uncertainty together.</p>
<p>Later in his life, Dick retrospectively viewed his work as expressing spiritual truths. He believed in unconventional concepts like “retrograde time,” he communed with and channeled a deceased Episcopalian Bishop, and he was immensely interested in both the Essenes and the Gnostics. In February and March of 1974, he had his most important spiritual experiences, launched by his encounter with a a delivery girl with an ichthysnecklace. </p>
<p>With a goal of publication on the 50th anniversary of those formative experiences, the editors invite submissions exploring theological, religious, and esoteric themes within the work and life of Philip K. Dick. Some possible topics are (and are certainly not limited to):</p>
<ul>
<li>The relationship between Dick's gnostic vision and his portrayal of religion and spirituality in his works.</li>
<li>The postmodern themes and motifs in Dick's writing and how they relate to his theological perspective.</li>
<li>The ways in which Dick's works engage with questions of epistemology and uncertainty and how this relates to larger theological and philosophical themes.</li>
<li>Dick's use of dystopian and apocalyptic imagery and how this relates to his understanding of human nature and the divine.</li>
<li>The relationship between science fiction and theology in Dick's writing and how he uses the genre to explore religious and spiritual themes.</li>
<li>The role of technology in Dick's works and how it relates to his larger theological and philosophical vision.</li>
<li>The relationship between ethics and theology in Dick's writing and how he uses his works to explore questions of morality and the divine.</li>
<li>The reception of Dick's works within the context of contemporary theology and religious studies and the ways in which his works continue to shape theological and philosophical discourse today.</li>
<li>The impact of Dick’s theology on the sci-fi genre.</li>
<li>Dick’s engagement with the Dead Sea Scrolls.</li>
<li>Dick’s eschatology.</li>
<li>Dick’s Apocalyptic Dualism.</li>
<li>The role of conspiracism in Dick’s work: secularized theology &amp; demonology</li>
<li>Mysticism in Dick’s work.</li>
<li>Augustine &amp; Dick on the concept of time.</li>
</ul>
<p>Interested authors should send chapter abstracts of 300-700 words and a CV to <a href="mailto:pkdandtheology@gmail.com">pkdandtheology@gmail.com</a>.</p>
<p>The call for chapters ends May 15, 2023. Authors will be notified of accepted proposals after June 1st, 2023, with the first drafts of chapters (6,000-8,000 words) being due by November 1st, 2023. Final manuscript is to be delivered to the publisher in January 2024.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 04:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680673038711651</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Saints and Mystics in Legend and Tradition</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/03/26/saints-and-mystics-in-legend-and-tradition</link>
						<dc:creator>Jeremy Harte</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, April 4, 2023 - 10:25am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Folklore Society</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:jrmharte@gmail.com">jrmharte@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/medieval">medieval</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/popular-culture">popular culture</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>August 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Where is the spring that rose where St. Alban’s blood fell? Who cares for Cuddy Ducks? Can we see Enoch and Elijah? When the Virgin fell in labour, was Romani St. Sarah at her side? How did St. Sebastian become a gay icon? Who were the Twin Saints, the Three Pure Ones, the Four Friends and the Five Major Prophets? What goes into a Dumb Cake for St. Agnes’ Eve? Does a wet St. Swithun’s day really foretell forty days of rain? Do girls still appeal to St. Andrew of the fishermen for a good catch in marriage? Can we still hear Old Clem at the hammer and the thunders of St. Barbara? Whether you weave a cross of reeds for Lá Féile Bríde, wear a daff for Dewi Sant, or bear a rose for St. George, come and join our day or we may have to call on St. Jude, patron saint of lost causes.</p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p>A two-day conference on Saints and Mystics in Legend and Tradition will be held on Saturday 2nd (St. Justus of Lyons) and Sunday 3rd (St. Gregory the Great) September 2023 at the Chapter House, St. Albans Cathedral. Anyone can join us – scholars, storytellers, hermits and hagiographers. We invite proposals about any saint, mystic, martyr or prophet. Presentations, which should be 20 minutes long, can take the form of talks, performances, or film. For more information, see <a href="https://folklore-society.com/events">https://folklore-society.com/events</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The conference fee is £35 for speakers, £70 for others attending. If you would like to attend or to present a paper or performance, please contact, by 1st July: Jeremy Harte, Bourne Hall, Spring Street, Ewell, Surrey KT17 1UF. Telephone: 020 8394 1734. Email: <a href="mailto:jrmharte@gmail.com">jrmharte@gmail.com</a></p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 17:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680673038711650</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Australia-India Encounters: Past, Present, Future</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/03/25/australia-india-encounters-past-present-future</link>
						<dc:creator>tanmoy.kundu@midnaporecollege.ac.in</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, April 4, 2023 - 10:26am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>The Centre for Australian Studies, Department of English and Culture Studies,  The University of Burdwan in collaboration with Australian Studies Institute, Australian National University, Canberra</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:cas.buruniv@gmail.com">cas.buruniv@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/ecocriticism-and-environmental-studies">ecocriticism and environmental studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/ethnicity-and-national-identity">ethnicity and national identity</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/international-conferences">international conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/world-literatures-and-indigenous-studies">world literatures and indigenous studies</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>April 20, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p align="center"><strong>Australia-India Encounters: Past, Present, Future</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>3-4 May, 2023</strong></p>
<p align="center"> </p>
<p align="center">Organised by</p>
<p align="center">The Centre for Australian Studies, Department of English and Culture Studies,</p>
<p align="center">The University of Burdwan</p>
<p align="center">in collaboration with</p>
<p align="center">Australian Studies Institute, Australian National University, Canberra</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The history of Australia-India encounters dates back to the first half of the nineteenth century. Even before the 1840s, the presence of the Indians (mainly servants to British families who were given land grants in colonies) in Australia has been traced. Many Indians, later, went to Australia as indentured labourers to work in sugar plantations and on farms. Some of them were ‘hawkers,’ small traders who travelled through different towns of Australia. The nineteenth century also saw a gradual increase in the number of Indian travellers to Australia (such as, Fazulbhoy Vikram, N.L. Doss and T. N. Mukharji), many of whom even documented their encounters with Australian polity, society and culture by writing journals and travelogues.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Australia-India encounters started taking new forms in the 1970s as Australia adopted multicultural policies rejecting ‘The White Australia Policy.’ This resulted in a steady flow of the Indian migrants to Australia fostering new cross-cultural exchanges between the two countries. In Australia, the Government organized events like Utsav Australia or Indian Art Exhibitions (Museum Victoria), while in Kolkata Book Fair, Australia has been projected several times either as “Guest of Honour Country” or the “Focus Country” (2007).</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Australian Government’s intention to establish international links has also contributed significantly to develop and re-shape its politico-economic-cultural relationships with India. India’s shift from its ‘Look East’ policy to ‘Act East’ policy has similarly strengthened India’s relationship with Australia in matters relating to international strategic planning, security, commerce and culture. In fact, India’s ‘Act East Policy’ is in tune with its growing interest in the Asia Pacific region and its ideological position of considering Australia as a part of larger Asia. In the post-pandemic era, both the countries are working towards transforming the Asia Pacific as a politically important region of independent and sovereign states.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>This international conference welcomes scholars from across disciplines to consider upon the past, present and the future of Australia-India encounters to identify new discursive strategies to facilitate a better understanding of each other in terms of history, politics and culture.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The conference will address, but not strictly limit itself to, the following issues:</p>
<p> </p>
<ul>
<li>Re-writing History</li>
<li>Race and Identity</li>
<li>Federalism</li>
<li>Terrorism and Conflict Resolution</li>
<li>International Relations</li>
<li>Economic Paradigms in Bilateral Relations</li>
<li>Linkages of Sports and Culture</li>
<li>Tourism and Cultural Exchange</li>
<li>Colonial/Postcolonial/ Contemporary Writings</li>
<li>Literature and Socio-cultural Activism</li>
<li>Indigenous Australian Literature</li>
<li>Literature and Films</li>
<li>Climate Change and Climate Fiction</li>
<li>Indian Diasporic Literature of Australia</li>
<li>Environment and Security</li>
<li>Judicial Activism </li>
<li>Australian Studies: Research and Methodology</li>
<li>Teaching Australia in India</li>
<li>Teaching India in Australia</li>
</ul>
<p> Abstracts (not exceeding 300 words) may be emailed to <a href="mailto:cas.buruniv@gmail.com">cas.buruniv@gmail.com</a></p>
<p> Registration Fees:    2000 INR (National)</p>
<p>                               150 AUD (International)</p>
<p>Online presentation facility will be available only for the international participants. Though it may not be possible to arrange accommodation, the conference team may provide assistance to the national participants, if contacted beforehand.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 16:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680673038711649</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ May 15, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Merleau-Ponty and Embodiment: Between the Cognitive, Aesthetic, and Socio-Political</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/109901</link>
						<description><p><strong>Merleau-Ponty and Embodiment: Between the Cognitive, Aesthetic, and Socio-Political</strong></p>
<p>47th Annual Meeting of the International Merleau-Ponty Circle</p>
<p>In-person and virtual (hybrid)</p>
<p>4-6 December 2023</p>
<p>Deakin University, Melbourne (Narrm), Australia </p>
<p><em>“Le corps est notre moyen général d’avoir un monde</em>. / <em>The body is our general means of having a world.”</em></p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p>Merleau-Ponty's seminal work on embodiment has been of enduring interest and influence in a wide range of fields. It has, for example, played a significant role in research on embodied cognition and enactivism, subjectivity and intersubjectivity, affectivity, movement, art, place, and more. Although sometimes criticised for providing an account of embodiment that is too general, Merleau-Ponty’s philosophical foregrounding of embodiment has also facilitated critical phenomenological studies attending to the specificities of how particular bodies inhabit social and political environments, through considerations of race, gender, disability, ageing, and illness. This year’s meeting of the IMPC seeks to bring together these rich and varied strands of enquiry, in order to think with, against, and beyond Merleau-Ponty’s own contributions on the lived body. </p>
<p>Only its third time outside North America, this year’s meeting will take place in Melbourne (Narrm), Australia, on the traditional and unceded lands of the Kulin Nation. The conference is being directed by Helen Ngo and Jack Reynolds, with support from Andrew Inkpin and others. Keynote and plenary speakers will be announced shortly. The conference will be held at the centrally located and accessible Deakin Downtown campus, and recommended accommodation options will be provided nearer the date. </p>
<p><strong>Full paper submissions</strong> of no more than 3,500 words should be prepared for anonymous review and sent to <em>both</em> the directors at helen.ngo@deakin.edu.au and jack.reynolds@deakin.edu.au with the subject heading "IMPC submission" <strong>by May 15, 2023</strong>. As is custom, submissions on any aspect of Merleau-Ponty’s work, in addition to the conference theme, are also welcome.</p>
<p>This year’s event will include a thematic stream on <em>Race, place, and bodies</em> curated by Helen Ngo for a research project funded by the Australian Research Council (DE220100329). A small number of bursaries will be available for students and unwaged early career researchers presenting in-person in this stream. Participants wishing to be considered for this are asked to indicate so on the cover letter of your submission. </p>
<p>The conference features the M. C. Dillon prize and lecture for the best graduate student paper submission (https://www.merleauponty.org/m-c-dillon-memorial/). To be considered for this prize, please indicate so on the cover letter of your submission. This year’s conference will also inaugurate a second graduate student prize, the Morstyn prize, which recognises our late colleague, from Sydney, Australia, Ron Morstyn, who contributed to and attended the IMPC over many years, with special interests in psychology and psychiatry. Details for consideration for this prize will be announced between now and the submission deadline.  </p>
<p>Finally, as this conference will be held as a hybrid event, please indicate whether, upon acceptance, you plan to attend in-person or virtually. In order to host the conference at a physical location, a certain percentage of talks will need to be presented in person, and this will be factored in during the anonymous review process. If you plan to attend virtually because doing so physically presents insurmountable accessibility issues (of whatever sort, including economic ones), you are welcome (but not required) to include that information. You are also welcome to include any anticipated accessibility needs, which will greatly assist in planning.</p>
<p>Helen Ngo and Jack Reynolds, on behalf of International Merleau-Ponty Circle.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 05:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680586628555805</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ December 4, 2023 -  December 6, 2023] Conference or similar: Merleau-Ponty and Embodiment: Between the Cognitive, Aesthetic, and Socio-Political</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/109897</link>
						<description>Venue: Deakin Downtown<br/><br/><p>47TH ANNUAL CONFERENCE OF THE INTERNATIONAL MERLEAU-PONTY CIRCLE</p>
<p>Dec 4th – Dec 6th 2023 | Deakin University, Melbourne (Narrm), Australia | In-person and virtual (hybrid)</p>
<p><em>“Le corps est notre moyen général d’avoir un monde</em>. / <em>The body is our general means of having a world.”</em></p>
<p>Merleau-Ponty’s seminal work on embodiment has been of enduring interest and influence in a wide range of fields. It has, for example, played a significant role in research on embodied cognition and enactivism, subjectivity and intersubjectivity, affectivity, movement, art, place, and more. Although sometimes criticized for providing an account of embodiment that is too general, Merleau-Ponty’s philosophical foregrounding of embodiment has also facilitated critical phenomenological studies attending to the specificities of how particular bodies inhabit social and political environments, through considerations of race, gender, disability, ageing, and illness. This year’s meeting of the IMPC seeks to bring together these rich and varied strands of enquiry, in order to think with, against, and beyond Merleau-Ponty’s own contributions on the lived body.</p>
<p>Only its third time outside North America, this year’s meeting of IMPC will take place in Melbourne (Narrm), Australia, on the traditional and unceded lands of the Kulin Nation.</p>
<p>The conference is being directed by Helen Ngo and Jack Reynolds.</p>
<p>Keynote and plenary speakers will be announced shortly. The conference will be held at the centrally located and accessible Deakin Downtown campus, and recommended accommodation options will be provided nearer the date. Registration will be required; this page will be updated when registration deadlines have been set.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 05:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680586628555804</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Methodist Studies Seminar (in person and online)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12640999/methodist-studies-seminar-person-and-online</link>
						<dc:creator>Geordan Hammond</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-05-12T00:00:00-04:00">May 12, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Methodist Studies Seminars provide an opportunity for established and emerging scholars of Methodist Studies to present the findings of their research. We conceive of Methodist Studies broadly and aim to provide opportunities for students of history, theology, literature, art, material culture and other fields related to Methodism.</p><p>The next seminar will be hosted by the Manchester Wesley Research Centre and Cliff College at Nazarene Theological College in Manchester and online on Friday 12 May 2023. There is no cost to attend, but registration is required. The registration link and seminar schedule can be found at: <a href="https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/methodist-studies-seminars" rel="nofollow">https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/methodist-studies-seminars</a>. </p><p>The conference will be on Friday 12 May from 10:00am to 4pm BST</p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Nazarene Theological College</p><p>Dene Road, Didsbury</p><p>Manchester M20 2GU</p><p>UK</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ghammond@nazarene.ac.uk">ghammond@nazarene.ac.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/methodist-studies-seminars" target="_blank">https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/methodist-studies-seminars</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 17:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680154627898615</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CfP: Baltic Orthodoxy: People, Practices, Places</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12639618/cfp-baltic-orthodoxy-people-practices-places</link>
						<dc:creator>James White</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Area Studies, Humanities, Religious Studies and Theology, Russian or Soviet History / Studies, Eastern Europe History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span>From the nineteenth century, Orthodox practices, identities, and institutions in the Baltic region have continually been rewoven to form a truly intriguing tapestry reflecting the particular perspectives and interests of a dazzling number of weavers. Initially the religion of Russian settlers, Orthodoxy attracted indigenous lower-class adherents during complex social manoeuvring between local elites and the imperial authorities. In the process, both rural and urban locales were transformed by the presence of Orthodox clergy, churches, charities, schools, and sacred narratives, some imposed from above, others created by agents on the ground. Following the devastation unleashed by the First World War and revolution, Baltic Orthodox churches and believers faced not only the formidable task of creating new institutions embodying both late imperial reform movements and new democratic trends, but also negotiating their position as minorities within avowedly secular republics. Following yet another round of destructive conflict in the Second World War, Orthodoxy in parts of the Baltic region had to confront yet another challenge, that of the militantly atheistic Soviet state, which shuttered churches, persecuted clergy and believers, and imposed strict regulations on religious activities. Today, Orthodoxy and its adherents continue to play an important role in the multicultural landscape of the modern Baltic region, adapting their faith and practices to a world thoroughly changed by digital revolution. </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Throughout this period, the Baltic region has been at the avant-garde of the changes associated with modernity. The population enjoyed levels of literacy that were impressively high compared to many countries of the time. Its transport and communication systems rapidly developed, as did the sciences, arts, and culture</span></span>: <span><span>Orthodoxy in the Baltic region has interacted with and reflected these developments. At the same time, Orthodoxy in the Baltic region was diverse, including representatives not only from ‘official Orthodoxy', but also varied Old Believer groups. </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>The study of Orthodoxy in the Baltic region has typically focused on the religion’s place within overarching political narratives – within imperial russification, as a minority faith in secular states, or as a target of Soviet persecution. Such a focus is certainly justified, but it has often led to the neglect of the everyday religious experiences of Orthodox parishioners, communities, and institutions within this multiconfessional, multiethnic, and multilinguistic region in the throes of modernization. Equally, it has led to a neglect of the agency of a variety of local groups and peoples, as such actors tend to be viewed as the recipients of projects and policies rather than active participants in them. </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Taking as its starting point a microhistorical perspective/Geertzian deep description, this proposed volume will decentralise narratives of Orthodoxy in the Baltic region and restore agency to local Orthodox actors, demonstrating how believers and communities, although not in isolation, have experienced and transformed Orthodoxy in the context of a variety of political regimes (empire, republic, Soviet federal unit, post-Soviet state) and in a period marked by modernization. <b>Contributing authors representing a variety of academic disciplines and national backgrounds will be asked to provide micro examinations of Orthodoxy in the Baltic region (Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, and Finland), choosing as their case studies individual people, communities, and practices from the nineteenth century to the present day</b>. </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>In presenting this research, this book will, for the first time in English, demonstrate the dizzying array of Orthodox experiences from a bottom-up perspective, understanding Orthodox identities as, at least in part, generated not only by central institutions but also by believers, clergymen, and communities. Orthodoxy in this volume will not be understood within a vacuum: the authors will be expected to demonstrate how individuals, communities, and practices influenced and were influenced by broader social, cultural, political, and economic trends, and how Orthodoxy affected and was affected by actors and institutions from other groups. Finally, the volume will also stress the fluid and penetrable nature of both state borders and various imagined communities, emphasising links not only between the Orthodox communities of four Baltic countries, but also connections with groups, people, and institutions in other parts of the globe. These links had and continue to have transformative potential, changing perspectives, attitudes, and the allocation of resources. </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>The contributions should consider the following questions:</span></span></b></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span>How have Baltic Orthodox actors and institutions (individuals, parish communities, schools, ecclesiastical institutions, etc.) developed (and continue to develop) in the context of religious and ethnic diversity? </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>How did/do aspects of modernity affect Orthodox communities and identities?</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>What was/is the impact of central policy (for instance, nationalizing imperial practices or Soviet anti-religious policy) on Orthodox individual and collective identities?</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>What role did/does women and gender issues play in Orthodox communities?  </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>What role has/does monasticism play in the image, identity, and attractiveness of Orthodoxy in the region?</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>How did/do connections with communities (Orthodox or otherwise) across the world transform Baltic Orthodox identities and practices?   </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>How did/do local environmental conditions affect the development of Baltic Orthodox communities? </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>How did/do Orthodox practices of conciliarity, such as the rituals and practices of self-government, develop on the level of the parish, deanery, and diocese? What conflicts did/do they provoke? </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>How did Orthodox theology change and develop in the Baltic context? How did such thought influence Baltic Orthodox praxis? </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>How did music and musical practices reflect developments in Baltic Orthodoxy?</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>In what distinctive ways did Old Believer communities, practices, and institutions develop from the nineteenth to the twenty-first centuries? How did Old Belief’s relationship with ‘official Orthodoxy’ change over this period? </span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>These questions could be studied through the following lenses: </span></span></b></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span>Biographical approaches to individuals, be they clergy or laity, Orthodox or connected with Orthodoxy; </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Focusing on an individual parish or group of parishes from a historical or anthropological/sociological perspective; </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Historical or sociological case studies examining religious institutions, including schools, parish institutions, missions, monasteries, archives, bureaucratic organs, and jurisdictions; </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Historical, ethnographic/anthropological, theological, and musicological approaches to the study of religious practices, including singing, pilgrimage, charity, cross processions, naming practices, etc. </span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span><span>This book is expected to appeal to specialists in the history and politics of states in the Baltic region, specialists in the history and contemporaneity of European religions, specialists in the lives of minority groups, interested members of the general public, and university students. </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>English-language editorial assistance will be provided to non-native speakers. </span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>Timetable for contributors</span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>1 June 2023 – Deadline for proposals (title, author details, abstracts of no more than 500 words, keywords)</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>1 July 2023 – Editorial decisions on contributors and contributions</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>30 January 2024 – Submission of draft articles</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Spring 2024 – Workshop for contributors to be held at the University of Tartu</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>1 April 2024 – Requests for revisions</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>1 September 2024 – Submission of second drafts</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>1 January 2025 – Submission of the book to the press</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>Please submit your proposal to the editors at </span></span></b><a href="mailto:irina.paert@ut.ee"><b><span><span>irina.paert@ut.ee</span></span></b></a><b><span><span>, </span></span></b><a href="mailto:liina.eek@ut.ee"><b><span><span>liina.eek@ut.ee</span></span></b></a><b><span><span>, and </span></span></b><a href="https:///C:/Users/James/Downloads/james.matthew.white@ut.ee"><b><span><span>james.matthew.white@ut.ee</span></span></b></a></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>Irina Paert (general)</span></span></b><i> </i><span><span>is an associate professor at the School of Theology and Religious Studies, University of Tartu. She has two books: <i>Old Believers, Religious Dissent and Gender in Russia, 1760-1850</i> (Manchester, 2003) and <i>Spiritual Elders: Charisma, Tradition and Orthodoxy in Imperial Russia</i> (DeKalb, 2010). She edited the collective monograph (in Russian) <i>Orthodoxy in the Baltic: Religion, Politics, Education 1840-1930 </i>(Tartu, 2018). She is PI in the research project “Orthodoxy as Solidarity: Conciliar and Popular Orthodoxy in Estonia”, funded by the Estonian Research Council. Email address: <a href="mailto:irina.paert@ut.ee">irina.paert@ut.ee</a>. </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>Liina Eek (sociology) </span></span></b><span><span>is a programme manager in Estonian Research Council and part-time researcher at the University of Tartu, School of Theology and Religious Studies, where she also defended her PhD in 2017 (“Catechesis and Beliefs among Contemporary Estonian-Speaking Orthodox”). Her research focus is contemporary Estonian-speaking Orthodox, their beliefs and views on Orthodoxy and Orthodox theology. She has edited a collection of articles about Orthodoxy in Estonia, <i>Mitut usku Eesti IV. Õigeusu eri</i>. Email address: <a href="mailto:liina.eek@ut.ee">liina.eek@ut.ee</a></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>James M. White (history)</span></span></b><i> </i><span><span>is a research fellow in church history at the University of Tartu. He published his first book,<i> Unity in Faith? Edinoverie, Russian Orthodoxy, and Old Belief, 1800-1918</i>, with Indiana University Press in 2020. His article "Russian Orthodox Monasticism in Riga Diocese, 1881-1917" won the Canadian Association of Slavists Article of the Year Award in 2020. He is the creator and runner of <a href="https:///C:/Users/James/Downloads/www.balticorthodoxy.com">www.balticorthodoxy.com</a>. Contact email address: <a href="mailto:james.matthew.white@ut.ee">james.matthew.white@ut.ee</a></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:james.matthew.white@ut.ee">james.matthew.white@ut.ee</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 17:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680154627898614</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Opportunities Digest – March 29, 2023</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-opportunities-digest-march-29-2023/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find 6 new job opportunities, 2 fellowships, 1 training, 3 awards, 3 grants, 9 Call for Papers, and 9 upcoming conferences/speakers.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 33!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Head of School: School of Humanities and Languages (Full-time,  5 yr. appointment)</h4>



<p>University of New South Wales, Australia</p>



<p>Deadline: April 11, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://external-careers.jobs.unsw.edu.au/cw/en/job/514826/head-of-school-school-of-humanities-and-languages">https://external-careers.jobs.unsw.edu.au/cw/en/job/514826/head-of-school-school-of-humanities-and-languages</a></p>



<h4>Teaching Specialist (Experiential Learning)</h4>



<p>University of Melbourne, Australia (Full-time)</p>



<p>Deadline: April 4, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=8f52a2c49f&amp;e=ea2dc4a949">https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=8f52a2c49f&amp;e=ea2dc4a949</a></p>



<h4>Union Organizer</h4>



<p>Melbourne, Australia</p>



<p>Deadline: April 4, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=57fcd63efc&amp;e=ea2dc4a949">https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=57fcd63efc&amp;e=ea2dc4a949</a></p>



<h4>University Assistant (Prae-doc) (1.5-year commitment, can be extended to 3 years)</h4>



<p>University of Vienna, Austria</p>



<p>Deadline: April 9, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://vdtr.univie.ac.at/en/admission/open-positions/">https://vdtr.univie.ac.at/en/admission/open-positions/</a></p>



<h4>Postdoctoral Research Associate (1-year term, possibility of renewal)</h4>



<p>Princeton University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: April 10, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://csr.princeton.edu/news/2023/apply-postdoc">https://csr.princeton.edu/news/2023/apply-postdoc</a></p>



<h4>Teaching Associate in Islamic Studies (Fixed term, part-time)</h4>



<p>University of Nottingham, UK</p>



<p>Deadline: April 28, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://jobs.nottingham.ac.uk/vacancy.aspx?ref=ARTS103323&amp;fbclid=IwAR18Cqj_AyOSJ2SLKhSkKV6F98RhSNpzbMUe2NGAd05QRkBwngUIRyjoJwU">https://jobs.nottingham.ac.uk/vacancy.aspx?ref=ARTS103323&amp;fbclid=IwAR18Cqj_AyOSJ2SLKhSkKV6F98RhSNpzbMUe2NGAd05QRkBwngUIRyjoJwU</a></p>



<p></p>



<h4>AAR/SBL Job Forum</h4>



<p><a href="https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search">https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search</a></p>



<h2>Fellowships:</h2>



<h4>Feinstein Center for American Jewish History</h4>



<p>Temple University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: March 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12553828/summer-fellowship-feinstein-center-american-jewish-history">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12553828/summer-fellowship-feinstein-center-american-jewish-history</a></p>



<h4>E. H Boundy Ph.D. Fellowship</h4>



<p>University of Exeter, UK</p>



<p>Deadline: June 5<sup>th</sup>, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.jobs.ac.uk/job/CYF535/eh-boundy-phd-studentship-theology-and-religion">https://www.jobs.ac.uk/job/CYF535/eh-boundy-phd-studentship-theology-and-religion</a></p>



<h2>Trainings:</h2>



<h4>Sacred Writes Summer Training Cohort (Online)</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 17, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/8Db5pa1taL">https://t.co/8Db5pa1taL</a></p>



<h2>Grants:</h2>



<h4>Outstanding Applied Research Award</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://rraweb.us10.list-manage.com/track/click?u=55bb1644f88e9457d182915ac&amp;id=a20d9da844&amp;e=c7b3861607">https://rraweb.us10.list-manage.com/track/click?u=55bb1644f88e9457d182915ac&amp;id=a20d9da844&amp;e=c7b3861607</a></p>



<h4>Constant H. Jacquet Research Awards</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://rraweb.us10.list-manage.com/track/click?u=55bb1644f88e9457d182915ac&amp;id=cbd632370a&amp;e=c7b3861607">https://rraweb.us10.list-manage.com/track/click?u=55bb1644f88e9457d182915ac&amp;id=cbd632370a&amp;e=c7b3861607</a></p>



<h4>RRA/SSSR Annual Meeting Travel</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://rraweb.us10.list-manage.com/track/click?u=55bb1644f88e9457d182915ac&amp;id=8c7664e1af&amp;e=c7b3861607">https://rraweb.us10.list-manage.com/track/click?u=55bb1644f88e9457d182915ac&amp;id=8c7664e1af&amp;e=c7b3861607</a></p>



<h2>Awards:</h2>



<h4>Excellence in the Study of Religion</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 12, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/ByvUjmGQ5r">https://t.co/ByvUjmGQ5r</a></p>



<h4>Best First Book in the History of Religions</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 12, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/ByvUjmGQ5r">https://t.co/ByvUjmGQ5r</a></p>



<h4>Religion and the Arts Book Award</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 12, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/ByvUjmGQ5r">https://t.co/ByvUjmGQ5r</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>The Afterlife in Popular Culture: <em>The Ausralasian Journal of Popular Culture</em></h4>



<p>Deadline: October 13, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12556769/cfp-afterlife-popular-culture-special-issue-australasian">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12556769/cfp-afterlife-popular-culture-special-issue-australasian</a></p>



<h4>Emerging Religious Geography of Australia</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="mailto:miriamdb@blanquerna.url.edu">miriamdb@blanquerna.url.edu</a></p>



<h4>Situating Religious Cognition</h4>



<p>Deadline: October 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/journal/religions/special_issues/7Q488424D1">https://www.mdpi.com/journal/religions/special_issues/7Q488424D1</a></p>



<h4>Society for Reformation Research: “Intercultural Reformations”</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 17, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12604235/society-reformation-research-intercultural-reformations">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12604235/society-reformation-research-intercultural-reformations</a></p>



<h4>Open Success!? Research and Publishing in Religion, Film, and Media</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://open-success.uni-graz.at/de/welcome/">https://open-success.uni-graz.at/de/welcome/</a></p>



<h4>Religion in Motion: Between Borders and Belonging</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/CfP-Religion-in-motion-NGG-conference-1.pdf</p>



<h4>New Moderate Narratives in Times of Extremism</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/109329">https://philevents.org/event/show/109329</a></p>



<h4>International Conference on the Middle Ages: Religion in Medieval Urban Europe</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12535058/international-conference-middle-ages-2023-religions-medieval">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12535058/international-conference-middle-ages-2023-religions-medieval</a></p>



<h4>Environmental Endings and Religious Futures</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 19, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://basr.ac.uk/2023/03/03/basr-annual-conference-2023-2/">BASR Annual Conference 2023</a></p>



<h2>Conferences:</h2>



<h4>Caught in the Current: British and Canadian Evangelicals in an Age of Self-Spirituality</h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>Date: April 18, 2023, 3 pm EST</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSc69xZ740Njz1g3y1_K4GljB3GMdfAHeHRpCqVX458Zi0j0cQ/viewform">“Caught in the Current: British and Canadian Evangelicals in an Age of Self-Spirituality” CSSR/CCSR Webinar Registration – Inscription pour le webinaire de la SCÉR/CCSR (google.com)</a></p>



<h4>Beyond the Black/White binary: Research on Race &amp; Congregations</h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>Date: April 13, 2023, 3 pm EST</p>



<h4>Shaping the Anthropos: Cosmologies, Mythologies, and Logics of Subjecthood</h4>



<p>Zoom or Columbia University USA</p>



<p>Date: April 7, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/0Rhvs3vfzl">https://t.co/0Rhvs3vfzl</a></p>



<h4>Colloquium on “Interreligious Interactions in South Asia”</h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>Date: April 3-12 10-11: EST</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Program_Interreligious-Interactions-in-South-Asia-1.pdf">https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Program_Interreligious-Interactions-in-South-Asia-1.pdf</a></p>



<h4>Learning Islam and Craft: Muslim Artisans’ Embodied &amp; Textual Knowledge in Colonial India</h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>Date: April 11, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/sKRb7buMtG">https://t.co/sKRb7buMtG</a></p>



<h4>Postsecular Studies, Literature, and Care</h4>



<p>University of Granada, Spain</p>



<p>Date: May 25-26, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/109513">https://philevents.org/event/show/109513</a></p>



<h4>Open Success!? Research and Publishing in Religion, Film, and Media</h4>



<p>University of Graz, Austria</p>



<p>Date: September 14-15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://open-success.uni-graz.at/de/welcome/">https://open-success.uni-graz.at/de/welcome/</a></p>



<h4>Unsettling Normality</h4>



<p>University Heidelberg, Germany</p>



<p>Deadline: September 20-22, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/109141">https://philevents.org/event/show/109141</a></p>



<h4>2023 Silber-Obrecht Lecture in Interreligious and Interfaith Studies with Francis X. Clooney, S.J.</h4>



<p>Loyola University Maryland, USA</p>



<p>Date: April 25-26, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12553960/2023-silber-obrecht-lecture-interreligious-and-interfaith">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12553960/2023-silber-obrecht-lecture-interreligious-and-interfaith</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680154627898613</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
