<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 03:32:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 03:32:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>New Issue of The Arrow Journal: Between Amitabha and Tubman: Black Buddhist Thought</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11208674/new-issue-arrow-journal-between-amitabha-and-tubman-black</link>
						<dc:creator>Shante Paradigm Smalls</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Journal</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-05T00:00:00-04:00">October 5, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>African American History / Studies, African History / Studies, Black History / Studies, Asian History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><h2>Issue Contents</h2><p><a href="https://arrow-journal.org/towards-the-impossible-possibility-of-black-buddhist-liberation/" rel="nofollow"><strong>Journal Editor’s Introduction: Towards the Impossible Possibility of Black Buddhist Liberation</strong></a><br/>shah noor hussein, Managing Editor</p><p><a href="https://arrow-journal.org/making-black-buddhist-writing-on-an-apocalyptic-earth/" rel="nofollow"><strong>Guest Editor’s Introduction: Making Black Buddhist Writing on an Apocalyptic Earth</strong></a><br/>Shanté Paradigm Smalls</p><p><strong>Roundtable: Black-led and BIPOC Sanghas</strong><br/>Shanté Paradigm Smalls in conversation with Zenju Earthlyn Manuel, Pamela Ayo Yetunde, Vimalasara Mason-John, Claudelle R. Glasgow, Sheryl Petty, Aishah Shahidah Simmons, and Laurie Amodeo</p><p><strong>Honoring Ancestors in Black Buddhist Practice: Rituals of Devotion and Resilience</strong><br/>Rima Vesely-Flad<br/><em>This article examines how Black Buddhists have embraced ancestral practices as they elaborate dharma teachings in convert Buddhist communities. Such practices include storytelling, devotional bowing, drumming, dancing, and chanting, as well as honoring African-derived images and ancestors on Buddhist altars. This article emphasizes the importance of honoring ancestors and the land within different lineages, as well as practices for incorporating indigenous rituals into Buddhist practices. For indigenous-oriented Buddhist practitioners, the history of ancestors carries meaning for themselves, their family members, and their broader community. Furthermore, the courage, determination, and perseverance embodied by ancestors is mirrored in the resilience of the land to withstand natural forces. Even when African Americans acknowledge their complex relationship with the land of the United States—land they were violently made to work as enslaved peoples to garner profits for white slaveowners—they acknowledge the importance of feeling located on land and the presence of First Nation peoples who populated the land prior to colonization. The ability to see the land as sacred, beyond the history of European colonialism, has been incorporated into numerous African-American healing initiatives.</em></p><p><strong>For Grandma, Pain as a Teacher</strong><br/>Chris Lang</p><p><strong>Of Color-Confrontation and Consumption: Black and Buddhist Insights into Racism</strong><br/>David Salisbury Brown Mitchell<br/><em>Functional racism is viewed as the consumptive force of White supremacy which counteracts the persistent fear of being annihilated by the Other. Manifestations of that fear, as well as ancient and modern attempts to identify and ameliorate it are considered. We begin by considering the potential roots of racism through Welsing’s Cress Theory of Color-Confrontation and Racism, then discuss Woodard’s treatment of consumption and parasitism during chattel slavery as well as the hungry ghost, or preta, in Buddhist thought and its unending appetite. Last, we consider modern and ancient means of recognizing and allaying racism-as-fear-of-death primarily through the work of Shulman on mindfulness and impermanence, Menakem on the “soul nerve,” and ancient Kemetic philosophy on Ma’at and the Ausarian drama. <strong>Keywords:</strong> functional racism, color-confrontation theory, consumption, hungry ghost, Kemet, death anxiety</em></p><p><strong>“Buddhish” Not Buddhist: Womanist Reflections on My Journey Towards Buddhism</strong><br/>Arisika Razak<br/><em>Alice Walker’s womanist definition celebrates the embodied spiritual culture, diverse sexualities, and leadership abilities of Black women. Several of these traits are found in the self-identified Black female preachers and freedom fighters of the 19th century. While there are numerous varieties of Buddhism, the Western, Theravada, meditation-based convert Buddhism brought back to the USA by Euro-American converts in the 1960’s has emphasized intellectual studies and silent meditation. These methodologies can be seen as oppositional to West African Diasporic cultural norms which privilege voice, movement, and physical embodiment, as well as women’s authority in the outer world. This essay explores some of the ways in which contemporary Black Buddhist teachers have begun to integrate African Diasporic norms into their Buddhist teachings. It also chronicles some of the struggles, connections and contradictions that I found as I tried to integrate my womanist self into my Buddhist practice</em></p><p><strong>Africana Yogi Personae: Black Women Yoga Practitioners’ Aesthetic Negotiations in Dress</strong><br/>Sha’mira Covington &amp; Carolyn Medine<br/><em>Western conceptions of the typical yoga practitioner envision her as a skinny, white, and often upper-class woman. If one searches for images of “yoga” or attempts to purchase yoga clothing online, visual representations overwhelmingly feature thin, able-bodied white women in acrobatic poses. These images perpetuate dominant Eurocentric standards of beauty which stem from colonization and white supremacy. This study aims to illuminate the voices of Black women yoga practitioners in the southern U.S. and investigate their aesthetic negotiations in dress. Using participant observation, qualitative interviews and autoethnographic methods, the first author inquires into the yoga and dress practices of five contemporary Black women yoga practitioners, as well as her own, to explore some of the aesthetic negotiations of dress for marginalized bodies in yoga spaces. The study examines the linkages between dress practices, acculturation strategies, and cultural identity by drawing on decolonization theory to shift marginalized voices to the center, the aesthetics of dress to highlight the role of dress in the creation and assertion of Black identity, and womanism to center the experiences, needs and thoughts of Black women. <strong>Keywords:</strong> Black women, yoga, decolonization, womanism, dress, embodiment</em></p><p><strong>Remember black run ‘cross my hips</strong><br/>Raquel Baker</p><p><strong>Transcending Internalized Racism with the Perfection of Resolve, Generosity, and Wisdom</strong><br/>Kamilah Majied<br/><em>Internalized racism can combine with natural human tendencies towards greed, envy and jealousy to limit the intrapersonal and interpersonal freedom of Black people. This short essay discusses practicing resolve and generosity to cultivate wisdom as a means by which Black people can experience abundance and absolute freedom. <strong>Keywords: </strong>internalized racism, greed, resolve, generosity, wisdom, freedom</em></p><p><strong>The Karma of Slavery: A Rumination</strong><br/>Tracy Watson<br/><em>American slavery is easily characterized as the most horrific act of inhumanity committed in this country’s history, second only to the attempted genocide of Native American identity and peoples. My family contains both histories. And I have struggled to humanistically confront the legacy of racialized violence bequeathed to my people. After more than 30 years of practicing Nichiren Buddhism, I began an exploration of my feelings on the subject, hoping to find answers to questions that have plagued me for most of my practice. The following essay is a chronicle of my attempt to confront my questions about the “karma of slavery” (and the ongoing legacy of it) and my efforts to transform the effect of that karma in my life, based on Nichiren Buddhism. I begin my essay with a brief introduction to the origins of my Buddhist practice. I then introduce two principles that are essential to Buddhism: the concepts of “fundamental darkness” (and how it relates to my life in particular) and “fundamental enlightenment” or universal “Buddhahood”. To expound the concept of fundamental enlightenment or Buddhahood, I explicate what is meant in Nichiren Buddhism by the term “Buddha” and the Buddha vow.</em></p><p><strong>ASÉ / Vital Energy</strong><br/>shah noor hussein</p><hr/><p>Artwork by Star Barker, Cheryl Derricotte, and authors</p><hr/><p><em>Note: A correction was made to the issue file on October 5, 2022. If you downloaded the issue before that time, please download the current version.</em></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><span><span><span><span>Dr. Shanté Paradigm Smalls (copy/paste to include my name’s diacritic)<br/><b>They, Them, Theirs</b></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Associate Professor, Department of English; Faculty in Critical Race &amp; Ethnic Studies</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Founding Co-Director, <a href="http://www.stjohns.edu/LGBTQ" rel="nofollow"><span>LGBTQ+ Center at St. John’s University</span></a></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>St. John’s University</span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:smallss@stjohns.edu">smallss@stjohns.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://arrow-journal.org/between-amitabha-and-tubman-black-buddhist-thought/" target="_blank">https://arrow-journal.org/between-amitabha-and-tubman-black-buddhist-thought/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 19:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1665466629069926</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>“Heretical Kabbalahs,” Secular Sublimations, and &quot;Modernist Mysticisms,&quot; a seminar sponsored by the ICLA Research Committee, Religion, Ethics, and Literature</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11195098/%E2%80%9Cheretical-kabbalahs%E2%80%9D-secular-sublimations-and-modernist</link>
						<dc:creator>Kitty Millet</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-30T00:00:00-04:00">October 30, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Illinois</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Cultural History / Studies, Humanities, Jewish History / Studies, Literature, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p> </p><p><span>“Heretical Kabbalahs,” Secular Sublimations, and "Modernist Mysticisms," a seminar sponsored by the ICLA Research Committee, Religion, Ethics, and Literature is a proposed seminar for the ACLA conference in Chicago in 2023</span></p><div><ul><li><a href="https://www.acla.org/node/add/paper?destination=/%E2%80%9Cheretical-kabbalahs%E2%80%9D-secular-sublimations-and-modernist-mysticisms-seminar-sponsored-icla-research&amp;seminar=37902" rel="nofollow">Submit a paper for this seminar.</a></li></ul><div><p><span>Organizer: </span><span>Kitty Millet</span></p><a href="mailto:kmillet1@sfsu.edu">Contact the Seminar Organizers</a></div><p><span>This seminar explores literature through the lens of “heretical kabbalah,”  secular sublimation, and  “modernist mysticism” projects during the nineteenth-, twentieth-, and twenty-first-centuries. Participants are free to analyze any one of these projects in the context of literature and its philosophical underpinnings. We invite papers that look comparatively at narrative traditions globally. We are especially interested in analyses that read "against the grain," that trouble the interpretations of texts within a variety of canons, that explore the suture points of translation, in relation to sacred and profane.</span></p><div><div><div><br/> </div></div></div></div></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Kitty Millet</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:kmillet1@sfsu.edu">kmillet1@sfsu.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.acla.org/%E2%80%9Cheretical-kabbalahs%E2%80%9D-secular-sublimations-and-modernist-mysticisms-seminar-sponsored-icla-research" target="_blank">https://www.acla.org/%E2%80%9Cheretical-kabbalahs%E2%80%9D-secular-sublimations-and-modernist-mysticisms-seminar-sponsor…</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 19:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1665466629069925</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Decolonizing Religion : Indian and Canadian Sci-fi literature</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/10/07/decolonizing-religion-indian-and-canadian-sci-fi-literature</link>
						<dc:creator>aparananda</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Monday, October 10, 2022 - 1:10pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>University of California, Berkeley</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:aparananda@berkeley.edu">aparananda@berkeley.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/ethnicity-and-national-identity">ethnicity and national identity</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/postcolonial">postcolonial</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/science-and-culture">science and culture</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/world-literatures-and-indigenous-studies">world literatures and indigenous studies</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>January 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p align="center"><strong>CALL FOR PAPERS</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Under the aegis of transnationalism and purposefully looking for interconnectedness and exchange of ideas, we are inviting contributions for a forthcoming book focusing on Sci-Fi literature from India and Canada and their renditions of religious themes.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Scholars working on or interested in Canadian and/or Indian Sci-Fi literature are invited to consider the topic of religion from a variety of perspectives. The book will ask and (hopefully) answer questions related to the status of religion in Sci-Fi literature from a postcolonial angle.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>In the words of Jessica Langer, “[t]he figure of the alien comes to signify all kinds of otherness, and the image of the far-away land, whether the undiscovered country or the imperial seat, comes to signify all kinds of diaspora and movement, in all directions.” (Langer, 2011: 4)</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Therefore, we are inviting contributions which could also make the transition from the real historic past of India and Canada to the fictional worlds depicted by Sci-Fi authors from the respective countries. A complete disconnection of reality and fiction is also a topic of interest for the present book.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>As former British colonies, India and Canada have a shared history of stifling religious diversity in colonized territories by the colonizers and afterwards consolidating on diversity of faiths, especially after Canada and India declared their independence. One of the research purposes of the present volume is to discover whether the postcolonial histories of Canada and India are traceable in Sci-Fi literature’s treatment of religious themes. Is Sci-Fi literature mirroring the postcolonial condition of both India and Canada? Have religions/ faiths been instrumental in establishing a pristine/out-of-history background in Sci-Fi texts? Are Canadian and Indian Sci-Fi writers offering solutions for a ‘de-colonized’ frame of mind or, on the contrary, are their texts reproducing a colonialist impetus which extends to the outer space? Is religion (with all its possible facets, institutional, spiritual, etc.) or absence of religion an instrument of power in Sci-Fi literature? These are only a few suggested research directions that the forthcoming book will dwell on.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The volume will have a few main strands on which interested authors can bring their contribution:</p>
<p>            - Defining and redefining religions and religious institutions in Indian and/or Canadian Sci-Fi literature;</p>
<p>            - Politics and religion in Indian and/or Canadian Sci-Fi literature (religious wars; religion as activism/ propaganda (e.g.: for space colonization));</p>
<p>- Absence of religions and their institutions in Indian and/or Canadian Sci-Fi literature (replacement of religion/ re-inventing or creating new religions/faiths; science as religion).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Possible themes (but not restricted to these)</strong></p>
<p>Apocalyptic futures</p>
<p>Religion and utopias/ dystopias/ New religions/ Alien faiths and religions</p>
<p>Religious symbols and supernatural beings (gods/angels/demons/saints)</p>
<p>(New) Creationist mythologies</p>
<p>Cyborgs and other beings/ New (transgender) beings and species and their faiths</p>
<p>Ethics, faith and religion – robots, AI and other sentient beings</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Suggested Canadian Sci-Fi writers (not restricted to)</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>William Gibson</p>
<p>Margaret Atwood</p>
<p>Elisabeth Vonarburg</p>
<p>Phyllis Gotlieb</p>
<p>Robert Charles Wilson</p>
<p>Emily St. John Mandel</p>
<p>Robert J. Sawyer</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Suggested Indian Sci-Fi writers (not restricted to)</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Rokeya Sakhawat Hossain</p>
<p>Priya Sarukkai Chabria</p>
<p>Manjula Padmanavan</p>
<p>Vandana Singh</p>
<p>Rimi Chatterjee</p>
<p>Mainak Dhar</p>
<p>Jayant Narlikar</p>
<p>Gautam Bhatia</p>
<p> </p>
<p>References:</p>
<p>Langer, J. <em>Postcolonialism and Science Fiction</em>, Palgrave Macmillan, 2011.</p>
<p>Rieder, John. <em>Colonialism and the Emergence of Science Fiction</em>. Middletown, 2008.</p>
<p>McGrath, James A. Ed. <em>Religion and Science Fiction</em>. Pickwick Publications, 2011.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>You are kindly invited to email your paper Abstract (500 words) &amp; Short Biodata (150 words) to both editors of the book:</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Aparajita Nanda</strong></p>
<p><a href="mailto:aparananda@berkeley.edu"><strong>aparananda@berkeley.edu</strong></a></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Lucia-Mihaela Grosu-R</strong><strong>ă</strong><strong>dulescu</strong></p>
<p><a href="mailto:lucia.grosu@rei.ase.ro"><strong>lucia.grosu@rei.ase.ro</strong></a></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Deadline for submission of abstracts:  15th January, 2023. You will be intimated of selection by 28th February, 2023.</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Accepted contributors will need to submit papers of around</strong><strong> 6,000 words by December 31st, 2023.</strong></p>
<p><strong><em> </em></strong></p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 02:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1665466629069924</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>American Literature Association 2023 Cormac McCarthy Sessions</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/10/06/american-literature-association-2023-cormac-mccarthy-sessions</link>
						<dc:creator>sfrye@csub.edu</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Monday, October 10, 2022 - 1:02pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>American Literature Association/Cormac McCarthy Society</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:sfrye@csub.edu">sfrye@csub.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/ecocriticism-and-environmental-studies">ecocriticism and environmental studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/twentieth-century-and-beyond">twentieth century and beyond</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>January 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p align="center"><strong>CALL FOR PAPERS</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>American Literature Association Annual Conference</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>Boston, MA</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>May 25-28, 2023</strong></p>
<p align="center">The Cormac McCarthy Society will sponsor three sessions at the American Literature Association Annual Conference in 2023.</p>
<p align="center"> Topics Open.</p>
<p align="center">Papers on <em>The Passenger </em>and <em>Stella Maris </em>are especially welcome </p>
<p align="center">Please submit proposals with one-page abstracts to Steven Frye, California State University, Bakersfield, at <a href="mailto:sfrye@csub.edu">sfrye@csub.edu</a></p>
<p align="center">Proposal Due Date: January 1, 2023</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 17:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1665466629069923</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ October 28, 2022] Conference or similar: Empathie nach Edith Stein: &quot;Ich will Dich sehen, wie Du bist&quot;</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103766</link>
						<description>Venue: Erzbischöfliches Palais, Wollzeile 2<br/><br/><p>„Das auffassende Vermögen, welches in den Geisteswissenschaften wirkt, ist der ganze Mensch“: nur wer sich selbst als Person, als sinnvolles Ganzes erlebt, kann andere Personen verstehen.</p>
<p>Freitag, den 28. Oktober 2022</p>
<p>18.00 Uhr</p>
<p>Messe im Stephansdom</p>
<p>Vorsitz: Doz. P. Dr. Martin Mayerhofer FSO</p>
<p>19.30 Uhr</p>
<p>Eröffenungsvortrag im Festsaal des Erzbischöflichen Palais:</p>
<p><em>Einfühlung als Verstehen geistiger Personen</em><em>: Die Ansätze der Dissertation Edith Steins</em></p>
<p>P. Dr. Roberto Maria Pirastu OCD, Rom</p>
<p>Samstag, den 29. Oktober 2022</p>
<p>10.00 Uhr</p>
<p><em>Empathie in der Psychotherapie: Ein entwicklungsförderndes und heilsames Prinzip mit Geschichte</em></p>
<p>Dr. Helga Ehrmann, Psychotherapeutin, Wien</p>
<p>11.30 Uhr</p>
<p><em>A glimpse of neuronal circuits and network dynamics of empathy: a neurobiological approach</em></p>
<p>Assoc. Prof. Priv. Doz. Dr. Ornella Valenti, Neurobiologin, Med Uni Wien</p>
<p>12.30 Uhr</p>
<p>Mittagspause</p>
<p>14.30 Uhr</p>
<p><em>Göttliche Ichhaftigkeit im „Für-den-anderen-Sein”: Trinitarische Aspekte der Empathie</em></p>
<p>Dr. theol. habil. P. Martin Mayerhofer FSO, I.T.I. Trumau</p>
<p>16.00 Uhr</p>
<p><em>Die Psalmen – eine Schule der Einfühlung</em></p>
<p>Prof. Dr Ludger Schwienshorst-Schönberger, Universität Wien</p>
<p>17.30 Uhr</p>
<p><em>Einfühlung und Gottesbezug. Zum „Grundriss“ der menschlichen Person</em></p>
<p>Prof. Dr. Hanna-Barbara Gerl-Falkovitz, Heiligenkreuz</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 05:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1665207433684198</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rights and Responsibility in Jewish Tradition</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11174940/rights-and-responsibility-jewish-tradition</link>
						<dc:creator>Roberta Sabbath</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-01T00:00:00-04:00">October 1, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-31T00:00:00-04:00">October 31, 2022</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>California</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology, Literature, Jewish History / Studies, Holocaust, Genocide, and Memory Studies, Human Rights</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>This year, the Western Region conference of the American Academy of Religion is examining present-day civil rights discourses, and the roles that religious groups, religious organizations, and scholars of religion can play in these conversations. Recent years had seen expansions, contractions, and redefinitions of civil rights, with significant real-world effects for women, marginalized ethnic groups, sexual minorities, religious minorities, and people with disabilities, among others. Civil rights issues also speak to who we are as communities on the local, state, and international level, touching on fundamental questions of freedom and responsibility, sometimes calling for careful adjudication between conflicting claims and values.</p><p>● What lessons can be drawn from Jewish history and present-day dynamics?</p><p>● Where might Jewish tradition and Jewish thought offer unique insights?</p><p>● Where do American Jews fit within the broader conversations taking place among and between different faith communities in the United States?</p><p>● What are the most difficult aspects of this conversation for Jews and Jewish Studies scholars?</p><p>● How can we, as Jewish Studies scholars, bring our unique perspectives to bear on these topics?</p><p>The Jewish Studies Unit of the AAR-WR welcomes papers responding to any aspects of the above topics and questions, from all disciplines pertaining to the study of Jews and Judaism.</p><p><strong>The deadline for submissions is October 31, 2022.</strong></p><p><strong>The conference meets March 24-26, 2023, University of California, Davis, campus.</strong></p><p>Click here for the full conference theme for this year and previous years: <a href="https://www.aarwr.com/conference-themes.html" rel="nofollow">https://www.aarwr.com/conference-themes.html</a></p><p>Submissions should be sent to the Jewish Studies chairs – Roberta Sabbath (<a href="mailto:roberta.sabbath@unlv.edu">roberta.sabbath@unlv.edu</a>) and Alexander Marcus (<a href="mailto:alexander.marcus@yale.edu">alexander.marcus@yale.edu</a>) – and should include an abstract of 250 words as well as a Program Participant Form (<a href="https://acrobat.adobe.com/link/review?uri=urn:aaid:scds:US:b72795c0-e3c4-34a3-9715-e0b9400a0ac8" rel="nofollow">https://acrobat.adobe.com/link/review?uri=urn:aaid:scds:US:b72795c0-e3c4...</a>), and a personal statement.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Roberta Sabbath, Director Religious Studies Program, University of Nevada, Las Vegas</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:roberta.sabbath@unlv.edu">roberta.sabbath@unlv.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.aarwr.com/" target="_blank">https://www.aarwr.com/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 17:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1665207433684197</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ September 14, 2023 -  September 16, 2023] Conference or similar: Nietzsche and the Lyric / Nietzsche und das Lyrische</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103746</link>
						<description>Venue: UNIL<br/><br/><p><a name="_Hlk114504170"></a></p>
<p><a name="_Hlk114504170"></a></p>
<p><a name="_Hlk114504170"></a></p>
<p>The 28th International Conference of the Friedrich Nietzsche Society</p>
<p><strong>“Nietzsche and the Lyric / Nietzsche und das Lyrische”</strong></p>
<p>Hosted by / Organisation: Philip Mills, Hans-Georg von Arburg, Simone Zurbuchen</p>
<p>University of Lausanne, Switzerland.</p>
<p>September 14-16 2023</p>
<p><a name="_Hlk114504170"></a></p>
<p><a name="_Hlk114504170"></a></p>
<p><a name="_Hlk114504170"></a>The lyric dimension of Nietzsche’s philosophy is undeniable, and he often asserts the importance of poetic and artistic expression in his philosophy. He for instance criticises his own style in his ‘Attempt at self-criticism’ of <em>The Birth of Tragedy</em>: ‘It should have <em>sung</em>, this “new soul”—rather than spoken! What a pity that I did not dare to say what I had to say then as a poet: I might have managed it!’ (BT ‘Attempt’ 3) In this attempt to write as a poet, the work Nietzsche considers as his <em>chef-d’oeuvre</em>, <em>Thus Spoke Zarathustra</em>,<em> </em>presents itself in the form of a long poem. As such it contains perhaps more images, metaphors, and allegories than philosophical concepts. The opposition and filiation between metaphor and concept is by the way at the centre of one of Nietzsche’s early unpublished essays, <em>On Truth and Lie in a Nonmoral Sense</em>. But what does it mean to express philosophical ideas as a poet?</p>
<p>While the poetic dimension of his philosophical writing has been extensively explored, Nietzsche furthermore wrote volumes of lyric poetry. His <em>Idyll from Messina </em>and his <em>Dionysus-Dithyrambs </em>are poetic volumes that explore his philosophical ideas in a different way. The relation between philosophy and poetry is further exemplified by <em>The</em> <em>Gay Science</em> which contains a prelude in rhymes. Two recent collected volumes in German have explored this lyrical production, but it remains rather unexplored in the English-speaking scholarship.<ahref>[1] This absence might be a consequence of the attempt to affirm Nietzsche’s philosophical significance that has been undertaken since Walter Kaufmann at least and that shadowed the lyric dimension of his work.</ahref></p>
<p>This themed conference aims to explore the relation between Nietzsche and the lyric. We welcome papers that explore the poetics of Nietzsche’s philosophy, his conception of metaphor and other poetic phenomena, his lyrical production as such, and the broader relation between philosophy and the lyric in his works.</p>

<p><ahref>[1] See Christian Benne and Claus Zittel, eds., <em>Nietzsche und die Lyrik: Ein Kompendium</em> (Stuttgart: J.B. Metzler, 2017); Katharina Grätz et al., eds., <em>Nietzsche als Dichter: Lyrik - Poetologie - Rezeption</em> (Berlin; Boston: De Gruyter, 2018).</ahref></p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 05:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1665121030557449</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ March 1, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Nietzsche and the Lyric / Nietzsche und das Lyrische</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103750</link>
						<description><p>The 28th International Conference of the Friedrich Nietzsche Society</p>
<p><strong>“Nietzsche and the Lyric / Nietzsche und das Lyrische”</strong></p>
<p>Hosted by / Organisation: Philip Mills, Hans-Georg von Arburg, Simone Zurbuchen</p>
<p>University of Lausanne, Switzerland.</p>
<p>September 14-16 2023</p>
<p><em>Deutsche Fassung folgt unten</em></p>
<p><strong>Call for abstracts</strong></p>
<p><strong></strong>The lyric dimension of Nietzsche’s philosophy is undeniable, and he often asserts the importance of poetic and artistic expression in his philosophy. He for instance criticises his own style in his ‘Attempt at self-criticism’ of <em>The Birth of Tragedy</em>: ‘It should have <em>sung</em>, this “new soul”—rather than spoken! What a pity that I did not dare to say what I had to say then as a poet: I might have managed it!’ (BT ‘Attempt’ 3) In this attempt to write as a poet, the work Nietzsche considers as his <em>chef-d’oeuvre</em>, <em>Thus Spoke Zarathustra</em>,<em> </em>presents itself in the form of a long poem. As such it contains perhaps more images, metaphors, and allegories than philosophical concepts. The opposition and filiation between metaphor and concept is by the way at the centre of one of Nietzsche’s early unpublished essays, <em>On Truth and Lie in a Nonmoral Sense</em>. But what does it mean to express philosophical ideas as a poet?</p>
<p>While the poetic dimension of his philosophical writing has been extensively explored, Nietzsche furthermore wrote volumes of lyric poetry. His <em>Idyll from Messina </em>and his <em>Dionysus-Dithyrambs </em>are poetic volumes that explore his philosophical ideas in a different way. The relation between philosophy and poetry is further exemplified by <em>The</em> <em>Gay Science</em> which contains a prelude in rhymes. Two recent collected volumes in German have explored this lyrical production, but it remains rather unexplored in the English-speaking scholarship.<ahref>[1] This absence might be a consequence of the attempt to affirm Nietzsche’s philosophical significance that has been undertaken since Walter Kaufmann at least and that shadowed the lyric dimension of his work.</ahref></p>
<p>This themed conference aims to explore the relation between Nietzsche and the lyric. We welcome papers that explore the poetics of Nietzsche’s philosophy, his conception of metaphor and other poetic phenomena, his lyrical production as such, and the broader relation between philosophy and the lyric in his works.</p>
<p>[1] See Christian Benne and Claus Zittel, eds., <em>Nietzsche und die Lyrik: Ein Kompendium</em> (Stuttgart: J.B. Metzler, 2017); Katharina Grätz et al., eds., <em>Nietzsche als Dichter: Lyrik - Poetologie - Rezeption</em> (Berlin; Boston: De Gruyter, 2018).</p>
<p><strong>Topics include but are not limited to</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Nietzsche as lyrical thinker</li>
<li>Nietzsche’s style: prose or poetry?</li>
<li>Translating Nietzsche’s lyric poetry</li>
<li>Nietzsche’s reception as a lyric poet</li>
<li>Lyrics as genre/lyric as gender in Nietzsche</li>
<li>Relations between the lyrical and the bodily in Nietzsche</li>
<li>Nietzsche and German Romanticism</li>
<li>Nietzsche and specific poets (Goethe, Baudelaire, Byron, etc.)</li>
<li>Nietzsche and music, theatre, tragedy, dance, song, etc.</li>
<li>Metaphor and concept in Nietzsche</li>
<li>Lyricism as evaluative criterion (e.g. pathos of distance, rank order of types, etc.)</li>
<li>Nietzsche‘s lyrical rhetoric: between poetry and politics</li>
<li>Close reading of his lyrical works that explore their lyrical form or content, for example from <em>Idyll from Messina</em>,<em> Dionysus-Dithyrambs</em>, <em>Thus Spoke Zarathustra</em>, etc.</li>
</ul>
<p><a name="_Hlk114504532"></a></p>
<p><strong>Abstract Guidelines</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Submitted abstracts should be 300-500 words long (500 words is a strict maximum). Abstracts should clearly describe proposals for a 25-minute presentation, must be written in English or German, and must be received by March 1st. We aim to communicate decisions by the end of April.</li>
<li>Abstracts must include a title and 3-5 keywords, set out a clear argument or thesis and included references to appropriate literature.</li>
<li>Abstracts should be sent by email attachment to the FNS Conference Committee at the FNS email address: friedrich.nietzsche.society(at)gmail.com</li>
<li>Please save your file using the following format: FNS2023ABSTRACT_YOURLASTNAME</li>
<li>In the body of the email, please state the following information for potential inclusion in the conference programme: (1) The title of the paper; (2) Your name and institutional affiliation; (3) Your preferred email contact address.</li>
<li>In the subject line of the email, please state only the following: FNS2023ABSTRACT_YOURLASTNAME_ENGLISH or FNS2023ABSTRACT_YOURLASTNAME_DEUTSCH according to the language of the abstract.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Junior Researchers Workshop</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>On September 13th, the day before the conference, a workshop will be held for MA students, PhD students, and post-doctoral researchers working on Nietzsche.</li>
<li>Pre- and recently post-doctoral researchers are offered the opportunity to present and receive feedback on their work to a panel of senior researchers.</li>
<li><strong>To apply, MA &amp; PhD students, and recently post-doctoral scholars, should submit full papers in English (~3000 words) by 31st December. We aim to communicate decisions by the end of February. </strong><strong>Please note this is an earlier deadline than for the main conference.</strong></li>
<li>Papers accepted for the workshop will automatically be selected for presentation at the conference.</li>
<li>Papers refused for the workshop might be accepted for presentation at the conference.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Ausschreibung</strong></p>
<p>Die poetische und speziell die lyrische Dimension sind in Nietzsches Philosophie omnipräsent. Nietzsche selbst unterstreicht die literarische und künstlerische Bedeutung seines Philosophierens immer wieder. So charakterisiert er im „Versuch einer Selbstkritik“ aus der <em>Geburt der Tragödie </em>seinen Stil mit folgenden Worten: „Sie hätte <em>singen</em> sollen, diese ,neue Seele‘ – und nicht reden! Wie schade, dass ich, was ich damals zu sagen hatte, es nicht als Dichter zu sagen wagte: ich hätte es vielleicht gekonnt!“ (GT „Versuch“, 3). Mit Blick auf seine literarischen Ambitionen betrachtete er deshalb den rhapsodischen Text von <em>Also sprach Zarathustra</em> als sein eigentliches Meisterwerk. Dieser Modelltext Nietzsches enthält vielleicht mehr Bilder, Metaphern und Allegorien als philosophische Konzepte. Eben diese Spannung und dieser Zusammenhang zwischen metaphorischem und konzeptuellem Sprechen und Schreiben stehen auch im Zentrum von Nietzsches unveröffentlichtem Frühwerk <em>Über Wahrheit und Lüge im außermoralischen Sinne</em>. Was aber heißt und was bedeutet es, wenn ein Philosoph wie Nietzsche seine Ideen dichterisch formuliert?</p>
<p>Die poetische Dimension von Nietzsches philosophischem Werk ist bereits gut erforscht. Seine lyrische Poesie im engeren Sinne hat bislang jedoch nur wenig Beachtung gefunden. Zu unrecht, denn über lyrische Textgebilde wie die <em>Idyllen aus Messina</em> oder die <em>Dionysos-Dithyramben</em> lässt sich der philosophische Kontinent von Nietzsches Ideen noch einmal auf einem anderen Weg erkunden. Dieser Weg führt in ein Wechselspiel zwischen Philosophie und Poesie hinein, wie es <em>Die fröhliche Wissenschaft</em> mit ihrem gereimten Vorspiel beispielhaft inszeniert. Der poetisch-philosophischen Produktion Nietzsches, die dabei sichtbar wird, widmen sich zwei neuere deutschsprachige Sammelbänden.<ahref>[2] Die englischsprachige Forschung hat sie dagegen weitgehend vernachlässigt. Das mag damit zu tun haben, dass man spätestens seit Walter Kaufmann immer wieder die philosophische Bedeutung von Nietzsche nachweisen wollte. Die poetische und lyrische Seite von Nietzsches Denken und Schreiben geriet dabei jedenfalls in den Schatten.</ahref></p>
<p>Unsere thematisch ausgerichtete Tagung setzt sich zum Ziel, das Verhältnis zwischen Nietzsche und dem Lyrischen aus diesem Schattendasein zu befreien. Wir freuen uns auf Vorschläge zur Poetik von Nietzsches Philosophie, zu Nietzches Theorie der Metapher und verwandter rhetorisch-poetischer Figuren, zu seiner lyrischen Textproduktion sowie zum allgemeinen Verhältnis zwischen der Philosophie, dem Philosophieren und dem Lyrischen in Nietzsches Werk.</p>
<p>[2] Vgl. Christian Benne und Claus Zittel (Hg.): <em>Nietzsche und die Lyrik. Ein Kompendium</em>. Stuttgart: J.B. Metzler, 2017; Katharina Grätz et al. (Hg.): <em>Nietzsche als Dichter. Lyrik – Poetologie – Rezeption</em>. Berlin, Boston: De Gruyter, 2018.</p>
<p><strong>Mögliche Themenfelder sind</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Nietzsches lyrisches Denken</li>
<li>Nietzsches Stil: Prosa oder Poesie?</li>
<li>Nietzsches lyrische Poesie in Überserzungen</li>
<li>Nietzsches Rezeption als Lyriker</li>
<li>Nietzsches Lyrik zwischen Genre und Gender</li>
<li>Lyrik und Körperlichkeit bei Nietzsche</li>
<li>Nietzsche und die Tradition der deutschen Romantik</li>
<li>Nietzsche und andere Dichter (Goethe, Baudelaire, Byron etc.)</li>
<li>Nietzsche und die musischen Künste (Musik, Theater, Tragödie, Tanz, Lied etc.)</li>
<li>Metapher und Konzept bei Nietzsche</li>
<li>Lyrik als Bewertungskriterium (vgl. ,Pathos der Distanz‘, ,Rangordnung‘ etc.)</li>
<li>Nietzsches lyrische Rhetorik: zwischen Poesie und Politik</li>
<li>Einzelanalysen von lyrischen Werken wie den <em>Idyllen aus Messina</em>,<em> </em>den<em> Dionysus-Dithyramben</em>, <em>Also sprach Zarathustra</em> etc.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bewerbungsverfahren und Abstracts</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Die eingesandten Abstracts sollen zwischen 300 und max. 500 Wörter lang sein und einen konzisen Vorschlag für einen 25-minütigen Vortrag auf Englisch oder Deutsch enthalten. Einsendeschluss ist der 1. März 2023. Die Bewerber:innen erhalten Ende April Bescheid.</li>
<li>Die Abstracts sollen enthalten: Titel, 3-5 Keywords, konzise Beschreibung von Thema, Korpus und Fragestellung, bibliografische Angaben zur einschlägigen Forschungsliteratur.</li>
<li>Die Abstracts sind den Tagungsorganisatoren der FNS als Email-Attachment an folgende Adresse einzusenden: friedrich.nietzsche.society(at)gmail.com.</li>
<li>Abstracts bitte unter folgendem Format abspeichern: FNS2023ABSTRACT_YOURLASTNAME.</li>
<li>Bitte schließen Sie in Ihren Email-Text für eine allfällige Aufnahme in das Tagungsprogramm folgende Informationen mit ein: (1) Vortragstitel; (2) Name und institutionelle Anbindung; (3) Email-Adresse (bevorzugter Kontakt).</li>
<li>In die Betreffzeile der Email bitte nur folgende Information aufnehmen: FNS2023ABSTRACT_YOURLASTNAME_ENGLISH oder FNS2023ABSTRACT_YOURLASTNAME_DEUTSCH</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Workshop für Nachwuchs-Wissenschaftler:innen</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Am 13. September (am Vortag der Tagung) findet ein Workshop für Masterstudierende, Doktorand:innen und Postdoktorand:innen mit einem Forschungsprojekt zu Nietzsche statt.</li>
<li>Die Teilnehmer:innen des Workshops erhalten die Gelegenheit, ihr Projekt einem Panel aus erfahrenen Nietzsche-Forscher:innen vorzustellen, und werden von diesen ein qualifiziertes Feedback erhalten.</li>
<li><strong>Bewerber:innen für den Nachwuchs-Workshop müssen bis zum 31. Dezember 2022 ein ca. 3000 Wörter langes Paper auf Englisch einsenden. Sie werden Ende Februar über die Selektion informiert. Achtung: Die Deadline für den Workshop ist früher als jene für die Tagung.</strong></li>
<li>Papers, die für den Workshop angenommen werden, sind automatisch auch für einen Vortrag auf der Tagung vorgesehen.</li>
<li>Papers, die für den Workshop abgelehnt wurden, können dennoch für einen Vortrag auf der Tagung in Frage kommen.</li>
</ul></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 05:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1665121030557448</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>OPEN FOR SUBMISSIONS: Journal of Contemplative Studies (JCS)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11160310/open-submissions-journal-contemplative-studies-jcs</link>
						<dc:creator>Michael Sheehy</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Journal</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2027-12-31T00:00:00-05:00">December 31, 2027</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Virginia</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Anthropology, Humanities, Philosophy, Psychology, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>On behalf of the Executive Board, we are happy to announce that the </span></span></span></span><a href="http://contemplativejournal.org/" rel="nofollow"><span><span><span><span><span><span>Journal of Contemplative Studies</span></span></span></span></span></span></a><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span> </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span>(JCS) is open for submissions.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The </span></span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Journal of Contemplative Studies</span></span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span> is a peer-reviewed, open access digital journal published by the Contemplative Sciences Center at the University of Virginia. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The journal publishes original research and scholarship on topics related to contemplation with a focus on humanities-based studies, in the most capacious sense, and transdisciplinary scholarship with a humanistic core.</span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span> </span></span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The mission of the journal is to provide an academic forum for specialists to publish rigorous, innovative, humanities-based scholarship on contemplation, and to promote interconnections across disciplines, perspectives, and traditions.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The journal is committed to supporting the growth of an academic field for a global community of scholars who study contemplation in all its diversity. This includes scholarship that examines practices, first-person meditative experiences, and the historical and cultural contexts in which forms of contemplation are embedded, and from which they derive. The journal publishes on a rolling basis and is committed to the public dissemination of scholarship free of charge to both authors and readers.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Submissions are open for Research Articles, Special Issues, Book Reviews, Community News and Research Notes for the journal's blog.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>We will be launching an associated preprint service for Contemplative Studies on December 1, which will be open to pre-published and published articles, whether or not the </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Journal of Contemplative Studies</span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span> is the publisher. </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Subscribe to journal news at the bottom of the Home page.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Michael Sheehy and David Germano</p><p>University of Virginia</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:contemplativejournal@virginia.edu">contemplativejournal@virginia.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://contemplativejournal.org/" target="_blank">https://contemplativejournal.org/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 17:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1665121030557447</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Research Fellowships at the Massachusetts Historical Society, 2023-2024</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11146871/research-fellowships-massachusetts-historical-society-2023</link>
						<dc:creator>Cassie Cloutier</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Fellowship</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-01T00:00:00-05:00">March 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>African American History / Studies, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies, Environmental History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Military History</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><a href="https://www.masshist.org/" rel="nofollow">The Massachusetts Historical Society</a> will offer dozens of research fellowships for the 2023-2024 academic year, ranging from short-term support to long-term residency. The <a href="https://www.masshist.org/collections" rel="nofollow">MHS collections</a> primarily consist of manuscripts, as well as books, pamphlets, maps, newspapers, graphics, photographs, works of art, and historical artifacts.</p><p>In addition to receiving funding, MHS Research Fellows become part of a scholarly community that includes other current fellows, MHS staff, Boston-area scholars, and former fellows. They may participate in our Brown Bag Lunch Series, present their own research, attend seminars, and join MHS staff and other fellows for weekly coffees.</p><p>For the latest information regarding fellowship offerings during and in the wake of Covid restrictions, <a href="https://www.masshist.org/research/fellowships" rel="nofollow">please see our website</a>. </p><p>Mark your calendar with the deadlines below! </p><p>Questions? See our <a href="https://www.masshist.org/research/fellowships/faq" rel="nofollow">FAQ</a> or e-mail <a href="mailto:fellowships@masshist.org">fellowships@masshist.org</a>.</p><p><a href="https://masshistfellowships.slideroom.com/" rel="nofollow">Start your application today!</a><br/> </p><p><strong>New England Regional Fellowship Consortium<br/>Deadline: February 1, 2023</strong></p><p>The Society also participates in the New England Regional Fellowship Consortium. These grants provide a stipend of $5,000 for a minimum of eight weeks of research conducted at three or more participating institutions. Thirty-one cultural institutions hope to offer a minimum of twenty fellowships in 2023-2024. <a href="https://www.masshist.org/fellowships/nerfc" rel="nofollow">Learn more.</a><br/> </p><p><strong>Suzanne and Caleb Loring Fellowship<br/>Deadline: February 15, 2023</strong></p><p>For those studying the U.S. Civil War, the Boston Athenaeum and the MHS will offer one Suzanne and Caleb Loring Fellowship on the Civil War, Its Origins, and Consequences. Fellows spend at least four weeks at each institution. This fellowship carries a stipend of $4,000. <a href="https://www.masshist.org/research/fellowships/suzanne-and-caleb-loring-research-fellowship" rel="nofollow">Learn more.</a><br/> </p><p><strong>MHS Short-Term Fellowships<br/>Deadline March 1, 2023</strong></p><p>Most MHS Short-term Fellowships carry a stipend of $3,000 to support a minimum of four weeks of research in the Society’s collections. One application automatically puts you into consideration for any applicable short-term fellowships. Graduate students, faculty, and independent researchers are welcome to apply. We will offer more than fifteen short-term fellowships in the coming year! <a href="https://www.masshist.org/research/fellowships/short-term-research-fellowships" rel="nofollow">Learn more.</a><br/> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:fellowships@masshist.org">fellowships@masshist.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.masshist.org/research/fellowships" target="_blank">https://www.masshist.org/research/fellowships</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 16:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1665121030557446</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – October 5th, 2022</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-october-5th-2022/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find two job listings and a Slack invation to join a community of religion scholars. </p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 38!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs</h2>



<h4>Mellon Assistant Professor of Russian History with expertise in Jewish histories of the region (Tenure-Track)</h4>



<p>Vanderbilt University, US</p>



<p>Deadline: January 6<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://apply.interfolio.com/114548">Apply – Interfolio</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor – Religious Ethics &amp; Social Justice (Tenure-Track)</h4>



<p>University of Kansas, US</p>



<p>Deadline: October 15<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://employment.ku.edu/assistant-professor-religious-ethics-social-justice/23374br?fbclid=IwAR2O-STljm1NdLr_Eg6TU8x0gWICk-2JA4aiZCBw44Fx_eQADnl0_V0JY-o">Assistant Professor – Religious Ethics &amp; Social Justice – 23374BR | Work at KU</a></p>



<h2>Miscellaneous</h2>



<h4>Join Slack and become part of a community of over 800 scholars studying religion through a variety of disciplines.</h4>



<p>Join slack at: join.slack.com/t/sociologyofreligion/shared_invite/</p>



<p>Should the link not work, contact <a href="mailto:chackett@pewresearch.org">chackett@pewresearch.org</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1665034628136464</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ January 31, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Fifth International Conference on Philosophy and Meaning in Life</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103626</link>
						<description><p><strong>Sponsor:</strong></p>
<p>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science, Japan</p>
<p><strong>Organisers:</strong></p>
<p>·       <a href="https://www.nhhumanities.org/programs/teacher/91/kiki-berk">Kiki Berk</a>, Southern New Hampshire University</p>
<p>·       <a href="https://philpeople.org/profiles/nobuo-kurata">Nobuo Kurata</a><u>,</u> Hokkaido University</p>
<p>·       <a href="https://philpeople.org/profiles/iddo-landau">Iddo Landau</a><u>,</u> University of Haifa</p>
<p>·       <a href="https://philpeople.org/profiles/thaddeus-metz">Thaddeus Metz</a><u>,</u> University of Pretoria</p>
<p>·       <a href="https://philpeople.org/profiles/masahiro-morioka">Masahiro Morioka</a><u>,</u> Waseda University</p>
<p>·       <a href="https://philpeople.org/profiles/tatsuya-murayama">Tatsuya Murayama</a><u>,</u> Tohoku University</p>
<p>·       <a href="https://philpeople.org/profiles/yujin-nagasawa">Yujin Nagasawa</a><u>,</u> University of Birmingham</p>
<p>·       <a href="https://www.scrippscollege.edu/academics/faculty/profile/rivka-weinberg">Rivka Weinberg</a><u>,</u> Scripps College</p>
<p><strong>Keynote speakers:</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://ethics.harvard.edu/people/frances-m-kamm">Frances Kamm</a>, Rutgers University</p>
<p>Other Keynotes to be confirmed</p>
<p><strong>Details:</strong></p>
<p>Meaning in life is one of the most fundamental philosophical problems, discussed for centuries but having acquired considerable depth in English-speaking philosophy over the past 30 years. Is there any meaning in life? If so, how can we find it? Can life be meaningful if death is the ultimate end of our existence? How is meaning related to well-being and happiness? What are the moral implications of philosophical debates on meaning in life? Can life be objectively meaningful, or can it only be subjectively meaningful? What are the links between God and meaning? What do we mean by ‘meaning’ in the first place?</p>
<p>The aim of the conference is to address these fundamental questions from a wide range of philosophical perspectives, including both western and non-western traditions. Potential topics could include, but are not limited to: theoretical approaches to meaning in/of life; the relationship between death and meaning; anti-natalism and nihilism; procreation and extinction; spiritual, religious, and psychological implications of meaning; linguistic, metaphysical, and epistemological issues concerning meaning; meaning in applied ethics, such as bioethics, environmental ethics, and transhumanism; the roles of narrative, identity, and agency; comparative accounts of meaning in religio-philosophical traditions around the world; implications of meaning for health, well-being, or virtue.</p>
<p><strong>Call for papers: </strong></p>
<p>We invite submissions concerning meaning in/of life as considered in the field of philosophy. Please send an abstract of approximately 500 words (excluding any references), prepared for blind review, to <a href="mailto:philosophymeaninglife@gmail.com">philosophymeaninglife@gmail.com</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Deadline:</strong> 31 January 2023</p>
<p><strong>Notification:</strong> Applicants will be notified of the result via email by mid-March 2023.</p>
<p><strong>Publication: </strong>Speakers are encouraged to submit their papers in a special issue of the Journal of Philosophy of Life. The submission deadline is 31 October 2023. The publication will be in the first half of 2024.</p>
<p><strong>Time for presentation: </strong>50 minutes for live presentations (roughly 20-25 minutes for talk and the rest for discussion).</p>
<p><strong>Format of presentation:  </strong>Online via Zoom and also Slack. Some talks will be pre-recorded, while others will be live.</p>
<p><strong>Official language: </strong>English</p>
<p><strong>Registration: </strong>Will conference registration be required? Yes, but accepted presenters will be notified closer to the time.</p>
<p>For questions, please email: <a href="mailto:philosophymeaninglife@gmail.com">philosophymeaninglife@gmail.com</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664948228288814</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ June 28, 2023 -  June 30, 2023] Conference or similar: Fifth International Conference on Philosophy and Meaning in Life</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103622</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p><strong>Sponsor:</strong></p>
<p>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science, Japan</p>
<p><strong>Organisers:</strong></p>
<p>·       <a href="https://www.nhhumanities.org/programs/teacher/91/kiki-berk">Kiki Berk</a>, Southern New Hampshire University</p>
<p>·       <a href="https://philpeople.org/profiles/nobuo-kurata">Nobuo Kurata</a><u>,</u> Hokkaido University</p>
<p>·       <a href="https://philpeople.org/profiles/iddo-landau">Iddo Landau</a><u>,</u> University of Haifa</p>
<p>·       <a href="https://philpeople.org/profiles/thaddeus-metz">Thaddeus Metz</a><u>,</u> University of Pretoria</p>
<p>·       <a href="https://philpeople.org/profiles/masahiro-morioka">Masahiro Morioka</a><u>,</u> Waseda University</p>
<p>·       <a href="https://philpeople.org/profiles/tatsuya-murayama">Tatsuya Murayama</a><u>,</u> Tohoku University</p>
<p>·       <a href="https://philpeople.org/profiles/yujin-nagasawa">Yujin Nagasawa</a><u>,</u> University of Birmingham</p>
<p>·       <a href="https://www.scrippscollege.edu/academics/faculty/profile/rivka-weinberg">Rivka Weinberg</a><u>,</u> Scripps College</p>
<p><strong>Keynote speakers:</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://ethics.harvard.edu/people/frances-m-kamm">Frances Kamm</a>, Rutgers University</p>
<p>Other Keynotes to be confirmed</p>
<p><strong>Details:</strong></p>
<p>Meaning in life is one of the most fundamental philosophical problems, discussed for centuries but having acquired considerable depth in English-speaking philosophy over the past 30 years. Is there any meaning in life? If so, how can we find it? Can life be meaningful if death is the ultimate end of our existence? How is meaning related to well-being and happiness? What are the moral implications of philosophical debates on meaning in life? Can life be objectively meaningful, or can it only be subjectively meaningful? What are the links between God and meaning? What do we mean by ‘meaning’ in the first place?</p>
<p>The aim of the conference is to address these fundamental questions from a wide range of philosophical perspectives, including both western and non-western traditions. Potential topics could include, but are not limited to: theoretical approaches to meaning in/of life; the relationship between death and meaning; anti-natalism and nihilism; procreation and extinction; spiritual, religious, and psychological implications of meaning; linguistic, metaphysical, and epistemological issues concerning meaning; meaning in applied ethics, such as bioethics, environmental ethics, and transhumanism; the roles of narrative, identity, and agency; comparative accounts of meaning in religio-philosophical traditions around the world; implications of meaning for health, well-being, or virtue.</p>
<p><strong>Call for papers: </strong></p>
<p>We invite submissions concerning meaning in/of life as considered in the field of philosophy. Please send an abstract of approximately 500 words (excluding any references), prepared for blind review, to <a href="mailto:philosophymeaninglife@gmail.com">philosophymeaninglife@gmail.com</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Deadline:</strong> 31 January 2023</p>
<p><strong>Notification:</strong> Applicants will be notified of the result via email by mid-March 2023.</p>
<p><strong>Publication: </strong>Speakers are encouraged to submit their papers in a special issue of the Journal of Philosophy of Life. The submission deadline is 31 October 2023. The publication will be in the first half of 2024.</p>
<p><strong>Time for presentation: </strong>50 minutes for live presentations (roughly 20-25 minutes for talk and the rest for discussion).</p>
<p><strong>Format of presentation:  </strong>Online via Zoom and also Slack. Some talks will be pre-recorded, while others will be live.</p>
<p><strong>Official language: </strong>English</p>
<p><strong>Registration: </strong>Will conference registration be required? Yes, but accepted presenters will be notified closer to the time.</p>
<p>For questions, please email: <a href="mailto:philosophymeaninglife@gmail.com">philosophymeaninglife@gmail.com</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664948228288813</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ December 1, 2022] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103650</link>
						<description>Publication Name: Phenomenological Psychopathology: Who, What and How. An analysis of key figures, advancements and challenges<br/><br/><p><strong>Call for papers</strong><strong></strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Phenomenological Psychopathology: Who, What and How? </em></strong><strong><em></em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>An analysis of key figures, advancements and challenges</em></strong><strong><em></em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em> </em></strong><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Special Issue of “Frontiers in Psychology” </strong><strong></strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Edited by </strong><strong></strong></p>
<p><strong>Susi Ferrarello, Francesca Brencio, Valeria Bizzari, Magnus Englander</strong><strong></strong></p>
<p>Phenomenology and psychopathology are two disciplines whose development intertwined over the past century thanks to key figures such as Binswanger, Jaspers, Fanon, Basaglia. Phenomenology offers psychopathology an approach that looks at the lived experience of the patient without presuppositions and preconceptions. Psychopathology offers phenomenology the possibility to investigate the manifold forms of plurality, a topic that only tangentially has been investigated by philosophy in its history. In that sense, phenomenological notions such as epoche’, first and second person perspective, lived time, and intersubjectivity are key to the advancement of a psychopathology, capable of truly understanding the lived experience of the person affected by a disorder and integrate it in society. Consequently, disorders such as autism, schizophrenia, bipolarism, borderline personality have gained a deeper understanding and integration in the society thanks to the combination of phenomenological studies within a multidisciplinary context (music, dance, theatre, visual arts).<br/> <br/> The goal of this issue is to collect papers that focus on:<br/> - key concepts, advancements and challenges in the development of phenomenological psychopathology and clinical applications<br/> - propose a theoretical overview of the major perspectives to contemporary challenges within phenomenological psychopathology such as embodiment, lived-time, interaffectivity, intentionality, existential moods<br/> - overview of theoretical perspectives to contemporary challenges within specific conditions studied by phenomenological psychopathology<br/> - tackle the study of specific emotions (e.g. envy, melancholy, resentment) contributing to the arousal of specific disorders (depression, BPD, bipolarism, etc.)<br/> -discussion of methodologies in use to conduct studies in phenomenological psychopathologies and concrete tools that phenomenology can offer (for instance, the phenomenological interview) and a critical analysis of the phenomenological gaze in the clinical meeting and in the therapeutic setting. - provide the readers with key studies in which the phenomenological toolbox is used in empirical and clinical occasions.<br/> <br/> Accordingly, this issue is interested in the following scope of research concerning phenomenological psychopathology:<br/> - Theoretical investigation of development of phenomenological psychopathology and its challenges in the empirical practice<br/> - Clinical applications of phenomenological psychopathology on specific disorders (autism, schizophrenia, borderline, bipolar)<br/> - Epistemological understanding of the limits of clinical applications and theoretical studies<br/> - Discussion of methodologies (tools, phenomenologically-informed therapies) in phenomenological psychopathology and their limits.</p>
<p><strong>Important dates: </strong><strong></strong></p>
<p>Deadline for abstract: December 1st</p>
<p>Notification of acceptance: December 15th</p>
<p>Deadline manuscripts: May 2023</p>
<p>More info at:<a href="https://www.frontiersin.org/research-topics/46802/phenomenological-psychopathology-who-what-and-how-an-analysis-of-key-figures-advancements-and-challe">https://www.frontiersin.org/research-topics/46802/phenomenological-psychopathology-who-what-and-how-an-analysis-of-key-figures-advancements-and-challe</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664948228288812</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP: &quot;Judaisms, Jewishness, and Time&quot; - Jewish Studies Graduate Association Conference (online)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11122603/cfp-judaisms-jewishness-and-time-jewish-studies-graduate</link>
						<dc:creator>Sabina Ali</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-30T00:00:00-04:00">October 30, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Anthropology, Art, Art History &amp; Visual Studies, Colonial and Post-Colonial History / Studies, Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><strong>CFP: "Judaisms, Jewishness, and Time"</strong></span></p><p><span><strong>11th Annual Jewish Studies Graduate Association Conference (online)</strong><br/>Borns Jewish Studies Program<br/>Indiana University, Bloomington</span></p><p><span><strong>Proposal Submission Deadline: October 30th, 2022</strong></span></p><p>In <em>The Sabbath: Its Meaning for Modern Man</em> (1951), Abraham Joshua Heschel says that “Judaism is a religion of time aiming at the sanctification of time.” With Heschel’s reflection on the centrality of time to Judaism in mind, the Jewish Studies Graduate Students Association at Indiana University invites graduate student proposals for a conference on <strong>Judaisms, Jewishness, and Time</strong>. We invite participants to consider how might Jewish studies as a field be positioned to interrogate time as a concept. This conference will be held <strong>February 2-3, 2023, online</strong> with an optional in-person reception and closing event.</p><p>Proposals are encouraged to think through questions that relate to how contemporary studies of Jews, Judaisms, and Jewishness offer new perspectives or rescue old concepts in the understanding of time throughout history. How can Jewish studies illuminate questions about time? How do the societies, organizations, or figures we research deal with temporal problems? We welcome proposals that engage/discuss Judaisms, Jewishness, and time in myriad ways, such as memory, narrative, and mourning; history and historiography; modernity, coloniality, and the nation-state; indigeneity and deep time; calendars, materiality, monuments, and ritual; ecology and climate change; the experience of time and other phenomenological issues; messianism and prophecy; or other topics.</p><p>The conference is open to all graduate students working in Jewish studies and adjacent fields. As an interdisciplinary conference, we welcome papers from many fields, including but not limited to Religious Studies, Anthropology, Sociology, Music, Literature, Folklore, Film Studies, Visual and Performance Art, History, and Political Science. Also, we encourage the proposal of unconventional presentations, including visual, musical, and performance arts.</p><p>We are excited to announce that this year’s Lillian Solotkin Keynote Lecture, titled “Memory Citizenship: Migration and Holocaust Memory in Contemporary Germany,” will be given by Dr. Michael Rothberg, 1939 Society Samuel Goetz Chair in Holocaust Studies and Professor of English and Comparative Literature at the University of California, Los Angeles.</p><p><strong>Please send an abstract (maximum 300 words), a title for your presentation, and contact information, including name, email address, telephone number, and institution to <a href="mailto:jsgsacon@indiana.edu">jsgsacon@indiana.edu</a> by October 30.</strong> Abstracts will be evaluated based on quality and fit. Participants will be notified of acceptance by <strong>November 15</strong>. Papers will need to be submitted by January 9 for circulation among faculty respondents. Participants will have 20 minutes to present.</p><p>Please email questions to <strong><a href="mailto:jsgsacon@indiana.edu">jsgsacon@indiana.edu</a></strong>.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Sabina Ali<br/>Jewish Studies Graduate Student Association<br/>Borns Jewish Studies Program<br/>Indiana University, Bloomington</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:jsgsacon@indiana.edu">jsgsacon@indiana.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 17:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664948228288811</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
