<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 12:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 12:32:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ July 26, 2023 -  July 29, 2023] Conference or similar: 13th International Whitehead Conference - Whitehead and the History of Philosophy</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104530</link>
						<description>Venue: Kaulbachstr. 33<br/><br/><p>Alfred North Whitehead developed his process philosophy with an explicit reliance on the value of the history of philosophy. While the trend of recent years has often suggested that different approaches to philosophical problems can be adequately categorized, using the dichotomy of purely systematic or purely historical interests, Whitehead offers an equally historically informed and systematically intended perspective.</p>
<p>This conference is dedicated to the philosophical-historical dimension in Whitehead’s oeuvre on the one hand and to its systematic relevance for numerous areas of research on the other hand.</p>
<p>Interested scholars are cordially invited to submit an abstract of no more than 500 words<br/>in one of the follwoing sections here: <a href="https://easychair.org/account/signin?l=8DUhKbvT0vCoX6K2LRHeX4">https://easychair.org/account/signin?l=8DUhKbvT0vCoX6K2LRHeX4</a></p>
<p>Whitehead and Aesthetics</p>
<p>Whitehead and Analytical Philosophy</p>
<p>Whitehead, Bergson and Deleuze</p>
<p>Whitehead and Biology</p>
<p>Whitehead and Education</p>
<p>Whitehead and the Philosophy of the 21st Century</p>
<p>Whitehead and classical Greek Philosophy</p>
<p>Whitehead and Integral Ecology</p>
<p>Whitehead and Integral Economics</p>
<p>Whitehead, Mathematics and Physics</p>
<p>German Whitehead research (in German)</p>
<p>Whitehead and Phenomenology</p>
<p>Whitehead and Pragmatism</p>
<p>Whitehead, Spinoza and Leibniz</p>
<p>Whitehead and Social Sciences</p>
<p>Whitehead and Theology</p>
<p>Whitehead and China<br/><br/></p>
<p>Dates and fees (in euro):</p>
<p>Early registration: Jan. 1 2023 – Jan. 31, 2023; fee: 75 (students)/150 (standard);</p>
<p>Normal registration: Feb. 1 – May 31, 2023; fee: 100 (students)/200 (standard);</p>
<p>Late registration: after June 1, 2023; fee: 125 (students)/250 (standard). </p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 05:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667108225385192</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ November 30, 2022] CFP for conference or similar: First-Person Science of Consciousness</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104486</link>
						<description><p>First-Person Science of Consciousness: Methodological Potentials, Challenges and Developmental Perspectives</p>

<p>This upcoming conference seeks to advance the field of a first-person science of consciousness – an important but still underrepresented area of research. The conference has a particular focus on methods of conducting first-person research. It seeks to explore the potentials and challenges associated with these methods and is intended to illuminate perspectives for the further development of the field. The conference will bring together leading researchers and young scholars in order to explore how third- and first-person methods can complement each other to allow for a more comprehensive phenomenology and understanding of consciousness.</p>

<p>Time and location: May 11th-13th 2023, University of Witten/Herdecke</p>

<p>Abstract Submission deadline: November 30, 2022</p>

<p>Details, Registration and Abstract submission: <a href="https://consciousness.uni-wh.de/">https://consciousness.uni-wh.de/</a></p>

<p>For the conference team:</p>
<p>Brentyn Ramm</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 05:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667021829677353</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ May 11, 2023 -  May 13, 2023] Conference or similar: First-Person Science of Consciousness</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104482</link>
						<description>Venue: Alfred-Herrhausen-Str. 50<br/><br/><p>First-Person Science of Consciousness: Methodological Potentials, Challenges and Developmental Perspectives</p>
<p>This upcoming conference seeks to advance the field of a first-person science of consciousness – an important but still underrepresented area of research. The conference has a particular focus on methods of conducting first-person research. It seeks to explore the potentials and challenges associated with these methods and is intended to illuminate perspectives for the further development of the field. The conference will bring together leading researchers and young scholars in order to explore how third- and first-person methods can complement each other to allow for a more comprehensive phenomenology and understanding of consciousness.</p>
<p>Time and location: May 11th-13th 2023, University of Witten/Herdecke</p>
<p>Abstract Submission deadline: November 30, 2022</p>
<p>Details, Registration and Abstract submission: https://consciousness.uni-wh.de/</p>
<p>For the conference team:</p>
<p>Brentyn Ramm</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 05:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667021829677352</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Football and Religion: Tales of Hope, Play and Passion (Closing Event)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11468637/football-and-religion-tales-hope-play-and-passion-closing</link>
						<dc:creator>Layal Mohammad</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Event</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-30T00:00:00-05:00">November 30, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Fine Arts, Religious Studies and Theology, Social History / Studies, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies, Sport History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span>Join us on Wednesday 30 November for the closing event of <i>Football and Religion: Tales of Hope, Play and Passion </i>exhibition. The event will include a panel discussion about football and religion with a particular emphasis on women’s football. The event will take place at the Aga Khan Centre, London, as well as online and will be followed by a viewing of the exhibition.<br/><br/><b>About the Exhibition</b></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Presented by the <a href="https://www.aku.edu/ismc/Pages/home.aspx" rel="nofollow">Aga Khan University’s Institute for the Study of Muslim Civilisations (AKU-ISMC)</a> and the <a href="https://www.agakhancentre.org.uk/gallery/" rel="nofollow">Aga Khan Centre Gallery</a>, this exhibition explores the relationship between football and religion and how the two are often connected, with players praying on the pitch and fans observing religious rituals in tandem. The wider narrative across the exhibition examines football’s ability to champion social causes, promote marginalised voices, and create opportunities for inclusion and diversity in ways no other sport can.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>The exhibition provides a narrative on the subject through a snapshot of social history and contemporary commentary with a selection of books, magazines and newspaper articles, relevant objects, and artefacts. This narrative provides the contextual backdrop for a series of new artworks created by visual artist, illustrator, and animator Ed Merlin Murray.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Murray has created a series of short animations presented as an immersive installation depicting interviews with a number of male and female football players describing their personal relationship to football and religion. The players selected are from across the world and all are at different stages of their careers — from Aksa Nisar, a 17-year-old south Asian player in the early stages of her career, to Cheikhou Kouyaté, a Senegalese professional footballer who plays for Premier League club Crystal Palace, and Linvoy Primus MBE, an English former professional footballer who played for Portsmouth and Charlton Athletic FC. The exhibition also includes full interview transcripts as way of sharing the wider conversations and individuals’ impassioned tales of hope, passion, and play.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>The exhibition, <i>Football and Religion</i>, includes something for everyone — from eye-catching immersive illustrated animations to interactive art and a host of inspirational media that allow visitors to delve into the subject as much as they wish. <a href="https://www.agakhancentre.org.uk/gallery/football-and-religion/" rel="nofollow">Find out more</a><br/><br/><b>Speakers</b></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>• Kevin Coleman (Chair): Formerly Kick It Out, The FA and Brentford FC.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>• Dal Darroch: Head of Diversity and Inclusion, The FA.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>• Karishma and Sumaria Inayat: Gilgit Baltistan Girls FC, Pakistan.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>• Lipa Nessa: Sports Activist, FIFA Fan Movement Member, Trustee Muslim Sports and Youth Sport Trust.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>• Linvoy Primus: MBE, Christians in Sports and formerly Portsmouth and Southampton FC.<br/><br/><b>Special Guests</b></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>• Ed Merlin Murray: Visual artist and animator.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>• Matt Baker: Director of Sports Chaplaincy UK and Chaplain for Charlton Athletic FC.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>• Yasmin Abukar: Founder of Sisterhood FC.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>• Qadria Saeedi: Club Coordinator, Afghanistan and Central Asian Association - Abresham Girls FC.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>• Dr Zafar Iqbal: Head of Sports Medicine, Crystal Palace FC.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>• Lat Blaylock: RE Today Editor, National RE Adviser.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>• Tony Burnett: CEO, Kick It Out.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>• Anwar Uddin: Campaign Manager for Fans for Diversity, Kick It Out, The FA ,and Assistant Manager at Aldershot Town FC.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>Dates and Times</span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Panel Discussion: 30 November 2022, 18:00 - 19:00 (London).</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Exhibition Viewing: 30 November 2022, 19:00 - 20:00.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>                                  Exhibition runs until: 4 December 2022.<br/><br/><b>Venue</b></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Aga Khan Centre (Atrium Conference Room and Gallery),<br/>10 Handyside Street,<br/>London N1C 4DN<br/><br/><b>Booking</b></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>The event is free, but booking is essential:</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>To attend in person, <a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/football-and-religion-tales-of-hope-play-and-passion-closing-event-tickets-450425523867" rel="nofollow"><b>register via Eventbrite</b></a>.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>To attend online, <a href="https://aku-edu.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_QMsNYjPpTgCElUZ5Odq41Q" rel="nofollow"><b>register via Eventbrite</b></a>.</span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p> Layal Mohammad<br/> Manager, Marketing and Communications<br/> The Aga Khan University (International) in the United Kingdom<br/> Aga Khan Centre, 10 Handyside Street, London N1C 4DN</p><p> Phone: +44 [0] 20 7380 3839<br/> Website: <a href="http://www.aku.edu/ismc" rel="nofollow">www.aku.edu/ismc</a></p><p> Incorporated in England as a company limited by guarantee no. 4448389 <br/> Registered Charity Number 1179136</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:layal.n.mohammad@aku.edu">layal.n.mohammad@aku.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.aku.edu/ismc/events/pages/event-detail.aspx" target="_blank">https://www.aku.edu/ismc/events/pages/event-detail.aspx?EventID=2179&amp;Title=Football%20and%20Religion%3A%20Tales%20of%20H…</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666935431416864</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP Deadline Extended American Academy of Religion Western Region: Asian American Religious Studies Unit</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11462668/cfp-deadline-extended-american-academy-religion-western-region</link>
						<dc:creator>Laura Snell</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-15T00:00:00-05:00">November 15, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>California</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>American History / Studies, Asian American History / Studies, Humanities, Race / Ethnic Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>American Academy of Religion - Western Region Annual Meeting 2023</p><p>University of California, Davis March 24-26, 2023</p><p>Call for Papers: The Role of Religion in Asian American Civil Rights Discourses</p><p>Panel: Asian American Religious Studies Unit</p><p>In recent years, we have seen how Asian Americans’ civil rights continue to be threatened. Such events include the resurgence of Asian American hate since the pandemic, as well as the ongoing court case against affirmative action: “Students for Fair Admissions v. Harvard.” It is a mistake to assume, however, that Asians have been passive agents in these events. Many Asian Americans have taken part in activism—but have their voices been loud enough to be heard or have they been muffled amidst the magnitude of Asian American hate that renders racism against them invisible? Adding more layers to these issues is the way that the civil rights struggle creates solidarity within the Asian American community and other minoritized communities, but at the same time it has also fostered divisiveness both within Asian American communities and outside. How have ideas about immigration, stereotypes, and boundaries been both embraced and challenged by Asian Americans?</p><p>Needless to say, the problem of defending the civil rights of Asian Americans is a complex matter, one in which religion struggles to find its place. For this year’s conference, we ask what role religion holds in communicating and addressing these social and political issues? How do religious discourses, rituals, doctrines, and teachings serve Asian Americans in terms of defending their civil rights, as well as fostering group solidarity amidst the plurality of Asian American religious traditions? As scholars of Asian American religion, what is our role in this political discourse? How do we see Asian American civil rights movements and scholarship moving forward?</p><p>Scholars of all levels are invited to participate in this dialogue. Interested parties may send abstracts (250 words) to Shannon Toribio (<a href="mailto:shannon_toribio@ucsb.edu">shannon_toribio@ucsb.edu</a>) or Laura Snell (<a href="mailto:laurasnell@ucsb.edu">laurasnell@ucsb.edu</a>). The deadline for submission is November 15, 2022. All participants must submit a Program Participant Form (<a href="https://www.aarwr.com/uploads/2/0/4/2/20420409/participation_form_aar_wr_general.doc" rel="nofollow">https://www.aarwr.com/uploads/2/0/4/2/20420409/participation_form_aar_wr...</a>). Participants at AARWR must be members of the AAR. The AAR membership information is found at aarweb.org.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><a href="mailto:laurasnell@ucsb.edu">laurasnell@ucsb.edu</a> </p><p><a href="mailto:shannon_toribio@ucsb.edu">shannon_toribio@ucsb.edu</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:lhsnell@gmail.com">lhsnell@gmail.com</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 17:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666935431416863</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rights and Responsibilities in the Jewish Tradition</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11462071/rights-and-responsibilities-jewish-tradition</link>
						<dc:creator>Roberta Sabbath</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-26T00:00:00-04:00">October 26, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Nevada</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology, Jewish History / Studies, Holocaust, Genocide, and Memory Studies, Human Rights, Literature</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>This year, the Western Region conference of the American Academy of Religion is examining present-day civil rights discourses, and the roles that religious groups, religious organizations, and scholars of religion can play in these conversations. Recent years had seen expansions, contractions, and redefinitions of civil rights, with significant real-world effects for women, marginalized ethnic groups, sexual minorities, religious minorities, and people with disabilities, among others. Civil rights issues also speak to who we are as communities on the local, state, and international level, touching on fundamental questions of freedom and responsibility, sometimes calling for careful adjudication between conflicting claims and values.</p><p>● What lessons can be drawn from Jewish history and present-day dynamics?</p><p>● Where might Jewish tradition and Jewish thought offer unique insights?</p><p>● Where do American Jews fit within the broader conversations taking place among and between different faith communities in the United States?</p><p>● What are the most difficult aspects of this conversation for Jews and Jewish Studies scholars?</p><p>● How can we, as Jewish Studies scholars, bring our unique perspectives to bear on these topics?</p><p>The Jewish Studies Unit of the AAR-WR welcomes papers responding to any aspects of the above topics and questions, from all disciplines pertaining to the study of Jews and Judaism.</p><p><strong>The deadline for submissions is November 15, 2022.</strong></p><p><strong>The conference meets March 24-26, 2023, University of California, Davis, campus.</strong></p><p>Click here for the full conference theme for this year and previous years: <a href="https://www.aarwr.com/conference-themes.html" rel="nofollow">https://www.aarwr.com/conference-themes.html</a></p><p>Submissions should be sent to the Jewish Studies chairs – Roberta Sabbath (<a href="mailto:roberta.sabbath@unlv.edu">roberta.sabbath@unlv.edu</a>) and Alexander Marcus (<a href="mailto:alexander.marcus@yale.edu">alexander.marcus@yale.edu</a>) – and should include an abstract of 250 words as well as a Program Participant Form (<a href="https://acrobat.adobe.com/link/review?uri=urn:aaid:scds:US:b72795c0-e3c4-34a3-9715-e0b9400a0ac8" rel="nofollow">https://acrobat.adobe.com/link/review?uri=urn:aaid:scds:US:b72795c0-e3c4...</a>), and a personal statement.</p><p>Contact Info: </p><p>Roberta Sabbath, Director Religious Studies Program, University of Nevada, Las Vegas</p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Roberta Sabbath, Director Religious Studies Program, University of Nevada, Las Vegas</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:roberta.sabbath@unlv.edu">roberta.sabbath@unlv.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.aarwr.com/" target="_blank">https://www.aarwr.com/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 17:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666935431416862</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – October 26th, 2022</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-october-26th-2022/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find multiple full-time job listings, several fellowships, two Call for Papers, and a Zoom seminar. </p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 36!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Religious Studies (Tenure Track)</h4>



<p>Elon University, US</p>



<p>Deadline: November 20<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.elon.edu/facultyemployment/openings?id=309&amp;fbclid=IwAR1QZJbqiu0Az61VJbuNBZwCrOKJLxNzlP4gpU9-BMm6OkD8KhQuE071CXw">https://www.elon.edu/facultyemployment/openings?id=309&amp;fbclid=IwAR1QZJbqiu0Az61VJbuNBZwCrOKJLxNzlP4gpU9-BMm6OkD8KhQuE071CXw</a></p>



<h3>Lumen Christ Institute – Programming Coordinator</h3>



<p>University of Chicago, US</p>



<p>Deadline: January 9<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php?id=64287">https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php?id=64287</a></p>



<h4>Associate Professor: Department of Middle Eastern, South Asian, and African Studies (Tenure Track)</h4>



<p>Columbia University, US</p>



<p>Deadline: November 15<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://apply.interfolio.com/115763">https://apply.interfolio.com/115763</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor and Severance Chair in the History of Religion (Tenure Track)</h4>



<p>Case Western Reserve University, US</p>



<p>Deadline: December 5, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://case.edu/academic-careers/assistant-professor-tenure-track-and-severance-chair-history-religion-department-religious-studies">https://case.edu/academic-careers/assistant-professor-tenure-track-and-severance-chair-history-religion-department-religious-studies</a></p>



<h4>Instructor Religious Studies (Full Time, Non-Tenure Track, Possibility of renewal and promotion)</h4>



<p>University of North Florida</p>



<p>Deadline: November 28<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.unfjobs.org/postings/22005">https://www.unfjobs.org/postings/22005</a></p>



<h2>Fellowships:</h2>



<h4>The Crossroads Project: Black Religious Histories, Communities, and Cultures</h4>



<p>Grants for Arts Fellows, Community Stories Fellows, Research Fellows, and Teaching Fellows</p>



<p>Deadline: December 16<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://crossroads.princeton.edu/grant-program/request-proposals">https://crossroads.princeton.edu/grant-program/request-proposals</a></p>



<h4>Asian Pacific American Religions Research Initiative</h4>



<p>Grants and Fellowships for Research, Working Groups, Collaborative Grants with Communities, and Media Fellows Program</p>



<p>Deadline: Varies depending on grant choice, earliest November 15<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://aparri.org/grants-and-fellowships/">https://aparri.org/grants-and-fellowships/</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>Alternative Spirituality and Religion Review, Wuhan Journal of Cultic Studies</h4>



<p>Deadline: ASAP</p>



<p>More Information: Contact Carole Cusack <a href="mailto:carole.cusack@sydney.edu.au">carole.cusack@sydney.edu.au</a></p>



<h4>2023 Nonreligion and Secularity Research Network Conference</h4>



<p>June 6-9, 2023, at University of Ottawa, Canada (In-person and online formats)</p>



<p>Deadline: December 16<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://thensrn.org/events/2023-nonreligion-and-secularity-research-network-conference/">https://thensrn.org/events/2023-nonreligion-and-secularity-research-network-conference/</a></p>



<h2>Seminars:</h2>



<h4>Book Talk with Yasmin El-Rifae – <em>Radius: A Story of Feminist Revolution</em></h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>October 27<sup>th</sup>, 2022, 6:30 PM EST (US and Canada)</p>



<p>More Information/Registration: <a href="https://georgetown.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_dmehNnxzSTuCf23_wC1jFw">https://georgetown.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_dmehNnxzSTuCf23_wC1jFw</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666849027866791</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ July 8, 2024 -  July 13, 2024] Conference or similar: The Psychology of Faith Academic Cross-Training Project</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104398</link>
						<description>Venue: 2115 Summit Ave<br/><br/><p>This is a workshop for the Psychology of Faith Academic Cross-Training Project. It is not open to the general public, but applications to the project can be made on our website: https://cas.stthomas.edu/departments/areas-of-study/philosophy/academic-cross-training-grant/.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666762628505355</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ January 23, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: The Psychology and Theology of Faith</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104402</link>
						<description><p>With the support of the John Templeton Foundation, the University of St. Thomas (MN) announces The Psychology and Theology of Faith sub-granting competition, to fund academic cross-training in the psychological sciences for scholars of Christian theology or philosophy of religion with research interests relating to religious belief or religious commitment. Six successful applicants will each receive a $70,000 award providing the opportunity to take courses in and work with mentors from the psychological sciences, in order to apply and leverage insights from the psychological sciences in their work as theologians and philosophers. Applications are due Jan 23, 2023. For more information, see our website:</p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666762628505354</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for entries:  Palgrave Encyclopedia of Islamic Economics and Finance</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11439983/call-entries-palgrave-encyclopedia-islamic-economics-and</link>
						<dc:creator>Cenap Cakmak</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Publications</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-12-31T00:00:00-05:00">December 31, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Turkey</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Area Studies, Islamic History / Studies, Law and Legal History, Middle East History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><b><span>Call for entries:</span></b></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><b><span>Palgrave Encyclopedia of Islamic Economics and Finance </span></b></span></span></p><p>(Inquire for remaining entries)</p><p><span><span><span><span>The concept of Islamic finance and economy has attracted a great deal of attention in the academic circles in recent years. The growing interest in the practices and products of Islamic finance and the integration of Islamic finance with global economy is a major factor; however, it is not appropriate to attribute the surge in academic publications on the subjects of Islamic finance to this factor alone. Islamic economics, as an alternative domain of study that offers innovative tools and approaches in place of conventional teachings in the literature, deserves greater attention in not only the realm of practice but also of academy and theory. </span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span>Interestingly, the concept of Islamic finance and economy takes greater attention in the West rather than predominantly Muslim countries. Even though there is visible interest in Islamic economy in such Muslim countries as Turkey, Malaysia, Iran and Malaysia, number and quality of academic studies in this field is far from being adequate and satisfactory. On the other hand, the Western academic circles, with the exception of some inherent prejudices and theological aloofness, are in pursuit of offering sincere answers to questions relevant to Islamic economic models and teachings. </span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span>It should be noted, however, that the initial steps towards formulating an Islamic finance and economy should be taken in a Muslim country, Turkey being a major candidate. Despite that it has been a long time since the introduction of Islamic finance institutions, the academic circles in Turkey have failed to catch up and delayed to fill the gap. Laying down the theoretical framework of the Islamic finance institutions that have exhibited a trend of growth and popularity not only in Turkey but also in the world is a matter of urgency for the academic institutions and figures. </span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span>This study seeks to address this problem and thus to offer an introductory account focusing on the subjects of Islamic finance and economics. There is visible need for such an account since there is no comprehensive literature that can be employed in courses being offered in courses on Islamic finance and economy. Additionally, there are not even much works of reference that can be consulted with by researchers who are in the initial phase of their studies. To this end, this work, an initiative that will address this gap by featuring a style of encyclopedia that holds a special place in Western academic tradition, collects and explains major concepts of Islamic finance and economics. The study that will present a solid framework for the elaboration of the major concepts of the subject will make use of the existing academic literature, as well as theological sources and the history of Islam and of Islamic financial practices. </span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span>For this reason, this encyclopedia relies on an interdisciplinary approach. Even though in some instances will it give the impression that it is a study of economics literature, the volume will also make room for discussions of Islamic theology, history and philosophy. The goal in doing this is to present the historical theoretical framework as well as the modern and contemporary views and tendencies. From this perspective, this study makes a strong claim that it will serve as a reference work for those who are eager to conduct research on different aspects of Islamic finance and economics. </span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span>This study primarily speaks to the academic community. Even though it could be considered an introductory effort for the academics who do research on Islamic finance, this volume presents an integrated and condensed account. The problems regarding eclecticism are persistent in different academic disciplines; but it is even more acute and pressing when it comes to the study of Islamic finance and economics. As a result, the researchers in most cases leave many issues out which thus make the outcome vague and imprecise in the literature. </span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span>The encyclopedia of Islamic economics and finance compiles and features what could be worth being researched further in an integrated manner. Every single entry in the encyclopedia represents a wider area where further research can be employed. What the researchers are expected to do is to pick one, identify the potential correlations and overlaps between different subjects and to draw a roadmap accordingly. </span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><b><span><span>Timetable:</span></span></b></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span>This work is to be completed in June 2023, as stipulated under the terms of a publication contract with Palgrave. The study features more than 400 entries, ranging from length of 500 to 5,000 words, depending on their significance. Even though a substantial part of the entries has already been solicited, there are still others open to expression of interest by the wider academic community. Inquiries on the list of the entries and their availability should be forwarded to </span></span><a href="mailto:apply.encyclopedia.ife@gmail.com"><span><span><span>apply.encyclopedia.ife@gmail.com</span></span></span></a><span>, along with a brief summary of personal information. Further details will be communicated with those showing interest in this project. </span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span>Editors:</span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span>Prof. Dr. Murat Ustaoğlu, Istanbul University</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Prof. Dr. Cenap Çakmak, Anadolu University</span></span></span></p><p> </p><p> </p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Interested parties may send their inquiries along with a brief CV to the following email addresses:</p><p>Cenap Cakmak, <a href="mailto:cenapcakmak75@gmail.com">cenapcakmak75@gmail.com</a></p><p>Also <a href="mailto:apply.encyclopedia.ife@gmail.com">apply.encyclopedia.ife@gmail.com</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:apply.encyclopedia.ife@gmail.com">apply.encyclopedia.ife@gmail.com</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 17:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666762628505353</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>National Library of Australia Fellowship presentation: Dr Sugata Nandi - ‘Spiritualist West, Magical Orient: Theosophists and India, 1875-1930’.</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11431759/national-library-australia-fellowship-presentation-dr-sugata</link>
						<dc:creator>Sharyn O'Brien</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-27T00:00:00-04:00">October 27, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Australia</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Asian History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span>The National Library of Australia invites you to join us online or in person for our latest Fellowship presentation by 2020 NLA Fellowship recipient Dr Sugata Nandi.  </span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><strong><span><span>Dr Sugata Nandi: ‘Spiritualist West, Magical Orient: Theosophists and India, 1875-1930’.  </span></span></strong></span></span></p><p><span><span><strong><span><span>Thursday October 27th, 2022.  </span></span></strong></span></span></p><p><span><span><strong><span><span>12.30pm AEDT. </span></span></strong></span></span></p><p><span><span><strong><span><span>Join online here: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/National.Library.of.Australia" rel="nofollow">National Library’s Facebook page</a>. </span></span></strong></span></span></p><p><span><span><strong><span><span>In person: National Library of Australia, Parkes Place. Lower Ground 1 Theatre. </span></span></strong></span></span></p><p><span><span><strong><span><span>This event is free and open to the public. A recording will be made available after the event on the <a href="https://www.nla.gov.au/stories/all?type%5Bvideo%5D=video" rel="nofollow">National Library’s website</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/NationalLibraryofAustralia/playlists" rel="nofollow">YouTube</a> channel. </span></span></strong></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span>Join Dr Sugata Nandi as he presents his 2020 National Library Fellowship research on theosophists and India from 1875 to 1930, and the resulting new interpretations and uses of Hinduism and Buddhism. </span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>In 1879, Helena Petrovna Blavatsky (1831-91), an émigré Russia noblewoman, and Henry Steel Olcott (1832-1907), an American, reached India in search of knowledge of her two religions, Hinduism and Buddhism. In 1875 they had founded The Theosophical Society in New York, a spiritualist organisation that, by the 1900s, enjoyed a global presence and had turned Western esoteric quests to India and her two religions, Hinduism and Buddhism. Their quest led to radically new interpretations and uses of the religions which gave rise to a new, diverse and highly controversial body of knowledge on India as the proverbial Magical Orient. </span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><strong><span><span>About Dr Sugata Nandi </span></span></strong></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Dr Sugata Nandi is Assistant Professor of History at the West Bengal State University, Kolkata, India, where he teaches Modern Indian History, the Industrial Revolution, Western Historiography and Research Methodology. He has been a visiting research fellow at the Institute for Advanced Studies in the Humanities of the University of Edinburgh (2018), Senate House Library Visiting Research Fellow at London University (2019) and a Fulbright–Nehru Doctoral and Professional Research Fellow at the University of Washington, Seattle, USA (2011-12). He has recently been awarded the Junior Fellowship at the Institute for Advanced Study of Central European University, Budapest, which he will commence in early 2023.</span></span></span></span></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:fellowships@nla.gov.au">fellowships@nla.gov.au</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 17:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666762628505352</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Christianity &amp; Culture Conference: The Family, Past &amp; Future</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11427802/christianity-culture-conference-family-past-future</link>
						<dc:creator>David Davis</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-03T00:00:00-05:00">February 3, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-04T00:00:00-05:00">February 4, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Texas</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Humanities, Literature, Philosophy, Religious Studies and Theology, Social Sciences</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The inaugural Christianity and Culture Conference at Houston Christian University (formerly Houston Baptist University) seeks to highlight the importance of the Family in the Western Tradition by exploring the different representations, significations, and roles of the Family. The conference will provide a cross-disciplinary venue to consider the past and future importance of the Family, particularly from a Christian perspective, that is evident in literature, philosophy, history, science, art, and religion.</p><p>Keynote Speaker: Dr. Mark Regnerus, Professor of Sociology (University of Texas at Austin): <a href="https://www.markregnerus.com/" rel="nofollow">https://www.markregnerus.com/</a></p><p> </p><p><strong>Panel and Paper Proposals</strong></p><p>Proposals may include academic papers/presentations from a variety of liberal arts and social sciences, as well as creative presentations (e.g. artwork, poetry readings, etc.) that illustrate the importance of the Family. Proposals emphasizing cross-disciplinarity are particularly encouraged.</p><p>Topics for proposals may include:</p><ul><li>Representations of the Family in literature and art</li><li>Changes to the notion of the Family over time</li><li>The Family and religious practice</li><li>Religious beliefs and Family values</li><li>Cultural and sociological changes to the Family</li><li>Philosophical issues related to the Family</li><li>Comparative studies of the Family</li></ul><p>Proposals from graduate and undergraduate students are welcome. </p><p><strong>Deadline for proposals is December 16, 2022. </strong></p><p>Proposal abstracts should be 200-300 words. Please email submissions and questions to Dr. David Davis: <a href="mailto:ddavis@hbu.edu">ddavis@hbu.edu</a>.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ddavis@hbu.edu">ddavis@hbu.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://hbu.edu/arts-humanities/events/christianity-and-culture-conference/" target="_blank">https://hbu.edu/arts-humanities/events/christianity-and-culture-conference/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 17:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666762628505351</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>&quot;Making the law. The role of religious women in the construction of law in the Viceroyalty of Peru in the eighteenth century&quot;</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11424567/making-law-role-religious-women-construction-law-viceroyalty</link>
						<dc:creator>Sarah Barthélemy</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Seminar</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-26T00:00:00-04:00">October 26, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology, Early Modern History and Period Studies, Latin American and Caribbean History / Studies, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><em>Despite the existence of several studies related to religious institutions and their regulations in the Hispanic monarchy, the histories of the principal actors in the case of Peru have been largely forgotten. This paper will bring to light the process of creating ecclesiastical regulations for the control and government of the female religious houses of Lima in the eighteenth century, paying special attention to the role played by both the ecclesiastical authorities and female religious, who were, far from being mere recipients of dictates, essential for the construction of these regulations.</em></p><p>D﻿r Liliana Pérez Miguel is a María Zambrano postdoctoral researcher at the Universidad de Sevilla.</p><p>This is part of the ISHWRA (<a href="https://www.durham.ac.uk/research/institutes-and-centres/catholic-studies/research/history-of-catholicism-/history-of-women-religious-association/" rel="nofollow">International Scholars of the History of Women Religious Association - Durham University</a>) Seminar Series 2022-2023.</p><h3>Date and time</h3><p>Wed, 26 Oct 2022, 13:00 BST</p><h3>Location</h3><p>Online</p><p> </p><p>Please register at: <a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/ishwra-seminar-october-2022-tickets-431607167657" rel="nofollow">ISHWRA Seminar October 2022 Tickets, Wed 26 Oct 2022 at 13:00 | Eventbrite</a></p><p>(You will receive the link to the seminar after registering)</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:sarah.barthelemy@durham.ac.uk">sarah.barthelemy@durham.ac.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/ishwra-seminar-october-2022-tickets-431607167657" target="_blank">https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/ishwra-seminar-october-2022-tickets-431607167657</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 17:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666676230608999</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Papers: Yale Journal of Music &amp; Religion special issue: Sacred Recitation and Ritual in Digital Worlds</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11412212/call-papers-yale-journal-music-religion-special-issue-sacred</link>
						<dc:creator>Joanna Murdoch</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-01-15T00:00:00-05:00">January 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Digital Humanities, Islamic History / Studies, Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Music and Music History</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Call for Papers: Sacred Recitation and Ritual in Digital Worlds</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The Yale Journal of Music &amp; Religion will publish a special issue on sacred recitation in digital worlds guest edited by Anne K. Rasmussen. We invite submissions documenting and interpreting routes of transmission and access, ritual communities, novel uses of media and technologies, and transformations of religious identities through the intersections of voice, scripture, and sacred text in digital worlds. As sacred recitation is performed and received in spatially and temporally dispersed spaces, this special issue seeks to understand the relationships of religion, media, and technology in their contemporary and emergent forms. Relevant topics include learning and listening; the consolidation of media and recitation styles; responses to the Covid pandemic; digital methods in historical research; diaspora and displacement; institutions, traditions, and identities; religious adaptations of digital technologies; and religious publics and politics.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Deadline for submissions: January 15, 2023 at <a href="https://elischolar.library.yale.edu/yjmr/" rel="nofollow"><span>https://elischolar.library.yale.edu/yjmr/</span></a></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Questions? Please contact guest editor Anne K. Rasmussen (<a href="mailto:akrasm@wm.edu"><span>akrasm@wm.edu</span></a>) or editor-in-chief Jeffers Engelhardt (<a href="mailto:jengelhardt@amherst.edu"><span>jengelhardt@amherst.edu</span></a>)</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Joanna Murdoch</p><p>Managing Editor, Yale Journal of Music &amp; Religion</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:joanna.murdoch@yale.edu">joanna.murdoch@yale.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="http://ism.yale.edu/yjmr" target="_blank">http://ism.yale.edu/yjmr</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 17:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666676230608998</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Hagiography Society Article Prize</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11398608/hagiography-society-article-prize</link>
						<dc:creator>Catherine Mooney</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Prize</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-22T00:00:00-04:00">October 22, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-01-15T00:00:00-05:00">January 15, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>European History / Studies, Islamic History / Studies, Jewish History / Studies, Medieval and Byzantine History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>This prize will be awarded to a scholarly essay or article written on any disciplinary subject that makes an outstanding contribution to the study and understanding of saints, holy men and women, virtue traditions, and the concept of sanctity in ideational, literary, artistic, and sociohistorical dimensions in the pre-modern period. Articles concerning all geographies and religious systems are eligible. The monetary value of the prize is $300. The author of the article must be a member of the (very affordable) Hagiography Society by the time of the article’s submission. All essays and articles that have been published in 2021 and 2022 are eligible for the prize. The submission deadline is Jan. 15, 2023. An electronic copy of your article should be sent to the President of the Hagiography Society, Catherine M. Mooney.  Email: <a href="mailto:catherine.mooney@bc.edu">catherine.mooney@bc.edu</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Catherine M. Mooney, President, The Hagiography Society</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:catherine.mooney@bc.edu">catherine.mooney@bc.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.hagiographysociety.org/" target="_blank">https://www.hagiographysociety.org/?page_id=265</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 17:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666676230608997</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Travel Award for grad student giving paper on saints/hagiography at 2023 International Congress on Medieval Studies</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11398604/travel-award-grad-student-giving-paper-saintshagiography-2023</link>
						<dc:creator>Catherine Mooney</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Prize</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-22T00:00:00-04:00">October 22, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-15T00:00:00-05:00">November 15, 2022</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><strong>The Sherry L. Reames Graduate Student Travel Award for Hagiographical Studies</strong></p><p>Named in honor of the beloved founder and long-time leader of the Society, the award now provides up to $1000 to be used toward registration, travel, lodging, and meals to present a paper at the International Congress on Medieval Studies, held annually at Western Michigan University in Kalamazoo, MI. The winners will be granted a free two-year membership in the Hagiography Society.</p><p><strong>Eligibility</strong></p><p>Students who are Hagiography Society members and enrolled in a graduate program (anywhere in the world) are eligible to apply if their paper, on a topic involving hagiography, has been accepted for inclusion on a regular panel (not a round table or other format) in the program of the International Congress on Medieval Studies in Kalamazoo, MI, at the time of application. They are also expected to attend the annual Hagiography Society Business Meeting held at the International Congress on Medieval Studies.</p><p><strong>Application</strong></p><p>Please submit the attached form with a current curriculum vitæ (combined in a single PDF with your last name in the document name) by November 15 to the Secretary / Treasurer of the Hagiography Society (<a href="mailto:secretary@hagiographysociety.org">secretary@hagiographysociety.org</a>).</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Secretary / Treasurer of The Hagiography Society</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:secretary@hagiographysociety.org">secretary@hagiographysociety.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.hagiographysociety.org/" target="_blank">https://www.hagiographysociety.org/?page_id=265</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 17:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666676230608996</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mapping the Spiritual Baptist Universe: Black Atlantic Cosmography and the Spatial Dimensions of Religious Imagination in Trinidad and Tobago</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11398280/mapping-spiritual-baptist-universe-black-atlantic-cosmography</link>
						<dc:creator>Jeanne Kilde</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-27T00:00:00-04:00">October 27, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Minnesota</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>African American History / Studies, Anthropology, Black History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Colonial and Post-Colonial History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Join us for the Roetzel Family Lecture in Religious Studies.  Ethnographer and religious studies scholar Brendan Jamal Thornton will discuss his research on Spiritual Baptists in Trinidad and Tobago, focusing on their unique, trans-global cosmography. Thornton examines the locational metaphors orienting local creole cosmologies and considers in detail the spatial dimentions that inform their ritual logics. By diagramming the Spiritual Baptist universe and the sacred geography of Spirit that enlivens it, he shows how churchgoers reconciled diverse religious influences (from Africa, South Asia, Europe, and beyond) and probes for cosmolgraphical clues to their sybolically rich but often enigmatic rites and traditions.  </p><p>This event is offered both in-person on the University of Minnesota campus and as a simulcast Webinar.  Thursday, October 27, 2022, 3:30 pm (CDT). </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Jeanne H. Kilde, Director of the Religious Studies Program</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:jkilde@umn.edu">jkilde@umn.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://events.tc.umn.edu/event/9335-mapping-the-spiritual-baptist-universe" target="_blank">https://events.tc.umn.edu/event/9335-mapping-the-spiritual-baptist-universe</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 17:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666676230608995</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
