<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 12:19:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 12:19:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ September 15, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: The Religious Roots of Environmental Justice</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/113082</link>
						<description><p><strong>When:</strong> Friday, October 13, 2023</p>
<p><strong>Where</strong>: Online (Zoom) – Registration Required</p>
<p><strong>Submission deadline for proposals:</strong> Friday, September 15, 2023</p>
<p><strong>Queries</strong></p>
<p><em>Call for Papers or Presentations</em></p>
<p><em>The Journal for Cultural and Religious Theory</em> and <em>The New Polis,</em> in co-operation with the University of Denver announces an upcoming<em> one-day, online conference</em> on “The Religious Roots of Environmental Justice” to be held Friday, October 13, 2023.  The two academic journals are published by The Whitestone Foundation, a Colorado-registered 501(c)3 non-profit corporation.</p>
<p>The concept of “environmental justice” is a relatively recent addition to the discourses of religious and political theory.  According to the Office of Legacy Management with the Department of Energy, environmental justice can be defined as “the fair treatment and meaningful involvement of all people, regardless of race, color, national origin, or income, with respect to the development, implementation, and enforcement of environmental laws, regulations, and policies.” </p>
<p>However, such laws are not <em>sui generis</em>, but have been elaborated in relatively recent times to long-standing spiritual attitudes and value propositions concerning what ought to be the human relationship to, and the character of our collective responsibility for, the natural order.  Virtually all of the world’s historical as well as indigenous religious traditions harbor both implicit and explicit views about how human and non-human beings should cohabit as well as interact with each other. </p>
<p>The overriding question for the conference is <em>in what specific ways do these traditions both inform and compel specific policies as well as ethical practices that constitute the spectrum of social action that counts as “environmental justice”.</em></p>
<p>The following kinds of questions may be considered in framing proposals, although they are not even remotely exhaustive.  They include:</p>
<ul>
<li>What does “environmental justice” mean in a broader sense than its juridical application?</li>
<li>What role should religious people play in environmental politics?</li>
<li>Shoulsd we pay environmental “reparations” to injured parties or species, and what might they look like?</li>
<li>What do specific religious traditions have to say about environmental justice? </li>
<li>What constructive steps can be taken to better marry environmental ethics with religious thinking?</li>
<li>Why is environmental theology still a marginalized sector of religious reflection, and what can be done to bring attention to this issue?</li>
<li>In what ways can the worlds religious communities enlist themselves towards revolutionary solutions regarding  the entwined crises of the Anthropocene</li>
<li>What views from spiritual traditions can expand the horizon of our environmental imagination?</li>
<li>How can indigenous resistance to governmental and corporate incursions on their land provide wisdom and inspiration for new approaches to environmental justice activism and policy?</li>
<li>In what ways can environmentally sensitive theological discussions break through the customary boundaries of ‘religious issues’ in political life?</li>
<li>Can environmental initiatives become a rallying point for interfaith conversations?</li>
<li>How do specific religious beliefs or doctrines (e.g.,  the Jewish concept of <em>tikkun olam</em>, or “repairing of the world”) support and even compel effective strategies of environmental activism?</li>
<li>How do certain monotheistic eschatologies, or “end of the world” beliefs, clash with or support the objectives of environmental justice?</li>
<li>Do the Abrahamic religions shy away from environmentalism because of the fear that the movement flirts too much with “paganism”?</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Submission Procedures</em></p>
<p>Participants are invited to submit proposals for papers, panels, or presentations to be included in the programming no later than Sept. 15, although earlier submissions are encouraged.   Notification of acceptance will be communicated within a week after submission, or no later than Sept. 15. </p>
<p>Submission of proposals, however, is encouraged well in advance of the August deadline.   Queries as well as proposals should contain the header “Conference on the Religious Roots of Environmental Justice. Length allotted for presentations will depend on the number of actually accepted. Proposals should include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Name</li>
<li>Working title of paper or presentation</li>
<li>Type (e.g., lecture, panel, video, formal paper)</li>
<li>Email address</li>
<li>Telephone number with country code</li>
<li>Professional title</li>
<li>Institutional affiliation (if none, please submit a short bio with degrees attained and names of degree-granting institutions)</li>
<li>500-800 word abstract or synopsis</li>
</ul>
<p>Following the conference, participants will be invited to submit within four months a final version of their paper or presentation for publication in the <em>Journal for Cultural and Religious Theory</em> and/or <em>The New Polis</em>. Both journals are peer-reviewed.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 05:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1689313025371699</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ October 13, 2023] Conference or similar: The Religious Roots of Environmental Justice</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/113078</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p><em>The Journal for Cultural and Religious Theory</em> and <em>The New Polis,</em> in co-operation with the University of Denver announces an upcoming<em> one-day, online conference</em> on “The Religious Roots of Environmental Justice” to be held Friday, October 13, 2023.  The two academic journals are published by The Whitestone Foundation, a Colorado-registered 501(c)3 non-profit corporation.</p>
<p>The concept of “environmental justice” is a relatively recent addition to the discourses of religious and political theory.  According to the Office of Legacy Management with the Department of Energy, environmental justice can be defined as “the fair treatment and meaningful involvement of all people, regardless of race, color, national origin, or income, with respect to the development, implementation, and enforcement of environmental laws, regulations, and policies.” </p>
<p>However, such laws are not <em>sui generis</em>, but have been elaborated in relatively recent times to long-standing spiritual attitudes and value propositions concerning what ought to be the human relationship to, and the character of our collective responsibility for, the natural order.  Virtually all of the world’s historical as well as indigenous religious traditions harbor both implicit and explicit views about how human and non-human beings should cohabit as well as interact with each other. </p>
<p>The overriding question for the conference is <em>in what specific ways do these traditions both inform and compel specific policies as well as ethical practices that constitute the spectrum of social action that counts as “environmental justice”.</em></p>
<p>The following kinds of questions may be considered in framing proposals, although they are not even remotely exhaustive.  They include:</p>
<ul>
<li>What does “environmental justice” mean in a broader sense than its juridical application?</li>
<li>What role should religious people play in environmental politics?</li>
<li>Shoulsd we pay environmental “reparations” to injured parties or species, and what might they look like?</li>
<li>What do specific religious traditions have to say about environmental justice? </li>
<li>What constructive steps can be taken to better marry environmental ethics with religious thinking?</li>
<li>Why is environmental theology still a marginalized sector of religious reflection, and what can be done to bring attention to this issue?</li>
<li>In what ways can the worlds religious communities enlist themselves towards revolutionary solutions regarding  the entwined crises of the Anthropocene</li>
<li>What views from spiritual traditions can expand the horizon of our environmental imagination?</li>
<li>How can indigenous resistance to governmental and corporate incursions on their land provide wisdom and inspiration for new approaches to environmental justice activism and policy?</li>
<li>In what ways can environmentally sensitive theological discussions break through the customary boundaries of ‘religious issues’ in political life?</li>
<li>Can environmental initiatives become a rallying point for interfaith conversations?</li>
<li>How do specific religious beliefs or doctrines (e.g.,  the Jewish concept of <em>tikkun olam</em>, or “repairing of the world”) support and even compel effective strategies of environmental activism?</li>
<li>How do certain monotheistic eschatologies, or “end of the world” beliefs, clash with or support the objectives of environmental justice?</li>
<li>Do the Abrahamic religions shy away from environmentalism because of the fear that the movement flirts too much with “paganism”?</li>
</ul></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 05:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1689313025371698</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>“Gain through Loss: Accruing Spiritual Wealth from Voluntary Poverty”</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/07/13/%E2%80%9Cgain-through-loss-accruing-spiritual-wealth-from-voluntary-poverty%E2%80%9D</link>
						<dc:creator>mwgeorge.51@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, July 13, 2023 - 12:01pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Illinois Medieval Association</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:fgrabowski@rsu.edu">fgrabowski@rsu.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/medieval">medieval</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/online-conferences">online conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>November 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>Illinois Medieval Association Symposium<br/></strong><strong>“Gain through Loss: Accruing Spiritual Wealth from Voluntary Poverty”<br/></strong><strong>Organizer: Francis A. Grabowski III<br/></strong><strong>January 26, 2024, 3:00 pm Central, online</strong></p>
<p>In response to the great expansion of wealth in Europe during the eleventh and twelfth centuries arose movements dedicated, ironically, to its renunciation. Francesco Bernardone (St. Francis of Assisi) is unquestionably the most notable medieval mendicant, yet he was but one of many who traded their conventional prosperity for evangelical poverty. Although it is easy to lump these movements together and treat them as though they were fundamentally the same, they were unique in terms of their origins, geographies, values, and receptions. This panel seeks to investigate those medieval movements committed to voluntary poverty in their varying forms and expressions, collectively or individually, and the figureheads that inspired them. The session is free and online</p>
<p>Send proposals of no longer than 300 words to <a href="mailto:fgrabowski@rsu.edu">fgrabowski@rsu.edu</a> no later than November 15, 2023.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 13:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1689313025371697</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Theology and Religion in Daredevil</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/07/12/theology-and-religion-in-daredevil</link>
						<dc:creator>radicalt</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, July 13, 2023 - 11:54am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Fortress Press &amp; Lexington Books, Theology, Religion and Pop Culture Series</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:radicalt@bu.edu">radicalt@bu.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/film-and-television">film and television</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/general-announcements">general announcements</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/popular-culture">popular culture</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>July 30, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>Title:</strong> Faith, Morality, and the Man without Fear: Theology and Religion in Daredevil</p>
<p><strong>Editors:</strong> Taylor Thomas and Regan Hardeman</p>
<p><strong>Abstract, CV, and Proposal due:</strong> July 30, 2023</p>
<p><strong>Initial Final Paper due:</strong> November 15, 2023</p>
<p>Created by Stan Lee, Bill Everett, and Jack Kirby in 1964, Daredevil is a triumph in comic book writing that provocatively combines the holy militancy of John Brown with the impassioned jurisprudence of Thurgood Marshall. Matt Murdock, commonly known as the blind lawyer from Hell’s Kitchen in the series, upholds the law while Daredevil, Murdock’s masked persona, breaks it when the justice system fails. Murdock’s costumed crusade has long been inextricably connected to a fragile, yet enduring, Christian worldview he engages, and often questions, throughout the series. This distinctively religious element of the character drives nuanced storylines that explore moral, theological, and interpersonal conflicts and raise existential questions about value, purpose, and the threat of nihilism in a seemingly godless world. In Faith, Morality, and the Man without Fear: Theology and Religion in Daredevil, scholars from various specializations related to the study of theology and religion will be invited to examine philosophical,  theological, and religious themes and concepts as they have appeared within the now almost sixty-year-long multimedia world of Daredevil.</p>
<p>The goal of Faith, Morality, and the Man without Fear is to engage interdisciplinary perspectives on topics ranging from (1) theodicy, metaphysics, epistemology, and axiology to (2) theological and ethical reflections on violence, pacifism, and moral duty. The editors want to continue uplifting comic and graphic novels as a narrative art that rewards scholarly analysis. The volume will be thematically grouped along three primary themes of inquiry: (1) Philosophy, theology, and ethics, (2) identity, embodiment, and recognition, and (3) religion, society, and the law. As such, we are seeking scholars from a variety of backgrounds and disciplines who can help us in our goal of designing a multi-author volume that is diverse in its content and broadly accessible to general audiences interested in theology and religion, while maintaining the scholarly merit required to be used as supplementary material in introductory level theology and religion courses. We ask that potential contributors explore Daredevil as the character has appeared both on and, very importantly, off the screen.</p>
<p>Potential Topics:</p>
<p>Freedom and Destiny</p>
<p>Law and Order</p>
<p>Justice and Mercy/Forgiveness and Judgement</p>
<p>Faith and Doubt</p>
<p>Violence and Pacifism</p>
<p>Morality and Virtue</p>
<p>Friendship and Fellowship</p>
<p>Parenthood and Mentorship</p>
<p>Vocation/Calling</p>
<p>Duty and Desire</p>
<p>Sacred Spaces</p>
<p>Love and Hate</p>
<p>Trauma and Restoration </p>
<p>Belonging and Acceptance</p>
<p>Politics and Religion</p>
<p>Religion and the Occult</p>
<p> 
</p><p>Aesthetics</p>
<p>The Nature of Good and Evil</p>
<p>Identity (Religious, Racial, Sexual, Gender, etc.)/Disability and Bodies</p>
<p>Domination and Liberation</p>
<p>Race and Racism/Gender and Sexuality</p>
<p>Timeframes: Please send a 250-300 word abstract, a paper proposal of up to 1000 words, and a current CV to <a href="mailto:radicalt@bu.edu">radicalt@bu.edu</a>. Acceptance notifications will be sent out by September 15,  2023. Full manuscripts will be capped at 6000 words a piece and due on November 15, 2023. The completed volume will be sent to the publisher on June 1, 2024.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 15:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1689313025371696</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ October 1, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: 2024 Meeting of the Society for Philosophy of Religion</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/113006</link>
						<description><p>2024 Meeting of the Society for Philosophy of Religion</p>
<p>March 7-9, 2024 at the Omni Hilton Head Oceanfront Resort in Hilton Head Island, SC.</p>
<p>Call for papers: Papers on any topic in philosophy of religion, broadly construed, are invited for submission to the annual meeting for the Society for Philosophy of Religion.</p>
<p>To be considered, your paper should be prepared for blind review. Make sure that the paper you submit can be read within the 40-minute time limit. Also note that we expect the paper read at the meeting not to deviate from the paper that is accepted. If you wish to propose a panel discussion, please send a proposal explaining the topic, with the names of the persons who have agreed to participate on the panel if it is selected for the program.</p>
<p>We welcome submissions from scholars interested in joining the SPR.  Membership is not a requirement to present, but we encourage any presenter to consider joining the Society. The SPR membership is open to anyone doing what may be considered “philosophy of religion”, broadly construed, no matter one’s religious/philosophical views or lack thereof. The aim is to develop a collegial membership from a range of philosophical, theological, and religious traditions, methodologies, and views. Please visit the SPR website (<a href="http://www.societyphilosophyreligion.org/">http://www.societyphilosophyreligion.org/</a>) for more information about the Society’s history, past programs, and so on.</p>
<p>Please submit your paper via email to <a href="mailto:tlytle@piedmont.edu">tlytle@piedmont.edu</a>.</p>
<p>The deadline for submission is October 1st, 2023.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1689140228689169</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ March 7, 2024 -  March 9, 2024] Conference or similar: 2024 Meeting of the Society for Philosophy of Religion</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/113002</link>
						<description>Venue: 23 Ocean Ln<br/><br/></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 05:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1689140228689168</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP: Northeast Popular/American Culture Association’s (NEPCA) Folklore, Belief and Religion Area invites proposals for the Fall Virtual Conference October 12 – October 14, 2023</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/07/08/cfp-northeast-popularamerican-culture-association%E2%80%99s-nepca-folklore-belief-and</link>
						<dc:creator>angela.whyland6@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, July 11, 2023 - 4:21pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Northeast Popular/American Culture Association</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:angela.whyland6@gmail.com">angela.whyland6@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/graduate-conferences">graduate conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/online-conferences">online conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/popular-culture">popular culture</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>August 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>The <strong>Northeast Popular/American Culture Association’s Folklore, Belief and Religion </strong>Area<strong> </strong>welcomes paper submissions for NEPCA’s 2023 <strong>fall virtual conference</strong> will be held <strong>October 12 – October 14, 2023, </strong>via Zoom. The deadline for proposals is <strong>August 1, 2023</strong>.  </p>
<p> </p>
<p>This Area creates a wide net to examine the intersection of religion/ myth/fairy tale/ folklore in popular American and global culture. “Religion” here is not limited to institutionalized expressions or formal practices but also encompasses the interface with popular culture of religion as a range of beliefs and practices, identities and narratives that also find expression in performances and performative spaces (theater), in forms of music, art, dance, and film. Myth, Fairy Tale, and Folklore are similarly expansive concepts and, like Religion, cut across geographical and chronological boundaries.  Papers may be drawn from a range of disciplines and methodologies and papers that express new conceptualizations of the area themes are also welcome.</p>
<p>Themes in some recent papers include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Folk religion and non-mainstream practices</li>
<li>Religious themes in adolescent literature</li>
<li>Folkloric beliefs and practices evidenced in popular culture</li>
<li>Religious themes in American politics and popular media (TV)</li>
</ul>
<p>Papers that address the intersection of religion/ belief/ folk motifs and politics (across time and geographies) are especially welcome.</p>
<p>If you have questions about this area, please reach out to the Folklore, Belief and Religion Chair: June-Ann Greeley, PhD - Sacred Heart University at <a href="mailto:greeleyj@sacredheart.edu">greeleyj@sacredheart.edu</a></p>
<p>Visit the <a href="https://nepca.blog/2023-annual-conference/">Conference Page</a> for more information about the conference, submission of abstracts and registration.</p>
<p>The deadline for the submission of abstracts is <strong>August 1, 2023</strong>.  <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeO-F5k26QxGQC08UY2E9axop4CCMoi3gNXqUhCPjD0EodjUA/viewform">Please use this form</a>. </p>
<p> </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 00:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1689140228689167</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Religious Origins of White Supremacy: Johnson v. M’Intosh and the Doctrine of Christian Discovery.</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/07/05/the-religious-origins-of-white-supremacy-johnson-v-m%E2%80%99intosh-and-the-doctrine-of</link>
						<dc:creator>adam@adamdjbrett.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, July 11, 2023 - 4:17pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Syracuse University Department of Religion &amp; Indigenous Values Initiative</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:info@indigenousvalues.org">info@indigenousvalues.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/african-american">african-american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/rhetoric-and-composition">rhetoric and composition</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>August 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Details
</p><ul>
<li>The conference will take place at Syracuse University from 8-10 December 2023.</li>
</ul>
<p>Sponsored by:
</p><ul>
<li>Henry Luce Foundation</li>
<li>Syracuse University</li>
</ul>
<p>Description
</p><p>In the 1823 US Supreme Court decision, <a href="https://www.oyez.org/cases/1789-1850/21us543"><em>Johnson v M'Intosh</em></a>, Chief Justice John Marshall wrote,"...discovery gave title to government...[and] the sole right of acquiring the soil from the natives." This decision underpins US property law. Marshall's deliberate use of the word "discovery" is an intentional reference to 15th Century Catholic Papal Bulls, which stated that any Christian who "discovers" a land populated by non-Christians has superior title, or rights of ownership, over that land. In essence, <em>Johnson</em> codifies into US law the principle of Euro-Christian domination over Indigenous Peoples. In the most devastating sense, the Doctrine of Christian Discovery (DoCD) legitimized exploitation, extraction, and enslavement globally and enshrined these practices as the basis of U.S. property law still cited today as recently as 2005 (in <a href="https://www.oyez.org/cases/2004/03-855"><em>Sherrill v. Oneida</em></a>) and 2020 (<a href="https://www.oyez.org/cases/2019/18-9526"><em>McGirt v. Oklahoma</em></a>).</p>
<p>In the 200th year of <em>Johnson</em>, there is an urgent need for global recognition of the decision's implications as reifying the DoCD and its exploitation of Indigenous Peoples and their connection to land, regarded as a living being (Mother Earth in English.) This conference builds on the history of collaboration at Syracuse University with Indigenous communities across Central New York by expanding dissemination of the pernicious ideologies of DOCD and <em>Johnson</em>, leading to further repudiation of these ideologies and towards healing and repair.</p>
<p>The project's key collaborators include <a href="https://syracuse.edu/">Syracuse University</a>, <a href="https://aila.ngo/">American Indian Law Alliance (AILA)</a>, <a href="https://indigenousvalues.org/">Indigenous Values Initiative (IVI)</a>, The <a href="https://www.skanonhcenter.org/">Skä-noñh -- Great Law of Peace Center</a>, and others. For more see the <a href="https://doctrineofdiscovery.org/">Doctrine of Discovery Project site (doctrineofdiscovery.org)</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://doctrineofdiscovery.org/assets/images/Religious-Origins-of-White-Supremacy-Flyer.png"></a> Event flyer. <a href="https://doctrineofdiscovery.org/assets/images/Religious-Origins-of-White-Supremacy-Flyer.png" rel="noopener" target="_blank">⤓ Download Image</a>, <a href="https://doctrineofdiscovery.org/assets/pdfs/CFP-Religious-Origins-Conference-Flyer-8.5x11-rev2.pdf" rel="noopener" target="_blank">⤓ Download PDF</a>.</p>
<p>Call for Papers
</p><p>We are interested in paper and session proposals from scholars, students, activists, artists, lawyers, policymakers, religious leaders, Indigenous leaders, and more. Our conference seeks to bring together a broad coalition of people working on examining not only the Doctrine of Christian Discovery but also the religious origins of white supremacy.</p>
<p>Downloads
</p><ul>
<li><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/assets/images/Religious-Origins-of-White-Supremacy-Flyer.png">Flyer image</a></li>
<li><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/assets/pdfs/CFP-Religious-Origins-Conference-Flyer-8.5x11-rev2.pdf">Flyer PDF</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Thematic Panels
</p><p>We are interested in creating thematic panels on the following topics:</p>
<ul>
<li>Religious Racism</li>
<li>White Christian Nationalism</li>
<li>What are the mythic origins of white supremacy within the Doctrine of Christian Discovery (DoCD)?</li>
<li>International implications of <em>Johnson v. M'Intosh</em></li>
<li>International implications of the DoCD and white supremacy</li>
<li>The continuing impact of <em>Johnson,</em> DoCD, and white supremacy on Indigenous peoples</li>
<li>Continuing Environmental impact of <em>Johnson,</em> DoCD, and white supremacy</li>
<li>The rise of Christian Nationalism around the world</li>
<li>Religious dimensions of racism</li>
<li>Religious repudiations and resistance the DoCD</li>
<li>Legal resistance to <em>Johnson</em> and the DoCD?</li>
<li>How do we address and resist <em>Johnson</em> and settler colonialism today?</li>
</ul>
<p>Paper Submission Instructions
</p><ul>
<li>Please send in a 300-word abstract of your paper and/or panel</li>
<li>CV/Resume</li>
<li>Proposals should be received by August 15</li>
<li>Acceptance notices will be sent on September 1</li>
<li>Papers from graduate students are encouraged.</li>
<li>Undergraduate panels with a professor are also encouraged.</li>
<li>For questions please email Prof. Philip P. Arnold at <a href="mailto:info@indigenousvalues.org">info@indigenousvalues.org</a></li>
<li>All submissions msut be via <a href="https://forms.gle/cZ1ZiUUbQ4BDXykU8">the form</a> on</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://forms.gle/cZ1ZiUUbQ4BDXykU8">Paper Submissions</a></p>
<p>Call for ArtistsEligibility:
</p><p>There are no hard restrictions on genre, subject matter, or media; however, we ask artists to keep the conference theme and description in mind when creating and/or selecting work for submission. The artwork must also be suitable or print-friendly for posters, promotional graphics, conference programs, etc.</p>
<p>There are no age restrictions. Artists of all ages may submit their work. For artists under the age of eighteen (18), parent or legal guardian permission is required.</p>
<p>Compensation and Transfer of Ownership:
</p><p>Each artist whose piece is selected for exhibition will receive a one-time payment of $1,500.00 USD. As part of this payment, artists will be required to sign an agreement transferring ownership of their piece (including any copyrights) to the Indigenous Values Initiative (IVI).</p>
<p>Artist will also receive one (1) conference pass to attend any and all conference sessions.</p>
<p>During the conference our distinguished jurists, other invited jurists, as well conference participants, will vote and select the best in show piece. There will be three awards given of first, second and third prize.</p>
<ul>
<li>First Prize -- $5,000 USD</li>
<li>Second Prize -- $3,000 USD</li>
<li>Third Prize -- $2,000 USD</li>
</ul>
<p>Submission requirements:
</p><ul>
<li>Artists may submit one piece of artwork for consideration.</li>
<li>Each submission must include a description of the artwork, detailing inspiration, medium, process of creation, physical dimensions.</li>
<li>Submitted artwork must be of high-resolution quality (300 DPI, .jpeg or .png recommended). If applicable, please include a layered version (.ai, psd, .indd) of the artwork</li>
<li>Digital Submission of Works by November 1</li>
<li>Artist Selection and Notification by November 15</li>
<li>If selected physical objects must be received by November 30 All selected artworks will be exhibited during the conference at Syracuse University from Dec 8-10.</li>
</ul>
<p>If you have questions, please email Prof. Philip P. Arnold at <a href="mailto:info@indigenousvalues.org">info@indigenousvalues.org</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://syracuseuniversity.qualtrics.com/jfe/form/SV_5u4auzuwe7xvRjw">Submissions</a></p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 21:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1689140228689166</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
