<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 03:41:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 03:41:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>New Podcast - En-Gender Conversations</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11039181/new-podcast-en-gender-conversations</link>
						<dc:creator>Jessica  Albrecht</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Online Digital Resources</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Colonial and Post-Colonial History / Studies, Indigenous Studies, Race / Ethnic Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The En-Gender Collective now publishes a podcast, called "En-Gender Conversations".</p><p>It is available on spotify, apple podcasts and via our feed (<a href="https://engenderacademia.com/en-gender-converstations-podcast/" rel="nofollow">https://engenderacademia.com/en-gender-converstations-podcast/</a>). </p><p>In the first season, "Feel Good Academia", we interviewed scholars who started projects within academia or at the brinks between academia and 'the outside world', such as writing groups, podcasts, youtube channels, etc. </p><p>Listen in to get inspired and meet amazing scholars!</p><p>The second season, "Gender in the discplines", focusses on early career scholars' research and highlights the challenges as well as the good parts we experience in academia. </p><p>If you want to join, please contact us.</p><p>If you want to help us, you can support us via our patreon page: <a href="https://www.patreon.com/Engender" rel="nofollow">https://www.patreon.com/Engender</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:engenderingthepast@gmail.com">engenderingthepast@gmail.com</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 17:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664343427948366</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>&quot;Contesting Authenticity in Literature, 1200-1700&quot; 2023 Conference</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/09/25/contesting-authenticity-in-literature-1200-1700-2023-conference</link>
						<dc:creator>rmenmuir@aol.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, September 27, 2022 - 1:50pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Rebecca Menmuir / Institute of English Studies (IES) London</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:authenticity2023@gmail.com">authenticity2023@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/classical-studies">classical studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/medieval">medieval</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/renaissance">renaissance</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/translation-studies">translation studies</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>November 11, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>“CONTESTING AUTHENTICITY IN LITERATURE, 1200-1700”</strong></p>
<p>30-31 March 2023 / Senate House, University of London</p>
<p>Event details and further information can be found at &lt;<a href="https://ies.sas.ac.uk/events/contesting-authenticity-literature-1200-1700%3E">https://ies.sas.ac.uk/events/contesting-authenticity-literature-1200-1700&gt;</a>. Papers will be given in-person, and attendance will be hybrid.</p>
<p>This two-day conference will explore the concept of “contesting authenticity” in later medieval and early modern literature, including both the production and ongoing reception of texts of contested authenticity. Proposals are welcome which consider literature in any<br/>language, including translations.</p>
<p>Topics may include, but are not limited to:<br/>● Literary fakes, forgeries, and pseudo-texts;<br/>● Continuations and supplements;<br/>● Translation as (in)authentic;<br/>● Imitation/imitatio and authenticity;<br/>● Plagiarism vs forgery;<br/>● Issues of truth in literature (e.g. narrative authenticity);<br/>● The reception of medieval and early modern inauthentic texts;<br/>● The practice of contesting literary authenticity;<br/>● Scholarly practices and methodologies;</p>
<p>● Languages of (in)authenticity.</p>
<p>Please submit a 200-300 word abstract to Rebecca Menmuir (<strong><a href="mailto:authenticity2023@gmail.com">authenticity2023@gmail.com</a></strong>) by <strong>Friday 11th November 2022</strong>.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 12:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664343427948365</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Inaugural Forum for Jewish-Muslim Theology and Thought</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10985463/inaugural-forum-jewish-muslim-theology-and-thought</link>
						<dc:creator>Maeve McGrath</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-24T00:00:00-04:00">October 24, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-26T00:00:00-04:00">October 26, 2022</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Germany</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Islamic History / Studies, Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies, Philosophy</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The inaugural Forum for Jewish-Muslim Theology and Thought will take place this October in Berlin and will be on the theme of: Cultures of Continuity. All discussions will be held in english. There is no fee to attend and registration is only required for the keynote sessions. Further information, including the complete programme, is available on our website.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:maeve.mcgrath@hu-berlin.de">maeve.mcgrath@hu-berlin.de</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://hu.berlin/JMForum" target="_blank">https://hu.berlin/JMForum</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 17:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664257027004442</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Worldly Weil: Simone Weil and Political Theology</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11017093/worldly-weil-simone-weil-and-political-theology</link>
						<dc:creator>Benjamin Davis</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-05-30T00:00:00-04:00">May 30, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-01T00:00:00-04:00">June 1, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Missouri</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Colonial and Post-Colonial History / Studies, French History / Studies, Philosophy, Political Science, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>A workshop on religion, politics, and Simone Weil at The John C. Danforth Center, Washington University in St. Louis</p><p>Dates: 30 May-1 June, 2023</p><p>What is the relationship between politics and religion, political commitment and religious commitment in the work of Simone Weil? To what extent does Weil’s theology influence her politics, and her politics influence her theology—and how might attention to this question change how we read Weil today? How does Weil separate questions of Church from questions of religion, and what can our answers to these questions tell us about connections between Church and State in the U.S.? This workshop will consider these and other questions about Simone Weil’s political theology and inquiries emerging from it.</p><p>This workshop will be held at the John C. Danforth Center on Religion and Politics at Washington University in St. Louis. In keeping with the Center’s focus on scholarly and public engagement with issues at the intersection of politics and religion in the United States, we invite reflection on Weil that considers her thought in dialogue with religious life in the U.S. While Weil kept her eyes largely on her native France, she spent the summer and early fall of 1942 in New York, where she conducted research at public libraries in order to “dig into the hidden recesses of theology.” Weil’s thought has been influential for leading U.S. public intellectuals, from Susan Sontag and Mary McCarthy to Christian Wiman, Christy Wampole, and others today.</p><p>The conference will convene at the John C. Danforth Center on the campus of Washington University in St. Louis, where lodging will be available for participants. Additional travel grants will also be available.</p><p>We call for proposals of works in progress, more polished moments of ongoing inquiries, experimental projects, and other approaches to thinking together about the above questions and contexts.</p><p>Please send your 500-word abstracts on Weil and political theology to Fannie Bialek and Ben Davis by November 15, 2022. Emails: abialek[at]wustl.edu and benjamin.davis.1[at]slu.edu.</p></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 17:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664257027004441</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FEATURED JOB: Assistant/Associate Professor, Judaism of 1st–11th Centuries, CE- Yale University</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11020607/featured-job-assistantassociate-professor-judaism-1st%E2%80%9311th</link>
						<dc:creator>Kendra Fuller</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Home Office Notices (Jobs, Reviews)</div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Connecticut</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Yale University’s Program in Judaic Studies and Department of Religious Studies seek to make an appointment in the field of Judaism/Jewish history, literature, religion, and culture beginning July 1, 2023. We are especially interested in reviewing applications from candidates for professorships at the assistant (non-tenured) or associate (tenured) levels.</p><p>A knowledge of classical rabbinic sources and an ability to teach innovative and interdisciplinary undergraduate and graduate courses in Jewish history, literature, religion, and culture prior to 1100 CE is required. Specific areas of research and teaching expertise are open, including but not limited to: biblical reception, midrash, magic, law and legal theory, political history, literary theory, gender studies.</p><p>The successful candidate will be a key contributor to EMWAR, Yale’s doctoral program in Early Mediterranean and West Asian Religions that enables historical, literary, and comparative study of the mutually imbricated religious texts, traditions, material cultures, and cultural formations of the Mediterranean and West Asian world. The successful candidate will train EMWAR students studying Jewish history, literature, religion, and culture as an integral part of the Mediterranean (Roman/Byzantine) and/or West Asian (Sasanian) and/or early Islamic contexts.</p><p>Review of applications will begin October 24, 2022 and will continue until the position is filled.</p><p>Yale University is an Affirmative Action/Equal Opportunity employer. Yale values diversity among its students, staff, and faculty and strongly welcomes applications from women, persons with disabilities, protected veterans, and underrepresented minorities.</p><hr/><p>To submit YOUR job posting, please visit the H-Net Job Guide:<a href="https://www.h-net.org/jobs" rel="nofollow"> https://www.h-net.org/jobs</a></p><p>Featured jobs receive an added boost on H-Announce and H-Net’s social media channels.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Renee Reed at <a href="mailto:renee.reed@yale.edu">renee.reed@yale.edu</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php" target="_blank">https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php?id=64045</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 17:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664257027004440</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP: Festschrift Special Edition in Memory of Yoshinaga Shin'ichi (1957-2022)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10992484/cfp-festschrift-special-edition-memory-yoshinaga-shinichi-1957</link>
						<dc:creator>Esben  Petersen</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-09-24T00:00:00-04:00">September 24, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-06T00:00:00-04:00">November 6, 2022</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Japan</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Japanese History / Studies, East Asian History / Studies, Early Modern History and Period Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p> </p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>A Life in Religious Scholarship:</span></span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>It was with great sadness that Professor Yoshinaga Shin’ichi </span></span><span>吉永</span> <span>進一</span><span><span>passed away earlier this year. Professor Yoshinaga was a moving force in the discovery and analysis of the rich archive of Japanese Religious Studies. His work as a scholar, editor, and critic, influenced several new research topics in the study of religion. He made significant contributions to the study of modern Buddhism and established the academic study of esotericism and occultism in Japan as well. Professor Yoshinaga was also the previous editor of <i>Japanese Religions</i>, and he did much for the journal in which he incarnated the spirit of <i>kokusaika</i> in research at best. In honour of the accomplishments of Professor Yoshinaga, the NCC Institute is planning to publish a special issue of <i>Japanese Religions</i> dedicated to the work of Professor Yoshinaga within the field of Japanese religious studies.  </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>We welcome contributions in any area of Professor Yoshinaga’s published resarch interest.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Topics may include but are not limited to: </span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span>- Modern Buddhism</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>- Theosophy</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>- Esotericism</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>- Spirituality</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>- Occultism</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>- Swedenborgianism</span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span>Please submit for consideration abstracts of at least 250 words. Please provide a full name, affiliation, and email address. <b>Proposals should be sent electronically to Dr. Esben Petersen, Ritsumeikan University, NCC Institute Coordinator, at </b></span></span><a href="mailto:petersen@fc.ritsumei.ac.jp">petersen@fc.ritsumei.ac.jp</a><b><span><span> by November 6th. Accepted proposals will be notified mid-November. Finished articles of between 4,000-7000 words must be received by February 2023.</span></span></b></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:petersen@fc.ritsumei.ac.jp">petersen@fc.ritsumei.ac.jp</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 17:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664257027004439</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ March 31, 2023 -  April 1, 2023] Conference or similar: Philosophy of religion in Asia</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103290</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p>The Veritas Research Center (at UIC, Yonsei University) is hosting a workshop on the philosophy of religion, which will be held in a hybrid format in Seoul/online on March 31 (Friday)/April 1 (Saturday) 2023.</p>
<p>The aim of this workshop is to diversify and globalize philosophy of religion. As it stands, philosophy of religion has traditionally tended to pay particular attention to philosophical questions arising within and about Christianity. Moreover, leading English philosophy of religion journals tend to receive far more submissions from English-speaking parts of the world. At the same time, philosophy of religion is a broad field that encompasses philosophically relevant questions arising within and about any religious tradition and about religion(s) in general. Relatedly, journals such as the <em>Journal of Analytic Theology</em>, <em>Religious Studies</em>, and the <em>International Journal for Philosophy of Religion</em> are seeking more submissions from non-English-speaking parts of the world. Thus, the field has much potential to continue its ongoing efforts to globalize and diversify.</p>
<p>In addition to talks on any topic of the philosophy of religion, the workshop will include a <strong>Publication Seminar</strong> held by Prof. Helen De Cruz, Executive Editor of the <em>Journal of Analytic Theology. </em>This seminar is aimed at early career researchers and doctoral students across Asia who are interested in publishing in leading English philosophy of religion journals. The seminar will offer practical advice on how to make a paper ready for submission (e.g., cover letter, formatting), where and how to submit, how to increase the odds that your paper survives the desk review stage, when to query an editor, etc.</p>
<p>We invite abstracts of between 150 and 300 words on any topic in philosophy of religion(s), broadly construed. We particularly encourage early career researchers working in Asia to apply.</p>
<p>Please send your abstract as an email attachment, with the subject line ‘Philosophy of Religion in Asia’ to <a href="mailto:nataljadeng@yonsei.ac.kr">nataljadeng at yonsei.ac.kr</a> by 23:59 (KST) on November 30 2022. Papers should be suitable for a 20-30 minute presentation. In the body of the email, please indicate (a) your current affiliation, and (b) whether you would prefer to present in person or online. (Please note that we cannot offer travel funding, so that you should only indicate that you prefer to present in person if you have travel funding or are based in Seoul or its surroundings.)</p>
<p>In case of questions, please feel free to contact <a href="mailto:nataljadeng@yonsei.ac.kr">nataljadeng at yonsei.ac.kr</a></p>
<p>The event is jointly sponsored by Prof. <strong>Yujin Nagasawa</strong>’s Global Philosophy of Religion Project at the University of Birmingham (<a href="https://urldefense.com/v3/__https:/www.global-philosophy.org/__;!!K543PA!OpbVpEmmnkasi-MEbQtSTI1olToT2CclUhFgqSHti4M3f_vpPjP-_WLmPgSEHQVeiF2I1NPlJ9DDCfsS%24">https://www.global-philosophy.org/</a>) and the Veritas Research Center, Underwood International College (UIC), Yonsei University.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663997827801221</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ November 30, 2022] CFP for conference or similar: Philosophy of religion in Asia</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103294</link>
						<description><p>The Veritas Research Center (at UIC, Yonsei University) is hosting a workshop on the philosophy of religion, which will be held in a hybrid format in Seoul/online on March 31 (Friday)/April 1 (Saturday) 2023.</p>
<p>The aim of this workshop is to diversify and globalize philosophy of religion. As it stands, philosophy of religion has traditionally tended to pay particular attention to philosophical questions arising within and about Christianity. Moreover, leading English philosophy of religion journals tend to receive far more submissions from English-speaking parts of the world. At the same time, philosophy of religion is a broad field that encompasses philosophically relevant questions arising within and about any religious tradition and about religion(s) in general. Relatedly, journals such as the <em>Journal of Analytic Theology</em>, <em>Religious Studies</em>, and the <em>International Journal for Philosophy of Religion</em> are seeking more submissions from non-English-speaking parts of the world. Thus, the field has much potential to continue its ongoing efforts to globalize and diversify.</p>
<p>In addition to talks on any topic of the philosophy of religion, the workshop will include a <strong>Publication Seminar</strong> held by Prof. Helen De Cruz, Executive Editor of the <em>Journal of Analytic Theology. </em>This seminar is aimed at early career researchers and doctoral students across Asia who are interested in publishing in leading English philosophy of religion journals. The seminar will offer practical advice on how to make a paper ready for submission (e.g., cover letter, formatting), where and how to submit, how to increase the odds that your paper survives the desk review stage, when to query an editor, etc.</p>
<p>We invite abstracts of between 150 and 300 words on any topic in philosophy of religion(s), broadly construed. We particularly encourage early career researchers working in Asia to apply.</p>
<p>Please send your abstract as an email attachment, with the subject line ‘Philosophy of Religion in Asia’ to <a href="mailto:nataljadeng@yonsei.ac.kr">nataljadeng at yonsei.ac.kr</a> by 23:59 (KST) on November 30 2022. Papers should be suitable for a 20-30 minute presentation. In the body of the email, please indicate (a) your current affiliation, and (b) whether you would prefer to present in person or online. (Please note that we cannot offer travel funding, so that you should only indicate that you prefer to present in person if you have travel funding or are based in Seoul or its surroundings.)</p>
<p>In case of questions, please feel free to contact <a href="mailto:nataljadeng@yonsei.ac.kr">nataljadeng at yonsei.ac.kr</a></p>
<p>The event is jointly sponsored by Prof. <strong>Yujin Nagasawa</strong>’s Global Philosophy of Religion Project at the University of Birmingham (<a href="https://urldefense.com/v3/__https:/www.global-philosophy.org/__;!!K543PA!OpbVpEmmnkasi-MEbQtSTI1olToT2CclUhFgqSHti4M3f_vpPjP-_WLmPgSEHQVeiF2I1NPlJ9DDCfsS%24">https://www.global-philosophy.org/</a>) and the Veritas Research Center, Underwood International College (UIC), Yonsei University.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663997827801220</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CQHA Online: Interpretive Approaches Sessions: October 2022</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10979999/cqha-online-interpretive-approaches-sessions-october-2022</link>
						<dc:creator>Susan Garfinkel</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Symposium</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-12T00:00:00-04:00">October 12, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-26T00:00:00-04:00">October 26, 2022</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>American History / Studies, Art, Art History &amp; Visual Studies, Atlantic History / Studies, Colonial and Post-Colonial History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><h3>CQHA ONLINE: INTERPRETATIVE APPROACHES SESSIONS: OCTOBER 2022&amp;</h3><p>Please join the Conference of Quaker Historians and Archivists (CQHA) on<strong> three days in October</strong> for a set of virtual sessions foregrounding expanded approaches to the study of Quaker history and culture. </p><p><strong>Our <a href="https://library.guilford.edu/cqha/june2022" rel="nofollow">October sessions</a> have been chosen with a focus on interpretive approaches in mind.</strong> In each, we are delighted to welcome both emerging and established practitioners in their areas of Quaker scholarship. We will also hold short CQHA informational briefings and our biennial CQHA business meeting as part of these sessions. We will meet over Zoom and there is no cost to attend. <a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/cqha-online-interpretative-approaches-sessions-october-2022-tickets-422164544517" rel="nofollow">Registration is via Eventbrite</a>. </p><p>The sessions are scheduled for<strong> October 12, 19, and 26, beginning at 12:30 pm EDT</strong>. They are: </p><p> </p><p><strong>♦ Graphic Novels: Quakers in Pictures and Print</strong><br/>   Wednesday, October 12, 2022 </p><p>12:30-2:00 pm EDT | Session<br/>  2:00-2:30 pm EDT | CQHA Briefing</p><p><em>Presenters:</em></p><ul><li><strong>Marcus Rediker</strong>, Distinguished Professor, University of Pittsburgh</li><li><strong>David Lester</strong>, Artist and musician (Mecca Normal) in Vancouver, Canada, and graphic novelist of Prophet against Slavery</li><li><strong>Will Fenton</strong>, Associate Director, Center for Spatial and Textual Analysis, Stanford University</li><li><strong>Katelyn L. Lucas</strong>, Tribal Historic Preservation Assistant for Delaware Nation and PhD Candidate, Temple University</li><li><strong>Dash Shaw</strong>, American comic book writer/artist and animator, and cartoonist of Discipline (2021) published by the New York Review Comics</li></ul><p><em>Description:</em></p><p>This session focuses on three historical graphic novels to consider issues of interpretation in presenting the Quaker past through the lens of graphic or visual presentation. <strong>David Lester </strong>and <strong>Marcus Rediker</strong> will discuss the collaboration of artist and historian in the making of Prophet against Slavery: Benjamin Lay, A Graphic Novel (Beacon Press, 2021), a graphic adaptation of Rediker’s biography of Benjamin Lay. <strong>Katelyn Lucas</strong> and <strong>Will Fenton</strong> will share insights from Ghost River: The Fall and Rise of the Conestoga (Library Company of Philadelphia, 2019), which reimagines the Paxton massacres of 1763 as an educational graphic novel, introducing new interpreters and new bodies of evidence to highlight Indigenous victims and their kin. <strong>Dash Shaw’s</strong> presentation will detail his process and the historical materials and references for Discipline (New York Review Comics, 2021), a graphic novel about a Quaker soldier in the American Civil War, which incorporates Civil War-era Quaker letters and diary entries. Together these presentations will give insights into innovative ways of engaging and imagining the Quaker past. </p><p><em>CQHA</em>: A short <strong>briefing on CQHA and upcoming business</strong> will follow the presentation. </p><p> </p><p><strong>♦ Thought and Action in Decolonizing Practices: A Conversation</strong><br/>   Wednesday, October 19, 2022 </p><p>12:30-1:00 pm EDT | CQHA Briefing<br/>  1:00-2:30 pm EDT | Session </p><p><em>Presenters</em>:</p><ul><li><strong>Sa’ed Atshan</strong>, Director of Undergraduate Studies and Professor of Anthropology, Emory University</li><li><strong>Paula Palmer</strong>, Director of Toward Right Relationship, a project of the Indigenous Peoples Concerns committee of the Boulder Friends Meeting</li><li><strong>Tanya Maus</strong> (moderator), Director, Peace Resource Center and Director, Quaker Heritage Center, Wilmington College</li></ul><p><em>Description</em>: </p><p>Focusing on academic practice and activism, this panel is devoted to a dialogue between <strong>Sa’ed Atshan</strong> and <strong>Paula Palmer</strong> regarding their interventions into upholding and uplifting the rights of first peoples and colonized peoples. <strong>Tanya Maus</strong> will moderate. <strong>Atshan’s</strong> scholarship has brought into focus the trauma of Palestinian identities including Queer and Quaker Palestinians as well as the potential for intersectional activism and solidarity among various constituents. <strong>Palmer’s</strong> lifework and activism have focused on the rights of Indigenous peoples. She witnesses the roles Quakers played in colonization and the forced assimilation of native children by means of the Quaker industrial boarding schools. Through dialogue, both participants will focus on the relationship between thought and practice, the various meanings of decolonization within the context of their work, and the necessity of restorative justice. </p><p><em>CQHA</em>: A short <strong>briefing on CQHA and upcoming business </strong>will precede the presentation. </p><p> </p><p><strong>♦ Quakers and Networks</strong><br/>   Wednesday, October 26, 2022 </p><p>12:30-2:00 pm EDT | Session<br/>  2:15-3:15 pm EDT | CQHA Business Meeting </p><p><em>Presenters:</em></p><ul><li><strong>Esther Sahle</strong>, Research Associate in Global History, Freie Universität Berlin</li><li><strong>Michael F. Suarez</strong>, S.J., Professor of English and Director of Rare Book School at the University of Virginia</li><li><strong>James Truitt</strong>, Senior Archives Technician, Friends Historical Library of Swarthmore College</li></ul><p><em>Description: </em></p><p>New attention to network analysis in the humanities has invited new opportunities to explore the dense set of religious, economic, and social interconnections that characterize historical Quakerism. In this session, <strong>Esther Sahle</strong> will revisit what we know on the development and significance of Quaker business networks, contextualizing them within broader social and economic developments of the long eighteenth century. <strong>Michael Suarez</strong> will discuss the essential role played by Transatlantic Quaker networks in the campaign to abolish the slave trade, c.1787–1807. <strong>James Truitt</strong> will introduce participants to Friendly Networks, an online project that maps social networks within archival sources using the journals of eighteenth-century New Jersey minister John Hunt together with EAC-CPF and TEI, widely-used standards for authority control and text encoding.</p><p><em>CQHA</em>: The biennial<strong> CQHA Business Meeting</strong> will follow the presentation. </p><p> </p><p><strong>Questions? </strong>Please see our website for full information, and don't hesitate to contact the session organizers by email. </p><ul><li>CQHA Website: <a href="http://libguides.guilford.edu/cqha" rel="nofollow">http://libguides.guilford.edu/cqha</a> </li><li>CQHA June Methodology Sessions: <a href="https://library.guilford.edu/cqha/june2022" rel="nofollow">https://library.guilford.edu/cqha/june2022</a></li><li>Facebook: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/quakerhistoriansandarchivists" rel="nofollow">https://www.facebook.com/quakerhistoriansandarchivists</a></li><li>Contact Us: <a href="mailto:quakerhistoriansandarchivists@gmail.com">quakerhistoriansandarchivists@gmail.com</a></li></ul></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Quaker Historians And Archivists<br/><a href="mailto:quakerhistoriansandarchivists@gmail.com">quakerhistoriansandarchivists@gmail.com</a><br/><a href="https://library.guilford.edu/cqha/june2022" rel="nofollow">https://library.guilford.edu/cqha/june2022</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:quakerhistoriansandarchivists@gmail.com">quakerhistoriansandarchivists@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://library.guilford.edu/cqha/june2022" target="_blank">https://library.guilford.edu/cqha/june2022</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 17:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663997827801219</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Special Topic:Confluence-- Thomas Merton (CEA 3/30/23-4/1/23</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/09/23/special-topicconfluence-thomas-merton-cea-33023-4123</link>
						<dc:creator>mweis9@naz.edu</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Friday, September 23, 2022 - 1:50pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>College English Association + International Thomas Merton Society</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:mweis9@naz.edu">mweis9@naz.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/ecocriticism-and-environmental-studies">ecocriticism and environmental studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/rhetoric-and-composition">rhetoric and composition</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>November 1, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p align="center"><strong>I</strong><strong>nternational </strong><strong>T</strong><strong>homas </strong><strong>M</strong><strong>erton </strong><strong>S</strong><strong>ociety</strong><strong> </strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>at the</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>C</strong><strong>ollege </strong><strong>E</strong><strong>nglish </strong><strong>A</strong><strong>ssociation</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>52nd ANNUAL CONFERENCE</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong> </strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>San Antonio, TX - Sheraton Gunter Hotel</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>March 30-April 1, 2023</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>Call for Papers</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>An allied organization of the College English Association (CEA), the International Thomas Merton Society (ITMS) will be sponsoring one or more panels at the annual CEA Conference next <strong>March 30-Apr. 1</strong>, as well as recommending individual proposals for other concurrent sessions<strong>.  Overarching theme of the Conference: CONFLUENCE.</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Suggested lines of inquiry about Merton's thinking and writing (but only suggested):</em></strong></p>
<p><strong>        </strong><strong>• Merging contemplation and action</strong></p>
<p><strong>         • Prophetic power of confluence: waves of justice, waves of peace</strong></p>
<p><strong>         • Uniting the personal and the public</strong></p>
<p><strong>         • Convergence of commitment: Merton and Dorothy Day; Merton and Heschel; Merton and ?</strong></p>
<p><strong>         • Blending mysticisms: East and West</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>You are invited to submit a title and proposal (200-500 words) for a 6-8 page paper (15 minute presentation time) and encouraged to contact Monica Weis SSJ (<a href="mailto:mweis9@naz.edu">mweis9@naz.edu</a>) for directions on how to submit your proposal to the CEA data base and how to negotiate your CEA membership ($50) by January 2023</p>
<p><strong>Deadline for electronic proposals is November 1, 2022</strong></p>
<p><strong>Online submission site: <a href="http://cea-web.org/">http://cea-web.org</a>   (site opens August 15)</strong></p>
<p>                                         <a href="https://www.conftool.pro/cea2020/" target="_blank">https://www.conftool.pro/cea2023/</a></p>
<p> </p>
<p>The annual CEA Conference is a wonderfully congenial gathering of 500+ scholar-teachers committed to literature, writing, college teaching, and related fields.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 16:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663997827801218</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Marilynne Robinson Society</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/09/22/marilynne-robinson-society</link>
						<dc:creator>hapark1@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Sunday, September 25, 2022 - 12:06am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>American Literature Association Conference (ALA); Boston, MA</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:haein.park@biola.edu">haein.park@biola.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/african-american">african-american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>November 15, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>The Marilynne Robinson Society will be hosting a panel on a wide variety of topics connected to Robinson’s essays and novels at the annual conference of the American Literature Association.</p>
<p>The annual American Literature Association (ALA) conference will take place in Boston, MA, May 25-28, 2023. </p>
<p>Please submit a 350-word proposal and short bio to <a href="mailto:haein.park@biola.edu">haein.park@biola.edu</a> by November 15, 2020.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663997827801217</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Marilynne Robinson, Jesus and John Wayne, and the American Evangelical Tradition</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/09/22/marilynne-robinson-jesus-and-john-wayne-and-the-american-evangelical-tradition</link>
						<dc:creator>hapark1@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Friday, September 23, 2022 - 3:25pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>American Literature Association Conference (ALA); Boston, MA; May 25-28, 2023</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:haein.park@biola.edu">haein.park@biola.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/african-american">african-american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>November 15, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Marilynne Robinson, <em>Jesus and John Wayne</em>, and the American Evangelical Tradition</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The Marilynne Robinson Society at the ALA is seeking papers that examine the author’s relationship to American evangelicalism.  Robinson’s spiritual vision has been shaped by the writings of Jonathan Edwards, who is considered to be the founding father of American evangelicalism.  How does Robinson’s body of work lead us to think critically about the evangelical tradition in the United States?  How do her essays and novels, particularly <em>Gilead</em>, provide a counter-narrative to the discourses found in modern and contemporary American evangelicalism?  In what ways can they respond to the incisive diagnosis presented by Kristen Du Mez’s recent book, <em>Jesus and John Wayne</em>, a text that examines the connection between American evangelicalism, Christian nationalism, rugged masculinity, and political power? How might Robinson’s novels and essays in conversation with Du Mez’s <em>Jesus and John Wayne</em> illuminate our understanding of the evangelical tradition in the United States?  These are some of the questions that the panel seeks to address.</p>
<p>The annual American Literature Association (ALA) conference will take place in Boston, MA, May 25-28, 2023.  </p>
<p>Please submit a 350-word paper proposal and short bio to <a href="mailto:haein.park@biola.edu">haein.park@biola.edu</a> by November 15, 2022. </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 23:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663997827801216</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ November 30, 2022] CFP for conference or similar: 2023 Uehiro Graduate Philosophy Conference - What Dreams May Come?: Philosophical Explorations in Dreaming, Suffering, and Death</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/101438</link>
						<description><p>Call For Papers - Spring 2023 Uehiro Philosophy Graduate Student Conference</p>
<p>Title/Topic: What Dreams May Come?: Philosophical Explorations in Dreaming, Suffering, and Death</p>
<p>Date: Thursday, March 2nd &amp; Friday, March 3rd, 2023</p>
<p>Location: University of Hawaii-Manoa, Honolulu, Hawaii</p>
<p>The University of Hawaii at Manoa Philosophy Department is calling for papers for its annual Uehiro Graduate Student Conference “What Dreams May Come?: Philosophical Explorations in Dreaming, Suffering, and Death”. We invite graduate students working in all areas of philosophy to submit papers on the conference theme. We welcome interdisciplinary submissions, and we strongly encourage submissions from members of underrepresented groups. The conference will take place in person. Travel costs will be subsidized for a small number of student presenters who submit full papers. Affordable lodging will be available for all presenters.</p>
<p>We are honored to have Dr. Michael Brady (University of Glasgow), Dr. Melanie Rosen (Trent University) and Dr. Arindam Chakrabarti (University of Hawaii-Manoa) as our keynote speakers.</p>
<p>This year’s conference title is inspired by the famous lines in Hamlet:</p>
<p>“To be, or not to be, that is the question:</p>
<p>Whether 'tis nobler in the mind to suffer</p>
<p>The slings and arrows of outrageous fortune,</p>
<p>Or to take Arms against a Sea of troubles,</p>
<p>And by opposing end them: to die, to sleep</p>
<p>No more; and by a sleep, to say we end</p>
<p>The heart-ache, and the thousand natural shocks</p>
<p>That Flesh is heir to? 'Tis a consummation</p>
<p>Devoutly to be wished. To die, to sleep,</p>
<p>To sleep, perchance to Dream; aye, there's the rub,</p>
<p>For in that sleep of death, what dreams may come,</p>
<p>When we have shuffled off this mortal coil, </p>
<p>Must give us pause. ”</p>
<p>Papers should explore dreaming, suffering, and death, and grapple with questions that arise out of these facets of life. These topics may also be broadly construed. For example, we welcome papers on "dreaming" as both a phenomena in philosophy of mind and as an "ideal" or "aspiration" in other areas of philosophy. Likewise, "suffering" can include the philosophy of pain, or "duḥkha" in Buddhist philosophy. As such, we invite papers from all philosophical fields and traditions.</p>
<p>Presentations should not exceed twenty (20) minutes in length, and another five (5) minutes for questions. Paper submissions should not exceed 4000 words. Abstracts are also welcome and should not exceed 250 words, but preference for travel funds will be given to completed papers. Submissions should be prepared for blind review. The deadline for submissions is November 30, 2022, and presenters will be notified of our decision by early January.</p>
<p>Send papers as a PDF file and prepared for blind review to uehriogradpc@gmail.com - In the body of the e-mail please include: 1) Your name, 2) Title of the paper, 3) Institutional affiliation, 4) Contact information (e-mail, phone, or mailing address)</p>
<p>The conference is free and open to the public.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663825028249979</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – September 21, 2022</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-september-21-2022/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find four tenure-track job openings.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 37!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Job</h2>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Contemporary Islam in the Americas (tenure-track)</h4>



<p>DePaul University, US</p>



<p>Deadline: October 15<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://mesana.org/resources-and-opportunities/2022/09/19/contemporary-islam-in-the-americas">https://mesana.org/resources-and-opportunities/2022/09/19/contemporary-islam-in-the-americas</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor in Religious Studies (tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Colby College, US</p>



<p>Deadline: October 21<sup>st</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://apply.interfolio.com/112793">https://apply.interfolio.com/112793</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor, Religion &amp; Politics in the Department for the Study of Religions (tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Wake Forest University, US</p>



<p>Deadline: October 21<sup>st</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://wfu.wd1.myworkdayjobs.com/en-US/Faculty_Career_Website_live/job/Assistant-Professor--Religion---Politics-in-the-Department-for-the-Study-of-Religions_R0004859?fbclid=IwAR31s5dUIHADeoFTdi6lRQXyy4Vd9qWpfHLl5XsJvZIIBMmh0G7MYBrE65o">Assistant Professor, Religion &amp; Politics in the Department for the Study of Religions (myworkdayjobs.com)</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor, East Asian Buddhism in the Department for the Study of Religions (tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Wake Forest, US</p>



<p>Deadline: October 21<sup>st</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://wfu.wd1.myworkdayjobs.com/en-US/Faculty_Career_Website_live/job/Assistant-Professor--East-Asian-Buddhism-in-the-Department-for-the-Study-of-Religions_R0004860?fbclid=IwAR3IEeK0FqtG4pcYdwH5tIXob6uixzykWddQ_1ftoDAVt1Acle1EOOfAbKw">Assistant Professor, East Asian Buddhism in the Department for the Study of Religions (myworkdayjobs.com)</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663825028249978</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
