<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 12:20:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 12:20:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ June 23, 2023] Talk or similar: The Unsettled Ground of Phenomenological Inquiry</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/112270</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/>Speakers at this event: <br/>Michael van Manen<br/><br/><p>The School of Sanskrit, Philosophy and Indic Studies (SSPIS) at Goa University cordially invites you to the online guest lecture titled "The Unsettled Ground of Phenomenological Inquiry" by Dr. Michael van Manen. Kindly join us on 23 June 2023 (Friday) from 7:30 to 9:30 PM IST at <a target="_blank">meet.google.com/ene-pdkv-ttc</a>. <br/><br/><br/><strong>Abstract</strong><br/>For the reader of qualitative research, phenomenological research at times may appear amorphous, varied, or even ambiguous. This is, without a doubt, in part, a consequence of the perfunctory popularization and cursory adaption of the phenomenological notion lived experience by writers who variably identify themselves as pursuing phenomenological research. For some, this term expresses little more than attending to an experience that an individual has lived through—contributing to confusion. And yet, the preoccupation of phenomenological inquiry is fundamentally deeper, exploring human experience in itself in its meaningfulness. The focus of this presentation will be to explore the ground of phenomenological inquiry and also its possibility for generating insights.<strong><br/></strong><br/><br/><strong>Bio</strong><br/>Dr. Michael van Manen, MD, PhD, FRCPC(Peds,NICU,CIP) Endowed Chair in Health Ethics is the Director of the John Dossetor Health Ethics Centre and an Associate Professor in the Department of Pediatrics at the University of Alberta. Dr. van Manen also has a clinical practice as a physician in neonatal-perinatal medicine with the Stollery Children’s Hospital. His research is primarily concerned with relational ethics, situated within the tradition of phenomenology. Dr. van Manen is considered an international expert in qualitative health research. He has made presentations at professional conferences around the world. His research projects relate to ethical decision-making, the experiential life of the fetus/newborn, the use of medical technologies in clinical encounters, and patient-family experiences of hospital care. Dr. van Manen has authored articles, book chapters, and books in the fields of phenomenological research methodology, health ethics, neonatal-perinatal medicine, and pedagogy; and has developed and taught numerous workshops and courses on phenomenological research. He is the author of <em>The Birth of Ethics: Phenomenological Reflections on Life’s Beginnings</em>, <em>Phenomenology of the Newborn: Life from Womb to World</em>, and <em>Classic Writings for a Phenomenology of Practice</em> (with Prof. Max van Manen).</p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 05:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1686721031389007</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ July 6, 2023 -  July 8, 2023] Conference or similar: Zur Frage des Prekären zwischen Kontingenz und Medialität</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/112214</link>
						<description>Venue: Steubenstr. 6<br/><br/><p><strong><u>Programm</u></strong></p>
<p>--- Donnerstag, 06.07.2023 ---</p>
<p>14:15                   Begrüßung und Einleitung</p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p><em>Politisierungen / Queerungen</em></p>
<p><em></em>14:30                   <strong>Thomas Biebricher</strong> - Prekarität als Ressource und Fluchtpunkt des Neoliberalismus?</p>
<p>15:30                   <strong>Jasmin Degeling</strong> - Prekäre Sicherheit</p>
<p>16:30                   Pause</p>
<p>17:00                   <strong>Franziska Dübgen</strong> - Prekäre Repräsentationsweisen: Epistemische Gewalt im Rahmen der NSU-Prozesse</p>

<p>--- Freitag, 07.07.2023 ---</p>
<p><em>Verkörperungen / Materialisierungen</em></p>
<p>10:00                   <strong>Marc Rölli</strong> -'Precarious Moves'. Zum Prekären anthropologischen Wissens</p>
<p>11:00                   <strong>Matthias Schloßberger</strong> - Prekäre Zukunft: der Mensch und die Natur</p>
<p>12:00                   Mittagspause</p>
<p><em><br/></em></p>
<p><em>Medialisierungen</em></p>
<p>14:00                   <strong>Sebastian Lederle</strong> - Prekarisierung als medienphilosophische Kategorie</p>
<p>15:00                   <strong>Sulgi Lie</strong> - Filmemachen/Nicht-Filmemachen. Prekarität und Prokastination in den Filmen von Hong Sangsoo</p>
<p>16:00                   Pause</p>
<p>16-30                   <strong>Lorenz Engell </strong>- Die Aufstellung des Prekären. Bemerkungen über das Habitat-Diorama</p>

<p>--- Samstag, 08.07.2023 ---</p>
<p><em>Ästhetisierungen</em></p>
<p>10:00                   <strong>Sophia Prinz</strong> - Ästhetische Zugänge zur Komplexität</p>
<p>11:00                   <strong>Christiane Voss</strong> - Entgrenzung und Verschiebung: Operationen des Prekärmachens des Substanziellen.</p>
<p>12:00                   Pause</p>
<p>12:30                   <strong>Judith-Frederike Popp</strong> - Ästhetisches und Nicht-Ästhetisches. Über eine prekäre Grenzziehung</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>Unter dem Oberbegriff der Prekarisierung lassen sich verschiedene theoretische Zugänge und mitunter hochgradig heterogene Phänomene fassen. Prekär sind Anstellungsvehältnisse genauso wie Zukunftsaussichten, Geschlechterzuschreibungen wie Aktienkurse, personale Nahbeziehungen wie social media‐Profile, mikropolitische Arrangements in Kleingrupppen wie hegemoniale Großformationen einer Gesellschaft oder politischer Einrichtungen. Es scheint nichts zu geben, von dem nicht gesagt werden könnte, es sei in der einen oder anderen Weise von Verunsicherung, Ungewissheit und Verzweideutigung betroffen und nicht in der einen oder anderen Weise abhängig von konflikthaften und umkämpften Deutungen und Auffassungen. Prekarität ist nicht nur eine wissenschaftliche Kategorie neben anderen, sondern der Punkt, an dem sich das Leben in der Spätmoderne in seinen vielfältigen Perspektiven kreuzt, überlagert und sich jeder Vereindeutigung und endgültigen Absicherung entzieht. Dass Prekärsein überall, zu jeder Zeit und bei allen angetroffen werden kann, macht es sowohl zu einem ontologischen wie auch historisch‐empirischen, methodisch wie auch gegenständlich einsetzbaren Operator. Darin liegt seine Attraktivität als zeitgenössischer Begriff: Prekarität ist, ob verdeckt oder offen, ubiquitär.</p>
<p>Sofern es um das soziale Zusammenleben in den heterogenen Aspekten seiner Verfasstheit geht, lässt sich Prekarisierung über die politikwissenschaftlich‐gesellschaftstheoretische Perspektive hinaus auch medienanthropologisch in den Blick nehmen. Medien und Technik sind dann keine bloßen Instrumente oder Hilfsmittel des Menschen, sondern, so lautet eine medienphilosophische These, bringen „den“ Menschen als Zuschreibungspunkt erst hervor. Menschsein heißt so hergestellt zu sein, wobei Praktiken der Selbstadressierung immer schon mediale und technische Leistungen in Anspruch nehmen, sodass hier von einer irreduziblen „Anthropomedialität“ gesprochen werden kann. Darin ist der Teilbegriff „anthropos“ in dem Term „Anthropomedialität“ strukturell prekär gefasst, weil er als jeweiliges Relatum immer nur als Teil einer Relation denkbar ist.</p>
<p>Was folgt, wenn vom „Menschen“ als Fundamentalkategorie abgesehen und stattdessen auf das technisch‐mediale Verfasstsein seiner Selbstverständnisse und seiner Ausfransungen in diverse mediale Milieus abgestellt wird? Welche diskursiven Autorisierungen entscheiden darüber, wer überhaupt als Mensch intelligibel ist und wer nicht? Welche Rolle spielen dabei Materialität und Verkörperungsvorgänge? Wie wird die Grenze zwischen Ästhetik und Nicht‐Ästhetik, Natur und Kultur verhandelt, wenn die Grenzziehung selbst wiederum prekär ist? Wie wirken Medialisierungen und Technisierungen über ihre instrumentelle Funktion hinaus an politischen Prozessen mit? Lässt sich Prekarität neoliberal subjektivieren und durch jeweilige Akteur*innen aneignen? Wie verhalten sich Prekarität, Komplexität, Kontingenz und Versicherheitlichung zueinander? Dass dieser Sachstand grundsätzlich auf prekäre Existenzweisen verweist, ist die leitende Intuition der Tagung. Einem derartig medienanthropologisch‐interdisziplinären Erkundungsgang durch die Allgegenwart des Prekären widmen sich die thematischen Panels „Politisierungen/Queerungen“, „Verkörperungen/Materialisierungen“, „Medialisierungen“ und „Ästhetisierungen“.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 05:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1686634633397571</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ August 23, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Imam Reza (PBUH) and Interreligious Dialogue</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/112210</link>
						<description><p><strong>CFP</strong></p>
<p><strong>The International Conference on Imam Reza (PBUH) and Interreligious Dialogue</strong></p>
<p>Astan Quds Razavi’s Foundation of Islamic Researches in collaboration with Imam Sadiq University and various Iranian and international academic and religious centers will hold the international conference on “Imam Reza (PBUH) and Interreligious Dialogue” from 16 to 18 January 2024. This conference aims to create an atmosphere for dialogue and peaceful coexistence between the followers of different religions and denominations, to strengthen scientific interaction between the scholars of different religions and denominations, to strengthen the scientific interaction between Iranian and International religious institutions, to laying a groundwork for Intellectual cooperation between different religions and denominations on contemporary social challenges, and to emphasize the role of the family as a sacred institution from the perspective of religions and denominations. Laying the groundwork for the conference, the scientific secretariat has planned to hold numerous virtual/in-person pre-con meetings in Persian, Arabic, and English at the different Iranian and international academic/religious centers.</p>
<p>Chairman: Mohammad Hadi Abdkhodaei (Professor, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Iran)</p>
<p>Scientific Secretary: Ahad Faramarz Qaramaleki (Professor, University of Tehran, Iran)</p>
<p>Executive Secretary: Mohsen Sharfaei (Ph. D Graduate, Astan Quds Razavi’s Foundation of Islamic Researches, Iran)</p>
<p>Executive Manager: Roohollah Fadaei (Ph. D Graduate, Tarbiat Modares University, Iran)</p>
<p>Venue: Mashhad, Iran</p>
<p>Conference issues: </p>
<p>1. Theory and Method in Interreligious Dialogue:</p>
<p>- Philosophical Approaches: Phenomenology, Epistemology, Narrative, Intercultural Philosophy, etc.</p>
<p>- Sociological Approaches</p>
<p>- Empirical Approaches</p>
<p>- Psychological Approaches</p>
<p>…</p>

<p>2. Family and Interreligious Dialogue</p>
<p>- Theological Attitudes Towards Family Relationships</p>
<p>- Religions and the Threats to Family Life</p>
<p>- Religions and the Mental Images of Family </p>
<p>- Theology of Gender</p>
<p>- Religions and the Rival Institutions to the Family</p>
<p>- Religions and the Family Roles</p>
<p>We are honored to host some of the well-known scholars in interfaith studies in the scientific board:</p>
<p>·       Rahim Acar: Marmara University, Turkey</p>
<p>·       Ahad Faramarz Qaramaleki: University of Tehran, Iran</p>
<p>·       Lucinda Allen Mosher: Hartford International University for Religion and Peace, USA</p>
<p>·       Seyyed Hossein Nasr: The George Washington University, USA</p>
<p>·       Rasoul Rasoulipour: Kharazmi University, Iran</p>
<p>·       Mohammad Saeedi Mehr: Tarbiat Modares University, Iran</p>
<p>·       Mun'im Sirry: Notre Dame University, USA</p>
<p>·       Amy Yu Fu: Hangzhou City University, China</p>
<p>….</p>
<p>Important Dates</p>
<p>·       Abstract submission deadline: August 23, 2023</p>
<p>·       Notification of acceptance: September 6, 2023</p>
<p>·       Paper submission deadline: November 22, 2023</p>
<p>·       Paper acceptance notification: December 6, 2023</p>
<p>·       Announcement of the selected papers and presentations’ schedule: December 21, 2023</p>
<p>·       Conference date: January 16-18, 2024</p>
<p>Only Ph. D holders and postgraduate students may submit abstracts and papers independently. Undergraduates' submissions should be coauthored by a professor.</p>
<p>Abstract Features: </p>
<p>·       Abstracts should be no less than 250 words in length and no more than 300.</p>
<p>·        Abstracts should be followed by 3 to 5 keywords. </p>
<p>Paper Features: </p>
<p>·       Papers should be no less than 1500 words in length and no more than 2000 (the abstract and bibliography are not counted).</p>
<p>·       Whole text should be typed in Times New Roman font (font-size: 11 for body and 9 for endnotes and bibliography).</p>
<p>·       All titles and subtitles in the paper should be arranged numerically (English numbers not Roman).</p>
<p>·       All marginal but useful and important notes should be mentioned as endnotes, not footnotes.</p>
<p>·       All references (in-text and reference list) should follow the 16th edition of Chicago citation style.</p>
<p>The conference will be held totally in-person.</p>
<p>The conference registration is free of charge. For those professors and researchers interested in participating in the conference in-person, conference organizers tried to decrease the costs of attendance by finding some funds. Accordingly, the attendance cost for any international participant would be 500 USD (which will be received in cash) including:</p>
<p>•        A 5to7-day stay in Iran (from about 13 to 19 January, 2024) at a five-star hotel</p>
<p>•        Complete food services at the hotel</p>
<p>•        Local transportation in Tehran from Imam Khomeini Airport to Mehrabad Airport and vice versa</p>
<p>•        A roundtrip flight ticket from Tehran to Mashhad</p>
<p>•        Local Transportation in Mashhad</p>
<p>It is kindly requested from those who want to attend the event to register on the conference website and to submit their abstracts. Moreover, due to the official process of visa issuance, the secretariat of the conference (irirdialogue@gmail.com) needs the following documents: </p>
<p>1. Passport first two pages</p>
<p>2.  A biometric photo</p>
<p>3. Form 1 (just fill out the English column)</p>

<p>Conference website, submissions and registration:  <a href="https://irirdialogue.ir/">https://irirdialogue.ir/</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 05:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1686634633397570</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ September 10, 2023] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/112194</link>
						<description>Publication Name: Existential Philosophy and Disability (collected volume)<br/><br/><p>Call for contributions for a collected volume</p>
<p><br/></p>
<p>Disability is a significant part of the experience of being human. As the World Health Organisation acknowledges: “Almost everyone will temporarily or permanently experience disability at some point in their life [and an] estimated 1.3 billion people—about 16% of the global population—currently experience disability.”<a name="_ftnref1">[1]</a>As a concept, the understanding of disability has been shifting over the past decades from medical models based on impairment, defect or deficit in the individual, to the social models upheld by the 2006 Convention on the Rights of Persons with Disabilities, recognising that “disability results from the interaction between persons with impairments and attitudinal and environmental barriers that hinders their full and effective participation in society on an equal basis with others.”<a name="_ftnref2">[2]</a></p>

<p>Despite these facts, disability remains largely ignored and stigmatised both in general discourse and in academic research outside of the recent field of Disability Studies. While accessibility policies and plans have been developed in many countries, persons with disabilities continue to face discrimination, stigmatisation, and the effects of ableism in all aspects of life, including access to health care and support, education and the protection of their fundamental human rights, leading to negative life outcomes and life expectancies.<a name="_ftnref3">[3]</a>Outside of recent disability rights movements, disability is generally viewed as something negative, a disorder to be repaired. Yet as Elizabeth Barnes has noted: “being disabled is not something that by itself or intrinsically makes you worse off. Being disabled is…a way of being a minority with respect to one’s body, just as being gay is a way of being a minority with respect to sexuality. It is something that makes you different from the majority, but that difference isn’t by itself a bad thing.”<a name="_ftnref4">[4]</a></p>

<p>One of the most serious challenges faced by persons with disabilities today is the lack of understanding, appreciation and acceptance of these different ways of being human, experiencing life and interacting, with regard to physical, mental, cognitive, sensory, and other health differences. This volume aims to make a positive contribution by engaging issues surrounding disability with perspectives from existential philosophy. Existential philosophy, broadly understood, places the focus on the individual and on the precedence of existence over essence, on the lived, subjective experience of the individual, rejecting metaphysical and universalist views on human nature and the human condition. As such, it may provide a path to better understand the plurality of human experience and existence conditions. At the same time, many of the traditional themes of existential philosophy, such as choice, freedom, and authentic selfhood, may need to be re-examined in light of the specific difficulties and challenges presented to persons with minority bodies, minds, modes of communication, or experiences in a world where social norms and institutions entail direct and indirect discrimination.</p>

<p>Existential philosophy suggests that we are what we are in the eyes or gaze of others (Sartre) or through our acts of disclosure in the world (Beauvoir), or perhaps through the shared language games through which meaning is created (Wittgenstein). But what does this entail for individuals with minority bodies, experiences or realities, and whose experiences may be stigmatised, misunderstood or invalidated by the general community? Do cognitive, intellectual, physical and sensory disabilities or differences represent challenges to authentic self-disclosure in a world that pathologizes difference and in which the language for self-understanding and communication with others, as well as an understanding and appreciation of these differences, may be lacking? </p>

<p>Do the concepts of existential philosophy have something to contribute to discussions about disability rights, identity and pride? Are some founding existential concepts, such as freedom and authenticity, potentially misguided regarding certain persons’ experiences? How do specific conditions or disabilities impact individuals’ life choices and potential, their identity and autonomy? Can existential philosophy provide new perspectives to promote the recognition, respect and appreciation of difference and diversity? And in what ways does rethinking human existence through the lens of disability call into question some of the potentially still essentialist (as well as ableist) views of human nature inherent in existential philosophy?</p>

<p>This volume seeks to broaden our philosophical understanding of disability, moving beyond traditional questions in bioethics, to perspectives on the specific lived experience of persons with disabilities. Contributions engaging with any specific form of disability, as well as more general contributions on disability and ableism that engage with perspectives from existential philosophy and phenomenology (such as Albert Camus, Theodor Adorno, Emil Cioran, Simone de Beauvoir, Jean-Paul Sartre, Karl Jaspers, Hannah Arendt, Martin Heidegger and Ludwig Wittgenstein, and their nineteenth-century predecessors [Kierkegaard, Nietzsche…]) are welcome. <em>Contributions from scholars with disabilities are particularly welcome</em>.</p>

<p><strong>To contribute:</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Scholars interested in contributing a chapter are invited to submit an abstract of 500 words and short bio-bibliography by <strong>10 September 2023 </strong>to <a>melissa.fox-muraton@esc-clermont.fr</a>. Early submission is welcome.</p>

<p>Full manuscripts for accepted proposals will be expected by <strong>31 December 2023</strong>. Manuscripts should be 20-35 pages, Times New Roman 12, double-spaced, with minimal formatting.</p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p>We hope that this collected volume will appear in the series <em>New Research in the History of Western Philosophy</em>, which is published by Brill.</p>
<p>https://brill.com/display/serial/NRHW?language=en</p>

<br/>

<p><a name="_ftn1">[1]</a>World Health Organisation, ‘Disability’, https://www.who.int/health-topics/disability#tab=tab_1(Consulted 2 June 2023).</p>


<p><a name="_ftn2">[2]</a>https://www.ohchr.org/en/instruments-mechanisms/instruments/convention-rights-persons-disabilities</p>


<p><a name="_ftn3">[3]</a>https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/disability-and-health</p>


<p><a name="_ftn4">[4]</a>Elizabeth Barnes, <em>The Minority Body. A Theory of Disability</em>, Oxford: Oxford University Press 2016, p. 6.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 05:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1686548237158117</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ June 19, 2023] Conference talk or similar: Schelling after Kant: Intellectual Intuition as Theoretical Presupposition and Practical Demand in Vom Ich</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/112182</link>
						<description>Venue: Online<br/><br/>Speakers at this event: <br/>Marcela García-Romero (Loyola Marymount University)<br/>Addison Ellis (American University in Cairo)<br/><br/><p><strong>The Athens Colloquium on Kant and German Idealism</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Department of Philosophy, University of Athens</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Monday <strong>19 June</strong> <strong>2023</strong>, 18:00 p.m. (Athens, Greece time)</p>

<p><strong>Marcela García-Romero (Loyola Marymount)</strong></p>

<p><em>Schelling after Kant: Intellectual Intuition as Theoretical Presupposition and Practical Demand in Vom Ich</em></p>

<p>Respondent: Addison Ellis (American University of Cairo)</p>

<p>***To receive the paper to be discussed please contact Ioannis Trisokkas at <strong>idtrisokkas@philosophy.uoa.gr</strong> ***</p>

<p><strong>Organizers</strong>: Ioannis Trisokkas, Sebastian Stein, Stavros Panagiotou</p>

<p><strong>Webpage</strong>: https://sites.google.com/view/theathenscolloquium/home</p>

<p>For any enquiries please contact Ioannis Trisokkas (<strong>idtrisokkas@philosophy.uoa.gr</strong>).</p>


<p><strong>WEBEX LINK</strong></p>

<p>https://uoa.webex.com/uoa/j.php?MTID=mfff86c73135744699905dac9f0ae9557</p>

<p>Meeting number: 2733 503 8392</p>
<p>Password: KNmJCx9ap38</p>


<p><strong><u>MARCELA GARCÍA-ROMERO</u></strong></p>
<p>Professor Marcela García-Romero was born and raised in Mexico City. She earned a BA in Philosophy at the <em>University of Navarre</em>, Spain. She received her PhD in Philosophy in 2008 from the <em>Ludwig-Maximilians-Universität</em> in Munich, Germany, where she then worked as assistant professor. In 2012, she returned to Mexico to teach at <em>Universidad Iberoamericana</em>. From 2014 to 2016 she was a full-time research fellow at the Institute for Philosophical Research in<em> Mexico's National University</em> (<em>UNAM</em>). Before coming to LMU, she was a researcher and professor at <em>UNAM</em> and at <em>Universidad Michoacana</em> in Morelia, Mexico, where she coordinated the PhD in Philosophy program. Professor García-Romero's work centers on two main areas of philosophy. One main focus is German idealism, particularly the philosophy of the late Schelling and discussions regarding reality, life, human activity, freedom, and the limits of reason. Her other area of specialization is Ontology, specifically discussions on what it is to be and to exist, and the degree to which our concepts can grasp actual being. Professor García-Romero has published extensively on these topics in German, English and Spanish. She is a member of the editorial board of the academic journal <em>Philosophisches Jahrbuch</em> and a member of the executive committee of the <em>North American Schelling Society</em>. She is currently working on a book project on the late Schelling's reception of Aristotelian metaphysics.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 05:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1686548237158116</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>ConVersing/ConServing: Care, Creation, Communion</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/06/06/conversingconserving-care-creation-communion</link>
						<dc:creator>hfnelson</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Monday, June 12, 2023 - 5:58am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Dr. Katharine Bubel</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:katharine.bubel@twu.ca">katharine.bubel@twu.ca</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/ecocriticism-and-environmental-studies">ecocriticism and environmental studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/graduate-conferences">graduate conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/science-and-culture">science and culture</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>November 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Call for Papers</p>
<p>Western Regional Conference on Christianity &amp; Literature 2024</p>
<p><strong>ConVersing/ConServing: Care, Creation, Communion</strong></p>
<p>May 9-11, 2024</p>
<p>Trinity Western University</p>
<p>22500 University Drive</p>
<p>Langley, BC Canada V2Y 1Y1</p>
<p><strong>Our keynote speaker</strong>:</p>
<p>Marilyn McEntyre’s teaching and writing focuses on topics including American literature, medical humanities, literature and the natural world, portraiture and character in literature and art, and approaches to autobiography. Her many articles and books include <em>Caring for Words in a Culture of Lies </em>and <em>Speaking</em> <em>Peace in a Climate of Conflict</em>. She leads retreats and writing workshops and is deeply interested in the connections among spirituality, language, and healing.</p>
<p><strong>Suggested topics include, but are not limited to, literary creation conversing with</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>the work of conservation: ecology, creation theology, contemplative/active practices of creation care</li>
<li>the work of dwelling: sacred, secular/post-secular accounts of place, pilgrimage, migration, exile, reinhabitation</li>
<li>the work of honoring First Nations or Indigenous ways of knowing and ways of life</li>
<li>the work of cultivating words: exemplars, strategies, practices of language stewardship</li>
<li>the work of recovery: re/discovering forgotten or marginalized voices</li>
<li>the work of empathy: emotion and affect, caregiving, accounts of suffering, grief, illness</li>
<li>the work of social justice: remembrance, lament, protest, reconciliation</li>
<li>the work of the Inklings: Christian imagination and cultural criticism, mythopoeisis, literary community</li>
<li>the work of liturgy: sacred services, sacrament, spiritual practices</li>
<li>the work of God: grace, transformation, restoring all things in Christ<strong> </strong></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Proposal submissions: </strong>E-mail an abstract of no more than 300 words for an individual presentation or a group panel session by November 1, 2023, to Dr. Katharine Bubel at <a href="mailto:katharine.bubel@twu.ca">katharine.bubel@twu.ca</a>. </p>
<p>Undergraduate students must submit their entire paper for consideration; eligible undergraduate papers will be entered into the national CCL Undergraduate Writing Contest for a cash prize and publication on the CCL website. Graduate students are encouraged to apply for the CCL Travel Grant. For more details on these undergraduate and graduate opportunities, visit <a href="https://www.christianityandliterature.com/Awards-and-Grants%C2%A0">https://www.christianityandliterature.com/Awards-and-Grants </a></p>
<p><em>In Caring for Words in a Culture of Lies</em>, our conference keynote speaker Marilyn McEntyre presents literary art and the study of literature as a form of stewardship. Caring for words is akin, she says, to environmental concern and action, for we hold both language and the land in common. The conference invites presentations and conversations exploring the relations among literature and conservation, of serving together creatively to keep and pass on what has been given to us. Our topic is intentionally broad to encourage engagement across historical periods and genres. We invite professors, graduate and undergraduate students, and scholars from multiple disciplines. </p>
<p><strong>“</strong><em>A large, almost sacramental sense of the import and efficacy of words can be found in early English usage, where . . . to converse was to foster community, to commune with, to dwell in a place with others. Conversation was understood to be a life-sustaining practice, a blessing, and a craft to be cultivated for the common good.” – </em>Marilyn McEntyre</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1686375423518644</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Conference &quot;Performing theatricality and imaging religious ceremonies in early modern Western Europe&quot; (Ghent, May 15-17, 2024)</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/06/05/conference-performing-theatricality-and-imaging-religious-ceremonies-in-early-modern</link>
						<dc:creator>Steffnellis</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Friday, June 9, 2023 - 2:52pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Steff Nellis / Ghent University</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:Steff.Nellis@UGent.be">Steff.Nellis@UGent.be</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/eighteenth-century">eighteenth century</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/popular-culture">popular culture</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/theatre">theatre</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/travel-writing">travel writing</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>October 2, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p align="center"><strong>Call for Papers – “Performing theatricality and imaging religious ceremonies in early modern Western Europe”</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p align="center">May 15-17, 2024 (Ghent University)</p>
<p> </p>
<p>2023 marks the 300th anniversary of the publication of the early eighteenth-century book series <em>Cérémonies et coutumes religieuses de tous les peuples du monde</em>, a work on all the world’s religions known to Europe at that time and originally published in seven volumes between 1723 and 1737 in Amsterdam. Edited by the exiled French Huguenot Jean Frederic Bernard, the original seven volumes of the <em>Cérémonies </em>knew a vast distribution across European readers in the Netherlands, France, England, and the Holy Roman Empire, among other countries. Its popularity was at least partly due to the impressive set of prints included within the books. After all, the engravings were for the most part manufactured by the exiled Parisian artist, Bernard Picart, who was known as one of Europe’s most distinguished engravers at that time.</p>
<p>More than ten years after the publication of some pioneering studies on the project – <em>Religionsbilder der frühen Aufklärung </em>(2006), <em>The Book That Changed Europe </em>(2010) and <em>The First Global Vision of Religion </em>(2010) – the intriguing ceremonies and customs of the various religions depicted in the books still capture the imagination. This is not only caused by their ingenuity regarding the comparative method of inquiry into religion in general, as earlier research widely acknowledged, but also because of their importance as an early modern compendium of imaging religious ceremonies. After all, as the title already indicates, the <em>Cérémonies </em>discusses global religious ceremonies and customs. It focusses on <em>performing </em>religion, instead of on religion as such. In line with Picart and Bernard’s project, this conference aims to focus on the ways in which early modern Europeans related to religious ceremonies of all kinds, ranging from customs that were familiar to Western Europe’s everyday religious life, to rituals from peoples across the globe that were still rather alien to early modern Europeans.</p>
<p>Largely initiated by a turbulent period of the Reformation and Europe’s imperialist drive, the early modern period witnessed a great growth in religious diversity. Europeans thus encountered a growing number of different religious movements. Hence, the sixteenth and seventeenth centuries witnessed a proliferation of treatises that discussed all kinds of European forms of religious worship, as well as an abundance of travelogues and reports by colonial settlers that narrated on the religious practices of 'overseas peoples' in Africa, Asia, and the Americas on the other hand. The social pursuit of knowledge during these previous ages, characteristic of the Enlightenment period, eventually led to the rise of early ethnography and anthropology. In the 18th century, various studies on religious worship around the world of, among others, Nicolas de Nicolay (1567), Theodore de Bry (1590), Thomas Coryate (1611), John Smith (1624), and Gottfried Wilhelm Leibniz (1708) grew into general, ethnographic studies of religion as a social and anthropological construct (e.g. Charles de Brosses (1760); Octavien de Guasco (1768)).</p>
<p>The <em>Cérémonies</em> operates as an important intermediary between the sixteenth- and seventeenth-century treaties on religious cults and the subsequent ethnographic and anthropological studies on religion of the eighteenth century. As Picart and Bernard’s focus is entirely on the ways in which ceremonies and customs are <em>performed</em> within the various religions of the world, they simultaneously attribute a high degree of theatricality as well as a certain performativity to religion. By focusing on the explicit, outward dimension of devotion that is expressed through the <em>performance</em> of standardized religious ceremonies and rituals, they utter a profound critique on the ‘manufacturability’ of religion. The inherent theatricality and artificiality of religious rites, however, had been the focus of attention throughout the previous centuries, both among Protestant critics that denounced ceremonial splendor, as well as among Catholic clerics who drew up and canonized the laws and restrictions regarding devotional practices. Consider the anti-clerical Protestant tracts of, for example, William Prynn (1632), or the structured religious regulations for performing Catholic worship of Jean-Jacques Olier (1656), Claude-François Ménestrier and Jacques-Bénigne Bossuet, among others (1689).</p>
<p>The focus in the <em>Cérémonies</em> oscillates between a striving for an encyclopedic approach of the world's various religious ceremonies and an ideological critique of the theatricality of religious devotion. Besides the general scholarly intentions and the ideological objectives, economic interest played an increasingly significant part in the studying of religion too. Ethnographic and anthropological depictions of religious ceremonies sold; it seems. As the early eighteenth century saw a proliferation of knowledge production, not least in the field of religion, these types of knowledge became commodities that could be traded, sold, and marketed, and were part of the evolving book industry. The <em>Cérémonies</em> knew a deliberate marketing campaign too, as Bernard heavily relied on Picart’s fame as a popular engraver to set up his project. Through engravers like Picart, Inger Leemans (2010) argues, the European Enlightenment learned to sell itself not only intellectually but also commercially. Correspondingly, not long after the publication of the first French volumes of the <em>Cérémonies</em>, translations in English, Dutch, and German spread across Europe, not least by virtue of Picart’s artisanship.</p>
<p>In a reference to the British anthropologists Alfred Gell, Paola Von Wyss-Giacosa (2019) stresses that Picart’s illustrations must be considered a ‘source of, and target for, social agency’. His imaging of religious ceremonies offered a thought-provoking challenge to the public’s conception of religion; to compare, to ponder, and to raise doubts. Correspondingly, this conference aims to bring together researchers from a wide variety of fields to discuss the ways in which early modernity related to <em>performing</em> religious ceremonies and customs across the globe, either in text, print, on stage, or in any other imaginable way. How did early modern Europeans perceive religious rituals practiced in other parts of the world, particularly those in overseas territories? To what extent did early modern knowledge production on religious customs contribute to the development of early anthropology and ethnography in the latter half of the eighteenth century? How did representations of religious rituals either endorse or challenge existing knowledge on various religious practices? In what ways did the early modern period witness a shift toward a more encyclopedic approach to representing the ceremonies and customs of various religions, and how did this reflect broader intellectual trends of the Enlightenment era?</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Ghent University’s research groups, Studies in Performing Arts and Media (S:PAM) and Thalia kindly invite scholars from a wide variety of research areas that may include (but are not limited to) the following: religious studies, theology, cultural studies, literature, performance studies, history, art history, history of the book, history of science, anthropology, ethnography, or any other relevant field. Contributions should be in the format of approximately 25-minute presentations. Proposals might consider, but are not limited to:</p>
<p> </p>
<p>-       Performing arts and religious ceremonies</p>
<p>-       Religious customs, rituals, and cults across the globe</p>
<p>-       Religion and Enlightenment</p>
<p>-       Early modern European ethnography and anthropology</p>
<p>-       Cross-cultural and/or cross-religious encounters between (non-)Europeans</p>
<p>-       Idolatry, fetishism, totemism, and exoticism</p>
<p>-       Religious conflict and toleration</p>
<p>-       Religious ceremonies in Reformation- and Counter Reformation- discourses</p>
<p>-       Bernard Picart &amp; Jean Frederic Bernard</p>
<p>-       Sixteenth-, seventeenth-, and eighteenth-century depictions of religious ceremonies</p>
<p>-       Ceremonial splendor</p>
<p> </p>
<p>To submit a proposal, send an abstract (250 words) and a brief biography to drs. Steff Nellis. All enquiries should be sent directly to Steff as well (<a href="mailto:steff.nellis@ugent.be">steff.nellis@ugent.be</a>).</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Suggested reading:</p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p>Gagné, R., Goldhill, S., &amp; Lloyd, G. E. R. (2019). <em>Regimes of Comparatism: Frameworks of</em></p>
<p><em>Comparison in History, Religion and Anthropology</em>.</p>
<p>Hunt, L., Jacob, M. C., &amp; Mijnhardt, W. (2010a). <em>The Book That Changed Europe: Picart</em></p>
<p><em>and Bernard’s Religious Ceremonies of the World</em>. Harvard University Press.</p>
<p>Hunt, L., Jacob, M. C., &amp; Mijnhardt, W. W. (2010b). <em>Bernard Picart and the First Global</em></p>
<p><em>Vision of Religion</em>. Getty Publications.</p>
<p>Palacios, J. (2022). <em>Ceremonial Splendor: Performing Priesthood in Early Modern France</em>.</p>
<p>University of Pennsylvania Press.</p>
<p>Tarantino, G., &amp; Von Wyss-Giacosa, P. (2021). <em>Through Your Eyes: Religious Alterity and</em></p>
<p><em>the Early Modern Western Imagination</em>. Jerusalem Studies in Religion.</p>
<p>Von Wyss-Giacosa, P. (2006). <em>Religionsbilder der frühen Aufklärung: Bernard Picarts</em></p>
<p><em>Tafeln für die “Cérémonies et coutumes religieuses de tous les peuples du monde.”</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Important dates:</p>
<p>Deadline for submissions: October 2, 2023</p>
<p>Notification of acceptance: November 3, 2023</p>
<p>Dates of the conference: May 15-17, 2024</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 09:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1686375423518643</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Identity in Flux: the Making and Unmaking of Medieval Social Categories</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/06/03/identity-in-flux-the-making-and-unmaking-of-medieval-social-categories</link>
						<dc:creator>hcushman</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Friday, June 9, 2023 - 7:02am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>H.M. Cushman and Mariah Min</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:hcush@email.unc.edu">hcush@email.unc.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/ethnicity-and-national-identity">ethnicity and national identity</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/gender-studies-and-sexuality">gender studies and sexuality</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/medieval">medieval</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>July 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>Deadline for submissions:</strong> July 15, 2023</p>
<p><strong>Date of conference:</strong> October 20, 2023</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Invitation: </strong>This virtual conference invites papers to consider medieval practices of identity formation and representations of identity. Examples of possible topics to consider include: How might medieval models of consciously constructed literary character illuminate the constructedness of identity and/or textual representations of identity? How do medieval notions of identity help us to understand it as unstable, contextually contingent, and its categories as mutually constitutive— as a species of performative participation rather than a static possession? Conversely, how might medieval texts work to stabilize or mystify the mutability of identity? We welcome papers that come to these and related questions from a variety of theoretical and methodological approaches and strongly encourage interdisciplinary approaches. Considerations of national, racial, religious, and gender/trans identity are welcome, as are papers concerned with kinship and familial affiliation, class/estate, and the intersections of these forms of identity.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Instructions for submission: </strong>Please send an abstract of no more than 150 words to <a href="mailto:hcush@email.unc.edu">hcush@email.unc.edu</a> and <a href="mailto:mariah_min@brown.edu">mariah_min@brown.edu</a> before the deadline. Include your name, affiliation, email, and pronouns. Please indicate in your submission whether you would like your essay to be considered for inclusion in a possible forum of published essays.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 17:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1686375423518642</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP: Journal of Lao Studies. New Submission Date and Email</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12875186/cfp-journal-lao-studies-new-submission-date-and-email</link>
						<dc:creator>Mike Rattanasengchanh</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Journal</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-12-31T00:00:00-05:00">December 31, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Asian American History / Studies, Asian History / Studies, Southeast Asian History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Environmental History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>*** <strong>Had issue with former email account so re-posting with new submission date and email </strong><br/><br/>The Journal of Lao Studies is accepting submissions of articles, book review suggestions, review articles (extended reviews of major publications, trends in the field, or of political, social, or economic events). These submissions can cover studies on Laos (all ethnic groups), Lao residing in bordering countries (Northeast Thailand, Northeast Cambodia, Vietnam, China, and Burma), ethnic groups bordering Laos with a representation in Laos (e.g. Akha, Mien, Khmu, Hmong, Tai Lue, etc.), or studies in regards to Lao disapora outside of Asia (the Americas, Australia, France, Argentina, etc.).<br/><br/>Papers will go through a double blind peer-review. <br/><br/>Please send submissions to <a href="mailto:mike.rattanasengchanh@msutexas.edu">mike.rattanasengchanh@msutexas.edu</a> and not the email address on the CLS website. <br/><br/>See the website for further information and guidelines, <a href="https://lnkd.in/giz42kPM" rel="nofollow">https://lnkd.in/giz42kPM</a>. <br/><br/>You can contact us at the editor’s email address, <a href="mailto:mike.rattanasengchanh@msutexas.edu">mike.rattanasengchanh@msutexas.edu</a><br/><br/>NEW deadline for submission in the upcoming journal issue is August 1, 2023. Submissions received after the due date will be considered for the next issue. Please submit papers to to <a href="mailto:mike.rattanasengchanh@msutexas.edu">mike.rattanasengchanh@msutexas.edu</a> and not the email address on the CLS website.<br/><br/>We are excited to see what new research has been done!<br/><br/>Sincerely,<br/><br/>Dr. P. Mike Rattanasengchanh, Editor<br/>Assistant Professor of History<br/>Midwestern State University<br/>Contact Email: <br/><a href="mailto:mike.rattanasengchanh@msutexas.edu">mike.rattanasengchanh@msutexas.edu</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:mike.rattanasengchanh@msutexas.edu">mike.rattanasengchanh@msutexas.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 20:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1686289031501779</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – June 7, 2023</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-june-7-2023/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find 17 new job opportunities, 6 Fellowships, 3 Grants, 4 Call for Papers, 2 upcoming conferences/speakers, and 3 other events/submissions.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 33!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Academia:</h4>



<h4>Assistant Director of Student Engagement – Arts &amp;Sciences (Ph.D. required, humanities preferred)</h4>



<p>Washing University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: June 23, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://wustl.wd1.myworkdayjobs.com/en-US/External/job/Assistant-Director-of-Student-Engagement---Arts---Sciences_JR75295">https://wustl.wd1.myworkdayjobs.com/en-US/External/job/Assistant-Director-of-Student-Engagement—Arts—Sciences_JR75295</a></p>



<h4>Early Career Teaching &amp; Research Fellow: Long 19<sup>th</sup> Century – Romanticism to Victorianism (Full-time, 3-year appointment)</h4>



<p>The University of Edinburgh, Scotland</p>



<p>Deadline: June 28, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.jobs.ac.uk/job/DAG207/early-career-teaching-and-research-fellow-long-nineteenth-century-romanticism-to-victorianism">https://www.jobs.ac.uk/job/DAG207/early-career-teaching-and-research-fellow-long-nineteenth-century-romanticism-to-victorianism</a></p>



<h4>Departmental Lecturer in International Relations</h4>



<p>University of Oxford, UK</p>



<p>Deadline: June 26, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.jobs.ac.uk/job/DAH128/departmental-lecturer-in-international-relations-in-association-with-st-hildas-college">https://www.jobs.ac.uk/job/DAH128/departmental-lecturer-in-international-relations-in-association-with-st-hildas-college</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Dean for Inclusion, Diversity, and Equity in Agriculture</h4>



<p>Colorado State University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: July 2, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://jobs.colostate.edu/postings/126081">https://jobs.colostate.edu/postings/126081</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor in Gender and Postcolonial Studies</h4>



<p>Utrecht University, Netherlands</p>



<p>Deadline: August 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.uu.nl/organisatie/werken-bij-de-universiteit-utrecht/vacatures/assistant-professor-in-gender-and-postcolonial-studies-10-fte">Assistant Professor in Gender and Postcolonial Studies (1.0 FTE) – Werken bij de Universiteit Utrecht – Universiteit Utrecht (uu.nl)</a></p>



<h4>Minerva Recruitment Job Listings Cite (with areas specifically tailored for Ph.D.)</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://minerva-recruitment.com/">Minerva Recruitment – Higher Education Graduate Jobs, UK &amp; Worldwide (minerva-recruitment.com)</a></p>



<h4>AAR/SBL Job Forum</h4>



<p><a href="https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search">https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search</a></p>



<h4>Non-Academia:</h4>



<h4>Educator</h4>



<p>Sydney Jewish Museum, Australia</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/jobs/view/3611104876/">https://www.linkedin.com/jobs/view/3611104876/</a></p>



<h4>Research &amp; Evaluation Specialist: Early Childhood Development and Health Board</h4>



<p>State of Arizona, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.azstatejobs.gov/jobs/research-evaluation-specialist-phoenix-arizona-united-states-1e5c2c25-a107-45ae-881e-d451aaf9c9fd">https://www.azstatejobs.gov/jobs/research-evaluation-specialist-phoenix-arizona-united-states-1e5c2c25-a107-45ae-881e-d451aaf9c9fd</a></p>



<h4>Fact-Checking and Research</h4>



<p>UNICEF, USA (Remote)</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/jobs/view/3615675262/">https://www.linkedin.com/jobs/view/3615675262/</a></p>



<h4>IRB Affairs Expedited Specialist</h4>



<p>WCG Clinical, USA (Remote)</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/dfCsn3LldV">https://t.co/dfCsn3LldV</a></p>



<h4>Coaching &amp; Training Specialist</h4>



<p>Close Up Foundation, USA</p>



<p> More Information: <a href="https://t.co/3c9FdCS2nP">https://t.co/3c9FdCS2nP</a></p>



<h4>Manager, Research, and Analysis</h4>



<p>US Chamber of Commerce, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/5XRwZrNQQF">https://t.co/5XRwZrNQQF</a></p>



<h4>Associate Peer Review Specialist</h4>



<p>Sage Publications, USA (Remote)</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/RAIoZILt3e">https://t.co/RAIoZILt3e</a></p>



<h4>Senior Project Manager, Gender Point</h4>



<p>Institute for Women’s Policy Research, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/jobs/view/3558895928/">https://www.linkedin.com/jobs/view/3558895928/</a></p>



<h4>Editor/Senior Editor</h4>



<p>Springer Nature Group, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.springernature.com/job/Dordrecht-EditorSenior-Editor-%28Books%29-Geography-and-Sustainability-Research/931934101/?feedId=366801">https://careers.springernature.com/job/Dordrecht-EditorSenior-Editor-%28Books%29-Geography-and-Sustainability-Research/931934101/?feedId=366801</a></p>



<h4>Coordinator of Professional Learning &amp; Org. Culture</h4>



<p>State Education Resource Center, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/pqWxU0tC4x">https://t.co/pqWxU0tC4x</a></p>



<h4>E-Learning Specialist</h4>



<p>The Mindbridge Center, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/jobs/view/3616983539/">https://www.linkedin.com/jobs/view/3616983539/</a></p>



<h4>Learning and Development Coordinator</h4>



<p>Community Food Bank of Southern Arizona, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/jobs/view/3611742962/">https://www.linkedin.com/jobs/view/3611742962/</a></p>



<h2>Fellowships:</h2>



<h4>Philosophy of AI (3-year appointment)</h4>



<p>Copenhagen University, Denmark</p>



<p>Deadline:  August 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://employment.ku.dk/phd/?show=159134">https://employment.ku.dk/phd/?show=159134</a></p>



<h4>Jews and Health</h4>



<p>University of Pennsylvania, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: October 18, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/4GzG8Dw2Oj">https://t.co/4GzG8Dw2Oj</a></p>



<h4>Institute for Advanced Study in Global South</h4>



<p>Northwestern – Qatar</p>



<p>Deadline: July 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/usIzukqN8n">https://t.co/usIzukqN8n</a></p>



<h4>Postdoctoral Fellowship</h4>



<p>Louisville Institute</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://louisville-institute.org/programs-grants-and-fellowships/fellowships/">https://louisville-institute.org/programs-grants-and-fellowships/fellowships/</a></p>



<h4>Dissertation Fellowship</h4>



<p>Louisville Institute</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://louisville-institute.org/programs-grants-and-fellowships/fellowships/">https://louisville-institute.org/programs-grants-and-fellowships/fellowships/</a></p>



<h4>Doctoral Fellowship</h4>



<p>Louisville Institute</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://louisville-institute.org/programs-grants-and-fellowships/fellowships/">https://louisville-institute.org/programs-grants-and-fellowships/fellowships/</a></p>



<h2>Grants:</h2>



<h4>Project Grant for Researchers</h4>



<p>Louisville Institute</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://louisville-institute.org/programs-grants-and-fellowships/grants/">Grants – Louisville Institute (louisville-institute.org)</a></p>



<h4>Sabbatical Grant for Researchers</h4>



<p>Louisville Institute</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://louisville-institute.org/programs-grants-and-fellowships/grants/">Grants – Louisville Institute (louisville-institute.org)</a></p>



<h4>First Book Grant for Scholars of Color</h4>



<p>Louisville Institute</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://louisville-institute.org/programs-grants-and-fellowships/grants/">Grants – Louisville Institute (louisville-institute.org)</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>Theology and Religion in Daredevil</h4>



<p>Deadline: July 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://popularcultureandtheology.com/2023/05/25/call-for-papers-theology-and-religion-in-daredevil/">https://popularcultureandtheology.com/2023/05/25/call-for-papers-theology-and-religion-in-daredevil/</a></p>



<h4>Zero Hour: Rethinking 1945 From Jewish Transnational Perspectives</h4>



<p>Deadline: July 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12871347/cfp-zero-hour-rethinking-1945-jewish-transnational">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12871347/cfp-zero-hour-rethinking-1945-jewish-transnational</a></p>



<h4>Devil 2024</h4>



<p>Deadline: October 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://twitter.com/rraiswell/status/1663884395122401281?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw">https://twitter.com/rraiswell/status/1663884395122401281?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw</a></p>



<h4>350 Years of Paradise Lost, A Poem in Twelve Books</h4>



<p>Deadline June 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/05/30/350-years-of-paradise-lost-a-poem-in-twelve-books-1674-2024">https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/05/30/350-years-of-paradise-lost-a-poem-in-twelve-books-1674-2024</a></p>



<h2>Conferences:</h2>



<h4>Kant on Dilemma of Rational Religion</h4>



<p>Date: June 22, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/112050">https://philevents.org/event/show/112050</a></p>



<h4>Exit Academia: How to land an industry job as a Ph.D. without an internship or a bootcamp.</h4>



<p>Date: June 8, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/YdiKwPc3kO">https://t.co/YdiKwPc3kO</a></p>



<h2>Miscellaneous:</h2>



<h4>Forum Basiliense: Platform for Interdisciplinary Dialogue</h4>



<p>University of Basel, Switzerland</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://forum-basiliense.unibas.ch/en/">https://forum-basiliense.unibas.ch/en/</a></p>



<h4>Young Scholars in American Religion</h4>



<p>Deadline: June 20, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://raac.iupui.edu/programs/young-scholars-in-american-religion/2023-25-ysar-application/">https://raac.iupui.edu/programs/young-scholars-in-american-religion/2023-25-ysar-application/</a></p>



<h4>2023 Wabash Center Teaching and Learning Workshops</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.wabashcenter.wabash.edu/programs/workshops/">https://www.wabashcenter.wabash.edu/programs/workshops/</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1686202625415520</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
