<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 03:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 03:08:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ July 8, 2024 -  July 13, 2024] Conference or similar: The Psychology of Faith Academic Cross-Training Project</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104398</link>
						<description>Venue: 2115 Summit Ave<br/><br/><p>This is a workshop for the Psychology of Faith Academic Cross-Training Project. It is not open to the general public, but applications to the project can be made on our website: https://cas.stthomas.edu/departments/areas-of-study/philosophy/academic-cross-training-grant/.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666762628505355</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ January 23, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: The Psychology and Theology of Faith</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104402</link>
						<description><p>With the support of the John Templeton Foundation, the University of St. Thomas (MN) announces The Psychology and Theology of Faith sub-granting competition, to fund academic cross-training in the psychological sciences for scholars of Christian theology or philosophy of religion with research interests relating to religious belief or religious commitment. Six successful applicants will each receive a $70,000 award providing the opportunity to take courses in and work with mentors from the psychological sciences, in order to apply and leverage insights from the psychological sciences in their work as theologians and philosophers. Applications are due Jan 23, 2023. For more information, see our website:</p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666762628505354</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for entries:  Palgrave Encyclopedia of Islamic Economics and Finance</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11439983/call-entries-palgrave-encyclopedia-islamic-economics-and</link>
						<dc:creator>Cenap Cakmak</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Publications</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-12-31T00:00:00-05:00">December 31, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Turkey</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Area Studies, Islamic History / Studies, Law and Legal History, Middle East History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><b><span>Call for entries:</span></b></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><b><span>Palgrave Encyclopedia of Islamic Economics and Finance </span></b></span></span></p><p>(Inquire for remaining entries)</p><p><span><span><span><span>The concept of Islamic finance and economy has attracted a great deal of attention in the academic circles in recent years. The growing interest in the practices and products of Islamic finance and the integration of Islamic finance with global economy is a major factor; however, it is not appropriate to attribute the surge in academic publications on the subjects of Islamic finance to this factor alone. Islamic economics, as an alternative domain of study that offers innovative tools and approaches in place of conventional teachings in the literature, deserves greater attention in not only the realm of practice but also of academy and theory. </span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span>Interestingly, the concept of Islamic finance and economy takes greater attention in the West rather than predominantly Muslim countries. Even though there is visible interest in Islamic economy in such Muslim countries as Turkey, Malaysia, Iran and Malaysia, number and quality of academic studies in this field is far from being adequate and satisfactory. On the other hand, the Western academic circles, with the exception of some inherent prejudices and theological aloofness, are in pursuit of offering sincere answers to questions relevant to Islamic economic models and teachings. </span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span>It should be noted, however, that the initial steps towards formulating an Islamic finance and economy should be taken in a Muslim country, Turkey being a major candidate. Despite that it has been a long time since the introduction of Islamic finance institutions, the academic circles in Turkey have failed to catch up and delayed to fill the gap. Laying down the theoretical framework of the Islamic finance institutions that have exhibited a trend of growth and popularity not only in Turkey but also in the world is a matter of urgency for the academic institutions and figures. </span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span>This study seeks to address this problem and thus to offer an introductory account focusing on the subjects of Islamic finance and economics. There is visible need for such an account since there is no comprehensive literature that can be employed in courses being offered in courses on Islamic finance and economy. Additionally, there are not even much works of reference that can be consulted with by researchers who are in the initial phase of their studies. To this end, this work, an initiative that will address this gap by featuring a style of encyclopedia that holds a special place in Western academic tradition, collects and explains major concepts of Islamic finance and economics. The study that will present a solid framework for the elaboration of the major concepts of the subject will make use of the existing academic literature, as well as theological sources and the history of Islam and of Islamic financial practices. </span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span>For this reason, this encyclopedia relies on an interdisciplinary approach. Even though in some instances will it give the impression that it is a study of economics literature, the volume will also make room for discussions of Islamic theology, history and philosophy. The goal in doing this is to present the historical theoretical framework as well as the modern and contemporary views and tendencies. From this perspective, this study makes a strong claim that it will serve as a reference work for those who are eager to conduct research on different aspects of Islamic finance and economics. </span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span>This study primarily speaks to the academic community. Even though it could be considered an introductory effort for the academics who do research on Islamic finance, this volume presents an integrated and condensed account. The problems regarding eclecticism are persistent in different academic disciplines; but it is even more acute and pressing when it comes to the study of Islamic finance and economics. As a result, the researchers in most cases leave many issues out which thus make the outcome vague and imprecise in the literature. </span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span>The encyclopedia of Islamic economics and finance compiles and features what could be worth being researched further in an integrated manner. Every single entry in the encyclopedia represents a wider area where further research can be employed. What the researchers are expected to do is to pick one, identify the potential correlations and overlaps between different subjects and to draw a roadmap accordingly. </span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><b><span><span>Timetable:</span></span></b></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span>This work is to be completed in June 2023, as stipulated under the terms of a publication contract with Palgrave. The study features more than 400 entries, ranging from length of 500 to 5,000 words, depending on their significance. Even though a substantial part of the entries has already been solicited, there are still others open to expression of interest by the wider academic community. Inquiries on the list of the entries and their availability should be forwarded to </span></span><a href="mailto:apply.encyclopedia.ife@gmail.com"><span><span><span>apply.encyclopedia.ife@gmail.com</span></span></span></a><span>, along with a brief summary of personal information. Further details will be communicated with those showing interest in this project. </span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span>Editors:</span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span>Prof. Dr. Murat Ustaoğlu, Istanbul University</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Prof. Dr. Cenap Çakmak, Anadolu University</span></span></span></p><p> </p><p> </p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Interested parties may send their inquiries along with a brief CV to the following email addresses:</p><p>Cenap Cakmak, <a href="mailto:cenapcakmak75@gmail.com">cenapcakmak75@gmail.com</a></p><p>Also <a href="mailto:apply.encyclopedia.ife@gmail.com">apply.encyclopedia.ife@gmail.com</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:apply.encyclopedia.ife@gmail.com">apply.encyclopedia.ife@gmail.com</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 17:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666762628505353</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>National Library of Australia Fellowship presentation: Dr Sugata Nandi - ‘Spiritualist West, Magical Orient: Theosophists and India, 1875-1930’.</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11431759/national-library-australia-fellowship-presentation-dr-sugata</link>
						<dc:creator>Sharyn O'Brien</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-27T00:00:00-04:00">October 27, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Australia</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Asian History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span>The National Library of Australia invites you to join us online or in person for our latest Fellowship presentation by 2020 NLA Fellowship recipient Dr Sugata Nandi.  </span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><strong><span><span>Dr Sugata Nandi: ‘Spiritualist West, Magical Orient: Theosophists and India, 1875-1930’.  </span></span></strong></span></span></p><p><span><span><strong><span><span>Thursday October 27th, 2022.  </span></span></strong></span></span></p><p><span><span><strong><span><span>12.30pm AEDT. </span></span></strong></span></span></p><p><span><span><strong><span><span>Join online here: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/National.Library.of.Australia" rel="nofollow">National Library’s Facebook page</a>. </span></span></strong></span></span></p><p><span><span><strong><span><span>In person: National Library of Australia, Parkes Place. Lower Ground 1 Theatre. </span></span></strong></span></span></p><p><span><span><strong><span><span>This event is free and open to the public. A recording will be made available after the event on the <a href="https://www.nla.gov.au/stories/all?type%5Bvideo%5D=video" rel="nofollow">National Library’s website</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/NationalLibraryofAustralia/playlists" rel="nofollow">YouTube</a> channel. </span></span></strong></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span>Join Dr Sugata Nandi as he presents his 2020 National Library Fellowship research on theosophists and India from 1875 to 1930, and the resulting new interpretations and uses of Hinduism and Buddhism. </span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>In 1879, Helena Petrovna Blavatsky (1831-91), an émigré Russia noblewoman, and Henry Steel Olcott (1832-1907), an American, reached India in search of knowledge of her two religions, Hinduism and Buddhism. In 1875 they had founded The Theosophical Society in New York, a spiritualist organisation that, by the 1900s, enjoyed a global presence and had turned Western esoteric quests to India and her two religions, Hinduism and Buddhism. Their quest led to radically new interpretations and uses of the religions which gave rise to a new, diverse and highly controversial body of knowledge on India as the proverbial Magical Orient. </span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><strong><span><span>About Dr Sugata Nandi </span></span></strong></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Dr Sugata Nandi is Assistant Professor of History at the West Bengal State University, Kolkata, India, where he teaches Modern Indian History, the Industrial Revolution, Western Historiography and Research Methodology. He has been a visiting research fellow at the Institute for Advanced Studies in the Humanities of the University of Edinburgh (2018), Senate House Library Visiting Research Fellow at London University (2019) and a Fulbright–Nehru Doctoral and Professional Research Fellow at the University of Washington, Seattle, USA (2011-12). He has recently been awarded the Junior Fellowship at the Institute for Advanced Study of Central European University, Budapest, which he will commence in early 2023.</span></span></span></span></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:fellowships@nla.gov.au">fellowships@nla.gov.au</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 17:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666762628505352</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Christianity &amp; Culture Conference: The Family, Past &amp; Future</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11427802/christianity-culture-conference-family-past-future</link>
						<dc:creator>David Davis</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-03T00:00:00-05:00">February 3, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-04T00:00:00-05:00">February 4, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Texas</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Humanities, Literature, Philosophy, Religious Studies and Theology, Social Sciences</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The inaugural Christianity and Culture Conference at Houston Christian University (formerly Houston Baptist University) seeks to highlight the importance of the Family in the Western Tradition by exploring the different representations, significations, and roles of the Family. The conference will provide a cross-disciplinary venue to consider the past and future importance of the Family, particularly from a Christian perspective, that is evident in literature, philosophy, history, science, art, and religion.</p><p>Keynote Speaker: Dr. Mark Regnerus, Professor of Sociology (University of Texas at Austin): <a href="https://www.markregnerus.com/" rel="nofollow">https://www.markregnerus.com/</a></p><p> </p><p><strong>Panel and Paper Proposals</strong></p><p>Proposals may include academic papers/presentations from a variety of liberal arts and social sciences, as well as creative presentations (e.g. artwork, poetry readings, etc.) that illustrate the importance of the Family. Proposals emphasizing cross-disciplinarity are particularly encouraged.</p><p>Topics for proposals may include:</p><ul><li>Representations of the Family in literature and art</li><li>Changes to the notion of the Family over time</li><li>The Family and religious practice</li><li>Religious beliefs and Family values</li><li>Cultural and sociological changes to the Family</li><li>Philosophical issues related to the Family</li><li>Comparative studies of the Family</li></ul><p>Proposals from graduate and undergraduate students are welcome. </p><p><strong>Deadline for proposals is December 16, 2022. </strong></p><p>Proposal abstracts should be 200-300 words. Please email submissions and questions to Dr. David Davis: <a href="mailto:ddavis@hbu.edu">ddavis@hbu.edu</a>.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ddavis@hbu.edu">ddavis@hbu.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://hbu.edu/arts-humanities/events/christianity-and-culture-conference/" target="_blank">https://hbu.edu/arts-humanities/events/christianity-and-culture-conference/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 17:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666762628505351</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>&quot;Making the law. The role of religious women in the construction of law in the Viceroyalty of Peru in the eighteenth century&quot;</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11424567/making-law-role-religious-women-construction-law-viceroyalty</link>
						<dc:creator>Sarah Barthélemy</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Seminar</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-26T00:00:00-04:00">October 26, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology, Early Modern History and Period Studies, Latin American and Caribbean History / Studies, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><em>Despite the existence of several studies related to religious institutions and their regulations in the Hispanic monarchy, the histories of the principal actors in the case of Peru have been largely forgotten. This paper will bring to light the process of creating ecclesiastical regulations for the control and government of the female religious houses of Lima in the eighteenth century, paying special attention to the role played by both the ecclesiastical authorities and female religious, who were, far from being mere recipients of dictates, essential for the construction of these regulations.</em></p><p>D﻿r Liliana Pérez Miguel is a María Zambrano postdoctoral researcher at the Universidad de Sevilla.</p><p>This is part of the ISHWRA (<a href="https://www.durham.ac.uk/research/institutes-and-centres/catholic-studies/research/history-of-catholicism-/history-of-women-religious-association/" rel="nofollow">International Scholars of the History of Women Religious Association - Durham University</a>) Seminar Series 2022-2023.</p><h3>Date and time</h3><p>Wed, 26 Oct 2022, 13:00 BST</p><h3>Location</h3><p>Online</p><p> </p><p>Please register at: <a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/ishwra-seminar-october-2022-tickets-431607167657" rel="nofollow">ISHWRA Seminar October 2022 Tickets, Wed 26 Oct 2022 at 13:00 | Eventbrite</a></p><p>(You will receive the link to the seminar after registering)</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:sarah.barthelemy@durham.ac.uk">sarah.barthelemy@durham.ac.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/ishwra-seminar-october-2022-tickets-431607167657" target="_blank">https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/ishwra-seminar-october-2022-tickets-431607167657</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 17:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666676230608999</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Papers: Yale Journal of Music &amp; Religion special issue: Sacred Recitation and Ritual in Digital Worlds</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11412212/call-papers-yale-journal-music-religion-special-issue-sacred</link>
						<dc:creator>Joanna Murdoch</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-01-15T00:00:00-05:00">January 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Digital Humanities, Islamic History / Studies, Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Music and Music History</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Call for Papers: Sacred Recitation and Ritual in Digital Worlds</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The Yale Journal of Music &amp; Religion will publish a special issue on sacred recitation in digital worlds guest edited by Anne K. Rasmussen. We invite submissions documenting and interpreting routes of transmission and access, ritual communities, novel uses of media and technologies, and transformations of religious identities through the intersections of voice, scripture, and sacred text in digital worlds. As sacred recitation is performed and received in spatially and temporally dispersed spaces, this special issue seeks to understand the relationships of religion, media, and technology in their contemporary and emergent forms. Relevant topics include learning and listening; the consolidation of media and recitation styles; responses to the Covid pandemic; digital methods in historical research; diaspora and displacement; institutions, traditions, and identities; religious adaptations of digital technologies; and religious publics and politics.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Deadline for submissions: January 15, 2023 at <a href="https://elischolar.library.yale.edu/yjmr/" rel="nofollow"><span>https://elischolar.library.yale.edu/yjmr/</span></a></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Questions? Please contact guest editor Anne K. Rasmussen (<a href="mailto:akrasm@wm.edu"><span>akrasm@wm.edu</span></a>) or editor-in-chief Jeffers Engelhardt (<a href="mailto:jengelhardt@amherst.edu"><span>jengelhardt@amherst.edu</span></a>)</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Joanna Murdoch</p><p>Managing Editor, Yale Journal of Music &amp; Religion</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:joanna.murdoch@yale.edu">joanna.murdoch@yale.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="http://ism.yale.edu/yjmr" target="_blank">http://ism.yale.edu/yjmr</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 17:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666676230608998</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Hagiography Society Article Prize</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11398608/hagiography-society-article-prize</link>
						<dc:creator>Catherine Mooney</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Prize</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-22T00:00:00-04:00">October 22, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-01-15T00:00:00-05:00">January 15, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>European History / Studies, Islamic History / Studies, Jewish History / Studies, Medieval and Byzantine History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>This prize will be awarded to a scholarly essay or article written on any disciplinary subject that makes an outstanding contribution to the study and understanding of saints, holy men and women, virtue traditions, and the concept of sanctity in ideational, literary, artistic, and sociohistorical dimensions in the pre-modern period. Articles concerning all geographies and religious systems are eligible. The monetary value of the prize is $300. The author of the article must be a member of the (very affordable) Hagiography Society by the time of the article’s submission. All essays and articles that have been published in 2021 and 2022 are eligible for the prize. The submission deadline is Jan. 15, 2023. An electronic copy of your article should be sent to the President of the Hagiography Society, Catherine M. Mooney.  Email: <a href="mailto:catherine.mooney@bc.edu">catherine.mooney@bc.edu</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Catherine M. Mooney, President, The Hagiography Society</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:catherine.mooney@bc.edu">catherine.mooney@bc.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.hagiographysociety.org/" target="_blank">https://www.hagiographysociety.org/?page_id=265</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 17:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666676230608997</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Travel Award for grad student giving paper on saints/hagiography at 2023 International Congress on Medieval Studies</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11398604/travel-award-grad-student-giving-paper-saintshagiography-2023</link>
						<dc:creator>Catherine Mooney</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Prize</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-22T00:00:00-04:00">October 22, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-15T00:00:00-05:00">November 15, 2022</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><strong>The Sherry L. Reames Graduate Student Travel Award for Hagiographical Studies</strong></p><p>Named in honor of the beloved founder and long-time leader of the Society, the award now provides up to $1000 to be used toward registration, travel, lodging, and meals to present a paper at the International Congress on Medieval Studies, held annually at Western Michigan University in Kalamazoo, MI. The winners will be granted a free two-year membership in the Hagiography Society.</p><p><strong>Eligibility</strong></p><p>Students who are Hagiography Society members and enrolled in a graduate program (anywhere in the world) are eligible to apply if their paper, on a topic involving hagiography, has been accepted for inclusion on a regular panel (not a round table or other format) in the program of the International Congress on Medieval Studies in Kalamazoo, MI, at the time of application. They are also expected to attend the annual Hagiography Society Business Meeting held at the International Congress on Medieval Studies.</p><p><strong>Application</strong></p><p>Please submit the attached form with a current curriculum vitæ (combined in a single PDF with your last name in the document name) by November 15 to the Secretary / Treasurer of the Hagiography Society (<a href="mailto:secretary@hagiographysociety.org">secretary@hagiographysociety.org</a>).</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Secretary / Treasurer of The Hagiography Society</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:secretary@hagiographysociety.org">secretary@hagiographysociety.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.hagiographysociety.org/" target="_blank">https://www.hagiographysociety.org/?page_id=265</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 17:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666676230608996</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mapping the Spiritual Baptist Universe: Black Atlantic Cosmography and the Spatial Dimensions of Religious Imagination in Trinidad and Tobago</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11398280/mapping-spiritual-baptist-universe-black-atlantic-cosmography</link>
						<dc:creator>Jeanne Kilde</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-27T00:00:00-04:00">October 27, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Minnesota</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>African American History / Studies, Anthropology, Black History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Colonial and Post-Colonial History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Join us for the Roetzel Family Lecture in Religious Studies.  Ethnographer and religious studies scholar Brendan Jamal Thornton will discuss his research on Spiritual Baptists in Trinidad and Tobago, focusing on their unique, trans-global cosmography. Thornton examines the locational metaphors orienting local creole cosmologies and considers in detail the spatial dimentions that inform their ritual logics. By diagramming the Spiritual Baptist universe and the sacred geography of Spirit that enlivens it, he shows how churchgoers reconciled diverse religious influences (from Africa, South Asia, Europe, and beyond) and probes for cosmolgraphical clues to their sybolically rich but often enigmatic rites and traditions.  </p><p>This event is offered both in-person on the University of Minnesota campus and as a simulcast Webinar.  Thursday, October 27, 2022, 3:30 pm (CDT). </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Jeanne H. Kilde, Director of the Religious Studies Program</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:jkilde@umn.edu">jkilde@umn.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://events.tc.umn.edu/event/9335-mapping-the-spiritual-baptist-universe" target="_blank">https://events.tc.umn.edu/event/9335-mapping-the-spiritual-baptist-universe</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 17:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666676230608995</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Grateful Dead presentations, PCA Conference, San Antonio Apr 5-8, 2023</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/10/23/grateful-dead-presentations-pca-conference-san-antonio-apr-5-8-2023</link>
						<dc:creator>ganterg@stjohns.edu</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Sunday, October 23, 2022 - 4:58pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Grateful Dead Studies Association</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ganterg@stjohns.edu">ganterg@stjohns.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/fan-studies-and-fandom">fan studies and fandom</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/popular-culture">popular culture</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>December 20, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Scholars from all disciplines are invited to submit proposals for papers, panels, and special sessions for the third annual <a href="https://nam10.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fdeadstudies.org%2F&amp;data=05%7C01%7Csusan.balterreitz%40msubillings.edu%7Cd4eb8594b848494ce1c408dab3568fa9%7C324aa97a03a644fc91e43846fbced113%7C0%7C0%7C638019481604753044%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=3J9YKlKMjf7wuhFW6geza8CkbSvcDN4ioIPjze2wAJ0%3D&amp;reserved=0" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-auth="NotApplicable" data-safelink="true" data-linkindex="0">Grateful Dead Studies Association</a> meeting, to be held in conjunction with the Grateful Dead area at the <a href="https://nam10.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fpcaaca.org%2Fconference&amp;data=05%7C01%7Csusan.balterreitz%40msubillings.edu%7Cd4eb8594b848494ce1c408dab3568fa9%7C324aa97a03a644fc91e43846fbced113%7C0%7C0%7C638019481604753044%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=1mm24wid3rfPHklFh89fDPM%2FBkYobDOEUCurLddMWMY%3D&amp;reserved=0" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-auth="NotApplicable" data-safelink="true" data-linkindex="1">Popular Culture Association conference</a>, April 5 – 8, 2023, in San Antonio. </p>
<p>The Grateful Dead Studies Association was founded in 2019, building on the work of the Grateful Dead area of the Southwest Popular Culture Association, which has met annually since 1998.  GDSA was founded to provide a lasting scholarly foundation for academics. A registered nonprofit association, we publish a peer-reviewed journal, <em>Grateful Dead Studies</em>, the <em>Proceedings</em> of our conferences, and a newsletter, along with Working Papers and other reports. We also sponsor the Duke University book series, Studies in the Grateful Dead.</p>
<p>We welcome papers and presentations on all aspects of the Grateful Dead’s music, cultural impact, and historical significance, and their associated contexts, including the counterculture, fan culture, the 1960s, rock poster art, and more. The Association is richly interdisciplinary and welcomes contributions representing all fields and theoretical perspectives. Our conferences regularly reflect research in musicology, theology, history, literature, linguistics, sociology, and more. </p>
<p>Abstracts are due <strong>December 20, 2022; 200-250 words</strong>. </p>
<p>Please review our <a href="https://nam10.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fdeadstudies.org%2Fconference-abstracts-checklist%2F&amp;data=05%7C01%7Csusan.balterreitz%40msubillings.edu%7Cd4eb8594b848494ce1c408dab3568fa9%7C324aa97a03a644fc91e43846fbced113%7C0%7C0%7C638019481604753044%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=1RqmUqKpXf1M%2BcXMLedRObt%2FOWUkEEIplIl9guqtqBk%3D&amp;reserved=0" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-auth="NotApplicable" data-safelink="true" data-linkindex="2">Conference Proposal Checklist</a> to see the criteria used to evaluate your proposal. </p>
<p>Submission information may be found <a href="https://nam10.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fpcaaca.org%2Fconference%2Fsubmitting-paper-proposal-pca-conference&amp;data=05%7C01%7Csusan.balterreitz%40msubillings.edu%7Cd4eb8594b848494ce1c408dab3568fa9%7C324aa97a03a644fc91e43846fbced113%7C0%7C0%7C638019481604753044%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=9SIOd5l21%2BVeaXNek2fpMP9zZpdvoilbaupgqxWRVD8%3D&amp;reserved=0" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-auth="NotApplicable" data-safelink="true" data-linkindex="3">here</a>. </p>
<p>All presenters must be <a href="https://nam10.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fpcaaca.org%2Fconference%2Fmembership&amp;data=05%7C01%7Csusan.balterreitz%40msubillings.edu%7Cd4eb8594b848494ce1c408dab3568fa9%7C324aa97a03a644fc91e43846fbced113%7C0%7C0%7C638019481604753044%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=BUIb1%2FSg1hjT3OWEy8mP370h%2BBZL1IEs49xvy5Z5Cos%3D&amp;reserved=0" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-auth="NotApplicable" data-safelink="true" data-linkindex="4">members</a> of the PCA. Membership in the GDSA is not required. Feel free to contact Granville Ganter at <a href="mailto:ganterg@stjohns.edu">ganterg@stjohns.edu</a> for informal questions of any kind.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666589823250399</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Indian Spiritual Traditions and Resistance to Colonial Epistemes</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/10/22/indian-spiritual-traditions-and-resistance-to-colonial-epistemes</link>
						<dc:creator>Subhayu</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Sunday, October 23, 2022 - 4:49pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Mirik college, university of North bengal, India</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:subhayubhattacharjee007@gmail.com">subhayubhattacharjee007@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/ethnicity-and-national-identity">ethnicity and national identity</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/postcolonial">postcolonial</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>November 20, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>While interest in postcolonialism has spanned a vast number of sub-fields and disciplines such as psychological explorations of resistance, the persistence of colonial topography in post-colonial governmentality, etc. not much attention has been given to the domain of Indian spirituality as an effective counter-discourse to the Colonial epistemic tradition. To vote an example, the problem concerning the Self/Other pedagogical formulation in Western discoursrs is met with an equally equitable pull in the notions of the Self as the latent Other ( 'tattvam asi') in Vedantic thought.  I would like to therefore invite abstracts for an edited volume of essays which explore the theme of Politico- spiritual resistance in postcolonial spiritual literatures.  The thrust of the essays would include the insistence on reading spirituality as an episteme that embodies political, ethical, and/or social approaches that constantly threaten the attempt at epistemological Selving in Western discourses on Oriental education and pedagogy. Broadly, the themes could be under the following ( though not exhaustive) heads: 1. Spiritual thinkers in the Indian caneon and their responses to Western epistemology 2. Analysis of 'religious' texts as political manifestos in the minor/major canons of postcolonial/ anti-colonial literature 3. Dialogic interventions between Oriental spiritual discourses and Western counterparts in the long 19th c.  4. Religious episteme and it's correspondences with the 'Scientific' episteme vis-a-vis Colonial enterprise  We are already in contact with an international publisher. Hope to see the project completed by mid-2023. </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 13:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666589823250398</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>‘I wished to tell the truth’: Anne Brontë at 200, a Special Issue of Brontë Studies</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/10/20/%E2%80%98i-wished-to-tell-the-truth%E2%80%99-anne-bront%C3%AB-at-200-a-special-issue-of-bront%C3%AB-studies</link>
						<dc:creator>C.OCallaghan@lboro.ac.uk</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Sunday, October 23, 2022 - 4:35pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Brontë Studies </div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:brontestudies@bronte.org">brontestudies@bronte.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/eighteenth-century">eighteenth century</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/romantic">romantic</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/victorian">victorian</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>December 15, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><em>Brontë Studies</em> is delighted to announce that it is hosting a Special Issue to celebrate the life and work of Anne Brontë. Led by articles emerging from the Brontë Society’s conference, <em>‘I wished to tell the truth’: Anne</em> <em>Brontë at 200</em> that was originally scheduled for 2020 but, due to the pandemic, was reorganised and held online in 2021, the Special Issue presents an ideal opportunity to challenge the long-held perception that the youngest Brontë sibling was the least talented and lacked the genius of her sisters. With Anne Brontë’s marginalisation in mind, potential topics for articles to be explored could include, but are not limited to, the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Relationship between life and art/ Realism and didacticism</li>
<li>Feminist politics/ Feminist reassessment/Progressive social and political agenda</li>
<li>Attitudes toward childhood – education and development</li>
<li>Representation of the Victorian female artist</li>
<li>Biographical readings/Representation in bio-fictions</li>
<li>Legacy/Afterlives</li>
<li>New approaches to understanding and/or reading Anne Brontë</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Submission guidelines: Please submit articles of no more than 6,000 words </strong>(inclusive of notes, references, abstract, bio(s), and keywords) to the editors via the journal’s submission platform, <a href="https://accounts.taylorfrancis.com/identity/#/login?authorize=true&amp;client_id=59f21242bb410562f60413514f5108d80ede3086581e834d9027687f7a875502&amp;response_type=code&amp;scope=mail&amp;redirect_uri=http:%2F%2Fapi.taylorandfrancis.com%2Fv1%2Fauthclient%2Fcallback&amp;state=&amp;flow=new&amp;brand=rptnf&amp;utm_source=CPB&amp;utm_medium=cms&amp;utm_campaign=JPG15743">Scholar One</a> by <strong>15 December 2022</strong>. Full instructions for authors can be found <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/action/authorSubmission?show=instructions&amp;journalCode=ybst20&amp;utm_source=CPB&amp;utm_medium=cms&amp;utm_campaign=JPG15743">here</a>. If you have any questions, please do not hesitate to email the journal’s Co-Editors-in-Chief, Sarah Fanning and Claire O’Callaghan, at <a href="mailto:brontestudies@bronte.org">brontestudies@bronte.org</a>. As per the journal’s policy, all articles will be subject to peer review. The Special Issue will be published in 2023. We look forward to receiving your submissions.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 14:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666589823250397</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ November 14, 2022] Conference talk or similar: Hegel and Levinas: On Truth and the Question of Interruption</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104318</link>
						<description>Venue: Online<br/><br/>Speakers at this event: <br/>Rozemund Uljée (Leiden University)<br/>Anne Clausen (Georg-August-Universität Göttingen)<br/><br/><p>Monday 14 November 2022, <strong>18:00 p.m</strong>. (<strong>ATHENS</strong>, Greece time)</p>
<p><strong><br/></strong></p>
<p><strong>WEBEX LINK</strong>:https://uoa.webex.com/uoa/j.php?MTID=m85b0180a170f1d9b4c02c634bf988c70</p>
<p>Meeting number (access code): 2731 324 7230</p>
<p>Meeting password: 9Grn7JPYmN2</p>
<p>The paper to be discussed can be found here:</p>
<p>https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/hegel-bulletin/article/hegel-and-levinas-on-truth-and-the-question-of-interruption/1B9085780A0178A2F3D4B856E7914E5E</p>
<p>***For any enquiries please contact Dr. Stavros Panagiotou (<strong>panayiot@philosophy.uoa.gr</strong>).***</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 05:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666503427191173</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ January 15, 2023] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104326</link>
						<description>Publication Name: Edited Volume on the Phenomenology of Simone de Beauvoir<br/><br/><p>Considered in contrast to the work of her compatriots Jean-Paul Sartre and Maurice Merleau-Ponty, Simone de Beauvoir's work as a phenomenologist has received relatively little scholarly attention, despite its significant philosophical merit and interest. This edited volume aims to correct that oversight.</p>
<p>We invite potential contributors to submit original abstracts of approximately 500 words (for eventual chapters in the approx. 8000-10000 word range). There are a wide variety of potential topics, but all contributions should speak to the significance of Beauvoir's work as "core" existential phenomenology. Possibilities include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Comparisons between Beauvoir and other major figures in Phenomenology as a philosophical movement</li>
<li>Beauvoir's work on traditional phenomenological problems or concepts (e.g., the problem of others / the Other, intersubjectivity, ambiguity, historicity, the body, etc.)</li>
<li>Unique emphases, concepts, or phenomena discussed in Beauvoir's work and their phenomenological significance (e.g. violence, oppression, gender, romantic love, childhood, etc.) </li>
<li>The significance of any of the above for contemporary phenomenologically-informed work</li>
</ul>
<p>Chapters should be scholarly but/and intelligible to non-specialists and advanced students. If interested, please submit abstracts by <strong>January 15, 2023 </strong>via email to <u>rharrison@vassar.edu</u> </p>
<p>Potential contributors will receive notification of acceptance by March 15. If your abstract is selected, full chapter drafts will be expected by January 2024. </p>
<p><strong>Questions? </strong>Contact Rebecca Harrison at rharrison@vassar.edu </p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 05:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666503427191172</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ February 1, 2023] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104304</link>
						<description>Publication Name: Cross-Training in Psychological Science at Baylor University<br/><br/><p>Thanks to a generous grant from the John Templeton Foundation, we are pleased to announce a Request for Proposals for cross-training opportunities with the psychological sciences, run by Dr. Devan Stahl (PI), Dr. Natalie Carnes, Dr. Anne Jeffrey, Dr. Sarah Schnitker, Dr. JoAnn Tsang. Those working in any discipline that engages theological inquiry are welcome to apply (moral theology, philosophy, aesthetics, etc.). This program will help successful applicants build supportive and collaborative interpersonal relationships with other scholars interested in the psychological sciences interested in working on research of interest to theologians. </p>
<p><br/> In addition to one funded year of cross training, successful applicants will then have the opportunity to apply for an additional $45,000 of salary funding for additional training and $5,000-40,000 for a collaborative empirical study with a psychology lab in subsequent years.   </p>
<p>If you or a colleague is interested in exploring issues relevant to Christian theology and philosophy, especially virtue, suffering and vulnerability, and religious aesthetics please consider applying.   </p>
<p>Applications are due February 1, 2023.</p>
<p>For more information on this project, and for the details of the funding request, please visit our website: https://www.baylor.edu/ethics/index.php?id=986085  </p>
<p>Questions should be directed to crosstraining@baylor.edu.  </p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666417028529899</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CONFERENCE: Amsterdam as Haven for Religious Refugees in the Early Modern Period (10, 11, 12 November, Amsterdam, hybrid)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11378515/conference-amsterdam-haven-religious-refugees-early-modern</link>
						<dc:creator>Kyra Gerber</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-10T00:00:00-05:00">November 10, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-12T00:00:00-05:00">November 12, 2022</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Netherlands</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Early Modern History and Period Studies, European History / Studies, Intellectual History, Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>In the 17th century Amsterdam became a hotbed of religious exchange, as religious exiles from all over the continent flocked to the Netherlands and especially its capital city because of relatively lax laws on religious expression and publishing. One center of such exchange was the so-called House with the Heads on Keizersgracht, the home of Louis de Geer and later his son Laurens. Both men acted as patrons to a variety of religious free thinkers and reformers. Figures such as Jan Comenius, Friedrich Breckling and Christian Hoburg gathered in the de Geer home to discuss their ideas. Today, the House with the Heads is home to the Bibliotheca Philosophica Hermetica and its associated museum, the Embassy of the Free Mind. We are currently preparing an exhibition on the history of the House with the Heads. As part of these preparations, we are hosting a conference 11-12 November 2022 on the role of Amsterdam as a haven for religious refugees.</p><p>Over two days, a group of international experts will explore different groups’ or individuals’ experiences (Jews, Radical Pietists, Huguenots, etc.), the role of publishing in the city, patronage, conflicts between groups, urban versus rural strategies for survival, the role of war in the era and other related topics. The conference will take place on-site, but will also accommodate speakers from afar through digital connection. Likewise, the public can attend in person or remotely. A conference publication is planned.</p><p>The complete conference program can be viewed <a href="https://embassyofthefreemind.com/en/library/271-amsterdam-as-haven" rel="nofollow">here</a>.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Those who wish to attend in person should contact the Director of the Ritman Research Institute, Lucinda Martin: <span><a href="mailto:lmartin@efm.amsterdam">lmartin@efm.amsterdam</a></span></p><p>Those who wish to view lectures remotely by zoom should request a link from Junior Researcher Kyra Gerber: <span><a href="mailto:kgerber@efm.amsterdam">kgerber@efm.amsterdam</a></span></p><p>Tickets to attend the evening lecture by Emil Schrijver will be sold separately. Tickets can be bought <a href="https://tickets.embassyofthefreemind.com/en/events/tickets" rel="nofollow">here</a>.</p><p>Learn more about the Ritman Research Institute <a href="https://embassyofthefreemind.com/en/library/269-ritman-research-institute" rel="nofollow">here</a>.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:lmartin@efm.amsterdam">lmartin@efm.amsterdam</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://embassyofthefreemind.com/en/library/271-amsterdam-as-haven" target="_blank">https://embassyofthefreemind.com/en/library/271-amsterdam-as-haven</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 17:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666417028529898</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ December 11, 2022] CFP for conference or similar: Husserl-Arbeitstage 2023. Reason and Relativity</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104284</link>
						<description><p><strong>Husserl-Arbeitstage 2023,</strong> <strong>REASON AND RELATIVITY</strong></p>
<p>From Husserl’s early critique of psychologism in the <em>Prolegomena,</em> to his criticism of both naturalism and historicism in the <em>Logos</em> article, and his later diagnosis of the inner fragmentation of science and philosophy in the <em>Crisis</em>, phenomenology has confronted  diverse forms of relativism and skepticism. As one strategy for facing this challenge, Husserl elaborated a phenomenology of reason embracing the theoretical sphere of being and truth, the axiological sphere of value and genuine evaluation, and the practical sphere of authentic ethical action. He thereby placed the rational ideals of autonomy and self-responsibility at the heart of his project of philosophy as a rigorous science. Moreover, he advanced investigations of social and cultural realities by developing a phenomenological science of what is often considered ‘merely’ relative: Culture, history, and community. For the 2023 <em>Husserl-Arbeitstage</em>, the Husserl-Archives Leuven are inviting contributions concerning “Reason and Relativity”. Papers on a wide range of thematic issues are welcome, including, but not limited to, <em>experience and rational justification, moral and epistemic responsibility, normativity and rationality, cultural relativism and scientific universalism, essentialism and marginalization, scientific and philosophical thinking, foundations of social science</em>, etc.</p>
<p>Please send a two-page abstract or full paper before December 11th, 2022 to husserl2023@kuleuven.be. All submissions should be anonymized. Notifications of acceptance will be issued on December 20th, 2022. The conference will be held in English.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 05:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666330630467876</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ March 22, 2023 -  March 24, 2023] Conference or similar: Husserl-Arbeitstage 2023. Reason and Relativity</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104280</link>
						<description>Venue: Kardinaal Mercierplein 2<br/><br/><p><strong>Husserl-Arbeitstage 2023,</strong> <strong>REASON AND RELATIVITY</strong></p>
<p>From Husserl’s early critique of psychologism in the <em>Prolegomena,</em> to his criticism of both naturalism and historicism in the <em>Logos</em> article, and his later diagnosis of the inner fragmentation of science and philosophy in the <em>Crisis</em>, phenomenology has confronted  diverse forms of relativism and skepticism. As one strategy for facing this challenge, Husserl elaborated a phenomenology of reason embracing the theoretical sphere of being and truth, the axiological sphere of value and genuine evaluation, and the practical sphere of authentic ethical action. He thereby placed the rational ideals of autonomy and self-responsibility at the heart of his project of philosophy as a rigorous science. Moreover, he advanced investigations of social and cultural realities by developing a phenomenological science of what is often considered ‘merely’ relative: Culture, history, and community. For the 2023 <em>Husserl-Arbeitstage</em>, the Husserl-Archives Leuven are inviting contributions concerning “Reason and Relativity”. Papers on a wide range of thematic issues are welcome, including, but not limited to, <em>experience and rational justification, moral and epistemic responsibility, normativity and rationality, cultural relativism and scientific universalism, essentialism and marginalization, scientific and philosophical thinking, foundations of social science</em>, etc.</p>
<p>Please send a two-page abstract or full paper before December 11th, 2022 to husserl2023@kuleuven.be. All submissions should be anonymized. Notifications of acceptance will be issued on December 20th, 2022. The conference will be held in English.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 05:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666330630467875</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Conference programme 3-4 November: Editing, Translating and Interpreting the Greek Fathers in the French-Speaking Regions of Europe (1450-1650)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11365962/conference-programme-3-4-november-editing-translating-and</link>
						<dc:creator>Paolo Sachet</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-03T00:00:00-04:00">November 3, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-04T00:00:00-04:00">November 4, 2022</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Switzerland</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Classical Studies, Early Modern History and Period Studies, French History / Studies, Humanities, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><b>Editing, Translating and Interpreting the Greek Fathers in the French-Speaking Regions of Europe (1450-1650)  / </b></p><p><b>Éditer, traduire et interpréter les Pères grecs  dans l’espace francophone européen (1450-1650)</b></p><p> </p><p>Geneva, Institut d'histoire de la Réformation, UNIGE</p><p><b>3-4 November</b></p><p> </p><p>Further information can be found <a href="https://www.unige.ch/ihr/fr/accueil/journees-detude-ihr-3-4-novembre-2022/" rel="nofollow">here</a>, including full <b>programme</b> and the Zoom link for <b>attending online</b>.</p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr Paolo Sachet, Institut d'histoire de la Réformation, UNIGE</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:paolo.sachet@unige.ch">paolo.sachet@unige.ch</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="http://www.unige.ch/ihr/fr/accueil/journees-detude-ihr-3-4-novembre-2022/" target="_blank">http://www.unige.ch/ihr/fr/accueil/journees-detude-ihr-3-4-novembre-2022/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 17:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666330630467874</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Papers: Religion and James Bond</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11360067/call-papers-religion-and-james-bond</link>
						<dc:creator>George Tsakiridis</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-19T00:00:00-04:00">October 19, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-12-31T00:00:00-05:00">December 31, 2022</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Film and Film History, Humanities, Philosophy, Popular Culture Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><strong>Call for Papers: <em>Religion and James Bond</em></strong></p><p> </p><p>Volume Editor: George Tsakiridis, PhD</p><p> </p><p>Abstract and CV Due: November 30, 2022</p><p> </p><p>Initial Final Paper Due: June 1, 2023</p><p> </p><p>Click <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U9FzgsF2T-s%3E" rel="nofollow">this link</a>, and close your eyes…wait a few seconds and start reading…</p><p> </p><p>It’s hard to imagine a more iconic action hero from the past 60 years than James Bond. He encapsulates the Western ideal in a spy hero from the Cold War Era till today. Though much has changed, this figure has been the focus of twenty-five (plus) films. He embodies popular culture for two generations of British and American viewers, and helps us to see the development of pop culture through film, social mores, and sexuality over time. He is a perfect topic for the <a href="https://rowman.com/Action/SERIES/_/LFATPC/Theology,-Religion,-and-Pop-Culture" rel="nofollow">Theology, Religion, and Pop Culture series</a>.</p><p>           </p><p>Having started in novels, and made more famous through film, Bond has spanned multiple generations of viewers, helping us to see the evolution of the character and the culture though the technology, sexual norms, and politics of several decades. He is a lens through which we can view religion and how religion has been portrayed over time. The accepted behavior of a character like Bond, as well as the accepted visuals of the series changed slowly, then rapidly over the course of the films. Having been played by six actors (not counting an outlier or two), he also has been interpreted and reinterpreted many times. As scholars, this gives us an opportunity to see how popular culture lenses have changed over time so that meaning, morals, and aesthetics can be central to this study. This is not meant to be a hit piece on Bond, as some scholars have done in recent years, but a critical study of a character that many of us enjoy, looking at the good while not ignoring the less than good. There’s a reason he is so beloved, despite his flaws; he taps into something underlying all of us – our very human nature.</p><p>           </p><p>The volume will focus on a number of themes, including, but not limited to: sin/redemption, sexuality, political theology, and religious plurality. Because of both its political and multicultural emphases, Bond gives us a glimpse at a British agent’s Cold War development as he engages multiple cultures and peoples. This is seen both in his own journey of redemption and his redemption of others. It is seen in his mistreatment of women and culture as well as his embrace of it. In Bond’s spycraft, we see both the good and the bad sides of human nature, sometimes at the same time. As can be inferred from the multitude of themes, this volume will engage both religious studies scholars and theologians, having some of both already signed on in the pre-seeding of this volume. Scholars of all types are welcome: religious studies, theology, philosophy, and other areas of the humanities.</p><p> </p><p>Though the volume will focus predominately on the films, I also hope to see proposals on Ian Fleming’s novels, the history and development of Bond, and perhaps even the video games and collectibles. We will have to see what the call for papers brings in, but there is a lot of fertile ground in the world of 007.</p><p> </p><p><strong>Some potential categories that are priorities for this volume are as follows (though other ideas are welcome!):</strong></p><p> </p><p>-World Religions in James Bond (and the accurate or inaccurate portrayal of them). This might be exploring the use of one religion, such as Hinduism or Buddhism throughout the Bond corpus, or examining a broader theme. (this topic is high priority)</p><p>-Redemption/Sacrifice/Salvation</p><p>-Sexual Ethics in Bond and Bond Girls</p><p>-Morality and Sin in the Context of Technology</p><p>-Ethics of Spycraft in the Cold War</p><p>-Good and Evil during the Cold War</p><p>-The Music of James Bond – Can either be a song or two, or the use of music throughout the series. (this topic is high priority)</p><p>-Political Theology in James Bond Films</p><p>-Religion in Ian Fleming’s James Bond Novels</p><p>-Religion/Theology in James Bond Comic Books (I know it will be tough to get this one, but if anyone is interested, I am listening!)</p><p>-M, Q, and Moneypenny – How do the supporting characters make for a robust theology in Bond?</p><p>-Bond by Actor: Looking for pieces that specifically will look at the individual film corpus of Connery, Lazenby, Moore, Dalton, Brosnan, and Craig (this topic is high priority – especially a piece on Lazenby/OHMSS)</p><p>-Bond by Film – Looking at the presentation of religion within individual films – implicit here is the cultural appropriation/interpretation of religion and culture in Bond films</p><p>-James Bond Collectables – the iconography of James Bond</p><p>-James Bond in Video Games (Goldeneye was groundbreaking in its development of first-person shooter games) – Exploring the philosophy of Bond on the small screen</p><p>Feel free to get creative. This volume looks to highlight creative, diverse, and well-researched chapters.</p><p>Abstracts should be approximately 300-500 words and should present a basic outline of your potential contribution to the volume and potential methodology. If you make the initial cut, you will be contacted by Dr. Tsakiridis to discuss and finalize your contribution to the volume. Send an abstract and a CV to <a href="mailto:religionandjamesbond@gmail.com">religionandjamesbond@gmail.com</a>. Final drafts will be approximately 6,000 to 7,000 words, but exact word counts for each article will be discussed at the time of acceptance. You are welcome to contact Dr. Tsakiridis in advance of the proposal deadline to float a potential topic if you are unsure. Early submissions are strongly encouraged.</p><p> </p><p>The tentative schedule for production is:</p><p> </p><p>November 30, 2022 – Call for Papers Ends</p><p>June 1, 2023 – First Drafts Due</p><p>July 1, 2023 – Drafts Reviewed and Returned</p><p>September 1, 2023 – Final Drafts Due</p><p>October 1, 2023 – Final Edits Made Before Peer Review</p><p>November 1, 2023 – Drafts to Peer Review</p><p>January 15, 2024 – Final Revisions Due</p><p>February 29, 2024 – Submission to Publisher</p><p>Summer/Fall 2024 – Publication</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr. George Tsakiridis</p><p>South Dakota State University</p><p><a href="mailto:george.tsakiridis@sdstate.edu">george.tsakiridis@sdstate.edu</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:george.tsakiridis@sdstate.edu">george.tsakiridis@sdstate.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://popularcultureandtheology.com/2022/08/31/call-for-papers-religion-and-james-bond/" target="_blank">https://popularcultureandtheology.com/2022/08/31/call-for-papers-religion-and-james-bond/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666330630467873</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Fourteenth International Conference on Religion &amp; Spirituality in Society (A Blended Conference)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11355161/fourteenth-international-conference-religion-spirituality</link>
						<dc:creator>Tamsyn Gilbert</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2024-05-23T00:00:00-04:00">May 23, 2024</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2024-05-24T00:00:00-04:00">May 24, 2024</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Spain</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology, Sociology, Cultural History / Studies, Human Rights, Anthropology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Fourteenth International Conference on Religion &amp; Spirituality in Society, Institute of Religious Studies, Complutense University of Madrid, Spain (23-24 May 2024) <br/>A Blended Conference <br/> </p><p>Founded in 2011, the <strong>Religion in Society Research Network</strong> explores the relationship between religion in society and the changing nature of spirituality. We seek to build an epistemic community where we can make linkages across disciplinary, geographic, and cultural boundaries. As a Research Network, we are defined by our scope and concerns and motivated to build strategies for action framed by our shared themes and tensions.<br/> <br/>The <strong>Fourteenth International Conference on Religion &amp; Spirituality in Society</strong> calls for research addressing the following annual themes and special focus:</p><ul><li><em>2024 Special Focus—Spaces, Movement, Time: Religions at Rest and in Movement</em></li><li><em>Theme 1: Interdisciplinary Approaches</em></li><li><em>Theme 2: Human Rights and Policy</em></li><li><em>Theme 3: Narratives and Identity</em></li><li><em>Theme 4: Culture and Education</em><br/> </li></ul></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:support@cgnetworks.org">support@cgnetworks.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://religioninsociety.com/2024-conference" target="_blank">https://religioninsociety.com/2024-conference</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 17:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666330630467872</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – October 19th, 2022</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-october-19th-2022/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find full-time job listings, an early scholar workshop, a conference, and a call for papers.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 36!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Sociology of Religion (Tenure-Track)</h4>



<p>University of Toronto Scarborough, Canada</p>



<p>Deadline: November 28, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.utsc.utoronto.ca/sociology/sites/utsc.utoronto.ca.sociology/files/docs/02%2026546%20Sociology%20of%20Religion%20External%20posting.pdf">https://www.utsc.utoronto.ca/sociology/sites/utsc.utoronto.ca.sociology/files/docs/02 26546 Sociology of Religion External posting.pdf</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor in the Department of Near Eastern and South Asian Languages and Cultures (Tenure-Track)</h4>



<p>Ohio State University, US</p>



<p>Deadline: November 15<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://academicjobsonline.org/ajo/jobs/22406">https://academicjobsonline.org/ajo/jobs/22406</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor in Spirituality and Religious Ethics (Tenure-Track)</h4>



<p>University of Montreal, Canada</p>



<p>Deadline: November 6<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information:  <a href="https://twitter.com/NAASReligion/status/1580975963428753408/photo/1">https://twitter.com/NAASReligion/status/1580975963428753408/photo/1</a> (PDF, English)</p>



<p><a href="https://etudes-religieuses.umontreal.ca/notre-institut/presentation/">https://etudes-religieuses.umontreal.ca/notre-institut/presentation/</a> (University website, French)</p>



<h2>Workshops:</h2>



<h4>2023 American Examples</h4>



<p>University of Alabama, US</p>



<p>Deadline: November 7<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://americanexamples.ua.edu/2023-call-for-participants/">https://americanexamples.ua.edu/2023-call-for-participants/</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>Critical Muslim Studies Online Colloquium II</h4>



<p>Online Colloquium</p>



<p>Deadline: 31 October 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://cers.leeds.ac.uk/2022/10/17/critical-muslim-studies-cms-online-colloquium-ii/">https://cers.leeds.ac.uk/2022/10/17/critical-muslim-studies-cms-online-colloquium-ii/</a></p>



<h2>Conferences:</h2>



<h4>Second Annual Black Feminist Theory Summer Institute</h4>



<p>Duke University, US</p>



<p>Deadline: December 15, 2022</p>



<p>More Information:  <a href="https://gendersexualityfeminist.duke.edu/black-feminist-theory-summer-institute">https://gendersexualityfeminist.duke.edu/black-feminist-theory-summer-institute</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1666244227512150</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
