<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 12:29:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 12:29:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>Call for Papers: The 20th Annual Religion Graduate Student Symposium at Florida State University</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11569294/call-papers-20th-annual-religion-graduate-student-symposium</link>
						<dc:creator>Devin Burns</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-12-01T00:00:00-05:00">December 1, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Florida</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>American History / Studies, Anthropology, Classical Studies, Philosophy, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span>Call for Papers: </span></p><p><span>The 20th Annual Religion Graduate Student Symposium at Florida State University </span></p><p><span>February 17 &amp; 18, 2023 </span></p><p><span>Tallahassee, Florida</span></p><p>This year’s symposium will center on the theme: “Sensational Religion” This is our first in-person symposium since the beginning of the Sars-Cov2 global pandemic and we invite scholars to present papers addressing sensory aspects of the "new normal" for the study of religion. Previous symposia have featured scholars from a wide array of disciplines, universities, and areas. We invite papers from fields as varied as History, Anthropology, Political Science, Literature, Philosophy, Religious Studies, and Classics.</p><p>Joseph Winters, Duke University, Religious Studies and African American Studies, will deliver this year’s keynote address.</p><p>Possible topics include, but are not limited to:</p><p>• Sensing Religion</p><p>• Embodiment, Corporeality, &amp; the Transhuman</p><p>• Religion &amp; Hip-hop</p><p>• Form and Feeling in Religious Discourse</p><p>• Religion &amp; Material Culture</p><p>• Religion &amp; Sound</p><p>• Affect Theory</p><p>• Feeling Space, Building Religion</p><p>• Religion, Taste &amp; Foodways</p><p>• Existentialism</p><p>• Religion &amp; the Experiences of Identity-Making: Race, Gender, Disability, Age, Class</p><p>• Passing, Hiding, and In/Visibility</p><p>• Religion, Disgust, and Heresy</p><p>• Exhaustion and Burnout in Religion and its Study</p><p>• Panic, Anxiety, and Emergency</p><p>• Feeling-Values and the Religious Experience</p><p>• Disgust, Pain, Pleasure, Fear, Terror</p><p>• Moral &amp; Ethics of Religious Beauty/Ugliness</p><p>• State-Mediated Public Emotions</p><p>• Ethics of Eco-Aesthetics</p><p> </p><p>Presentations should be approximately 15 to 18 minutes in length and will receive faculty responses. In addition, every year respondents select the best graduate paper to receive the Leo F. Sandon Award, an endowed award named for the Religion Department's former chair. Proposals including an abstract of approximately 300 words, a list of key terms, and institutional affiliation should be submitted by December 1, 2022 for review.</p><p>Please submit proposals via this provided link: <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfC8WJlqAFXTBhdLELLFRcuw5-mypHoCrHHzWiMT3jvUiEMbQ/viewform?usp=sf_link" rel="nofollow">https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfC8WJlqAFXTBhdLELLFRcuw5-mypHo...</a></p><p> </p><p>Thank you for your interest. We look forward to hearing from you and hope to see you at the 2023 Graduate Student Symposium at Florida State University.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:fsureligionsymposium@gmail.com">fsureligionsymposium@gmail.com</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 18:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667540232558574</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Transcendent Transnationalism? Jewish History and Heritage Across Time and Space Call for Contributions to Volume 8 of the Yearbook of Transnational History</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11567425/transcendent-transnationalism-jewish-history-and-heritage</link>
						<dc:creator>Hernan  Tesler-Mabe</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-15T00:00:00-04:00">March 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Historic Preservation, Holocaust, Genocide, and Memory Studies, Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, World History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>CALL FOR PAPERS:<br/>Transcendent Transnationalism? Jewish History and Heritage <a name="_Hlk114777991">Across Time and Space</a></span></span></span></b></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Call for Contributions to Volume 8 of the <i>Yearbook of Transnational History</i> (published with Fairleigh Dickinson University Press/Rowman &amp; Littlefield) in spring 2025</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><a name="_Hlk114774022"><span><span><span>Hernan Tesler-Mabé </span></span></span></a><span><span><span>(Huron at Western) &amp; Shelley-Anne Peleg (University of Haifa, Israel) </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Although originated thousands of years ago from historical Israel and Judah, the Jewish people today are an ethnoreligious group and a nation that transcends physical borders and is spread throughout the world. Connected by faith, ethnicity, and culture, Jews possess a unique collective identity. The Jewish peoples are a universal phenomenon with a distinct story of multiculturalism, diversity, and constant renewal.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Jewish history and heritage can be found in tangible places and objects as well as intangible heritage such as shared practices, common themes, materials, and ideas. Jewish history and heritage manifests itself in different ways, crossing over time spans and bears numerous tangible and intangible connections. Jewish history and heritage is often not limited by national borders and, like the people it represents, connected as a Diaspora.  </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Crossing over time and borders, Jewish history and heritage includes themes that appear and disappear, layers of rituals and a combination of identities. It suggests changes over time and space. Therefore, Jewish history and heritage suggests a discussion unbounded by national concepts and theories<b> </b>crossing over time and spatial boundaries. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>This means that instead of dealing with a particular issue of a given nation, experts in the field of Jewish Studies are encouraged and obliged to engage in international debates and discussions that address understanding this heritage and these ideas. These frameworks focus on vast and various aspects.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The objective of this volume is to discuss these issues, through case studies and original research of Jewish issues from around the world, from various cultural and geographic settings. We welcome articles from academics, professionals, and advanced graduate students based upon a broad range of Jewish studies approaches. Topics might relate to one of the following topics:</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ol><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Conflicts or connections between Jewish monuments and sub features of Jewish history and heritage with local cultures and sites over the globe (e.g., the influences of specific Jewish features and characteristics and local cultures as manifested in art and architecture)</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Layers of Jewish history and heritage across time – changes and preserved Jewish features (e.g., development of symbols and structures) </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Common intangible rituals versus unorthodox traditions (e.g., practice &amp; living heritage, different interpretations …)</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>How do "others" view Jewish history and heritage (e.g., antisemitism and responses to antisemitism, Judaism as a culture in the diaspora and in Israel) </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Travels of Jewish history and heritage (e.g., Judaism moving with immigrants from one country to another, from Israel to the diaspora and from the diaspora to Israel).</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Historiographical engagements  </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Recent academic trends (e.g., Decolonizing the bible, Colonial histories, land and resources)</span></span></span></span></span></span></li></ol><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Interested contributors should submit a 250-500 word proposal abstract along with a short CV (2 pages max) by March 15, 2023 to Shelley-Anne Peleg (</span></span></span><a href="mailto:shelleypeleg@gmail.com"><span><span><span>shelleypeleg@gmail.com</span></span></span></a><span><span><span>) and Hernan Tesler-Mabé (<span><span><a href="mailto:hteslerm@huron.uwo.ca">hteslerm@huron.uwo.ca</a></span></span>) with the subject line “<b>Transcendent Transnationalism? Jewish History and Heritage Across Time and Space.</b>” Decisions on paper proposals will be made by April 15, 2023. Full papers (including Chicago style citations – endnotes and bibliography) should be between 5,000 to 10,000 words in length using American spelling, grammar, and punctuation conventions. Non-native English speakers should have their papers reviewed and edited by an English speaker prior to submission. Final paper drafts are due October 1, 2023.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><span><span><span>Shelley-Anne Peleg (</span></span></span><span><span><span><a href="mailto:shelleypeleg@gmail.com"><span><span><span>shelleypeleg@gmail.com</span></span></span></a></span></span></span><span><span><span>) and Hernan Tesler-Mabé (<span><span><a href="mailto:hteslerm@huron.uwo.ca">hteslerm@huron.uwo.ca</a></span></span>) </span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:hteslerm@huron.uwo.ca">hteslerm@huron.uwo.ca</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667540232558573</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>More Universal Than Catholicism? Mary Among Asian Religions</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11561780/more-universal-catholicism-mary-among-asian-religions</link>
						<dc:creator>Michel Chambon</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-01T00:00:00-05:00">February 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Singapore</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>East Asian History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, South Asian History / Studies, Southeast Asian History / Studies, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The figure of Mary, mother of Jesus Christ, has long been present among Asian people. Scholars have extensively explored how Asian Catholics use their local culture and national context to translate the features and meaning of this religious figure (Cruz 2015). However, Mary has also crossed religious boundaries and been integrated into the continent’s various religious traditions. Among Filipino-Chinese Catholics, Mary can be juxtaposed to and identified with Chinese deities like Mazu and Guanyin (Dy 2014). In Japan, she has long embraced the attributes of the bodhisattva Kannon (Habito 1994). In India, Indonesia, and Pakistan, Marian shrines attract thousands of Hindu and Muslim pilgrims (Bloomer 2018, Laksana 2014). And in Trinidad, Hindu migrants come to worship Mary as a representation of the goddess Kali (Tsuji 2020). Across Asian people, places, and traditions, Mary stands as a pan religious figure.</p><p> </p><p>Furthermore, ways to approach and engage with her vary tremendously among people of different faiths. Often, Mary is made present through the display of images and statues with artistic, ethnic, and gender particularities which call for critical attention (Habito 2014, Ninh 2017). Those statues can become the center of larger rituals including material offerings, collective pilgrimages, and chanting ceremonies. Rooted in broader cultural meanings, these practices involve various modes of subjective and bodily engagement. And for some healing rituals and counseling sessions, Mary can even be encountered through highly codified possession (Bloomer 2018). </p><p>​</p><p>This workshop investigates the many ways Mary is understood and engaged by Asian people around the world. It explores how Buddhists, Hindus, Muslims, and Asian devotees from various faiths approach her. It discusses the rituals, collective practices, and artistic expressions they deploy in relation to her. At a more theoretical level, this workshop seeks to question what those Marian devotions say about the notions of religion, migration, interreligious relations, gender, and popular religiosity.</p><p>​</p><p>While this workshop seeks contributions from social scientific and historical perspectives, paper presenters are invited to consider the following questions to frame the investigations addressed at the conference:</p><p>• How do Asian communities perceive and display Mary? What do these activities reflect with regard to religion, gender roles, ethnic identity, etc. across time and space? </p><p>• How are specific forms of Mary localized across places where Asians live? What are the material and ritual practices involved in this geographic translation of Mary?  </p><p>• How does Mary cross or reinforce boundaries between ethnic, religious and economic groups?  Which kind of inter-religious dialogues are mediated through her? How is Mary used to negotiate boundaries between different types of Christian communities? </p><p>• Which kind of bodily and subjective engagements are promoted through Marian practices? Who are the religious experts guiding and regulating those engagements?  </p><p>• How do Asian clergies, religious experts, and civil authorities respond to the various forms of Mary? In what ways is Mary promoted and endorsed by the continent’s civil and religious institutions? How are some manifestations of Mary despised, sidelined, or condemned by various kinds of authorities?  </p><p>​</p><p>As part of the Asian Marianism pilot research project, this online conference is jointly organized by the <a href="http://www.isac-research.org/" rel="nofollow">Initiative for the Study of Asian Catholics</a> (ISAC) – an initiative hosted by the Asia Research Institute, National University of Singapore – and the <a href="https://www.marianstudies.ac.uk/" rel="nofollow">Centre for Marian Studies</a>, St Mary’s University, Twickenham, London, UK.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Paper proposals should include a title, an abstract (250 words maximum) and a brief personal biography of 100 words for submission, including your location to indicate your time zone. Please send it as a word document file to <a href="mailto:asianmary2023@gmail.com">asianmary2023@gmail.com</a> by 1 February 2023. Successful applicants will be notified by mid-March 2023.</p><p>Please also include a statement confirming that your paper has not been published previously, it is not committed elsewhere, and that you are willing to revise your paper for potential inclusion in a special publication (in collaboration with the workshop organizers and other participants).</p><p>Panel presenters will be required to submit drafts of their papers (6,000 words) by 1 May 2023. These drafts will be circulated to fellow panelists and discussants in advance. Drafts need not be fully polished. Indeed, we expect that presenters will be open to feedback from fellow participants.</p><p>For any inquiry, please contact Catherine O'Brien at <a href="mailto:asianmary2023@gmail.com">asianmary2023@gmail.com</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:asianmary2023@gmail.com">asianmary2023@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.isac-research.org/asianmary2023" target="_blank">https://www.isac-research.org/asianmary2023</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 17:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667540232558572</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>&quot;Victorian Gothic and the Occult&quot; Edited Collection</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/10/31/victorian-gothic-and-the-occult-edited-collection</link>
						<dc:creator>KirstinMills</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, November 3, 2022 - 11:41am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Kirstin A. Mills (Macquarie University)</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:kirstin.mills@mq.edu.au">kirstin.mills@mq.edu.au</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/science-and-culture">science and culture</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/victorian">victorian</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>December 31, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>The Victorian era, and the Nineteenth Century more broadly, witnessed a flourishing of interest in the supernatural, spiritualism, magic, and the physical and psychological sciences, which culminated in the emergence of occult beliefs, practices and societies. During this period also, the Gothic literature and art that had taken hold of the public imagination in the Romantic period continued to haunt the Victorian era, emerging in new forms that often embraced and experimented with ideas of occultism. Nineteenth-century occultism has received much critical attention, particularly in relation to its role in bringing about the apogee of British and American occultism in the early twentieth century. Yet while occult phenomena is generally accepted within Gothic fiction alongside other supernatural elements like ghosts, witches and vampires, the particular relationship between the Victorian Gothic and the emerging occult beliefs and practices in this period requires closer attention.</p>
<p>This edited book, intended for the Palgrave Gothic series published by Palgrave/Springer, seeks to examine this relationship, exploring the lines of connection, influence and contention between the Gothic and Occult in the Victorian period. It aims to consider the ways that the Victorian Gothic was shaped by – and in turn perhaps influenced or stoked – occult beliefs and practices in the period. Chapters should aim to address the Gothic as a genre or mode in the Victorian period, exploring: how the Victorian interest in the occult augments, extends, updates or challenges the Gothic mode; the impact, if any, of the Gothic on the Victorian Occult, even as an avenue for deploying and experimenting with occult ideas; and the potential wider uses that the Victorian Gothic makes of occultism for social and/or political commentary.</p>
<p>This volume takes a broad temporal view of the Victorian period, beginning with its early-nineteenth-century origins as it moved out of the Romantic period, and ending with its transition into the early-twentieth-century art forms that both drew on and rebelled against their forbears. It also aims to consider Gothic occultism not only in Britain but also in its global manifestations, interrogating particularly the imperial and colonial forces shaping the genre’s development.</p>
<p>Possible topics include but are by no means limited to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Spiritualism, Theosophy, Theology, Religion</li>
<li>Specific Occult Orders and Societies (e.g. Hermetic Order of the Golden Dawn; Society for Psychical Research; The Ghost Club; Freemasonry)</li>
<li>Ghosts, Mediums, Seances, Automatic Writing, Clairvoyance, Fortune-telling etc</li>
<li>Occult ‘sciences’ and pseudoscience, medicine, technology</li>
<li>Witches and witchcraft, Mages and magic, Alchemy, Astrology</li>
<li>Vampires, psychic vampires, werewolves and monsters</li>
<li>Arcane knowledge, philosophy, ‘secret’ or ‘lost’ texts</li>
<li>Raising the Dead, Life and Death boundaries</li>
<li>Victorian Occultism’s appropriation of and/or exchange with other cultures, e.g. Egyptian, Chinese, Indian etc</li>
<li>Race, imperialism and post-colonial narratives</li>
<li>Women and the occult (women authors, women occult figures, women in the occult, women characters, New Women)</li>
<li>Gothic Occultism as a space through which to explore alternatives to mainstream narratives e.g. class, gender, heterosexuality, monogamy, etc</li>
<li>The natural world, the environment, eco-Gothic/eco-horror</li>
<li>Art and visual culture</li>
<li>Aestheticism, Decadence, Fin-de-siecle Gothic</li>
<li>Crime and Occult Detective Gothic</li>
<li>Rural/Folk Gothic</li>
<li>Periodicals, magazines, popular fiction</li>
<li>Animals and the Occult</li>
<li>Space and Place</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Please submit abstracts of c.500 words and brief (c. 100-words) biographies for consideration to Dr Kirstin Mills (Macquarie University) <a href="mailto:kirstin.mills@mq.edu.au">kirstin.mills@mq.edu.au</a> by 31st December 2022. If accepted, completed articles are expected to be c.6000 words and will be due 31st October 2023. </strong>This volume is intended for the Palgrave Gothic series published by Palgrave/Springer.</p>
<p><strong>Abstracts due:</strong> 31st December 2022</p>
<p><strong>Completed articles due:</strong> 31st October 2023</p>
<p><strong>Enquiries to:</strong> Dr Kirstin Mills (Macquarie University) – <a href="mailto:kirstin.mills@mq.edu.au">kirstin.mills@mq.edu.au</a></p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 01:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667540232558571</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ February 17, 2023] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104606</link>
						<description>Publication Name: Violence and Conflict in Alexandre Kojève's works<br/><br/><p><strong>Call for Papers: Violence and Conflict in Alexandre Kojève’s works.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Special issue of <em>The Philosophical Journal of Conflict and Violence</em> guest-edited by Luis Javier Pedrazuela</strong></p>
<p><strong><br/></strong></p>
<p>Alexandre Kojève is well known for having initiated a whole generation of intellectuals into a certain reading of Hegel. His idea of the end of history has been linked by some of its popularizers to the expansion of liberal democracy around the globe. According to this version the western welfare order since 1945 owes to thinkers like Kojève a great part of its success all the more so because he worked for it in a practical manner from his post in the French ministry of economy. Whatever the truth of this version, the fact is that in its wake some essential aspects of Kojève´s thought become blunt, if not altogether disappear. These aspects refer to his treatment of conflict and violence and are worth an insightful reexamination.</p>
<p>From the claim that the struggle for recognition must be necessarily a “bloody” one to the assessment that the replacement of those elites whose authority has expired may call for their annihilation, not to mention his equation of biological “death” with human freedom or his interpretation of revolutionary terror as a pedagogical tool to bring forth the perfect citizen of the post-historical age, Kojève´s corpus offers not few topics in which to ground such a reexamination.</p>
<p>PJCV seeks cutting-age articles from contributors which openly explore the aforementioned topics as well as others along the same lines such as (although not restricted to):</p>
<p>1.     Morality, violence, and general will in Alexandre Kojève</p>
<p>2.     The merits and/or limitations of Kojève's interpretations on conflict and violence in Hegel's philosophy.</p>
<p>3.     Kojèvean interpretations of current social or international conflicts.</p>
<p>4.     The anti-political nature of Kojève´s End-State against the backdrop of Schmitt´s political decision.</p>
<p>5.     The Lacanian subject and the Kojèvean struggle to the death</p>
<p>6.     Alexandre Kojève and Vichy France.</p>
<p>7.     The Hegelian notion of “Bildung” in Alexandre Kojève.</p>
<p>8.     Stalinism and Kojève´s Universal and Homogeneous State.</p>
<p>9.     Conflict, violence, and Alexandre Kojève’s standpoint on the “intellectual”</p>
<p>10.  Pedagogy, authority, and propaganda in Kojève´s work</p>
<p>11.  The College of Sociology and the Kojèvean notions of exchange and distribution.</p>
<p>12.  Kojève´s anti-utopian bias.</p>
<p>13.  The Buddhist roots of Kojève´s “annihilation”</p>
<p>14.  The issue of the compatibility between Kojève's theory of the "end of history" and conflict and violence in the 21st century.</p>
<p>15.  Kojève and competing views on world history with respect to conflict and violence.</p>
<p><strong>Editor</strong></p>
<p>This special issue will be edited by Luis Javier Pedrazuela.</p>
<p><strong>Submission guidelines</strong></p>
<p>Interested parties should send a proposed abstract of 200-300 words to <a href="mailto:idoetaluisj@gmail.com">idoetaluisj@gmail.com</a>  and <a href="mailto:andreas.wilmes@trivent-publishing.eu">andreas.wilmes@trivent-publishing.eu</a> by February 17, 2023. Authors will be informed of acceptance no later than March 15, 2023. Full papers should be submitted by September 8, 2023, should follow the <em>PJCV</em> template available at trivent-publishing.eu/pjcv.html, and should be maximum 20 pages in length. The final publication is planned for May 2024.</p>
<p>Website : <a href="https://trivent-publishing.eu/32-philosophical-journal-of-conflict-and-violence-pjcv">https://trivent-publishing.eu/32-philosophical-journal-of-conflict-and-violence-pjcv</a></p>
<p>FB: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/philosophicaljournalofconflictandviolence/">https://www.facebook.com/philosophicaljournalofconflictandviolence/</a></p>
<p>Twitter: @thePJCV</p></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 05:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667453830942729</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religion and Ethnicity in the Making of Nigeria's Fourth Republic</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11550897/religion-and-ethnicity-making-nigerias-fourth-republic</link>
						<dc:creator>Olusegun Olaniyi</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-12-14T00:00:00-05:00">December 14, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-12-16T00:00:00-05:00">December 16, 2022</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Nigeria</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>African History / Studies, Humanities, Languages, Political History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>First Joint International Conference of the College of Liberal Studies, Bowen University, Iwo and African Studies Institute (ASI), University of Georgia, U.S.A on</span></span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>Religion and Ethnicity in the Making of Nigeria’s Fourth Republic</span></span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>Date:   14th-16th December, 2022.               </span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b>                        </b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>CALL FOR ABSTRACT</span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>The fourth republic just like the previous republics in Nigeria has lived up to its billings in terms of the dynamics determining or influencing elections. These are ethnicity  and religion. Only in the 1993 Presidential election were the issues played down as Nigerians seemed comfortable with a Muslim/Muslim ticket that was presented by the Social Democratic Party (SDP) as its Presidential and Vice-Presidential Candidates. Since the turn of the fourth republic, these two factors have continued to play prominent roles in shaping elections and electoral processes and victories in the country and they have been made more particularly important due to the influence of politicians who have always exploited these diversities to their own advantage. The year 2023 in particular is fundamentally crucial as it is monumental in the history of Nigeria. Apart from being an election year when the people will go to the polls to elect a new leader for the country after the current leader President Muhammadu Buhari would have completed the constitutionally guaranteed eight years for a President, it also marks the year when history seems on the verge of repeating itself. Without doubt, religion and ethnicity have returned and continued to be recurrent factors in the electoral process in Nigeria, however, in 2023, the stake seems to be higher.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span>The stake is higher in 2023 especially with various factors such as the North-South dichotomy (or what is sometimes referred to as rotational Presidency) in the People’s Democratic Party (PDP), same religion (Muslim-Muslim) tickets of the All Progressives Congress (APC) among others. The question arises whether the country should not have outgrown such diversities that have been holding the country down since independence and what becomes of the country’s democracy if these dichotomies are not checked.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Paper for Presentation are hereby invited to be submitted for a conference on the above stated theme scheduled to hold from 14th to 16th December, 2022. </span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>The Sub-themes include but are not limited to the following:</span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Theoretical and Thematic Discussions on Nigeria’s Democracy</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Politics, Religion and Ethnicity in Nigeria</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Impact of Religion and Ethnicity on Nigeria’s Democracy</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>History of Democracy in Nigeria.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Religion, Ethnicity and Citizen’s Response.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Primary Elections and Intra-Party squabbles in Nigeria.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Gender Perspectives on Elections and Electoral Processes in Nigeria.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>The concept of Rotational Presidency and its Implications on Nigeria’s Democracy</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Power Rotation (Zoning) and Politics of Identity in Nigeria</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Restructuring, Power Domination and Power Devolution</span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Dr. E. Ajani                                                                             Dr. O.O. Olaniyi</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Chairman, LOC                                                                      Secretary, LOC</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>08033588168                                                                          08037150917</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Dr. E. Ajani                                                                             Dr. O.O. Olaniyi</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Chairman, LOC                                                                      Secretary, LOC</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>08033588168                                                                          08037150917</span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:bowenliberalcollegeconference@gmail.com">bowenliberalcollegeconference@gmail.com </a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 17:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667453830942728</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Papers: 53rd Annual Scholars' Conference on the Holocaust and the Churches</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11542566/call-papers-53rd-annual-scholars-conference-holocaust-and</link>
						<dc:creator>Cynthia Seton-Rogers</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-04T00:00:00-05:00">March 4, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-06T00:00:00-05:00">March 6, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Texas</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>European History / Studies, Historic Preservation, Religious Studies and Theology, Social History / Studies, World History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Dear Colleague,</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span> </span></span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The Ackerman Center for Holocaust Studies at The University of Texas at Dallas invites you to join fellow scholars <b>March 4-6, 2023</b>, as we celebrate the 53rd anniversary of this important conference and continue the legacy established by Franklin H. Littell and Hubert G. Locke more than fifty years ago. This conference offers the opportunity to address the historical significance of the Holocaust through scholarship that is interfaith, international, and interdisciplinary. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span> </span></span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><b><span><span>The central theme of the 53rd ASC is “(Dis)Continuities in the Third Reich.”</span></span></b><span><span> 2023 marks the 90th anniversary of Hitler's rise to power, the 85th anniversary of Kristallnacht in November of 1938, and the 80th anniversaries of significant military losses and uprisings against the Nazis in 1943. The aim of this conference is to examine these major turning points in the history of the Third Reich, their impact on the persecution and systematic extermination of European Jews, and their subsequent remembrance. Proposals on related topics from all disciplines are welcome.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span> </span></span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Please email presentation proposals to <a href="mailto:annualscholarsconference@utdallas.edu">annualscholarsconference@utdallas.edu</a> with “ASC Proposal” as the subject by <b>December 10, 2022</b>. The proposal should include the title of the paper with an abstract of 250-500 words and a brief (150 word) bio and a short CV. Proposals may be for a panel, round table, or individual paper.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span> </span></span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Registration, which includes the cost of all meals served during the Conference, will open in January 2023 and will include a tiered pricing level: </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span>Students/Retired Participants: $200 </span></span></li><li><span><span>Regular Registration: $250 </span></span></li><li><span><span>Late Registration (any registration after Feb. 15): $300 </span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span> </span></span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>There will be limited financial support available for graduate students and junior scholars. Please indicate in your proposal if you would like to apply for one of these awards, including how this conference will help you in your research and/or professionally.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Interested participants are encouraged to visit <a href="http://www.utdallas.edu/ackerman/asc" rel="nofollow">www.utdallas.edu/asc </a>for more information or email Cindy Seton-Rogers at <a href="mailto:annualscholarsconference@utdallas.edu">annualscholarsconference@utdallas.edu</a> with any questions.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>Cindy Seton-Rogers</span></span></span></b><br/><b><span><span>Academic and Outreach Events Manager</span></span></b></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Ackerman Center for Holocaust Studies<br/>The University of Texas at Dallas</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:annualscholarsconference@utdallas.edu">annualscholarsconference@utdallas.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="http://www.utdallas.edu/asc" target="_blank">http://www.utdallas.edu/asc</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 17:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667453830942727</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religion and Cities Unit Sessions at the 2022 American Academy of Religions Annual Meeting</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11541634/religion-and-cities-unit-sessions-2022-american-academy</link>
						<dc:creator>Fatimah Fanusie</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Event</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-18T00:00:00-05:00">November 18, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-22T00:00:00-05:00">November 22, 2022</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Cultural History / Studies, Demographic History / Studies, Ethnic History / Studies, Immigration &amp; Migration History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span>Please join the the Religion and Cities Unit at this year's American Academy of Religions 2022 meeting which will be held in Denver, Colorodo. The Religion and Cities Unit will host 3 sessions. For more information please contact Fatimah or Rupa. </span></p><p><span><strong>Imagining and Remembering Urban Communities Panel</strong> </span><span>SATURDAY. NOV. 19TH 5:00 PM - 6:30 PM This panel features papers that examine how urban communities are imagined or remembered. From case studies of Denver, Durham, and Richmond, this panel considers who is part of a city, how communities “remember”, and how religion/spirituality inform the ethics of urban community formation.HYATT REGENCY-CAPITOL 2 (FOURTH LEVEL), EDWARD DUNBAR, ALBERTUS MAGNUS COLLEGE, PRESIDING</span></p><p><span><strong>Centering Community: A Roundtable Discussion on Lived Religion and the City</strong></span><span> Sunday, Nov. 20th 9:00 - 10:30am This roundtable session puts the directors of three recently launched university-based projects focused on lived religion and cities into conversation: Engaging Lived Religion in the 21st Century Museum (UCLA), Lived Religion in the Digital Age (St. Louis University), and the Center for the Study of Religion and the City (Morgan State University). In this session, project directors will reflect on the importance of cities in defining religion and religious space. This roundtable will offer insight into emergent and innovative models for the study of lived religion through new pedagogical frameworks, including active community inclusion in educational programming (including teacher institutes, university courses, and K-12 resources) and creating new historically and ethnographically informed publicly accessible museum exhibitions, oral history collections, and digital repositories of lived religious practice in the United States.Hyatt Regency-Mineral G (Third Level), Daisy Vargas, University of Arizona, Presiding</span></p><p><span><strong>Community Engaged Research: Lessons from the Good Life Project (Roundtable)</strong></span></p><p>This roundtable features five scholars from across the US who participated in the CRC at Morgan State University collaboration, “The Good Life Project,” launched in 2021. Scholars and activists working at the intersections of religion, theology, and forms of justice-centered work, documented how urban communities pursue justice and foster healthy relationships between themselves and their environment–a pursuit that is implicitly and explicitly informed by a history of mass atrocities, such as the extermination of Indigenous Peoples and American Slavery. The discussion will include overlapping concerns of the Project collaborators and scholars of genocide and mass atrocities–such as frameworks of mutual responsibility and care ethics among community members, institutions, non-human life, and land rights. Roundtable participants will also discuss the ethical standards of Community-Based Research processes that promote non-exploitative relationships. <span>Sunday, Nov. 20th 12:30 PM - 2:30 PM; Hyatt Regency-Mineral G (Third Level) Fatima Bamba, Presiding </span><em>Co-Sponsored with Religion, Genocide, and Holocaust</em></p><p><strong><em>The Religion &amp; Cities Business Meeting</em></strong> is open to all and will take place at 10:30am on Sunday, November 20th, 2022. </p><p><span>Rupa Pillai, University of Pennsylvania, Presiding<br/>Fatimah Fanusie, Institute for Islamic, Christian, and Jewish Studies, Presiding</span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Fatimah Fanusie and Rupa Pillai</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:fanusie@icjs.org">fanusie@icjs.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.religionandcities.org/aar" target="_blank">https://www.religionandcities.org/aar</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 17:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667453830942726</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Diges – November 2, 2022</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-diges-november-2-2022/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find multiple full-time job listings, fellowships, a workshop, a Call for Papers, and two upcoming conferences.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 36!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Assistant, Associate, or Full Professor Middle East History (Full-Time, 4-year term, Fluency in Arabic not required)</h4>



<p>American University Cairo, Egypt</p>



<p>Deadline: November 15<sup>th</sup>, 2022.</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://aucegypt.interviewexchange.com/jobofferdetails.jsp;jsessionid=F92DE03B8084110EA653D4C3A2E6B745;jsessionid=2ED25732E83BECFDC6397D07ADCD3136?JOBID=154577">https://aucegypt.interviewexchange.com/jobofferdetails.jsp;jsessionid=F92DE03B8084110EA653D4C3A2E6B745;jsessionid=2ED25732E83BECFDC6397D07ADCD3136?JOBID=154577</a></p>



<h4>Lecturer in Buddhist Languages and Cultures (Full-Time, 3-year fixed term)</h4>



<p>University of Edinburgh, Scotland</p>



<p>Deadline: December 23<sup>rd</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://elxw.fa.em3.oraclecloud.com/hcmUI/CandidateExperience/en/sites/CX_1001/job/5624/?utm_medium=jobshare">https://elxw.fa.em3.oraclecloud.com/hcmUI/CandidateExperience/en/sites/CX_1001/job/5624/?utm_medium=jobshare</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor: Emphasis on Global African Diaspora (Full-Time Tenure-Track)</h4>



<p>Spelman College, US</p>



<p>Deadline: November 20<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://jobs.chronicle.com/job/37332552/assistant-professor-/">https://jobs.chronicle.com/job/37332552/assistant-professor-/</a></p>



<h4>Lecturer in Sociology/Anthropology (Full-Time)</h4>



<p>University of Newcastle, Australia</p>



<p>Deadline: November 6<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.seek.com.au/job/58841540?type=standout#sol=60ec2e166d08c667b65e3880a43a9a7cd0725bdb">https://www.seek.com.au/job/58841540?type=standout – sol=60ec2e166d08c667b65e3880a43a9a7cd0725bdb</a></p>



<h4>Mellon Islamicate Digital Humanities Post-Doctoral Associate (on-Tenure Track)</h4>



<p>University of Maryland, US</p>



<p>Deadline: November 15<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://ejobs.umd.edu/postings/101235?fbclid=IwAR061ZZO7p9ios7VwcVvUHQjzNlkrSGHiSHvr3LB6J6cQEIHOGpkjhp-mOo">https://ejobs.umd.edu/postings/101235?fbclid=IwAR061ZZO7p9ios7VwcVvUHQjzNlkrSGHiSHvr3LB6J6cQEIHOGpkjhp-mOo</a></p>



<h4>Postdoctoral Research Associate in Religion and Politics (1 year, possibility of renewal for 2<sup>nd</sup> year)</h4>



<p>Washington University, US</p>



<p>Deadline: January 5<sup>th</sup>, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://apply.interfolio.com/114752">https://apply.interfolio.com/114752</a></p>



<h4>Lecturer of Religious Studies: Emphasis in South Asian Religions (non-Tenure Track, renewable)</h4>



<p>Southern Methodist University, US</p>



<p>Deadline: November 7<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://apply.interfolio.com/114520">https://apply.interfolio.com/114520</a></p>



<h4>Associate or Full Professor: Eileen Lamb O’Gara Endowed Chair in Women’s Philanthropy (Tenure-Track)</h4>



<p>Indiana University, US</p>



<p>Deadline: November 30, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.rraweb.org/2022/10/eileen-lamb-ogara-endowed-chair-in-womens-philanthropy-indiana-university-lilly-family-school-of-philanthropy/">https://www.rraweb.org/2022/10/eileen-lamb-ogara-endowed-chair-in-womens-philanthropy-indiana-university-lilly-family-school-of-philanthropy/</a></p>



<h2>Fellowships:</h2>



<h4>Research Fellow at The Institute of Ethics and Society</h4>



<p>University of Notre Dame, Australia</p>



<p>Deadline: November 11<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.seek.com.au/job/58838730?tracking=TMC-SAU-eDM-SharedJob-13246">https://www.seek.com.au/job/58838730?tracking=TMC-SAU-eDM-SharedJob-13246</a></p>



<h4>Becoming Muslim in Rural Leicestershire: An Oral History Project Exploring Identity and Belonging</h4>



<p>Coventry University, UK</p>



<p>Deadline: January 12<sup>th</sup>, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.coventry.ac.uk/research/research-opportunities/research-students/midlands4cities/">https://www.coventry.ac.uk/research/research-opportunities/research-students/midlands4cities/</a></p>



<h2>Workshops:</h2>



<h4>Sacred Writes: Public Scholarship on Religion (asynchronous and Zoom workshops)</h4>



<p>Northeastern University, US</p>



<p>Deadline: January 9<sup>th</sup>, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.sacred-writes.org/public-scholarship-trainings">https://www.sacred-writes.org/public-scholarship-trainings</a></p>



<h2>Call For Papers:</h2>



<h4>“Religion and Bioethics: A Sociological Perspective” <em>Frontiers in Sociology </em>journal.</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 31<sup>st</sup>, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.frontiersin.org/research-topics/25414/religion-and-bioethics-a-sociological-perspective">https://www.frontiersin.org/research-topics/25414/religion-and-bioethics-a-sociological-perspective</a></p>



<h2>Conferences:</h2>



<h4><em>Religion in Modern Education: Conflict, Policy, and Practice:</em> April 13-15, 2023</h4>



<p>Australian National University, Australia</p>



<p>Abstract Deadline: February 14<sup>th</sup>, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.anu.edu.au/events/religion-in-modern-education-conflict-policy-and-practice">https://www.anu.edu.au/events/religion-in-modern-education-conflict-policy-and-practice</a></p>



<h4>Congress of the Humanities, Arts, and Social Sciences</h4>



<p>Melbourne Australia</p>



<p>November 28<sup>th</sup> – December 3<sup>rd</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://chass.org.au/content.aspx?page_id=22&amp;club_id=239946&amp;module_id=502484">https://chass.org.au/content.aspx?page_id=22&amp;club_id=239946&amp;module_id=502484</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667453830942725</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>ICCH 2023 : 2023 7th International Conference on Culture and History (ICCH 2023)</title>
			<link>http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=169919&amp;copyownerid=13881</link>
						<description>2023 7th International Conference on Culture and History (ICCH 2023) [Vienna, Austria] [Jul 25, 2023 - Jul 27, 2023]</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 05:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667367429381983</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[Today - Tomorrow] Conference or similar: 2022 Philosophy Born of Struggle Conference</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/102790</link>
						<description>Venue: 601 University Drive<br/><br/><p>Please visit the conference webpage for more information about the 2022 Philosophy Born of Struggle conference.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 05:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667367429381982</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CSI Exeter Monday Majlis (17:00-18:30, UK Time, Zoom): Is It Religion or Magic, and What Is Between Them? New (Old) Approaches to Ottoman Institutional Sunnism (1600-1800)/A Talk by Nikola Pantic</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11536391/csi-exeter-monday-majlis-1700-1830-uk-time-zoom-it-religion-or</link>
						<dc:creator>Nikola Pantic</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-07T00:00:00-05:00">November 7, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Arabic History / Studies, Early Modern History and Period Studies, Islamic History / Studies, Middle East History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><b>Nikola Pantic, <i>Is It Religion or Magic, and What Is Between Them? New (Old) Approaches to Ottoman Institutional Sunnism (1600-1800), </i></b><strong>17:00-18:30 (UK time)</strong></p><p><b>Register in advance for this meeting: </b><a href="https://universityofexeter.zoom.us/meeting/register/tJIocOmsrDIoHdS1MGcJFfNI0oMSanzYoLna" rel="nofollow">https://Universityofexeter.zoom.us/meeting/register/tJIocOmsrDIoHdS1MGcJFfNI0oMSanzYoLna</a></p><p><b>Abstract:</b></p><p>My talk discusses relations between religion, wonder-working, and magic in early modern Sunni Islam. Broadly analyzing the history of Ottoman religious dynamics, the talk presents arguments for defining a Muslim priestly sodality. This corporate entity is identified through a considerable overlap between the Sufi and ulamaic functions, and is represented by state-appointed religious authorities. I further focus on the collective representations of <i>baraka, </i>often interpreted by the ulamaic circles as Allah’s grace. It was believed that religious professionals used <i>baraka</i> to cause wonders. Wonder-working, as the mechanical aspect of Ottoman Sunni Islam, was for the most part included by Sufi teachings and practices, which were therefore integral to Ottoman Sunnism. Most prominent Sufi masters and their disciples formed a part of the institutionalized priestly sodality networks that were present in the region. Ottoman religious professionals over time made doctrinal and social distinctions between their own thaumaturgical (wonder-working) beliefs and practices, and those commonly interpreted as magic (<i>siḥr</i>). Although conceptually and anthropologically congruent, thaumaturgy and magic retained their distinctive character until the modern reforms and beyond. Looking into the thin line between wonder-working and magic allows for rich socio-anthropological discussions about the relationships between religion and magic in history, which represents another main point of my presentation.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:panticn@ceu.edu">panticn@ceu.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 17:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667367429381981</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>From “Fuzzy” to “Eclectic” and Everything in Between: Intercultural Encounters in the Pre-Modern World</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11487375/%E2%80%9Cfuzzy%E2%80%9D-%E2%80%9Ceclectic%E2%80%9D-and-everything-between-intercultural</link>
						<dc:creator>Adela Foo</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-01-02T00:00:00-05:00">January 2, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Connecticut</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Art, Art History &amp; Visual Studies, Humanities, Languages, Religious Studies and Theology, World History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>From “Fuzzy” to “Eclectic” and Everything in Between: Intercultural Encounters in the Pre-Modern World</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>April 14 – April 15, 2023; New Haven, CT</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Yale University </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>In-person Graduate Conference </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>hosted by the </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>History of Art Pre/Early Modern Forum </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>and generously sponsored by </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Yale History of Art, Early Modern Studies, Council for East Asian Studies, and Medieval Studies</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Keynote Speaker: </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Holly Shaffer, Assistant Professor of History of Art and Architecture, Brown University</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The pre-modern world was shaped by encounters and engagements that spanned geographical, cultural, political, and temporal boundaries. Scholars have employed a variety of terms to describe such moments of convergence, including “hybridity,” “creolization,” “syncretism,” “eclecticism,” and even “fuzziness.”</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>In 2009, historians Sünne Juterczenka and Gesa Mackenthun used the mathematical concept of “fuzzy logic” as a framework for examining the entanglements, ambiguities, and mutual impacts resulting from interactions between multiple cultures. “Fuzzy logic” argues for the presence of multiple truth values on a spectrum from absolute truth to falsehood. It allows for the exploration of blurred boundaries and the diffusion of practices. More recently, art historian Holly Schafer employs the term “eclecticism” to describe intercultural objects whose disparate elements retain their independence while creating a new form. Broadly defined as a practice inspired by a multiplicity of cultural, artistic, and stylistic sources, eclecticism provides a way of thinking about the intercultural nature of the pre-modern world. </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Building on these concepts, the Pre/Early Modern Forum invites graduate students working in the humanities to explore all things “eclectic” and “fuzzy” that complicate cultural and geographical boundaries in the pre-1800 world. We encourage submissions from all geographical distinctions, especially those that explore topics related to East Asia. Interrogating the ways in which intercultural encounters blur and maintain boundaries, the conference aims to foster creative and innovative dialogue across cultures, regions, time periods, and disciplines. </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Possible topics include, but are not limited to:</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Contact zones, intersectionality, and peripheries</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Movement of objects, people, and ideas across boundaries </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Authorship and ownership</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Translation and transcription</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Religious proselytization and conversion</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Micro-histories addressing specific instances of encounter</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Gift exchange, diplomacy, and trade</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Technology and methodology</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Patronage and collecting</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Power dynamics within systems of colonialism </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Identity formation and articulation </span></span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Interested participants are invited to submit an abstract of no more than 300 words, along with a short biography, to </span></span></span></span></span></span><a href="mailto:yalepem@gmail.com"><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>yalepemf@gmail.com</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></a><span><span><span><span><span><span> by </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Monday, January 2, 2023</span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>. Accepted participants will be notified in late-January. Accommodation will be provided for all participants. At this time, we are planning for an in-person symposium but will adapt to a virtual format if Covid-19 conditions and University policies change.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>The Pre/Early Modern Forum at Yale University</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:yalepemf@gmail.com">yalepemf@gmail.com </a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 17:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667367429381980</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Newberry Seminar on Religion and Culture in the Americas, November 11, 2022</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11526872/newberry-seminar-religion-and-culture-americas-november-11</link>
						<dc:creator>Malachy R. McCarthy</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Seminar</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-31T00:00:00-04:00">October 31, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-14T00:00:00-05:00">November 14, 2022</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Illinois</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Asian History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><b><span>Friday, November 11, 2022 </span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span>3:00-4:30 pm Central Time</span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span>Virtual Seminar, Register for link</span></b></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><b><span><span>Tikkun Olam: War-Injured Vietnamese Children and (Hidden?) Jewish Humanitarian Efforts</span></span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span><span>Theresa Keeley, University of Louisville</span></span></b></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>In the late 1960s and early 1970s, the Committee to Save War-Burned and War-Injured Vietnamese Children (COR) brought children to the United States for free medical care. Jews, especially Jewish doctors, played key roles in founding and leading COR, yet archival documents and contemporaneous press coverage virtually ignore this fact. Privately, some Jews expressed fear that antisemitism might derail COR if the organization was seen as “too Jewish.” This paper explores what Jews’ involvement with COR – and attempts to perhaps downplay their own role - reveals about Jewish humanitarian efforts, Jewish identity, and religious activism versus religiously-influenced activism.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Respondent: </span></span></span><span><span><span>Shana Bernstein, Northwestern University</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>This event is free, but all participants must register in advance and space is limited. To register and request a copy of the pre-circulated paper, click </span></span></span><a href="https://reg.learningstream.com/reg/event_page.aspx?ek=0057-0014-4adbb580c8f9489c9b2863e28c83c6e4" rel="nofollow"><span><span><span>here</span></span></span></a><span><span><span>. Please do not request a paper unless you plan to attend.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Emily Altman</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:scholarlyseminars@newberry.org">scholarlyseminars@newberry.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.newberry.org/calendar/theresa-keeley-university-of-louisville" target="_blank">https://www.newberry.org/calendar/theresa-keeley-university-of-louisville</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 17:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667367429381979</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rhetoric and Religion as Resources for Resistance: An Interdisciplinary Conference</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11486143/rhetoric-and-religion-resources-resistance-interdisciplinary</link>
						<dc:creator>Andre E. Johnson</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Tennessee</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Communication, Composition &amp; Rhetoric, Religious Studies and Theology, Digital Humanities, Linguistics</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><strong>RHETORIC AND RELIGION AS RESOURCES FOR RESISTANCE:</strong><br/><strong>An Interdisciplinary Conference</strong><br/>The University of Memphis<br/>Memphis, TN<br/><strong>October 19-21, 2023</strong><br/>~</p><p><em>In times of unabashed misogyny, xenophobia, “alternative facts,” “fake news,” open vitriol, racism, and hate, if I do not preach and act out the fundamental truth that God loves all, then I lose my self-respect. If I do not reach deep into moral imagination and envision a world beyond the supremacist, nationalistic, and oppressive culture in which I live, then I have sacrificed my principles and embarrassed my calling as a minister of the gospel.</em><br/>– Frank A. Thomas,<br/><em>How to Preach a Dangerous Sermon</em></p><p> </p><p><em>Rhetoric is indeed, as many theologians feared,</em> <em>risky and messy</em>.<br/>– Majorie O’Rourke Boyle,<br/>“Rhetorical Theology: Charity Seeking Charity”</p><p>~</p><p>In <em>Life’s Too Short to Pretend You’re Not Religious</em>, David Dark observes that religion — and we’d add rhetoric — “is the question of how we dispose our energies, how we see fit to organize our own lives and, in many cases, the lives of others.” Majorie O’Rourke Boyle nicely captures the contingency of such a claim when she notes that rhetoric — and we’d add religion — is risky and messy. Religion and rhetoric coalesce around virtually every human concern, which is why we feel compelled to open this call for papers asking what roles religious rhetorics, and rhetorics of religion more generally, play in helping us to “envision a world beyond the supremacist, nationalistic, and oppressive culture” that Frank Thomas calls out in <em>How To Preach a Dangerous Sermon</em>? It’s a perennial question, of course, but as scholarship that interrogates the intersections of rhetoric and religion continues to proliferate, Thomas reminds us of the role religious rhetorics play in cultivating communities of resistance, especially ones that can rise to the challenge of imagining a more hopeful and just future starting in the present.</p><p>We invite scholars to submit individual or coauthored paper and panel proposals focusing on any project related to rhetoric and religion, but we are especially interested in work that helps us imagine the resources that can be cultivated from the study of religious rhetorics, whether those resources are pedagogical, philosophical, homiletic, activist-focused, or something else.</p><p>As with the previous <a href="https://sites.google.com/a/utk.edu/rhetoric-and-religion/" rel="nofollow">Rhetoric &amp; Religious Traditions</a> conference that took place in 2018, presenters might examine the intersections between work on religious rhetorics and other subfields of communication studies, rhetoric and writing studies, religious studies, homiletics, sociology, anthropology, or other fields that engage with the philosophy of language and communication. Presenters might discuss the ways scholarship on religion and rhetoric might be invigorated by studying spiritual traditions and practices of particular groups. Other researchers might examine the ways scholarship on rhetoric and religion can help us explore key cultural concerns in our current moment, including how problems like the ones Thomas names — things like white supremacy, xenophobia, and misinformation — can be engaged using the resources of particular rhetorical and religious traditions.</p><p>Importantly, we also want to make space for work that is anti-religious, non-religious, or takes a critical perspective on religious rhetoric. We wish to cultivate an interdisciplinary space that welcomes believers, skeptics, atheists, activists, scholars, and religious leaders. We especially hope scholars doing work on non-Western religious traditions will consider submitting a proposal.</p><p>We welcome Single Paper and Full Panel (3-4 speakers) proposals. Please limit Single Paper proposals to 250 words and Full Panel Proposals to 500 words. For Full Panel proposals, please include the names/email addresses of each speaker.</p><p>Please submit proposals via this <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfMkl30ZuAHbQyLnm30Fv47SUt-EEA29P58GVy1xTUEV7Cz3Q/viewform" rel="nofollow"><strong>submission link</strong></a> by March 15, 2023.</p><p>Inquires can be sent to Dr. Will Duffy and Dr. Andre E. Johnson at <a href="mailto:rrtconference@gmail.com">rrtconference@gmail.com</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Andre E. Johnson</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ajohnsn6@memphis.edu">ajohnsn6@memphis.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 20:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667281031168797</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Emerson Society Program Committee Members</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/10/31/call-for-emerson-society-program-committee-members</link>
						<dc:creator>prentissclark@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Monday, October 31, 2022 - 3:32pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Ralph Waldo Emerson Society</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:prentiss.clark@usd.edu">prentiss.clark@usd.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/general-announcements">general announcements</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/pedagogy">pedagogy</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>January 30, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>The <strong>Ralph Waldo Emerson Society</strong> seeks two persons to serve on the <strong>Emerson Society Program Committee</strong>, beginning in January 2023. This committee annually organizes panels for <a href="https://americanliteratureassociation.org/ala-conferences/ala-annual-conference/">ALA</a> (the American Literature Association) and <a href="https://secure.thoreausociety.org/events/annual-gathering-2022/">TAG</a> (the Thoreau Society Annual Gathering), and panels for <a href="https://american-philosophy.org/">SAAP</a> (the Society for the Advancement of American Philosophy), regional <a href="https://www.mla.org/">MLA</a> associations, and <a href="https://www.c19society.org/">C19</a> (the Society of Nineteenth-Century Americanists) as interests and opportunities allow. In past years the Emerson Society co-sponsored “Transatlanticism in American Literature” (Oxford 2006), “Conversazioni in Italia” (Florence 2012), and “Transcendentalist Intersections: Literature, Philosophy, Religion” (Heidelberg 2018). We’re looking for persons interested in supporting and developing RWES programs that nurture international conversation, interdisciplinary inquiry, and collaboration between scholarly societies. Committee members on this four-person committee serve two-year terms (renewable). Service includes drafting and circulating CFPs, organizing and chairing panels (when relevant), communicating with the Emerson Society Media Committee, and attending biannual RWES board meetings (remotely or in person). If interested, please contact <strong>Prentiss Clark</strong>(<a href="mailto:Prentiss.Clark@usd.edu">Prentiss.Clark@usd.edu</a>).</p>
<p>The Ralph Waldo Emerson Society <a href="https://emersonsociety.org/">https://emersonsociety.org</a></p>
<p>@EmersonSociety</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 13:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667281031168796</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ July 26, 2023 -  July 29, 2023] Conference or similar: 13th International Whitehead Conference - Whitehead and the History of Philosophy</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104530</link>
						<description>Venue: Kaulbachstr. 33<br/><br/><p>Alfred North Whitehead developed his process philosophy with an explicit reliance on the value of the history of philosophy. While the trend of recent years has often suggested that different approaches to philosophical problems can be adequately categorized, using the dichotomy of purely systematic or purely historical interests, Whitehead offers an equally historically informed and systematically intended perspective.</p>
<p>This conference is dedicated to the philosophical-historical dimension in Whitehead’s oeuvre on the one hand and to its systematic relevance for numerous areas of research on the other hand.</p>
<p>Interested scholars are cordially invited to submit an abstract of no more than 500 words<br/>in one of the follwoing sections here: <a href="https://easychair.org/account/signin?l=8DUhKbvT0vCoX6K2LRHeX4">https://easychair.org/account/signin?l=8DUhKbvT0vCoX6K2LRHeX4</a></p>
<p>Whitehead and Aesthetics</p>
<p>Whitehead and Analytical Philosophy</p>
<p>Whitehead, Bergson and Deleuze</p>
<p>Whitehead and Biology</p>
<p>Whitehead and Education</p>
<p>Whitehead and the Philosophy of the 21st Century</p>
<p>Whitehead and classical Greek Philosophy</p>
<p>Whitehead and Integral Ecology</p>
<p>Whitehead and Integral Economics</p>
<p>Whitehead, Mathematics and Physics</p>
<p>German Whitehead research (in German)</p>
<p>Whitehead and Phenomenology</p>
<p>Whitehead and Pragmatism</p>
<p>Whitehead, Spinoza and Leibniz</p>
<p>Whitehead and Social Sciences</p>
<p>Whitehead and Theology</p>
<p>Whitehead and China<br/><br/></p>
<p>Dates and fees (in euro):</p>
<p>Early registration: Jan. 1 2023 – Jan. 31, 2023; fee: 75 (students)/150 (standard);</p>
<p>Normal registration: Feb. 1 – May 31, 2023; fee: 100 (students)/200 (standard);</p>
<p>Late registration: after June 1, 2023; fee: 125 (students)/250 (standard). </p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 05:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667108225385192</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ November 30, 2022] CFP for conference or similar: First-Person Science of Consciousness</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104486</link>
						<description><p>First-Person Science of Consciousness: Methodological Potentials, Challenges and Developmental Perspectives</p>

<p>This upcoming conference seeks to advance the field of a first-person science of consciousness – an important but still underrepresented area of research. The conference has a particular focus on methods of conducting first-person research. It seeks to explore the potentials and challenges associated with these methods and is intended to illuminate perspectives for the further development of the field. The conference will bring together leading researchers and young scholars in order to explore how third- and first-person methods can complement each other to allow for a more comprehensive phenomenology and understanding of consciousness.</p>

<p>Time and location: May 11th-13th 2023, University of Witten/Herdecke</p>

<p>Abstract Submission deadline: November 30, 2022</p>

<p>Details, Registration and Abstract submission: <a href="https://consciousness.uni-wh.de/">https://consciousness.uni-wh.de/</a></p>

<p>For the conference team:</p>
<p>Brentyn Ramm</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 05:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667021829677353</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ May 11, 2023 -  May 13, 2023] Conference or similar: First-Person Science of Consciousness</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104482</link>
						<description>Venue: Alfred-Herrhausen-Str. 50<br/><br/><p>First-Person Science of Consciousness: Methodological Potentials, Challenges and Developmental Perspectives</p>
<p>This upcoming conference seeks to advance the field of a first-person science of consciousness – an important but still underrepresented area of research. The conference has a particular focus on methods of conducting first-person research. It seeks to explore the potentials and challenges associated with these methods and is intended to illuminate perspectives for the further development of the field. The conference will bring together leading researchers and young scholars in order to explore how third- and first-person methods can complement each other to allow for a more comprehensive phenomenology and understanding of consciousness.</p>
<p>Time and location: May 11th-13th 2023, University of Witten/Herdecke</p>
<p>Abstract Submission deadline: November 30, 2022</p>
<p>Details, Registration and Abstract submission: https://consciousness.uni-wh.de/</p>
<p>For the conference team:</p>
<p>Brentyn Ramm</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 05:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667021829677352</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
