<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 12:22:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 12:22:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ April 15, 2023] Conference or similar: West Chester University Graduate Philosophy Conference</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/107345</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 06:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675147029895805</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ September 28, 2023 -  September 30, 2023] Conference or similar: Eco-phenomenology and Passivity</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/107309</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p><strong>Eco-Phenomenology and Passivity Conference</strong></p>
<p><strong>Call for Papers</strong></p>
<p><strong>Place: UiT – The Arctic University of Norway (Tromsø)</strong></p>
<p><strong>Dates: 28-30 September 2023</strong></p>
<p>Phenomenology is a tradition of thinking that acknowledges the already-givenness of our bodies, our relationships to others, and the ecosystems in which we live. Since the founding of the field in the early twentieth century, phenomenologists have taken an interest in the ways that humans engage the world that precedes us, but it was only in the last twenty years that scholars recognized the potential phenomenology could have for environmental ethics and the ongoing multi-disciplinary rethinking of our human relationship to the more-than-human world. Since then, scholars approaching environmental ethics from within philosophy, literature, theology, anthropology, and cognitive science have drawn consistently on the vocabulary and methodologies of phenomenology to approach questions of: how we understand and can better anticipate human impacts on ecosystems; what it means to dwell/be at home in a specific ecosystem; what role the perception of animals plays in individual and community environmental impact; and how human embodiment can be reconceived as dependent on the natural world that exceeds us. Related to this are questions of cultural ways of being toward nature that undermine the assumption of human dominance.</p>
<p>Building on prior work on the phenomenology of embodiment, subjectivity, ethics, and most recently passivity, this conference consolidates contemporary thinking on the phenomenology of passivity and environmental ethics. Passivity is a key concept in phenomenology. By passivity, we refer to all the ways in which we receive and are conditioned by the surrounding world prior to active attempts to master it. Thus far, passivity´s relevance to environmental philosophy and ethics has been obscured by a focus on environmental activism. Indeed, from an activist perspective, passivity tends to be understood as a “do-nothing” attitude that will lead to environmental disaster. Rather than defining passivity in opposition to activism, participants in this conference will explore passivity as linked to givenness, inter-dependence and environmental response-ability, conceived of in relation to the present generation´s need to respond to prior human damage to the earth, natural forces beyond our control, and the anticipated needs of multi-species future.</p>
<p>Ted Toadvine, Arne Johan Vetlesen, Michael Marder and Simone Kotva will give keynote presentations. We welcome proposals for additional presentations of around 20 minutes each.</p>
<p>Please send abstracts of 300-400 words to Cassandra.falke@uit.no by March 15th 2023. Emails regarding acceptance will be sent by April 15th.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 06:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675147029895804</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ March 6, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: West Chester University Graduate Philosophy Conference</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/107349</link>
						<description><p><strong>Call for Papers for Philosophy Grad Student Association</strong></p>
<p><strong>Spring Conference 2023: Morality &amp; Religion</strong></p>
<p>The PGSA Spring Philosophy Conference 2023 is scheduled for <u>Saturday, April 15 at 1 pm</u>. We are now accepting submissions of papers addressing questions and theories on the topic of “Morality &amp; Religion”, including but not limited to:</p>
<p>What is morality? What is religion? How do these concepts come into play in our lives? How are they related? How are they different? How do they originate? How do they conflict? Are they necessary? Do they affect to our ethics and politics, and how? Do they affect our decisions and our actions, and how? Do they affect our identities, and how? Ultimately, what is the future of morality and religion in the world we live in?</p>
<p><strong>Graduate Student and Faculty Submissions: </strong>Please email an <strong>abstract </strong>of no more than 550 words in a file prepared for blind review, meaning without any personal identifying information. In the body of the e-mail include author’s name, paper title, institutional affiliation, faculty or graduate student status, address, phone number, and email address.</p>
<p>Final papers should be of a length that permits a <u>20-25 minute presentation</u>.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Undergraduate Student Submissions: </strong>Please submit a <strong>paper, </strong>formatted with double-spaced, numbered pages, 3000 words maximum (not counting notes) in a file prepared for blind review as described above. Include in a separate file an <strong>abstract </strong>of no more than 250 words. In the body of the e-mail include author’s name, paper title, institutional affiliation, address, phone number, and word count for the paper. Time for presentation will be <u>15-20 minutes</u>.</p>
<p>Additionally, we are happy to announce that we will have two speakers for this event:</p>
<p>Dr. Katie Brennan, Temple University</p>
<p>Dr. Nicolas de Warren, Penn State University</p>


<p>Please send materials for blind review to dc985230@wcupa.edu</p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 06:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675147029895803</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hasidism in America: New Research and Teaching Resource</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12272772/hasidism-america-new-research-and-teaching-resource</link>
						<dc:creator>Roberta Newman</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Online Digital Resources</div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>New York</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Immigration &amp; Migration History / Studies, Holocaust, Genocide, and Memory Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>In 2021 the National Historical Publications and Records Commission (NHPRC) awarded the Brooklyn College Library’s Archives and Special Collections unit a grant to digitize and share with the public unused footage from the creation of the 1997 landmark documentary <i>A Life Apart: Hasidism in America, </i>which was funded by the National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH).</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The project, overseen by Brooklyn College Archivist Colleen Bradley-Sanders, digitized approximately 69 hours of outtakes, which are now available at </span></span></span><span><span><a href="https:///C:/Users/rgnew/Dropbox/A%20Life%20Apart%202020/Post-project%20publicity/tinyurl.com/A-Life-Apart-Collection-Guide">tinyurl.com/A-Life-Apart-Collection-Guide</a> The footage, cataloged by Project Archivist Roberta Newman,  can also be accessed from the Archives website<a href="https:///C:/Users/rgnew/Dropbox/A%20Life%20Apart%202020/Post-project%20publicity/tinyurl.com/A-Life-Apart-Digital-Content">: tinyurl.com/A-Life-Apart-Digital-Content</a>, along with a finding aid to the collection. </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Described by producers Menachem Daum  and Oren Rudavsky as “audiovisual field notes” on the religious practices, cultural mores, communal organization, family life, inter-communal relations, and the Americanization process of a distinctive immigrant community from 1936-1996, the film and the outtakes include interviews with scholars (Ann Braude, Yaffa Eliach, David Fishman, Samuel Heilman, Arthur Hertzberg, Martin Marty, Zalman Schachter Shalomi) community members and neighbors from the Brooklyn neighborhoods where the majority of America’s Hasidim live. </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The material has great potential for enriching scholarship in a broad range of humanities disciplines, including religious studies, immigration history, urban studies, sociology, anthropology, ethnology, folklore and ethnomusicology. It also has the potential for adaptation for use in secondary school and university classrooms.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>See the PBS website for information about the original documentary film:</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><a href="https://www.pbs.org/alifeapart/" rel="nofollow">https://www.pbs.org/alifeapart/</a></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Questions about the collection may be sent to:</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><a href="https:///C:/Users/rgnew/Dropbox/A%20Life%20Apart%202020/Post-project%20publicity/specialcollections@brooklyn.cuny.edu">specialcollections@brooklyn.cuny.edu</a></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>For information about arranging a screening of the full-length documentary <i><span>A Life Apart: Hasidism in America, </span></i><span>contact Menemsha Films at </span><a href="https://www.menemshafilms.com/" rel="nofollow">https://www.menemshafilms.com/</a><span>  or Oren Rudavsky at </span><a href="mailto:oren.rudavsky@gmail.com">oren.rudavsky@gmail.com</a></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><div>Prof. Colleen Bradley-Sanders</div><div>Head of Archives and Special Collections</div><div>Brooklyn College Library</div><div>2900 Bedford Ave.</div><div>Brooklyn, NY 11210</div><div>Tel: 718.951.5581</div><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:specialcollections@brooklyn.cuny.edu">specialcollections@brooklyn.cuny.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="http://tinyurl.com/A-Life-Apart-Collection-Guide" target="_blank">http://tinyurl.com/A-Life-Apart-Collection-Guide</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 19:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675147029895802</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Aramaic Incantation Bowls and Social History: The Case of Slaves and Demons</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12258114/aramaic-incantation-bowls-and-social-history-case-slaves-and</link>
						<dc:creator>Sara Ben-Isaac</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-01T00:00:00-05:00">February 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Ancient History, Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The Babylonian Talmud is the principal surviving literary source for the Jewish communities in the Sasanian empire (3rd to 7th centuries AD). As a result, scholarship has primarily focused on the rabbinic elite represented in and responsible for the Talmud. However, hundreds of Jewish magical amulets written on bowls provide access to the unknown lives and practices of Jews in the very cities in which the Babylonian rabbis flourished. These magical texts may serve as a rare vantage point from which to reconstruct the social and cultural history of Jews in the Sasanian empire. This lecture will focus on slavery and enslaved individuals in the Sasanian empire through their appearance in the Aramaic incantation bowl texts. In addition, the speaker will point to evidence that connects slaves with the demonic in the magic bowls and in other magical sources, through texts and in imagery.</p><p>Dr. Avigail Manekin-Bamberger is a senior lecturer in the Department of Jewish History and Contemporary Jewry at the Hebrew University of Jerusalem. Her research focuses on the social and cultural history of Jews in antiquity, with a special emphasis on Jewish society in the Sasanian Empire and ancient Jewish magic.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>UCL Institute of Jewish Studies</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ijs@ucl.ac.uk">ijs@ucl.ac.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/511680358727" target="_blank">https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/511680358727</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 18:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675147029895801</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ April 1, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: 17th Annual Society for Ricoeur Studies Conference,</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/107257</link>
						<description></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 06:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1674974228221537</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ October 13, 2023 -  October 15, 2023] Conference or similar: 17th Annual Society for Ricoeur Studies Conference,</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/107253</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 06:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1674974228221536</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ March 23, 2023] Talk or similar: Simon Hewitt, 'God and Abstract Objects: a new proposal'</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/107177</link>
						<description>Venue: Botany House<br/><br/>Speakers at this event: <br/>Simon Hewitt (University of Leeds)<br/>Simon Hewitt (University of Leeds)<br/><br/><p>Botany House seminar room (Room 1.03) from 11.30am till 1pm. </p>
<p>Should you be unable to attend in person, you can still tune in by Zoom: <a url:clicktarget="_blank">https://universityofleeds.zoom.us/j/89598770653?pwd=cFNUUW1adHhQSnMzVUxiYmxPcE1vUT09</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 06:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1674801427653575</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ March 9, 2023] Talk or similar: Mikel Burley,’Not so much thought out as danced out’: Diversifying philosophy of religion in the light of Afro-Brazilian Candomblé</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/107173</link>
						<description>Venue: Botany House<br/><br/>Speakers at this event: <br/>Mikel Burley (University of Leeds)<br/>Mikel Burley (University of Leeds)<br/><br/><p>Botany House seminar room (Room 1.03) from 11.30am till 1pm. </p>
<p>Should you be unable to attend in person, you can still tune in by Zoom: <a url:clicktarget="_blank">https://universityofleeds.zoom.us/j/89598770653?pwd=cFNUUW1adHhQSnMzVUxiYmxPcE1vUT09</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 06:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1674801427653574</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[CFP] Journal of Religious Minorities  under Muslim Rule</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12256336/cfp-journal-religious-minorities-under-muslim-rule</link>
						<dc:creator>Abbas Aghdassi</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology, Middle East History / Studies, Islamic History / Studies, Arabic History / Studies, Law and Legal History</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><em><b><span><span><span>Journal of Religious Minorities </span></span></span></b></em></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><em><b><span><span><span>under Muslim Rule</span></span></span></b></em></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>BRILL</span></span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><b><u><span><span><span><span>CALL FOR PAPERS</span></span></span></span></u></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The </span></span></span><a href="https://brill.com/view/journals/rmmr/rmmr-overview.xml?" rel="nofollow"><i><span><span><span>Journal of Religious Minorities under Muslim Rule</span></span></span></i></a><span><span><span> provides a primary venue for scholarly studies that examine religious minorities (such as Christians, Jews, Zoroastrians, Hindus, and other minoritarian Muslim groups) under majoritarian Muslim rule. The journal covers a large temporal period, spanning from 7th century Arabia to 1922 (the end of Ottoman rule), in addition to a large geographic area from North Africa and al-Andalus in the West to Iran, some Central Asian lands, well into Pakistan, Bangladesh, Malaysia, and Indonesia in the East. The focus includes minority-minority, minority-majority, and minority-state relations. In addition to its broad temporal and geographic reach, this is an interdisciplinary journal which will appeal to those working in specific disciplines, including history, religious studies, literature, legal studies, and archaeology.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><i><span><span><span>JRMMR</span></span></span></i><span><span><span> welcomes original papers and review essays that focus on any temporal and geographic areas. We are particularly interested in, but not limited to, papers that,</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>offer an inter-/multi-disciplinary approach to the topic</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>re-examine monolithic view(s) on minorities and their status</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>analyze minority relations as dynamic, fluid, and ever-changing</span></span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The following questions are of particular interest,  </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>What can we learn about the complexity of Islam and Muslims from understanding the minorities in its and their midst? </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>What do we learn about these minoritarian traditions from their existence within a larger Muslim environment?</span></span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p> </p><p><span><span><span><b><u><span><span><span><span>SUBMIT YOUR PAPER</span></span></span></span></u></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>We would like to invite all authors to submit their papers directly to the editors-in-chief, Abbas Aghdassi (</span></span></span><a href="mailto:aghdassi@um.ac.ir"><span><span><span>aghdassi@um.ac.ir</span></span></span></a><span><span><span>) &amp; Aaron W. Hughes (</span></span></span><a href="mailto:aaron.hughes@rochester.edu"><span><span><span>aaron.hughes@rochester.edu</span></span></span></a><span><span><span>). We receive manuscripts on a rolling basis, and we will publish two issues per year. If you have any questions before submitting, please contact us.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>For more information, please visit: </span></span></span><a href="https://edinburghuniversitypress.com/series-advances-in-the-study-of-islam" rel="nofollow"> <span><span><span>https://brill.com/rmmr/</span></span></span></a></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p> </p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:aghdassi@um.ac.ir">aghdassi@um.ac.ir</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://brill.com/rmmr/" target="_blank">https://brill.com/rmmr/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 18:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1674801427653573</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[Announcement] Journal of Religious Minorities under Muslim Rule (Brill)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12256331/announcement-journal-religious-minorities-under-muslim-rule</link>
						<dc:creator>Abbas Aghdassi</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Journal</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology, Middle East History / Studies, Islamic History / Studies, Arabic History / Studies, Law and Legal History</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The <i>Journal of Religious Minorities under Muslim Rule</i> provides a primary venue for scholarly studies that examine religious minorities (such as Christians, Jews, Zoroastrians, Hindus, and other minoritarian Muslim groups) under majoritarian Muslim rule. The journal covers a large temporal period, spanning from 7th century Arabia to 1922 (the end of Ottoman rule), in addition to a large geographic area from North Africa and al-Andalus in the West to Iran, some Central Asian lands, well into Pakistan, Bangladesh, Malaysia, and Indonesia in the East. The focus includes minority-minority, minority-majority, and minority-state relations. In addition to its broad temporal and geographic reach, this is an interdisciplinary journal which will appeal to those working in specific disciplines, including history, religious studies, literature, legal studies, and archaeology.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:aghdassi@um.ac.ir">aghdassi@um.ac.ir</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://brill.com/view/journals/rmmr/rmmr-overview.xml" target="_blank">https://brill.com/view/journals/rmmr/rmmr-overview.xml?</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 18:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1674801427653572</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Global Christianities and Global Literatures</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/01/23/global-christianities-and-global-literatures</link>
						<dc:creator>cwallace@stmcollege.ca</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, January 26, 2023 - 12:39pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Christianity and Literature (Journa Special Issuel)</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:cwallace@stmcollege.ca">cwallace@stmcollege.ca</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/postcolonial">postcolonial</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/twentieth-century-and-beyond">twentieth century and beyond</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/world-literatures-and-indigenous-studies">world literatures and indigenous studies</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>March 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Religious practice has arguably declined in Euro-American contexts in late modernity, provoking intense debates about secularization, but Christian movements continue to grow in the Global South, giving rise to new modes of literary production. The cultural, social, and theological aspects of these religious and literary expressions throughout Latin and South America, Africa, and Asia complicate and challenge commonly held notions about the field of Christianity and literature, inviting a widened scope of scholarly engagement. </p>
<p>The journal <em>Christianity and Literature </em>welcomes paper proposals for a special issue on Global Christianities and Global Literatures to be guest edited by Cynthia R. Wallace (St. Thomas More College, University of Saskatchewan). We welcome studies across geographical and national borders, Christian traditions, historical periods, literary genres, and languages. </p>
<p>Possible topics include</p>
<ul>
<li>literature as a site of decolonization and/as religious enculturation</li>
<li>emerging literary devotional forms in a global context</li>
<li>Christian classics in global translation and performance</li>
<li>anthologies as a site of ecumenical communion</li>
<li>literary texts' interplay with postcolonial and other liberation theologies</li>
<li>interreligious, transnational, and cross-cultural encounters in literature and publishing</li>
<li>the literary intersections of race, gender, religion, and history</li>
<li>literatures of the Global South and the (post)secular</li>
<li>new approaches to postcolonial classics</li>
</ul>
<p>We anticipate the following timeline: </p>
<ul>
<li>1 March 2023: abstracts due</li>
<li>15 May 2023: essay drafts due for accepted abstracts</li>
<li>May - June 2023: first round of edits</li>
<li>July 2023: anonymous peer review</li>
<li>Fall or winter 2023: publication of the special issue</li>
</ul>
<p> Please direct any questions, as well as abstract and paper submissions, to Cynthia Wallace (cwallace[at]stmcollege.ca).</p>
<p> </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 16:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1674801427653571</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Theology, Religion, and Dungeons &amp; Dragons</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/01/21/theology-religion-and-dungeons-dragons</link>
						<dc:creator>simonson</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, January 26, 2023 - 10:44am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Fortress Press &amp; Lexington Books, Theology, Religion and Pop Culture Series</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:theology.religion.dnd@gmail.com">theology.religion.dnd@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/fan-studies-and-fandom">fan studies and fandom</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/popular-culture">popular culture</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>February 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p data-adtags-visited="true">Call for Abstracts: <em>Theology, Religion, and Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em></p>
<p data-adtags-visited="true">Edited by Scott Donahue-Martens and Brandon Simonson</p>
<p data-adtags-visited="true">Dungeons &amp; Dragons is a tabletop role-playing game (TTRPG) that was created in 1974 and popularized in the 1970’s and 1980’s, though it has found a renaissance in contemporary popular culture due in part to its prominent role in the Netflix series Stranger Things. The COVID-19 pandemic saw a surge in virtual Dungeons &amp; Dragons (D&amp;D) gaming via work-from-home platforms such as Zoom; from their living rooms, people across the world would work in the virtual office by day and venture into the fantasy worlds of D&amp;D by evening. Additionally, the rising popularity of live-streamers and groups with enormous followings, such as Critical Role, underscores the prominent role that the game continues to hold with tabletop gamers and speaks to the diverse manners in which D&amp;D is enjoyed.</p>
<p data-adtags-visited="true">The fantasy worlds of D&amp;D are replete with religious imagery and rely on the theological imagination. Real-world theological and religious concepts and ideas inform this theological imagination, placing human players in foreign yet familiar settings. Guidebooks provide source material for religious and belief structures, as well as deities and player classes that engage both religion and theology. D&amp;D utilizes theology and religion in its expansive mythos, worldbuilding, and everyday experiences of adventures.</p>
<p data-adtags-visited="true">The editors gladly invite submissions on, but not limited to, the topics below for a volume on the intersections of academic disciplines of theology, religious studies, and the creative world of Dungeons &amp; Dragons (D&amp;D), to be published in the Theology, Religion, and Popular Culture book series. Interested authors should send chapter abstracts of 300-700 words, along with a CV or resume, to <a href="mailto:theology.religion.dnd@gmail.com">theology.religion.dnd@gmail.com</a>.</p>
<p data-adtags-visited="true">Methodologies and Approaches: theological, religious, or other disciplines intersecting with some aspect or concepts from the D&amp;D universe. Topics might include:</p>
<ul>
<li>The relationship between theology and role-play for spiritual formation.</li>
<li>Pastoral theology: D&amp;D and spiritual care.</li>
<li>The three-tiered universe, the sacred canopy, and postmodern epistemology.</li>
<li>Gaming or games as spiritual or religious practice.</li>
<li>The collaborative roles of the Dungeon Master and players, the roles of clergy and laity.</li>
<li>The place of ritual and spellcasting, the place of liturgy and sacrament.</li>
<li>Diverse theological systems, henotheism, polytheism, etc. and D&amp;D pantheons.</li>
<li>Mythology and formation: understanding the structuring role of narrative.</li>
<li>Existentialism, adventuring, and the quest for meaningful living.</li>
</ul>
<p data-adtags-visited="true">Themes: theological and/or religious explorations of major themes related to the D&amp;D universe. Topics might include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Mainstream acceptance, how popular culture contributed to shifting public perceptions of D&amp;D.</li>
<li>Race (now changed to species), class, gender, and other revisions in the D&amp;D universe.</li>
<li>The commodification of hobbies, capitalism and D&amp;D.</li>
<li>Fantasy/Tolkien’s influence on D&amp;D.</li>
<li>Can good people play evil characters?</li>
<li>Theological or religious tolerance and pluralism amid competing complex belief structures.</li>
<li>The lingering impact of past-trauma in characters’ backstories and the enactment of woundedness. The death of an imagined character and loss.</li>
<li>Interaction between human and non-human (“others”). </li>
<li>Non-combative conflict transformation.</li>
<li>Are the dice gods mad at me, determinism and free-will?</li>
<li>Good versus evil, are devils beyond redemption?</li>
<li>Friendship, companionship, and mental health.</li>
<li>Vocation/Calling and teamwork: multiclassing outside of traditional boxes.</li>
</ul>
<p data-adtags-visited="true">Works: Topics might include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Stranger Things and Christian fear of D&amp;D.</li>
<li>An analysis of part of some aspect of a prominent campaign or popular culture portrayal of D&amp;D (like Critical Role, the “C” Team, or Onward).</li>
<li>Media portrayal of D&amp;D, or stereotypes of table-top gamers and bullying, exclusion, or escapism.</li>
<li>An analysis of a major D&amp;D campaign like Tomb of Annihilation, Lost Mine of Phandelver, Storm King’s Thunder, etc.</li>
<li>Engagement with the fantasy books set in the D&amp;D universe like The Legend of Drizzt.</li>
<li>Baldur’s Gate: online RPG in the D&amp;D universe</li>
</ul>
<p data-adtags-visited="true">The call for chapters ends February 15, 2023. Authors will be notified of accepted proposals on March 1st, 2023. Authors will submit their accepted chapters by August 31st, 2023. Final chapters with revisions will be due March 1st, 2024 with an anticipated publication date honoring the upcoming 50thanniversary of D&amp;D.</p>
<p data-adtags-width="494" data-adtags-visited="true">The editors ask that all contributors engage with the existing academic literature on D&amp;D. While the editors will not prescribe particular sources or methodologies, proposals should reflect acquaintance with current scholarship on D&amp;D and final drafts are expected to engage with this scholarship. In other words, we expect each chapter to critically engage D&amp;D along with other scholars.</p>
<p data-adtags-visited="true">Scott Donahue-Martens is a Ph.D. candidate at Boston University School of Theology. He studies the narrative phenomenology of Paul Ricoeur, especially as it relates to homiletics and hermeneutics. He holds a Master of Sacred Theology from Boston University School of Theology and a Master of Divinity from Princeton Theological Seminary.</p>
<p data-adtags-visited="true">Brandon Simonson holds a Ph.D. in Religious Studies from Boston University. Dr. Simonson is currently an Instructor of Biblical Studies at Boston University School of Theology and an adjunct lecturer in the Department of Religious and Theological Studies at Merrimack College. He frequently employs popular culture, music, and literature in his undergraduate Religious Studies pedagogy.</p>
<p data-adtags-visited="true">Donahue-Martens and Simonson co-edited the book <em>Theology, Religion, and Dystopia</em>, which was published in the Theology, Religion, and Pop Culture series by Lexington Books and Fortress Academic in October 2022.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 23:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1674801427653570</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ April 30, 2023] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/107141</link>
						<description>Publication Name: "Doctor Virtualis" no. 19 'Fragments of Order and Disorder in the Middle Ages'<br/><br/><p><strong>Call for paper “Doctor Virtualis” 19</strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Fragments of order and disorder in the Middle Ages</em></strong></p>
<p>«Sosteneva, fra l’altro, che le inopinate catastrofi non sono mai la conseguenza o l’effetto che dir si voglia d’un unico motivo, d’una causa al singolare: ma sono come un vortice, un punto di depressione ciclonica nella coscienza del mondo, verso cui hanno cospirato tutta una molteplicità di causali convergenti. Diceva anche nodo o groviglio, o garbuglio, o gnommero, che alla romana vuol dire gomitolo»</p>
<p>(C.E. Gadda, <em>Quer pasticciaccio brutto de via Merulana</em>)</p>
<p>If, as Paul Valéry says in his <em>Introduction to the Method of Leonardo da Vinci</em>, “thinking is only an effort to pass from disorder to order”, it can then be complicated to move from need to knowledge and to be able to grasp, if indeed there is one, the ordered structure of the world.</p>
<p>Starting from the conviction that the requirement for order is peculiar to man, almost like a cognitive and practical need, this issue intends to reflect on the problem of order in a particular historical moment, the Middle Ages. It is a period in which, unlike the Greek world, eternity, which should present itself almost as a paradigm of order, appears cluttered and intricate. “His eternity registers once and for all (<em>uno intelligendi actu</em>) not only every moment of this replete world but also all that would take place if the most evanescent instant were to change – as well as all that are impossible. His precise and combinatory eternity is much more copious than the universe” (J.L. Borges, <em>History of Eternity</em>, p. 134).</p>
<p>The Middle Ages provide an interesting viewpoint from which to observe the problem of order, beginning with its significant declination in the thought of Augustine of Hippo, where it is closely connected to the concept of “relation” that allows one to think about and articulate the complexity of the world. It is not so much the objects that are of interest, but rather their relationships, not least because the very paradigm of the ordered texture of the world, namely the Trinitarian God, is by essence relationship.</p>
<p>“Doctor Virtualis” 19 therefore intends to collect contributions that reflect on the theme of order and disorder and their relationships, seeking to encourage both investigations into medieval thought, as well as research that intends to emphasise the real or merely possible dialogues that the Middle Ages entertains or may entertain with other historical periods.</p>
<p>We propose to articulate the issue in two general section that nevertheless cannot be conceived as radically distinct.</p>
<p>Firstly, the question of order can refer to the “understanding of the world”, i.e. how the phenomena that appear, the cognitive structures that grasp them and their mutual relationship are conceivable. Observing the entanglement of connections that connect natural, human and divine phenomena, and attempting to intervene in the search for a meaning, a criterion, an order to understand the world, represent a first possible line of investigation. Throughout the Middle Ages, various disciplines were established as attempts to respond to the need to understand the world: from theories of knowledge and language, through physics to eschatology.</p>
<p>Secondly, alongside the attempt to understand the world, there emerges the desire to create and organise new ones, which would rationalise and regulate a sometimes shapeless and evolving matter in order to turn it towards higher aims, such as the good and justice. The order-disorder dialectic is therefore also manifested in the proposals that aspire to confer an order, a legality to human actions and associated life. Ethics, politics and law present themselves not only as models for understanding the world, but also as instruments for the constitution of the self and associated living.</p>
<p>Contributions are therefore welcome that reflect on the theme of complexity, of the nexus between order and disorder in the Middle Ages, trying to fit within (though not exclusively) the following thematic lines:</p>
<p><strong>1. Understanding the world </strong></p>
<p>How did the Middle Ages attempt to respond to the need to understand the complexity of the world? What understanding of complexity and relational entanglement?</p>
<p><strong>a)</strong> Gnoseological theme: disciplines, language, exegesis.</p>
<p><strong>b)</strong> Physical subject matter: metaphysics of the relationship, exegetical symbolism, Platonic and Aristotelian physics; does the Middle Ages question contemporary physics?</p>
<p><strong>c)</strong> Eschatological theme: salvation history and revealed signs in the Scriptures, in the world, in history; relationship between Old and New Testament; relationship between eschatology and forms of life.</p>
<p><strong>2. Creating and regulating worlds</strong></p>
<p>How did the Middle Ages attempt to intervene not only to understand, but also to regulate passions, actions, behaviour? Did theoretical reflection help to create a new ethical, political, legal 'subject'?</p>
<p><strong>a)</strong> Ethical theme: the passions of the soul and their classification, moral order and disorder</p>
<p><strong>b)</strong> Political: order and disorder in the constitution of associated life, political harmony/harmony</p>
<p><strong>c)</strong> Legal theme: plurality of legal norms (<em>ordo iuris and horror discordantium canonum</em>), expressions of the spirit (movements, doctrines, arts) and law, social behaviour and legal norms</p>
<p><strong>Deadlines</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Submission of the article proposal in the form of an abstract (6000/8000 characters) by <strong>30 April 2023</strong>.</li>
<li>Following acceptance of the proposal, articles (35/45 thousand characters) will be due by 15 January 2024 (please follow the journal's editorial rules available on the <a href="https://riviste.unimi.it/index.php/DoctorVirtualis/about/submissions">website</a>).</li>
<li>Expected publication: September 2024.</li>
</ol>
<p>Please send your article proposal to the following addresses:</p>
<p><a href="mailto:massimo.parodi@unimi.it">massimo.parodi@unimi.it</a></p>
<p><a href="mailto:marco.rossini58@gmail.com">marco.rossini58@gmail.com</a>  </p>
<p><a href="mailto:amalia.salvestrini@gmail.com">amalia.salvestrini@gmail.com</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 06:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1674715028020295</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>UPDATED: In the Name of God: A Voice for War, a Call for Peace</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12250349/updated-name-god-voice-war-call-peace</link>
						<dc:creator>Serena Bazemore</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-07-04T00:00:00-04:00">July 4, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>North Carolina</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Human Rights, Humanities, Nationalism History / Studies, Peace History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><b><span><span>In the Name of God: A Voice for War, a Call for Peace <span>– CFP</span></span></span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Date:  July 4-6, 2023</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Location: Duke University, Durham, North Carolina, United States. </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>An interdisciplinary workshop, exploring the role of religion in political and social disputes over war and peace. Workshop is organized by INIRE – the International Network for Interreligious Research and Education: </span></span></span><span><span><span><a href="https://sites.duke.edu/inire/" rel="nofollow"><span>https://sites.duke.edu/inire/</span></a></span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span> </span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Many think of religion as a major cause of global conflicts while others see religion as promoting harmony. </span></span></span></span><span><span>Holy texts provide support for both war and peace. In recent decades especially, religion has been viewed as contributing to global strife. The war between Russia and Ukraine has become also a battle between Ukraine’s claim for spiritual independence and Russia’s vision of salvation for ethnic Russians.  In fragile states, such as Myanmar, the Democratic Republic of Congo and Sri Lanka, religious divisions exacerbate strife. Yet, religion has also played a major role in peace-making and conflict resolution.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Our conference will look at the question of religion and conflict. We are cognizant of the gravity of the moment: Religious voices compete in supporting peace and war. Religion is at the heart of political decision.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The conference is multidisciplinary and interreligious. Among the topics:</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span>Why and how do religious activists deploy belief to harm and heal? </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Why do so many perpetrators think their actions are just and holy?</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>How should religious communities remember their violent past or confront their violent present? </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>What, if anything, separates scholars of religious violence from perpetrators? </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Is secularism the solution to religious violence or part of the problem?</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>How can religious extremism best be met – religious critique or secular argument?</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Is a commitment to religious pluralism a requirement for a peaceful interpretation of religion?</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>How might believers be equipped to respond to religious violence harder?</span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span>Possible panels: </span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span>Texts of violence/peace</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Causes of religious violence/religious rescue or pacification</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Holiness and justice in the minds of perpetrators/pacifiers</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Teaching about religion and violence/peace in the classroom</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Critiquing one’s own tradition/voice of pluralism in religious traditions</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Characteristics of religious peacemakers</span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The list is not exclusive. Additions are welcome.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Send <b>title </b>and<b> </b><b>a short abstract</b> (150 words) by <b>22/2/2023</b> to <b><a href="mailto:julie.maxwell@duke.edu"><span>julie.maxwell@duke.edu</span></a>.</b></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Acceptance letters will be sent out by March 7, 2023.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span> </span></span></span><span><span><i><span><span><span>This conference is being cosponsored by </span></span></span></i><i><span><span>Bar-Ilan University <span>(and especially the Judaism and Society Chair)</span>, Duke University (the Duke Center for Jewish Studies, Duke Islamic Studies Center, Franklin Humanities Institute, Duke Divinity School, and Religions and Public Life at the Kenan Institute for Ethics).</span></span></i></span></span></p><p><span><span> </span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The Organizing Committee</span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><span><b>Serena Bazemore</b></span></p><p><span><b>Executive Director</b></span></p><p><span><b>Duke Center for Jewish Studies</b></span></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:serena.elliott@duke.edu">serena.elliott@duke.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://jewishstudies.duke.edu/conferences/inire-2023-name-god-voice-war-call-peace" target="_blank">https://jewishstudies.duke.edu/conferences/inire-2023-name-god-voice-war-call-peace</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 19:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1674715028020294</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>2023/2024 Call for Applications: GERDA HENKEL Fellowships</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12250002/20232024-call-applications-gerda-henkel-fellowships</link>
						<dc:creator>Dimiter Dimov</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Fellowship</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-31T00:00:00-04:00">March 31, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Bulgaria</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Political Science, Religious Studies and Theology, Russian or Soviet History / Studies, Eastern Europe History / Studies, Modern European History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>CALL FOR APPLICATIONS</p><p>2023/2024 GERDA HENKEL FELLOWSHIPS</p><p><em>With the support of the Gerda Henkel Stiftung</em></p><p>The Centre for Advanced Study Sofia (CAS Sofia) announces a Call for Applications for its GERDA HENKEL Fellowship for fundamental historical research in the field the social sciences and the humanities. The five-months in-residence fellowships are granted under the framework of the CAS Advanced Academia programme and supports PhD holders from the following countries: Afghanistan, Armenia, Azerbaijan, Belarus, China (only Tibet and Xinjiang Autonomous Regions), Georgia, Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Moldova, Mongolia, Russia, Tajikistan, Turkmenistan, Turkey, Ukraine, and Uzbekistan.</p><p><strong>OBJECTIVE</strong></p><p>CAS Sofia is an independent Institute with international and multidisciplinary profile. Located in Sofia, Bulgaria, it promotes high-level scholarship in the social sciences and the humanities. In addition to supporting focus-group research, CAS Sofia invites outstanding scholars to pursue their individual research projects during in-residence periods of up to five months. The invited Fellows participate in the intellectual life and the scholarly community of the Centre (Bulgarian and foreign fellows) while working on projects of their own choice. Fellows receive adequate material and intellectual support and can profit from the Centre’s wide international networks, international seminar- and guest-lecturer programme. CAS Sofia assists Fellows in all practical matters concerning travel, residence and research in Sofia.</p><p><strong>FORMAT OF THE GERDA HENKEL FELLOWSHIPS</strong></p><p>Fellows are entitled to:</p><ul><li>A monthly stipend of 850 Euro (liable to 10% income tax) to cover living expenses related to the stay in Sofia;</li><li>Accommodation in Sofia, comprising living quarters and working space. The Fellows will also have free access to the CAS library and electronic resources/databases;</li><li>Travel from the home country to Sofia and back, visa and insurance costs (up to 800 Euro);</li><li>Research field trip abroad during the fellowship period – up to 1200 Euro (a one-time allowance);</li><li>Research expenses (100 Euro per month).</li></ul><p><strong>DURATION AND CONDITIONS</strong></p><p>Candidates may apply for two periods:</p><ul><li>1 October 2023 – 28 February 2024 (Winter semester)</li><li>1 March 2024 – 31 July 2024 (Summer semester)</li></ul><p>N.B. The final invitation for fellowship depends on the ranking of the application and the preferred period. Availability for both periods is an advantage for the applicant. Please, indicate in the application form whether you prefer one or either period.</p><p>The selected Fellows will take part in the regular Fellow seminars and the other scientific events organized by the Centre (workshops, conferences, lectures, etc.) and are invited to present and discuss their project in lectures or seminars. The results of their work shall be summarized in a paper (in English), to be published in the electronic CAS Working Paper Series.</p><p><strong>ELIGIBILITY</strong></p><p>Candidates must:</p><ul><li>Be citizens of one of the following countries: Afghanistan, Armenia, Azerbaijan, Belarus, China (only Tibet and Xinjiang Autonomous Regions), Georgia, Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Moldova, Mongolia, Russia, Tajikistan, Turkmenistan, Turkey, Ukraine, and Uzbekistan;</li><li>Have completed a PhD in the fields of the humanities and social sciences;</li><li>Have international research experience (participation in projects and refereed conferences) and publications in peer-reviewed academic editions are strong advantages;</li><li>Preference will be given to candidates below the age of 45.</li></ul><p><strong>WORKING LANGUAGE</strong></p><p>As an international academic institution CAS conducts most of its work in English which is also the language of the presentations of research results. Therefore, a good command of English is highly desirable.</p><p><strong>APPLICATION</strong></p><p>Links for downloading:</p><ul><li><a href="https://cas.bg/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Intl_Application_Form_CAS_Gerda-Henkel_2023_2024.doc" rel="nofollow">Application Form</a></li><li><a href="https://cas.bg/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CAS-Proposal-Guide.doc" rel="nofollow">Proposal Guide</a></li><li><a href="https://cas.bg/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Intl_Reference_Form_CAS_Fellowships_2023-2024.doc" rel="nofollow">Reference Form</a></li><li><a href="https://cas.bg/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Intl_Checklist_CAS_Gerda-Henkel_2023_2024.doc" rel="nofollow">Checklist</a></li></ul><p>Please carefully consider these documents when preparing your application. They can be downloaded also from <a href="http://www.cas.bg/" rel="nofollow">www.cas.bg</a>. Two letters of recommendation by scholars familiar with the applicant’s academic work should be emailed to CAS by the referees. Extensions to this period may be allowed in case of eligible career breaks which must be properly documented (maternity leave, long-term illness leave, national service).</p><p>All application documents should be presented in English and sent by e-mail to <a href="mailto:dimov@cas.bg">dimov@cas.bg</a> with a subject entry “Gerda Henkel Fellowships”.</p><p>Deadline for applications: <strong><u>March 31, 2023</u></strong></p><p><strong>SELECTION CRITERIA</strong></p><ul><li>High quality of the candidate’s academic portfolio and publications, participation in international research;</li><li>Innovative fundamental research proposal with significant contribution;</li><li>Interdisciplinary and/or comparative approaches are an advantage.</li></ul><p><strong>SELECTION PROCEDURE</strong></p><p>The selection will be carried out by the international Academic Council of CAS based on evaluation of the potential of the candidate relative to his/her career stage and the quality of the proposed project. The short-listed candidates will be invited for an on-line interview in the second half of June 2023. The results will be announced in July 2023 by e-mail and at the website of the institute: <a href="https://cas.bg/" rel="nofollow">https://cas.bg/</a>. Members of the CAS Academic Council do not disclose their assessment reports on the applications to candidates.</p><p>The Academic Council reserves the right, in cases of candidatures with equal quality, to grant advantage to candidates that have not been CAS Fellows within the preceding 3 years / have not repeatedly held CAS fellowships in the past.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dimiter Dimov</p><p>Project Coordinator</p><p>Centre for Advanced Study Sofia</p><p>7 Stefan Karadzha Str., entr. 3, apt. 23, Sofia 1000, Bulgaria</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:dimov@cas.bg">dimov@cas.bg</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://cas.bg/" target="_blank">https://cas.bg</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 19:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1674715028020293</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP: Theology, Religion, and Dungeons &amp; Dragons (Fortress Academic and Lexington Books)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12232770/cfp-theology-religion-and-dungeons-dragons-fortress-academic</link>
						<dc:creator>Brandon Simonson</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-01-01T00:00:00-05:00">January 1, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-15T00:00:00-05:00">February 15, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Cultural History / Studies, Humanities, Philosophy, Popular Culture Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Call for Abstracts: <em>Theology, Religion, and Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em></p><p>Edited by Scott Donahue-Martens and Brandon Simonson</p><p>Dungeons &amp; Dragons is a tabletop role-playing game (TTRPG) that was created in 1974 and popularized in the 1970’s and 1980’s, though it has found a renaissance in contemporary popular culture due in part to its prominent role in the Netflix series Stranger Things. The COVID-19 pandemic saw a surge in virtual Dungeons &amp; Dragons (D&amp;D) gaming via work-from-home platforms such as Zoom; from their living rooms, people across the world would work in the virtual office by day and venture into the fantasy worlds of D&amp;D by evening. Additionally, the rising popularity of live-streamers and groups with enormous followings, such as Critical Role, underscores the prominent role that the game continues to hold with tabletop gamers and speaks to the diverse manners in which D&amp;D is enjoyed.</p><p>The fantasy worlds of D&amp;D are replete with religious imagery and rely on the theological imagination. Real-world theological and religious concepts and ideas inform this theological imagination, placing human players in foreign yet familiar settings. Guidebooks provide source material for religious and belief structures, as well as deities and player classes that engage both religion and theology. D&amp;D utilizes theology and religion in its expansive mythos, worldbuilding, and everyday experiences of adventures.</p><p>The editors gladly invite submissions on, but not limited to, the topics below for a volume on the intersections of academic disciplines of theology, religious studies, and the creative world of Dungeons &amp; Dragons (D&amp;D), to be published in the Theology, Religion, and Popular Culture book series. Interested authors should send chapter abstracts of 300-700 words, along with a CV or resume, to <a href="mailto:theology.religion.dnd@gmail.com">theology.religion.dnd@gmail.com</a>.</p><p>Methodologies and Approaches: theological, religious, or other disciplines intersecting with some aspect or concepts from the D&amp;D universe. Topics might include:</p><ul><li>The relationship between theology and role-play for spiritual formation.</li><li>Pastoral theology: D&amp;D and spiritual care.</li><li>The three-tiered universe, the sacred canopy, and postmodern epistemology.</li><li>Gaming or games as spiritual or religious practice.</li><li>The collaborative roles of the Dungeon Master and players, the roles of clergy and laity.</li><li>The place of ritual and spellcasting, the place of liturgy and sacrament.</li><li>Diverse theological systems, henotheism, polytheism, etc. and D&amp;D pantheons.</li><li>Mythology and formation: understanding the structuring role of narrative.</li><li>Existentialism, adventuring, and the quest for meaningful living.</li></ul><p>Themes: theological and/or religious explorations of major themes related to the D&amp;D universe. Topics might include:</p><ul><li>Mainstream acceptance, how popular culture contributed to shifting public perceptions of D&amp;D.</li><li>Race (now changed to species), class, gender, and other revisions in the D&amp;D universe.</li><li>The commodification of hobbies, capitalism and D&amp;D.</li><li>Fantasy/Tolkien’s influence on D&amp;D.</li><li>Can good people play evil characters?</li><li>Theological or religious tolerance and pluralism amid competing complex belief structures.</li><li>The lingering impact of past-trauma in characters’ backstories and the enactment of woundedness. The death of an imagined character and loss.</li><li>Interaction between human and non-human (“others”). </li><li>Non-combative conflict transformation.</li><li>Are the dice gods mad at me, determinism and free-will?</li><li>Good versus evil, are devils beyond redemption?</li><li>Friendship, companionship, and mental health.</li><li>Vocation/Calling and teamwork: multiclassing outside of traditional boxes.</li></ul><p>Works: Topics might include:</p><ul><li><em>Stranger Things </em>and Christian fear of D&amp;D.</li><li>An analysis of part of some aspect of a prominent campaign or popular culture portrayal of D&amp;D (like Critical Role, the “C” Team, or <em>Onward</em>).</li><li>Media portrayal of D&amp;D, or stereotypes of table-top gamers and bullying, exclusion, or escapism.</li><li>An analysis of a major D&amp;D campaign like<em> Tomb of Annihilation</em>, <em>Lost Mine of Phandelver, Storm King’s Thunder</em>, etc.</li><li>Engagement with the fantasy books set in the D&amp;D universe like <em>The Legend of Drizzt</em>.</li><li>Baldur’s Gate: online RPG in the D&amp;D universe</li></ul><p>The call for chapters ends February 15, 2023. Authors will be notified of accepted proposals on March 1<sup>st</sup>, 2023. Authors will submit their accepted chapters by August 31<sup>st</sup>, 2023. Final chapters with revisions will be due March 1<sup>st</sup>, 2024 with an anticipated publication date honoring the upcoming 50<sup>th</sup>anniversary of D&amp;D.</p><p>The editors ask that all contributors engage with the existing academic literature on D&amp;D. While the editors will not prescribe particular sources or methodologies, proposals should reflect acquaintance with current scholarship on D&amp;D and final drafts are expected to engage with this scholarship. In other words, we expect each chapter to critically engage D&amp;D along with other scholars.</p><p>Scott Donahue-Martens is a Ph.D. candidate at Boston University School of Theology. He studies the narrative phenomenology of Paul Ricoeur, especially as it relates to homiletics and hermeneutics. He holds a Master of Sacred Theology from Boston University School of Theology and a Master of Divinity from Princeton Theological Seminary.</p><p>Brandon Simonson holds a Ph.D. in Religious Studies from Boston University. Dr. Simonson is currently an Instructor of Biblical Studies at Boston University School of Theology and an adjunct lecturer in the Department of Religious and Theological Studies at Merrimack College. He frequently employs popular culture, music, and literature in his undergraduate Religious Studies pedagogy.</p><p>Donahue-Martens and Simonson co-edited the book <em>Theology, Religion, and Dystopia</em>, which was published in the Theology, Religion, and Pop Culture series by Lexington Books and Fortress Academic in October 2022.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Scott Donahue-Martens and Brandon Simonson, Editors</p><p><a href="mailto:theology.religion.dnd@gmail.com">theology.religion.dnd@gmail.com</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:theology.religion.dnd@gmail.com">theology.religion.dnd@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://popularcultureandtheology.com/2022/12/28/call-for-papers-theology-religion-and-dungeons-dragons/" target="_blank">https://popularcultureandtheology.com/2022/12/28/call-for-papers-theology-religion-and-dungeons-dragons/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 18:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1674715028020292</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – January 25, 2023</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-january-25-2023/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find 4 jobs, 5 fellowships, 1 grants and awards, 9 Call For Papers, and a submission for new SBL Program Units.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 32!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Assistant Professor in Religious Studies and Cultural Heritage</h4>



<p>University of Amsterdam, NL</p>



<p>Deadline: March 12, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/UD-in-Religious-Studies-and-Cultural-Heritage/763429402/">https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/UD-in-Religious-Studies-and-Cultural-Heritage/763429402/</a></p>



<h4>Lecturer in History of Christianity (4-year renewable contract)</h4>



<p>Pacific Theological College, Fiji</p>



<p>Deadline: February 16, 2023</p>



<h4>Duke University Press Journals Associate Director</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.dukeupress.edu/About/Job-Opportunities/Job-Postings/Associate-Journals-Director">https://www.dukeupress.edu/About/Job-Opportunities/Job-Postings/Associate-Journals-Director</a></p>



<h4>AAR/SBL Job Forum</h4>



<p><a href="https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search">https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search</a></p>



<h2>Fellowships:</h2>



<h4>Leverhulme Early Career Fellowships</h4>



<p>University of Exeter, UK</p>



<p>Deadline: February 23, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.exeter.ac.uk/research/ourfaculties/hass/hassfunding/">https://www.exeter.ac.uk/research/ourfaculties/hass/hassfunding/</a></p>



<h4>Scripture and Secularism: Mapping the Impact of the Bible on the Conceptualizations of Europe</h4>



<p>Lund University, SE</p>



<p>Deadline: February 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://lu.varbi.com/en/what:job/jobID:582299/type:job/where:4/apply:1?mibextid=Zxz2cZ&amp;fbclid=IwAR0cRUZ_a_CNK4pagClg8imc4U9IYBBWsZITNNQcuS83zPmGRg2m4vN_aXc">https://lu.varbi.com/en/what:job/jobID:582299/type:job/where:4/apply:1?mibextid=Zxz2cZ&amp;fbclid=IwAR0cRUZ_a_CNK4pagClg8imc4U9IYBBWsZITNNQcuS83zPmGRg2m4vN_aXc</a></p>



<h4>Ph.D. Fellowship in Islamic Studies (2 available)</h4>



<p>Lund University, SE</p>



<p>Deadline: February 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12207806/2-phd-studentships-islamic-studies-lund-university-sweden">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12207806/2-phd-studentships-islamic-studies-lund-university-sweden</a></p>



<h4>Scholar in Practice Postdoctoral Fellowship (2 years, intended for those looking to pursue a career outside academia)</h4>



<p>Boston University, US</p>



<p>Deadline: February 28, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.bu.edu/antiracism-center/career-opportunities/scholar-in-practice/">https://www.bu.edu/antiracism-center/career-opportunities/scholar-in-practice/</a></p>



<h4>Ph.D. Fellowship in Digital Religion and/or Didactics of Religion (3 years, research only)</h4>



<p>University of Stavanger, NO</p>



<p>Deadline: NA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.jobbnorge.no/en/available-jobs/job/236309/phd-fellowship-in-digital-religion-and-or-didactics-of-religion">https://www.jobbnorge.no/en/available-jobs/job/236309/phd-fellowship-in-digital-religion-and-or-didactics-of-religion</a></p>



<h2>Grants:</h2>



<h4>Supporting Diverse Voices: Book Proposal Development Grants</h4>



<p>Deadline: February 22, 2023, 12:00 pm EDT</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://press.princeton.edu/book-proposal-development-grants">https://press.princeton.edu/book-proposal-development-grants</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>Food and Religion: People, Land, Ritual, Ecology, Spirituality</h4>



<p>February 26, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/01/18/food-and-religion-people-land-ritual-ecology-spirituality">https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/01/18/food-and-religion-people-land-ritual-ecology-spirituality</a></p>



<h4>Christianity and Racemaking in the Early Modern Atlantic World</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 14<sup>th</sup>, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/2aBgJ8qD4A">https://t.co/2aBgJ8qD4A</a></p>



<h4>Translations, Transgressions, and Transformations: The Global Movement of Objects in Catholic Cultures</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12221553/translations-transgressions-and-transformations-global">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12221553/translations-transgressions-and-transformations-global</a></p>



<h4>Representations of Islam in Germanophone Literature: Cultural Perspectives from the Enlightenment to the Present</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information:  <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12211895/call-papers-si-representations-islam-germanophone-literature">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12211895/call-papers-si-representations-islam-germanophone-literature</a></p>



<h4>Global and Transnational Perspectives on Islamophobia</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.intersectingflows.com/events/call-for-papers-global-and-transnational-perspectives-on-islamophobia">https://www.intersectingflows.com/events/call-for-papers-global-and-transnational-perspectives-on-islamophobia</a></p>



<h4>Metaphor &amp; Misinformation: Religion in Media-Driven Worlds (International Society for Media, Religion, and Culture)</h4>



<p>Deadline: January 28, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.ismrc.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Call-for-Papers-ISMRC-2023-FINAL.pdf">https://www.ismrc.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Call-for-Papers-ISMRC-2023-FINAL.pdf</a></p>



<h4>Religion and Technology</h4>



<p>Deadline: January 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.easr2023.org/call-for-papers/">https://www.easr2023.org/call-for-papers/</a></p>



<h4>“Ecological Conversion” of Christian Communities: Green Technologies and Sustainable Practices</h4>



<p>Deadline: January 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12209391/conference-panel-ecological-conversion-christian-communities">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12209391/conference-panel-ecological-conversion-christian-communities</a></p>



<h4>Psychology and Epistemology of Religious Experiences</h4>



<p>Deadline: February 28, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/106913">https://philevents.org/event/show/106913</a></p>



<h2>Miscellaneous:</h2>



<h4>SBL New Program Unit Application</h4>



<p>Deadline: February 10, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://societyofbiblicalliterature.formstack.com/forms/amnewunit">https://societyofbiblicalliterature.formstack.com/forms/amnewunit</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1674715028020291</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>TRD&amp;D 2023 : CFP: Theology, Religion, and Dungeons &amp; Dragons (Fortress Academic and Lexington Books)</title>
			<link>http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=171332&amp;copyownerid=179289</link>
						<description>CFP: Theology, Religion, and Dungeons &amp; Dragons (Fortress Academic and Lexington Books) [Feb 15, 2023 - Feb 15, 2023]</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 06:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1674628628045639</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religion and Spirituality in Everyday Li 2023 : Call For Papers - Religion and Spirituality in Everyday Life</title>
			<link>http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=171418&amp;copyownerid=173363</link>
						<description>Call For Papers - Religion and Spirituality in Everyday Life [Online] [Jun 1, 2023 - Jun 1, 2023]</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 06:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1674628628045638</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>ICSAH 2023 : Women in religion: from spiritual leadership to female empowerment</title>
			<link>http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=171400&amp;copyownerid=108478</link>
						<description>Women in religion: from spiritual leadership to female empowerment [Milan, Italy] [May 8, 2023 - May 9, 2023]</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 06:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1674628628045637</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
