<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 12:22:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 12:22:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>The Political Theology and the State of  2023 : REMINDER: Call For Papers - The Political Theology and the State of Exception: Critical readings on the centenary of Political Theology &amp; Roman Catholicism and</title>
			<link>http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=171267&amp;copyownerid=173363</link>
						<description>REMINDER: Call For Papers - The Political Theology and the State of Exception: Critical readings on the centenary of Political Theology &amp; Roman Catholicism and</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 06:37:10 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1674023830863166</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Liberal Education in the Era of Migration, Refugee Crises, and Decolonization</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/01/13/liberal-education-in-the-era-of-migration-refugee-crises-and-decolonization</link>
						<dc:creator>kdharamsi@mtroyal.ca</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, January 17, 2023 - 10:01pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>University of Lethbridge, Medicine Hat College, Mount Royal University</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:libed2023@gmail.com">libed2023@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/pedagogy">pedagogy</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/postcolonial">postcolonial</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/world-literatures-and-indigenous-studies">world literatures and indigenous studies</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>February 20, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>The present realities of decolonization, immigration, and refugee migration require critical enquiries into the provision of liberal studies in higher education. The aims and methods of liberal education as a pedagogical exercise and a cultural practice need to be examined within the dynamic intellectual, social, economic, and political contexts created by today’s unprecedented movement of peoples and intersections of cultures. Variously seen as forced migration, exile, dislocation, statelessness and even environmentally induced displacement, the Global refugee crises present multilocational and multilayered challenges. This conference aims to create a focused debate around not only the phenomenon of refugee migration but also seeks to understand the crises as within a continuum of other constructions of the refugee as the non-Western Other. This construction leads to the near necessity of speaking of decolonization as an imperative located possibly within liberal education and its practices. The intertwining of the refugee experience with Indigenous communities’ lived experience calls for thoughtful intervention. Can liberal education aid in the process of decolonization? Is it a singular process, or are there multiple ways in which decolonization can occur? What does decolonization look like?</p>
<p>The aims of liberal education are variously articulated as an instrument for the teaching of transferable practical skills, the making and enabling of responsible citizens, or the cultivation of virtue, self- knowledge, and broad, general wisdom. These aims and the means of achieving them all need to be reassessed as our wider society is transformed by both by the infusion of new peoples and the increased engagement of Indigenous communities.</p>
<p>The Department of General Education at Mount Royal University in Calgary, Alberta, Canada, and its partner, Medicine Hat College, in Medicine Hat Alberta, Canada and U of Lethbridge invite papers and panel presentations      for our fifth Liberal Education Conference on the theme of <em>Liberal Education in an Era of Migration, Refugee Crises, and Decolonization. </em>Broad topic areas related to this may include, but are not excluded to:</p>
<ul>
<li>the challenges to the historical grounding of liberal education in a time of increased cultural heterogeneity</li>
<li>the place of liberal education in the construction of a common meeting place in society embracing diverse, distinct cultures</li>
<li>the experience of arrival and purposes of liberal education for refugee or recent immigrant</li>
<li>the possibility of a coherent program of liberal education in the absence of a common culture</li>
<li>liberal education as a progressive instrument in the face of hostility to migration, decolonization and cultural diversity</li>
<li>the aims of liberal education in a multi-cultural society</li>
<li>the idea of openness and Liberal Education</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<ul>
<li>Intersectionality of the refugees and the indigenous communities</li>
<li>International refugee law and the overlap with liberal education</li>
<li>the curriculum of liberal education: which are the great books; or is liberal education dependent on canonical texts, whatever they may be</li>
<li>Decolonization and canonization</li>
<li>pedagogical practice in the presence of cultural diversity — the problems “language proficiency,” cultural capital, and behavioral norms in the classroom</li>
<li>contending cultural norms and the possibility of a general, liberal education</li>
<li>should liberal education be an instrument of social and cultural integration?</li>
<li>trauma, memory and identity formation and how liberal education might address the issues</li>
<li>liberal education and the building of intercultural solidarity</li>
<li>immigration and the infusion; inspiration; and transformation of liberal education</li>
</ul>
<p>We seek abstracts for high quality papers on the conference’s theme, some of the topics we have suggested, or any matters related to ‘liberal education in an era of refugee migration and decolonization’. Please prepare your abstract of no longer than 300 words for blind-review by February 20, 2023. Send your abstracts, suitable for blind-review, to <a href="mailto:libed2023@gmail.com">libed2023@gmail.com</a>. Decisions will be announced by February 28, 2023. Please include a separate cover page with</p>
<ul>
<li>the title of your paper or panel</li>
<li>Name of presenter(s) or panelists</li>
<li>Institutional Affiliation (if any)</li>
<li>Contact details</li>
</ul>
<p>Please send documents in PDF or Word format.</p>
<p>Registration is $350.00. Graduate and undergraduate students can attend the entire conference for $100.00. All funds are Canadian. Registration, conference venue, and an    announcement of keynotes are forthcoming. Our intention is to publish a selection of papers from this conference as we have in the past.</p>
<p>Affordable accommodations will likely be available near the campus of Mount Royal University in Calgary, Alberta, Canada. More information is forthcoming.</p>
<p>This conference is sponsored by the generous support of Medicine Hat College, U of Lethbridge and Mount Royal  University. </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 20:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1674023830863165</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ June 1, 2023 -  June 2, 2023] Conference or similar: Critical phenomenology of the we</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/106817</link>
						<description>Venue: 23.0.49<br/><br/><p>Classical phenomenology offers not only incisive analyses of intentionality, experience, selfhood, empathy and interpersonal understanding, but also quite sophisticated investigations of collective intentionality, affective sharing, social participation, communal experience, and group-identity. Indeed, while starting out with an interest in the individual mind, phenomenologists began exploring dyadic forms of interpersonal relations shortly before the start of World War I, and were deeply engaged in extensive analyses of communal forms of intentionality during the interwar period – at a time when nationalism was on the rise.</p>
<p>Today, the "We" has not lost its place in philosophical, political, or popular discourse. Within the last decade especially, we have witnessed renewed interest in the early phenomenological reflections on group formations, communal experiences, empathy, and fellow-feeling. Does this renewed interest suggest a need to revise our understandings of the "We", or does it attest to its enduring philosophical, social, and political significance/relevance? How have, for instance, perspectives from critical theory and feminist philosophy provided insights into the importance and limitations of questions of belonging, We-experiences, and We-identities? The aim of the current conference is to investigate how this recent critical turn in phenomenology might support, challenge, extend or qualify the classical phenomenological analyses.</p>
<p>Speakers include Alia Al-Saji, Linda Alcoff, Robert Bernasconi, Lisa Guenther, Sara Heinämaa, Steffen Hermann, Sophie Loidolt, Johanna Oksala, Michael Staudigl and Dan Zahavi.</p>
<p>More info to follow.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 06:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673937432071494</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ February 13, 2023] Conference talk or similar: Hegel's Philosophy of Bildung</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/106813</link>
						<description>Venue: Online<br/><br/>Speakers at this event: <br/>Marina F. Bykova (North Carolina State University)<br/>Timothy L. Brownlee (Xavier University)<br/><br/><p><strong>[ONLINE COLLOQUIUM] Marina F. Bykova (North Carolina State) @ The Athens Colloquium on Kant and German Idealism</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>The Athens Colloquium on Kant and German Idealism</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Department of Philosophy, University of Athens</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Monday <strong>13 February</strong> <strong>2023</strong>, 18:00 p.m. (Athens, Greece time)</p>
<p><strong>Marina F. Bykova (North Carolina State)</strong><strong></strong></p>
<p><em>Hegel’s Philosophy of Bildung</em><em></em></p>
<p>Respondent: Timothy Brownlee (Xavier)</p>
<p>***To receive the paper to be discussed please contact Dr. Stavros Panagiotou at <strong>panayiot@philosophy.uoa.gr</strong> ***</p>
<p><strong>Organizers</strong>: Ioannis Trisokkas, Sebastian Stein, Stavros Panagiotou</p>
<p><strong>Webpage</strong>: https://sites.google.com/view/theathenscolloquium/home</p>
<p>For any enquiries please contact Dr. Stavros Panagiotou (<strong>panayiot@philosophy.uoa.gr</strong>).</p>
<p>WEBEX LINK</p>
<p>https://uoa.webex.com/uoa/j.php?MTID=md29419c32338d3a0f84d5a952d47d5ff</p>
<p>Monday, Feb 13, 2023 5:40 pm | 3 hours | (UTC+02:00) Athens, Bucharest</p>
<p>Meeting number: 2734 981 7953</p>
<p>Password: A5TajJSRp33</p>
<p>Join by video system</p>
<p>Dial 27349817953@uoa.webex.com</p>
<p>You can also dial 62.109.219.4 and enter your meeting number.</p>
<p>Join by phone</p>
<p>+30-21-1990-2394 Greece Toll</p>
<p>+30-21-1198-1029 Greece Toll 2</p>
<p>Access code: 273 498 17953</p>
<p><strong><u>MARINA F. BYKOVA</u></strong></p>
<p>Marina F. Bykova is Professor of Philosophy at North Carolina State University and the Editor-in-chief of two philosophical journals: <em>Studies in East European Thought</em> (Springer) and <em>Russian Studies in Philosophy</em> (Routledge). Her main area of specialization is the history of the nineteenth century continental philosophy, with a focus on German idealism, especially on Fichte and Hegel. Her most recent books include <em>The German Idealism Reader: Ideas, Responses and Legacies</em> (Bloomsbury, 2019), <em>Hegel’s Philosophy of Spirit: A Critical Guide</em> (ed., Cambridge UP, 2019), <em>The Bloomsbury Handbook of Fichte</em> (ed., Bloomsbury, 2020), and <em>The Palgrave Hegel Handbook</em> (co-ed. with K. Westphal; Palgrave Macmillan, 2020). She has also published books on Russian intellectual tradition, including <em>Philosophical Thought in Russia in the Second Half of the 20th Century: A Contemporary Views from Russia and Abroad</em> (co-ed. with V.A. Lektorsky; Bloomsbury, 2019) and <em>The Palgrave Handbook of Russian Thought</em> (co-ed. with M. Forster and L. Steiner; Palgrave MacMillan, 2021). Her new book, <em>Hegel’s Philosophy of Nature: A Critical Guide</em> is forthcoming from Cambridge University Press in 2023.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 06:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673937432071493</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Third International Conference on Bartolomé de Las Casas</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12191415/third-international-conference-bartolom%C3%A9-de-las-casas</link>
						<dc:creator>Andrew Wilson</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-01T00:00:00-05:00">February 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Atlantic History / Studies, Colonial and Post-Colonial History / Studies, Early Modern History and Period Studies, Latin American and Caribbean History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>All scholars critically engaging with the complex life, diverse work, and mixed legacy of Bartolomé de Las Casas are invited to submit proposals for the <em>Third International Conference on Bartolomé de Las Casas</em>, to be held at <strong>Providence College</strong> from <strong>June 21–24, 2023</strong>. Confirmed speakers <strong>Mariano Delgado</strong> and <strong>Paola Uparela</strong> will present new research seeking to understand Las Casas as a transatlantic “reformer.”</p><p>Charles Taylor’s provocative study, <em>A Secular Age</em>, identifies Reform as a broad conviction “felt with increasing power during the Middle Ages and early modern period, that not just an élite, but as far as possible all the faithful live up to the demands of the Gospel” (104). In line with this theme, organizers welcome proposals that put Las Casas in conversation with broader trends in sixteenth-century European expansionism, reformations, Christian humanism, secularization, theology, print culture, and law. Engagements stemming from post-colonial theory, literary studies, philosophy, anthropology, and other critical disciplines are also welcome.</p><p>Importantly, this conference calls attention to Las Casas’s entrance into a self-consciously reforming Dominican Order, itself an expression of trends in the renewal of religious life. Participants will benefit from and contribute to the rich combination of unique research interests afforded by this interdisciplinary invitation to consider Las Casas as a reformer in his own right. <strong>Proposals</strong> (in English, French, Portuguese, or Spanish) of <strong>250 to 500 words</strong> in length and a <strong>short bio of 250 words</strong> are due by <strong>February 1, 2023</strong>: sent to <a href="mailto:submissions@lascasianstudies.org?subject=Conference%202023">submissions@lascasianstudies.org with “Conference 2023” as the subject</a>. The conference will be held in Spanish and English.</p><p>Accepted proposals will be invited to submit a written version of their presentations for consideration to be included in a projected <a href="https://brill.com/view/title/38269" rel="nofollow">third double-blind peer-reviewed collection</a>. For up to date information, visit<a href="https://mission-ministry.providence.edu/las-casas-studies-at-providence-college/" rel="nofollow"> Lascasian Studies at Providence College</a>.</p><p>The Third International Conference of Lascasian Studies will also provide the occasion for the official launching of the Society for Lascasian Studies and its Bulletin for Lascasian Studies. <strong>The conference will take place on the campus of Providence College in the picturesque city of Providence, Rhode Island. Limited opportunities for remote online presentations may be provided.</strong></p><p>Confirmed Keynote Speakers:<br/><a href="https://www.unifr.ch/theo/de/fak/pers/professoren/people/4379/544d5" rel="nofollow">Mariano Delgado</a>, Professor of Church and Mission History, University of Freiburg, Switzerland<br/><a href="https://people.clas.ufl.edu/paolauparela/" rel="nofollow">Paola Uparela</a>, Assistant Professor Spanish &amp; Portuguese Studies, University of Florida</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Fr. David T. Orique, O.P., Ph.D. Professor, Director of Latin American and Latina/o Studies (LALS), Department of History, Providence College, 549 River Avenue, Providence, RI 02918</p><p>Rady Roldán-Figueroa, Th.D., Associate Professor of the History of Christianity; Director, Center for Latin American Studies, Frederick S. Pardee School of Global Studies, Boston University, 745 Commonwealth Ave, Boston, MA, 02215</p><p>Andrew Wilson, Ph.D., Associate Professor of Church History, Japan Lutheran College and Seminary, 3-10-20 Osawa, Mitaka, Tokyo, 181-0015, Japan</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:submissions@lascasianstudies.org">submissions@lascasianstudies.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://mission-ministry.providence.edu/2023-las-casas-conference/" target="_blank">https://mission-ministry.providence.edu/2023-las-casas-conference/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 19:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673678231669458</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFA/CFP: Simone Weil (1909-1943): Receptions and Actuality</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12190974/cfacfp-simone-weil-1909-1943-receptions-and-actuality</link>
						<dc:creator>Yvanka Raynova</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-15T00:00:00-05:00">February 15, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-07-30T00:00:00-04:00">July 30, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Austria</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Humanities, Philosophy, Religious Studies and Theology, Intellectual History, Jewish History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><b>Simone Weil (1909-1943): Receptions and Actuality</b></p><p><span><span><span><i><span><span><a href="https://www.axiapublishers.com/ojs/index.php/labyrinth/index" rel="nofollow"><span>Labyrinth: An International Journal for Philosophy, Value Theory and Sociocultural Hermeneutics</span></a></span></span></i><span><span> is preparing a special issue on the the occasion of the 80th death anniversary of Simone Weil (1909-1943). Of special interest are new readings and discussions dealing with the main topics of Weil's Philosophy as for example:</span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span>The sources of Simone Weil's philosophical and religious thought</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Natural and supernatural </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Origin and diversity of the religions</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Materialism, religious experience and mystical thought </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Ethics and aesthetics: the good and the beautiful</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Happiness, suffering, and unhappiness</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Love, truth, and justice</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Freedom, obedience, oppression</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Violence and non-violence, war and peace</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>The worker‘s condition and capitalism critique</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Ecological issues</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Receptions and influences of Simone Weil's thought </span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span><span>Researchers working in the field of Simone Weil's philosophical and religious thought are invited to submit a brief abstract until the 15 of February 2023 with a brief biograhic information including name, academic affiliation, and main publications.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Authors who have already a finished unpublished paper are welcome to submit it within the abstract in order to help the peer review and the publishing process. Papers in their final form, i.e. proof read, formatted according to the journal guidelines, and print ready, should be submitted no later than the 30 of July 2023. </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>As a multilingual Journal <i>Labyrinth</i> accepts papers in English, French, and German. For more information about the journal policies and the submission's guidelines please visit: <a href="https://www.axiapublishers.com/ojs/index.php/labyrinth/AuthorGuidelines" rel="nofollow"><span>https://www.axiapublishers.com/ojs/index.php/labyrinth/AuthorGuidelines</span></a></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>All abstracts and papers should be sent to labyrinth [at] axiapublishers.com</span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><span><span><span><i><span><span><a href="https://www.axiapublishers.com/ojs/index.php/labyrinth/index" rel="nofollow"><span>Labyrinth: An International Journal for Philosophy, Value Theory and Sociocultural Hermeneutics</span></a></span></span></i></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:labyrinth@axiapublishers.com">labyrinth@axiapublishers.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.axiapublishers.com/ojs/index.php/labyrinth/announcement/view/12" target="_blank">https://www.axiapublishers.com/ojs/index.php/labyrinth/announcement/view/12</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 18:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673678231669457</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Applications: Center for Jewish History-Fordham University Research Fellowship</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12190746/call-applications-center-jewish-history-fordham-university</link>
						<dc:creator>Julie Kaplan</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Fellowship</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-01T00:00:00-05:00">March 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>New York</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, European History / Studies, Holocaust, Genocide, and Memory Studies, American History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Fordham University's Center for Jewish Studies and the Center for Jewish History offer a joint short-term research fellowship in Jewish Studies for scholars outside the New York City metropolitan area whose research engages Jewish studies in conversation with other fields and who wish to conduct research based on materials housed at the Center for Jewish History and Fordham University. The goal of the fellowship to engage Jewish studies in conversation with other fields and encourage scholars whose primary research lies in Jewish studies to engage with fields outside their field and scholars whose primary expertise lies in other fields to explore sources and methodologies in Jewish studies.  </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The fellow is expected to spend at least a month at the two host institutions but may stay as long as five months. The fellow's stay must coincide with either the fall or spring Fordham University academic semesters. The stipend for this fellowship is $5,000.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The fellow will receive affiliation with Fordham University, and will be required to offer a faculty seminar, and a public lecture, which would be a joint event of Fordham and CJH with alternate venues. The fellow is also expected to participate in scholarly seminars and other meetings at the Center for Jewish History and Fordham University.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The CJH-Fordham Research Fellowship is made possible by funds from the Center for Jewish History, the Eugene Shvidler Gift Fund at Fordham University, and additional gift funds to Jewish Studies at Fordham University.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>This fellowship is open to both established scholars and graduate students.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><u><span><span><span>Applications should include:</span></span></span></u></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Cover letter stating area of interest, knowledge of relevant languages, and how the project relates to the general mission of the Center for Jewish History</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Curriculum Vitae, including contact information, education, publications, scholarly and/or museum activities, teaching experience, and any other relevant work experience</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Research proposal of no more than four pages double-spaced, including specific reference to the collections at the Center and Fordham University and clearly stated goals for research during the period of the fellowship</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>A one-page bibliography of important secondary sources for the project</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>One letter of recommendation, to be sent separately, directly by the recommender – preferably by email to </span></span><a href="mailto:fellowships@cjh.org"><span><span>fellowships@cjh.org</span></span></a><span><span>.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><u><span><span><span>For graduate student applicants, please also include:</span></span></span></u></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The letter of recommendation should come from the candidate’s primary advisor. The letter should address the significance of the candidate’s work for their field, as well as the candidate’s ability to fulfill the proposed work. Please ensure that your application indicates the name and contact information of the person writing the letter on your behalf. (Letter of recommendation should be sent separately, directly by the recommender – preferably by email to </span></span><a href="mailto:fellowships@cjh.org"><span><span>fellowships@cjh.org</span></span></a><span><span><span><span>)</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Graduate School transcript</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Please submit all application materials electronically as one continuous PDF document (except the letter of recommendation).</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><h4><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Applications are to be submitted by March 1, 2023 to:</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></h4><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Email: </span></span></span><span><a href="mailto:fellowships@cjh.org?subject=CJH-Fordham%20University%20Research%20Fellowship"><b><span><span><span>fellowships@cjh.org</span></span></span></b></a></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Miriam Eve Mora, PhD</p><p>Director of Programs</p><p>Center for Jewish History</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:fellowships@cjh.org">fellowships@cjh.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://cjh.org/research/fellowships-at-the-center/fordham" target="_blank">https://cjh.org/research/fellowships-at-the-center/fordham#fordham</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 18:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673678231669456</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ March 31, 2023] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/106689</link>
						<description>Publication Name: The British Society for the Philosophy of Religion, Biennial Conference: Love, Religion, and God<br/><br/><p><strong>Keynote Speakers:</strong></p>
<p>Fiona Ellis (University of Roehampton)</p>
<p>Talbot Brewer (University of Virginia)</p>
<p>Judith Wolfe (University of St Andrews)</p>
<p>Paul Fiddes (University of Oxford)</p>
<p>The question of the relation between love, religion, and God is a central concern for both atheists and theists; and philosophers, theologians, and scientists have drawn interesting and sometimes conflicting conclusions about the nature of this relation and of the things related in this context. Can love be understood in the absence of God? Is love one thing or many things? And what is the relation between love and desire, or love and redemption? How are we to assess Nietzsche’s critique of Christian love? What is the role and value of love in non-theistic religious traditions? And in what sense, if any, should we accept that love is deeply mysterious?</p>
<p>These questions are attracting attention in recent scholarship, and the conference organisers are keen to examine the relevant issues from the vantage point of philosophy of religion as broadly conceived. We welcome papers taking a philosophical and/or theological approach to all aspects of love, religion, and God, including secular and diverse religious perspectives. We also encourage submissions from scholars who seek to make connections with other disciplines, such as religious studies, psychology, literature, and cognitive science. Members of under-represented groups are particularly encouraged to submit an abstract.</p>
<p>Those interested in presenting a short paper should send a proposal of no more than 250 words in a Word document to Dr David Worsley (david.worsley@york.ac.uk)<strong> no later than 31 March 2023.</strong> Please include the paper's title, and your name, institutional affiliation, and email address (these are not included in the 250 word word limit). We expect to notify people about whether their proposals have been accepted by 30 April 2023.</p>
<p>Some partial bursaries (including bursaries to cover the cost of childcare) may be available for participants who do not have another source of funding for attending the conference, with preference for these given to those who are presenting a paper. If you anticipate being in need of a bursary, please indicate this in your submission.</p>
<p>Conference registration closes on 13 August. Registration can be done via Eventbrite, here: https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/the-bsprs-fifteenth-conference-love-religion-and-god-tickets-507654677807</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 06:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673591831286420</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ February 15, 2023] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/106697</link>
						<description>Publication Name: Simone Weil (1909-1943): Receptions and Actuality<br/><br/><p><strong>CFA/CFP: Simone Weil (1909-1943): Receptions and Actuality</strong></p>
<p><em><a target="_blank">Labyrinth: An International Journal for Philosophy, Value Theory and Sociocultural Hermeneutics</a></em> is preparing a special issue on the the occasion of the 80th death anniversary of Simone Weil (1909-1943). Of special interest are new readings and discussions dealing with the main topics of Weil's Philosophy as for example:</p>
<p>·       The sources of Simone Weil's philosophical and religious thought</p>
<p>·       Natural and supernatural</p>
<p>·       Origin and diversity of the religions</p>
<p>·       Materialism, religious experience and mystical thought</p>
<p>·       Ethics and aesthetics: the good and the beautiful</p>
<p>·       Happiness, suffering, and unhappiness</p>
<p>·       Love, truth, and justice</p>
<p>·       Freedom, obedience, oppression</p>
<p>·       Violence and non-violence, war and peace</p>
<p>·       The worker‘s condition and capitalism critique</p>
<p>·       Ecological issues</p>
<p>·       Receptions and influences of Simone Weil's thought</p>
<p>Researchers working in the field of Simone Weil's philosophical and religious thought are invited to submit a brief abstract until the <strong>15 of February 2023 </strong>with a brief biograhic information including name, academic affiliation, and main publications.</p>
<p>Authors who have already a finished unpublished paper are welcome to submit it within the abstract in order to help the peer review and the publishing process. <strong>Papers in their final form</strong>, i.e. proof read, formatted according to the journal guidelines, and print ready, should be submitted <strong>no later than the 30 of July 2023</strong>. </p>
<p>As a multilingual Journal <em>Labyrinth</em> accepts papers in English, French, and German. For more information about the journal policies and the submission's guidelines please visit: <a href="https://www.axiapublishers.com/ojs/index.php/labyrinth/AuthorGuidelines">https://www.axiapublishers.com/ojs/index.php/labyrinth/AuthorGuidelines</a></p>
<p>All abstracts and papers should be sent to labyrinth [at] axiapublishers.com</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 06:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673591831286419</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mass Extinction: Art, Ritual, Story, and the Sacred (Webinar Series)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12189403/mass-extinction-art-ritual-story-and-sacred-webinar-series</link>
						<dc:creator>Ryan Darr</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Event</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-01-27T00:00:00-05:00">January 27, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-24T00:00:00-05:00">February 24, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Connecticut</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Animal Studies, Art, Art History &amp; Visual Studies, Environmental History / Studies, Humanities, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>In January and February 2023, the Yale Institute of Sacred Music is hosting a series of four webinars titled <span><span><span><span><a href="https://ism.yale.edu/news/mass-extinction-art-ritual-story-and-sacred" rel="nofollow"><em>Mass Extinction: Art, Ritual, Story, and the Sacred</em></a>. The talks are all offered via Zoom from 12-1 p.m.  EST. Anyone is welcome to join, though registration is required. Please register for each webinar event separately.  </span></span></span></span></p><p><strong><span><span><span><span>Webinars at a glance</span></span></span></span></strong></p><p><strong>January 27</strong>: <em>Sacred Lands, Sacred Ecologies: Poetic and Photographic Engagements</em> with Craig Santos Perez and Subhankar Banerjee</p><p><strong>February 3</strong>: <em>Narrating Extinction in History and Myth</em> with Sadiah Qureshi and Nancy Menning</p><p><strong>February 17: </strong><em>Aesthetics of Extinction</em> with Sugata Ray and Stefan Skrimshire</p><p><strong><strong>February 24</strong></strong>: <em>Remembering Lost Species: Rituals for the Anthropocene</em> with Persephone Pearl, Emily Laurens, and Rachel Porter<strong> </strong></p><p>Details and registration can be found <a href="https://ism.yale.edu/news/mass-extinction-art-ritual-story-and-sacred" rel="nofollow">here</a>.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Ryan Darr</p><p>Yale Institute of Sacred Music</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ryan.darr@yale.edu">ryan.darr@yale.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://ism.yale.edu/news/mass-extinction-art-ritual-story-and-sacred" target="_blank">https://ism.yale.edu/news/mass-extinction-art-ritual-story-and-sacred</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 18:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673591831286418</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP: Drew University, Trandisciplinary Theological Colloquium - Haunted (by) Speech: Translating Religions and Religious Translations, CALL EXTENDED</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12189402/cfp-drew-university-trandisciplinary-theological-colloquium</link>
						<dc:creator>Michael Anderson</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-17T00:00:00-04:00">March 17, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-19T00:00:00-04:00">March 19, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology, South Asian History / Studies, Islamic History / Studies, Jewish History / Studies, African History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The Drew University Graduate Division of Religion is pleased to announce its <strong>21st Transdisciplinary Theological Colloquium</strong> to be held <strong>March 17th to 19th</strong>. This year’s conversation will be centered around our conference theme:</p><p><strong><em>Haunted (by) Speech: Translating Religions and Religious Translations</em></strong></p><p><em>“What is it, then, to translate? Deep language learning of the original, straining to be haunted by it so it can be learned before reason.” — Gayatri Spivak</em></p><p>TTC 2023 is inspired by previous colloquia (Planetary Loves in 2007; Decolonizing Epistemologies in 2008; Life Under the Baobab Tree in 2017; and Trans: Human/Divine Bodies Beyond Boundaries in 2018). However, while these conferences considered the importance of “translation” in relation to postcolonial and decolonial theory, Africana studies, and gender and trans studies, this conference narrows its focus quite specifically on the problematic of “translation” itself. Indeed, we ask what is lost, but also what is gained in the act of translating religion.</p><p>Our starting point is translation theory and studies, the rich and vibrant field that takes into account questions of coloniality, cultural fluency, linguistic equivalence, and accented speech. To think about translation opens up the question of being haunted, possessed by, even surrendering to language and all of the cultural, political, and religious implications found within it. But, this process is one that is marked by risk, as the very act of translation prompts us to consider the enacting of wounds, the losses that manifest in the process. We acknowledge that the very form of this conference participates in monolingualism (namely, a particular form of English) in a U.S. based university, and thus, it is marked by the risk of another symbolic violence of translation in the transnational imbalance of power. We call attention to such limitations in hopes of generating a more thoughtful debate on these important issues. We hope this self-reflective awareness will be a consideration for participants.</p><p>In addition, we do not seek to remain solely within the realm of words and language. We also want to see what happens when “translation” moves into other registers, religious and interreligious registers that require us to think about the translation of beliefs, feelings, and thoughts into action or practice. We also turn to the problem of translation to consider what might not be translatable. Where might the procedures of equivalence and comparison become hegemonic practices that do not enact an appeal to “planetarity” but instead to power and control? As such, this conference seeks to consider how practices, ethics, and aesthetics of untranslatability might reroute or even upend such controlling grammars.</p><p>TTC invites papers from graduate students that explore the many dimensions of translation: its politics, methods, figures, concepts, and future directions, especially as these relate to the domain of religion. This year’s conference will be hybrid in its modality, and as such, we eagerly encourage submissions from those individuals who will present via Zoom as well as those who will be present on campus.</p><p>Proposals should be 200-300 words in length and include, as an attachment, a CV or brief bio that indicates the applicant’s institution, program, stage of completion, and area of focus/research interests. We welcome proposals for transdisciplinary papers as well as proposals for teaching sessions, activist engagement, art, or storytelling, and other creative approaches to engage the conference theme. <strong>Please submit your proposal to <a href="mailto:ttc@drew.edu">ttc@drew.edu</a> by January 15th in order to be considered.</strong> If accepted, presentations should be approximately 20 minutes in length (1,800-2,000 words).</p><p>Below are a few ideas of the kinds of conversations we are interested in having:</p><ul><li>The politics and aesthetics of translation</li><li>The figure of the “translator” or “interpreter” within religious, theological, and biblical studies</li><li>Community interpretation or the “community of interpreters”</li><li>Critical methods and methodologies for translation</li><li>Translating the category of “religion” across contexts (geographical, temporal, political, religious, etc.)</li><li>Symbols, symbolism, and symbolic languages</li><li>Untranslatable religious concepts or words</li><li>Translating thoughts, feelings, affects, or beliefs into action</li><li>The ineffable or ineffability</li><li>Poetics or theopoetics</li><li>Productive or inhibiting misinterpretations/mistranslations</li><li>The gift of tongues or speaking in tongues (glossolalia)</li></ul></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ttc@drew.edu">ttc@drew.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://drew.edu/theological-school/academics/doctor-of-philosophy/transdisciplinary-theological-colloquium/" target="_blank">https://drew.edu/theological-school/academics/doctor-of-philosophy/transdisciplinary-theological-colloquium/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673591831286417</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Spotlight on Mahloket</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12185379/spotlight-mahloket</link>
						<dc:creator>Elizabeth DiNolfo</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Event</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-28T00:00:00-05:00">February 28, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>February 28, 2023<br/>1 - 2:15 ET via Zoom</p><p>Register at <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/www.brandeis.edu/mandel/events/spotlight-sessions">https://www.brandeis.edu/mandel/events/spotlight-session</a><br/>Free. Registration required. You will receive a zoom link after registering.</p><p>Mahloket—that is, dispute or principled debate—has long been celebrated as a Jewish ideal, not only within Jewish texts (where sages debate laws, interpretations and principles) but within the practice of engagement with those texts as well (where, for example, students might engage in debate about laws, interpretations or about principles). What does Mahloket look like at its best? How does Mahloket function as a kind of signature pedagogy (or at least a signature practice) within Jewish education? What does it mean to “educate for Mahloket,” and what are the benefits and challenges of doing so? In what ways is Mahloket a model for substantive engagement across difference?</p><p><a href="https://www.jewishdemocracy.org/about" rel="nofollow">Aaron Dorfman</a> (A More Perfect Union: The Jewish Partnership for Democracy), <a href="https://www.robbiegringras.com/" rel="nofollow">Robbie Gringas</a> (educator, performer and writer/For the Sake of Argument), <a href="https://www.hadar.org/faculty-staff/orit-kent" rel="nofollow">Orit Ken</a>t (Pedagogy of Partnership), <a href="https://www.forthesakeofargument.org/authors" rel="nofollow">Abi Dauber Sterne</a> (For the Sake of Argument), and <a href="https://www.pardes.org.il/faculty/mike-uram/" rel="nofollow">Mike Uram</a> (Pardes), moderated by Jon Levisohn.</p><p>ABOUT THE MANDEL CENTER SPOTLIGHT SESSIONS</p><p><em>Mandel Center Spotlight Sessions shine a light on an area of focus in Jewish education, bringing together several diverse scholarly perspectives for a shared conversation. Videos and podcasts of past conversations are available at <a href="https://www.brandeis.edu/mandel/events/videos.html" rel="nofollow">https://www.brandeis.edu/mandel/events/videos.html</a>.</em></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:mandelcenter@brandeis.edu">mandelcenter@brandeis.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.brandeis.edu/mandel/index.html" target="_blank">https://www.brandeis.edu/mandel/index.html</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 18:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673591831286416</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Children's Theories About Judaism</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12185381/childrens-theories-about-judaism</link>
						<dc:creator>Elizabeth DiNolfo</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Event</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-08T00:00:00-05:00">February 8, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Learning About Learning: A Conversation with Dr. Anna Hartman<br/>Children’s Theories About Judaism</p><p>February 8, 1-1:30 p.m.<br/>Via Zoom. Register at <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/www.brandeis.edu/mandel/events/learning-about-learning">https://www.brandeis.edu/mandel/events/learning-about-learning.html</a><br/>Free. Registration required. You will recieve a zoom link after registering.</p><p>Children’s ideas about the world are rich, nuanced, sometimes amusing and surprising, and for Anna Hartman, always fascinating. In this session, she will share her doctoral research in the field of early childhood Jewish education, in which she explores the theories about Judaism that are held by young children, and provides a window into their process of exploring and participating in Jewish life.</p><p><em><a href="https://networks.h-net.org/www.aju.edu/faculty/anna-hartman">Anna Hartman</a> is the Director of Early Childhood Excellence at the Jewish United Fund (JUF) and the Director of the Paradigm Project. She is also a 2021-22 fellow of the MCSJE Doctoral Fellows Program. Anna holds a master's in Jewish educational leadership from Hebrew Union College-Jewish Institute of Religion and is a doctorate in Jewish Education at the Jewish Theological Seminary. Anna is a recipient of the Pomegranate Prize, JUF's Samuel A. Goldsmith Young Professional Award, and the Covenant Award.</em></p><p>ABOUT THE LEARNING ABOUT LEARNING SERIES</p><p>Join us virtually for a series of half-hour conversations hosted by Mandel Center Director <a href="https://www.brandeis.edu/mandel/about/faculty-staff/bios/levisohn.html" rel="nofollow">Jon A. Levisohn</a>, in which leading scholars of Jewish education discuss what they have learned from their investigations of various aspects of Jewish education, and why it matters. Videos and podcasts of past conversations are available at <a href="https://www.brandeis.edu/mandel/events/videos.html" rel="nofollow">https://www.brandeis.edu/mandel/events/videos.html</a>.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Jack, Joseph and Morton Mandel Center for Studies in Jewish Education / Brandeis University</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:mandelcenter@brandeis.edu">mandelcenter@brandeis.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.brandeis.edu/mandel/index.html" target="_blank">https://www.brandeis.edu/mandel/index.html</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 18:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673591831286415</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Dying with the Buddha: The Twenty-four Buddhist Talismans in Chosŏn Korea</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12185264/dying-buddha-twenty-four-buddhist-talismans-chos%C5%8Fn-korea</link>
						<dc:creator>LaGretia Copp</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-09T00:00:00-05:00">February 9, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Kansas</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Asian History / Studies, East Asian History / Studies, Korean History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><h2>Dying with the Buddha: The Twenty-four Buddhist Talismans in Chos<span><span>ŏ</span></span>n Korea</h2><h3>Dr. Sujung Kim, Associate Professor of Religious Studies (DePauw University)</h3><h3>February 9, 2023  /  7 PM CT  /  Zoom</h3><h3><span><span><a href="https://kansas.zoom.us/meeting/register/tJcpf-isqzMvGdwMI9sRI3NOgFRM6NrTkE7y" rel="nofollow">REGISTER HERE</a> (bit.ly/DyingwiththeBuddha)</span></span></h3><p> </p><p><span><span>As a state-of-the-art “wearable technology” of the time, talismans provided protection, perquisites, and prescriptions for the devotees of premodern Korean Buddhism. Among the varied array of talismans discovered from tombs, stupas, and ritual manuals, this talk focuses on a collage of the 24 Buddhist talismans to illustrate how these talismans provided vocabulary and structure to transform believers’ soteriological concerns and cosmological views in the Buddhist mortuary setting. Each talisman in the group was introduced from China and circulated independently from the early Koryŏ period (935–1392). But once combined in the Chosŏn period (1392–1910), the 24 talismans functioned as one giant talisman communicating a complex vision and comprehensive benefits. My findings ultimately suggest that multiple layers of ambiguities built around talismans, such as tensions between text and image, legibility and illegibility, as well as accessibility and inaccessibility, played a key role in enacting the efficacy and potency of talismans, and that the twenty-four talismans occupied a central place in sustaining Chosŏn Buddhist devotionalism.</span></span></p><h3>About the Speaker</h3><p><span><span>Sujung  Kim is Associate professor of Religious Studies at DePauw University. Sujung is specialized in Japanese and Korean Buddhism, interested in tracing the interaction between Buddhist cultures using textual and material sources in East Asian context. Her first book, <em>Shinra Myojin and Buddhist Networks of the East Asian “Mediterranean”</em> (University of Hawai‘i Press, 2019) focuses on a deity called Shinra Myōjin. The book explains that Shinra Myojin is not only an influential protector god of the Onjōji temple in Japan, but also part of the transnational network of people, ideas, and gods, spanning China, Korea, and Japan. Currently, Sujung is working on her second book project tentatively titled, <em>Korean Magical Medicine: Buddhist Healing Talismans in Chosŏn Korea</em>, which she investigates the religious, historical, and iconographic dimensions of healing talismans produced in Buddhist settings during the Chosŏn period. Although its primary focus is Korean talismans, the book also locates itself in the broader East Asian context, aiming at showing the complex web of talismanic culture in East Asia. This book project is supported by ACLS/Robert H.N. Ho Family Foundation (AY 2021–2022), and she is also the recipient of the 1st KABS (Korean Association of Buddhist Studies) Mujin Writing Award (2021).</span></span></p><h4><span><span>Sponsored by the KU Center for East Asian Studies and the Department of East Asian Languages and Cultures.</span></span></h4></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>LaGretia Copp</p><p>Program Assistant</p><p>Center for East Asian Studies</p><p>University of Kansas</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ceas@ku.edu">ceas@ku.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="http://ceas.ku.edu/" target="_blank">http://ceas.ku.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 19:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673505429966189</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Syncretic Spread of Indian Traditions</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12096518/syncretic-spread-indian-traditions</link>
						<dc:creator>Arvind Kaushik</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-04-30T00:00:00-04:00">April 30, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>India</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>South Asian History / Studies, Social Sciences, Humanities, Religious Studies and Theology, Anthropology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span>Foreigners who come to India are often astounded by the diversity of the Indic traditions. As has been repeated often, we have crores of <i>devatas</i>, one for each individual. Each<i> jati</i> within each locality have their own unique set of practices and traditions. Equally fascinating as the diversity of the Indic traditions is their breadth of spread. The Buddhist traditions, for example, are to be found across the length and breadth of Asia, from Northern Mongolia to China to Japan and all the way down to Southeast Asia. </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Given that the Indic traditions did not expand through proselytization, what was the mechanism through which these traditions spread and established themselves in other regions? How did they do so without some centralized institution driving the process?</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Articles will be accepted in Word Format only in English submitted to <a href="mailto:editor@indictoday.com">editor@indictoday.com</a></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span>The articles may be submitted as either quick reads (around 1000-1200 words) or as long reads (2000-4000 words). Selected articles from long reads will be published as a part of an anthology: ‘The Mechanism of the Spread of Indic Traditions’. The deadline for submission of the article is March 30, 2023</span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:editor@indictoday.com">editor@indictoday.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.indica.today/announcements/call-for-papers-the-mechanism-of-the-spread-of-indic-traditions/" target="_blank">https://www.indica.today/announcements/call-for-papers-the-mechanism-of-the-spread-of-indic-traditions/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 19:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673505429966188</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ph.D. Research Grant Announcement 2023/24 Orient-Institut Istanbul</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12184098/phd-research-grant-announcement-202324-orient-institut</link>
						<dc:creator>Gottfried Plagemann</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Grant</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-01-22T00:00:00-05:00">January 22, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Turkey</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Middle East History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Anthropology, History of Science, Medicine, and Technology, Humanities</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>Ph.D. Research Grant Announcement 2023/24</span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>-- <i>Call for Applications</i> --</span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The <b>Orient-Institut Istanbul</b> is pleased to invite applications for Ph.D. research grants for 2023/24. </span></span><span><span>The purpose of the grant is to provide support for research in Turkey to Ph.D. candidates not living in Turkey. </span></span><span><span>If the fellowship is not, or only partially</span></span><span><span>,</span></span><span><span> spent in Istanbul, a close connection to the institute is required. Upon consultation this may also be arranged through supervision by members of the Orient-Institut's Scientific Advisory Board or other scholars associated with the institute. Grants are preferably available to support research in one of the institute’s research areas (</span></span><span><a href="https://www.oiist.org/en/forschungsprofil/" rel="nofollow"><span><span>https://www.oiist.org/en/forschungsprofil/</span></span></a></span><span><span>), namely </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ol><li><span><span><span><span><b><span>Musicological research on the Ottoman Empire and Turkey</span></b></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><b><span>Narrative sources on Istanbul and the Ottoman Empire</span></b></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><b><span>Past and contemporary forms of religious expression in Anatolia since the 11<sup>th</sup> century</span></b></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><b><span>Linguistic Turkology</span></b></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><b><span>Science, Technology and Society in Turkey </span></b></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><b><span>Iran </span></b></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><b><span>Entanglements between Turkish or Ottoman society, culture and literatures on the one, and Southeast Europe, the Mediterranean, Iran, The Caucasus and Eastern Europe on the other side. The migration of academics and artists is part of this field.</span></b></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><b><span>Ottoman modernities.</span></b></span></span></span></span></li></ol><p><span><span><span><span>The research grant consists of a monthly stipend of <b>€ 1,100</b> for the duration of <b>usually ten to twelve months</b>. Short term grants of up to 90 days may also be made available. Travel expenses of a journey to and from Turkey will be reimbursed. Start of the scholarship should be at the earliest <b>April 15th, 2023 </b>and at latest <b>September 15th, 2023</b>.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Prospective applicants are expected to hold an M.A. degree in a related academic discipline. As a rule, a complete application is to demonstrate the necessity of conducting research in Istanbul or Turkey at large. Good command of Turkish or another source language necessary for the proposed project is obligatory. As the Orient-Institut Istanbul aims at creating an open and supportive academic environment, grant holders are expected to attend colloquia and conferences organised by the institute and to give a public presentation of their own research. Research stays outside Istanbul must be cleared with the institute's director.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Applications to</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Prof. Dr. Christoph K. Neumann<br/>Director of the Orient-Institut Istanbul</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>must be submitted </span><span>via our </span><a href="https://www.oiist.org/en/ausschreibungen" rel="nofollow"><b><span>online application portal</span></b></a><span> by</span><span> <b>January 22<sup>nd</sup>, 2023</b>. For the reference letter, please share the link </span><a href="https://www.oiist.org/en/referenzschreiben/" rel="nofollow">https://www.oiist.org/en/referenzschreiben/</a><span> with the academic supervisor you have asked for a reference letter to upload the reference letter there.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span>Complete applications</span></b><span> must include the following:</span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span>Cover letter with indication of the desired period of the fellowship</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>CV</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Outline of the Ph.D./ research project</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Explanatory statement and research schedule for the stay in Istanbul/Turkey </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Letter of recommendation written and uploaded by an academic supervisor</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Copy of M.A. diploma</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Documentation of proficiency in Turkish or another relevant source language</span></span></span></span></span></li></ul></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.oiist.org/en/scholarship/" target="_blank">https://www.oiist.org/en/scholarship/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 19:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673505429966187</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>#MeToo, the Talmud, and the Ethics of Accountability, Prof. Mira Beth Wasserman (Rabbinical College in Philadelphia)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12179288/metoo-talmud-and-ethics-accountability-prof-mira-beth</link>
						<dc:creator>Manuel Lopez</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-01-17T00:00:00-05:00">January 17, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Florida</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Ancient History, Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><strong>PUBLIC LECTURE (In person and live stream): #MeToo, the Talmud, and the Ethics of Accountability, Prof. Mira Beth Wasserman (Rabbinical College in Philadelphia)<br/>When</strong>: TUESDAY, JANUARY 17, 2023<br/><strong>Time</strong>: 5:30 – 7:00 PM (EST)<br/><strong>Where</strong>: NEW COLLEGE OF FLORIDA, SAINER AUDITORIUM (located at NCF's Caple Campus, 5313 Bay Shore Rd)<br/><strong>Live Streaming</strong>: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkBFuIfa1OFGv7XrgMomkpw" rel="nofollow">New College of Florida Religious Studies YouTube Channel</a>.</p><p><strong>#MeToo, the Talmud, and the Ethics of Accountability</strong><br/>Prof. Mira Beth Wasserman<br/>Director of the Center for Jewish Ethics and Associate Professor of Rabbinic Literature at the Reconstructionist Rabbinical College in Philadelphia.</p><p>With the rise of the #MeToo movement, Jewish activists invoked the Jewish ethical tradition to support principles of accountability, dignity, and gender justice. The Talmud seemed to offer a perfect precedent for #MeToo in the story of a rabbinic leader who was chastened and dismissed for sexual violations. But is this an accurate reading of Moed Katan 17a? In this talk, I take a second look at the talmudic text I at first celebrated and discover a more complicated and disturbing story. I offer my reading and re-reading as a case study in how the Talmud can--and can't--advance contemporary ethics.</p><p>Professor Wasserman’s research focuses on the art of the Babylonian Talmud and on how the Talmud can be deployed to support contemporary Jewish ethics. Her book, Jews, Gentiles, and Other Animals: The Talmud after the Humanities (Penn Press), was awarded the Baron Prize for the best first book in Jewish studies published in 2017. Her current projects include a history of the idea of aggadah, and the direction of NEH-funded public scholarship on race, religion, and American Judaism.</p><p>Read more here: <a href="https://www.ncf.edu/ncf-events/klingenstein-lecture-series/" rel="nofollow">https://www.ncf.edu/ncf-events/klingenstein-lecture-series/</a><br/>About Prof. Mira Beth Wasserman: <a href="https://www.reconstructingjudaism.org/profile/rabbi-mira-beth-wasserman-phd/%C2%A0" rel="nofollow">https://www.reconstructingjudaism.org/profile/rabbi-mira-beth-wasserman-phd/ </a></p><p>With Best Wishes,<br/>Prof. Susan Marks<br/> </p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Susan Marks<br/>Professor of Judaic Studies /Klingenstein Chair<br/>New College of Florida<br/>Division of Humanities<br/>5800 Bay Shore Road<br/>Sarasota, Florida 34243-2109<br/><a>smarks@ncf.edu</a><br/>941.487.4271 Fax 941.487.4479<br/>She/Her/Herself</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:smarks@ncf.edu">smarks@ncf.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.ncf.edu/ncf-events/klingenstein-lecture-series/" target="_blank">https://www.ncf.edu/ncf-events/klingenstein-lecture-series/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673505429966186</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – January 11, 2023</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-january-11-2023/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find 3 jobs, 4 fellowships, 3 grants, and 8 Call For Papers.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 30!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Lecturer in Theology, Race, and Ethnicity (Full-Time with continuous renewal, non-Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Leeds University, UK</p>



<p>Deadline: January 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://jobs.leeds.ac.uk/vacancy.aspx?ref=AHCPR1053">https://jobs.leeds.ac.uk/vacancy.aspx?ref=AHCPR1053</a></p>



<h4>Lecturer in Anthropology (Full-time, fixed term until December 31, 2023)</h4>



<p>University of Melbourne, Australia</p>



<p>Deadline: January 22, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://jobs.unimelb.edu.au/en/job/911216/lecturer-in-anthropology">https://jobs.unimelb.edu.au/en/job/911216/lecturer-in-anthropology</a></p>



<h4>Bhagvan Vimalnath Endowed Chair in Jain Studies and South Asian Studies</h4>



<p>UC Santa Barbara, US</p>



<p>Deadline: June 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://recruit.ap.ucsb.edu/JPF02315">https://recruit.ap.ucsb.edu/JPF02315</a></p>



<h4>AAR/SBL Job Forum</h4>



<p><a href="https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search">https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search</a></p>



<h2>Fellowships:</h2>



<h4>Psychology Ph.D. Studentship in Conspiracy Theories (Covered fees, stipend, research funding, conference, and travel funding)</h4>



<p>University of Kent, UK</p>



<p>Deadline: February 28, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.kent.ac.uk/psychology/news/4990/erc-funded-phd-studentship-opportunity-consequences-of-conspiracy-theories">https://www.kent.ac.uk/psychology/news/4990/erc-funded-phd-studentship-opportunity-consequences-of-conspiracy-theories</a></p>



<h4>Swarthmore College Special Collections’ Moore Research Fellowship (2023-2024)</h4>



<p>Swarthmore College, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: April 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12154655/cfp-swarthmore-college-special-collectionss-moore-research">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12154655/cfp-swarthmore-college-special-collectionss-moore-research</a></p>



<h4>New Graduate School Fellowships in Islamic Studies</h4>



<p>Sweden</p>



<p>Deadline: Varies on which institutions you fit best</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://lnu.se/en/research/PhD-studies/religion/graduate-school-in-islamic-studies/">https://lnu.se/en/research/PhD-studies/religion/graduate-school-in-islamic-studies/</a></p>



<h4>Ph.D. funding through Open University, Oxford, and Cambridge</h4>



<p>Deadline: January 11, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.oocdtp.ac.uk/how-to-apply">https://www.oocdtp.ac.uk/how-to-apply</a></p>



<h2>Grants:</h2>



<h4>2023 Frist Book Grant for Scholars of Color (assisting early career, non-tenured religion scholars of color with grants up to $40,000)</h4>



<p>Deadline: January 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://louisville-institute.org/programs-grants-and-fellowships/grants/first-book-grant-for-scholars-of-color/">https://louisville-institute.org/programs-grants-and-fellowships/grants/first-book-grant-for-scholars-of-color/</a></p>



<h4>AAR – Eastern International Region Conference Travel Grants</h4>



<p>Deadline: February 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://eiraar.org/index.php/regional-news/regional-meeting-travel-grants">https://eiraar.org/index.php/regional-news/regional-meeting-travel-grants</a></p>



<h4>Luce – AAR Advancing Public Scholarship Grant</h4>



<p>Deadline: January 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/QS90yCp9Pn">https://t.co/QS90yCp9Pn</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>American Catholic Historical Association 2023 Annual Meeting</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://twitter.com/achahistory/status/1612072394880958464?s=12&amp;t=033LBhhevenzNwJoZ2P4og">American Catholic Historical Association on Twitter: “And just like that, the ACHA 2023 Annual Meeting is over! The call for papers is already out for next year’s meeting. Our deadline is March 15, 2023! https://t.co/S73VsLob2b” / Twitter</a></p>



<h4>Fordham States’ Catholic Studies in the Americas “New Scholar Essay Prize” – $1500 prize</h4>



<p>Deadline: February 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/FKodXblosV">https://t.co/FKodXblosV</a></p>



<h4>Yale Journal of Music &amp; Religion</h4>



<p>Deadline: January 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://elischolar.library.yale.edu/yjmr/">https://elischolar.library.yale.edu/yjmr/</a></p>



<h4>Sacred Journeys 10<sup>th</sup> Global Conference</h4>



<p>Deadline: Conference July 4 – 7, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12154888/sacred-journeys-10th-global-conference">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12154888/sacred-journeys-10th-global-conference</a></p>



<h4>Avar: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Life and Society in the Ancient Near East</h4>



<p>Deadline: August 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12143401/avar%C2%A0-interdisciplinary-journal-life-and-society-ancient-near">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12143401/avar%C2%A0-interdisciplinary-journal-life-and-society-ancient-near</a></p>



<h4>Religion and Spirituality as Sites of Learning Conference</h4>



<p>Deadline: January 17, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://blogs2.abo.fi/religionlearning/?fbclid=IwAR2-Kz85Nu74LFTOuQnTl5rXup_u8m2cRsLi0q6jSemoOlQXLI6BZT6oM0w">https://blogs2.abo.fi/religionlearning/?fbclid=IwAR2-Kz85Nu74LFTOuQnTl5rXup_u8m2cRsLi0q6jSemoOlQXLI6BZT6oM0w</a></p>



<h4>The Other, Persecution and Response</h4>



<p>Deadline: February 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://relcfp.com/blog/2023/01/01/cfp-eir-aar-queens/">https://relcfp.com/blog/2023/01/01/cfp-eir-aar-queens/</a></p>



<h4>Ecclesiology &amp; Ethnography Network</h4>



<p>Deadline: January 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/KYJXgOAwLc">https://t.co/KYJXgOAwLc</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673505429966185</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Materiality of Lived Religion on the Atlantic Edge</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/01/10/the-materiality-of-lived-religion-on-the-atlantic-edge</link>
						<dc:creator>avner.goldstein</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Wednesday, January 11, 2023 - 4:40pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Avner Goldstein (Boston College, USA) and Eleanor March (University of Exeter, UK)</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:avner.goldstein@bc.edu">avner.goldstein@bc.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/classical-studies">classical studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/ecocriticism-and-environmental-studies">ecocriticism and environmental studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/medieval">medieval</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>February 9, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>CALL FOR PAPERS -- EAA 2023 -- BELFAST</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Avner Goldstein and Eleanor March invite abstract submission to session #107 ("The Materiality of Religion on the Atlantic Edge") at the 2023 annual meeting of the European Association of Archaeologists in Belfast. Please see the text below for further details. Any questions may be addressed to the main session organiser at <a href="mailto:avner.goldstein@bc.edu">avner.goldstein@bc.edu</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Session Title and Number:<br/></strong>#107. The Materiality of Religion on the Atlantic Edge</p>
<p><strong>Organizers:</strong><br/>Avner Goldstein (Boston College, USA)<br/>Eleanor March (University of Exeter, UK)</p>
<p><strong>Deadline:</strong><br/>9 February 2023</p>
<p><strong>Submissions:</strong><br/><a href="https://eaa.klinkhamergroup.com/eaa2023/">https://eaa.klinkhamergroup.com/eaa2023/</a></p>
<p><strong>Abstract:</strong><br/>Papers in this session explore the material culture of lived religion on the edge of the European Atlantic, from the Iron Age through the end of the Middle Ages. Following the successful EAA 2022 session “The Materiality of Lived Religion Under and After Rome,” we wish to continue discussions exploring the opportunities and interpretative challenges of using material culture for understanding ritual and religion. This year, particular attention is given to the materials, practices, performances, and experiences of religion in regions that lie along the European Atlantic, including Ireland, Great Britain, the North Sea, France, and Iberia. As well as introducing listeners to the particular materials of religion that are the focus of the paper, presenters should also address at least one of the following issues: the impact that Atlantic environments and landscapes had on ritual practices and understandings, or how lived religion’s material expressions were impacted depending on whether they were found at the centre or on the margins of empires, kingdoms, territories, communities, or societies. This session provides a space for serious discussion between practitioners working in different time periods, places, and disciplines about how to think about and use material evidence to reconstruct the lived experience of religion along the Atlantic’s edge.</p>
<p><strong>Keywords:</strong><br/>religion, history, environment, Iron Age, Roman, medieval</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 20:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1673505429966184</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
