<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 12:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 12:19:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ May 31, 2024] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/117593</link>
						<description>Publication Name: Call for Papers for  Symphilosophie 6 (2024) - Romanticism and its Kantian Legacy<br/><br/><p>SYMPHILOSOPHIE: International Journal of Philosophical Romanticism<strong> is now accepting submissions of original research articles, review essays, book reviews and new translations for its sixth issue</strong>, which will appear in late 2024. </p>
<p>We are pleased to announce <strong>Marie-Michèle Blondin</strong> (Collège Montmorency / CCEAE, Université de Montréal), <strong>Luigi Filieri</strong> (Universität Mainz), <strong>Cody Staton</strong> (Kennesaw State University), and <strong>Gesa Wellmann</strong> (Universität Oldenburg), as guest editors of this issue. They will be in charge of the main section devoted to the topic: </p>
<p><strong>Romanticism and its Kantian Legacy</strong></p>
<p>For the 300th anniversary of the birth of Immanuel Kant, SYMPHILOSOPHIE welcomes submissions dealing with the indelible legacy of Kantian philosophy among the German romantic philosophers. That is to say, investigations detailing the different ways the romantics engaged with the critical philosophy and how these interactions shaped some of the central tenets of German Romanticism itself. We are particularly interested in vestiges of Kantian philosophy among thinkers such as Friedrich Schlegel, Novalis, Friedrich Schleiermacher, and Hölderlin, as well as romantic figures who transformed Kantian philosophy in languages other than German, like Samuel Taylor Coleridge. </p>
<p>The deadline for all contributions to this sixth issue is: <strong>31 May 2024</strong>. Contributions should be sent to the following email address: </p>
<p><strong>editors@symphilosophie.com</strong></p>
<p>For more details see: </p></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 06:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1701671824544301</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ December 18, 2023] Talk or similar: Talk on Chapter 1 生不如死? (regarding life and death) of Prof. Ho's book 人鬼神</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/117473</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/>Speakers at this event: <br/>Man Wui Richard Prof. Ho<br/><br/><p>We are extremely delighted to have Professor Richard Ho to join SDCF IChing Zoom session on 18th December.  Details are set out as below:</p>
<p>Date: 18th December 2023, Monday</p>
<p>Time:  20:30-22:00 Hong Kong Time (GMT+8) / 07:30-09:00 NYT / 12:30-14:00 UKT</p>
<p>(Zoom details to be provided after registration)</p>
<p>Prof. Ho will discuss a chapter of one of his books 人鬼神 regarding life and death. This chapter combines his personal reflections with readings of the Zhuangzi.  Please enrol at this link: https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScT8-ROpH5v2k_x3XzPpxwhj-kaNTzWMwnhYJ9iM4ngM6U_oQ/viewform</p>
<p>if you are interested to attend.  </p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 06:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1701412625047636</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ April 4, 2024 -  April 6, 2024] Conference or similar: Unity &amp; Disunity in Science: Philosophical, Historical, and Theological Perspectives</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/117509</link>
						<description>Venue: University of Notre Dame<br/><br/><p>From debates in the New Zealand parliament concerning the value of Maori knowledge of nature, to debates about racial and gender bias in medicine, to the recent realization that the work of a Nobel prize winner was consistently rejected for falling outside scientific consensus, it is clear that there are tensions inherent in Western society’s commitment to universal reason alongside epistemic diversity  Aware of these tensions, many historians of science have sought to recover the stories of non-standard science and to emphasize a diversity of ways of knowing the natural world. Moreover, many philosophers of science have suggested that pluralism within science is not a matter of justice to diverse stakeholders but a generic feature of scientific reasoning. They claim that the pursuit of manifold, perhaps even inconsistent, research programs is the appropriate response to the complexity of target systems and the perspectival limitations of knowing. Scholars in science and religion have even begun to question the validity of “science” as a transhistorical monolithic category suggesting that it consists of a variety of traditions each with its own internal history and rationality. Each of these three strands considers the possibility and, sometimes, inevitability of a more pluralist science, one that progresses along multiple paths rather than insisting on the closing down of alternatives. This conference seeks to bring these strands together to further investigate the historical and conceptual foundations of pluralist science as well as to evaluate its promises and risks in our globalist society. </p>
<p><strong><br/></strong></p>
<p>We are accepting submissions for twenty minute papers and for posters. We welcome contributions from history and philosophy of science, theology and science, science studies, and adjacent disciplines. Abstracts should be approximately 250 words. A limited number of travel bursaries are available.</p>
<p><strong><br/></strong></p>
<p>Possible questions include:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Is pluralism a permanent part of the scientific endeavor, or is it merely a transitory feature of our current epistemic situation?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Is pluralism a desired feature of scientific theorizing, or a roadblock to a final, unified science? What risks does pluralism pose, either epistemically or socially?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Should we value a diversity of perspectives at all? for epistemic or non-epistemic reasons? Instrumentally or for its own sake? </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do inconsistent models imply some form of epistemic relativism?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Does a commitment to scientific pluralism imply that nature itself is pluralistic, or merely that different ways of modeling nature represent different aspects of a univocal nature?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do different cultural, metaphysical, and religious perspectives result in salient differences in the kinds of scientific knowledge that are possible?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Is science inherently secular? Is it culturally or metaphysically neutral? What are the implications of proposing a non-secular, culturally situated science?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How might disunity in science affect the way other disciplines engage with it? </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How should different ways of knowing nature be characterized with respect to one another and with respect to European, empirical science? Do specific cases clarify this relationship?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do our methods of historically investigating science by attending to particular cases lead to the conclusion that science is pluralistic or merely assume its pluralism from the start? </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Are there aspects of science that we presume to be universal that are, in fact, culturally situated? </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How prevalent in the history of science is the Semmelweiss reflex, whereby established scientific authorities reject new evidence or knowledge in favor of entrenched norms, beliefs, or practices? Does that prevalence vary by discipline, region, or period? Do specific cases of this reflex (or its absence) teach us something about how prone science is to unification? </p>
</li>
</ul></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 06:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1701412625047635</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ January 10, 2024] CFP for conference or similar: Unity &amp; Disunity in Science: Philosophical, Historical, and Theological Perspectives</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/117513</link>
						<description><p>From debates in the New Zealand parliament concerning the value of Maori knowledge of nature, to debates about racial and gender bias in medicine, to the recent realization that the work of a Nobel prize winner was consistently rejected for falling outside scientific consensus, it is clear that there are tensions inherent in Western society’s commitment to universal reason alongside epistemic diversity Aware of these tensions, many historians of science have sought to recover the stories of non-standard science and to emphasize a diversity of ways of knowing the natural world. Moreover, many philosophers of science have suggested that pluralism within science is not a matter of justice to diverse stakeholders but a generic feature of scientific reasoning. They claim that the pursuit of manifold, perhaps even inconsistent, research programs is the appropriate response to the complexity of target systems and the perspectival limitations of knowing. Scholars in science and religion have even begun to question the validity of “science” as a transhistorical monolithic category suggesting that it consists of a variety of traditions each with its own internal history and rationality. Each of these three strands considers the possibility and, sometimes, inevitability of a more pluralist science, one that progresses along multiple paths rather than insisting on the closing down of alternatives. This conference seeks to bring these strands together to further investigate the historical and conceptual foundations of pluralist science as well as to evaluate its promises and risks in our globalist society.</p>
<p>We are accepting submissions for twenty minute papers and for posters. We welcome contributions from history and philosophy of science, theology and science, science studies, and adjacent disciplines. Abstracts should be approximately 250 words. A limited number of travel bursaries are available.</p>
<p>Possible questions include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Is pluralism a permanent part of the scientific endeavor, or is it merely a transitory feature of our current epistemic situation?</li>
<li>Is pluralism a desired feature of scientific theorizing, or a roadblock to a final, unified science? What risks does pluralism pose, either epistemically or socially?</li>
<li>Should we value a diversity of perspectives at all? for epistemic or non-epistemic reasons? Instrumentally or for its own sake? </li>
<li>Do inconsistent models imply some form of epistemic relativism?</li>
<li>Does a commitment to scientific pluralism imply that nature itself is pluralistic, or merely that different ways of modeling nature represent different aspects of a univocal nature?</li>
<li>Do different cultural, metaphysical, and religious perspectives result in salient differences in the kinds of scientific knowledge that are possible?</li>
<li>Is science inherently secular? Is it culturally or metaphysically neutral? What are the implications of proposing a non-secular, culturally situated science?</li>
<li>How might disunity in science affect the way other disciplines engage with it? </li>
<li>How should different ways of knowing nature be characterized with respect to one another and with respect to European, empirical science? Do specific cases clarify this relationship?</li>
<li>Do our methods of historically investigating science by attending to particular cases lead to the conclusion that science is pluralistic or merely assume its pluralism from the start? </li>
<li>Are there aspects of science that we presume to be universal that are, in fact, culturally situated? </li>
<li>How prevalent in the history of science is the Semmelweiss reflex, whereby established scientific authorities reject new evidence or knowledge in favor of entrenched norms, beliefs, or practices? Does that prevalence vary by discipline, region, or period? Do specific cases of this reflex (or its absence) teach us something about how prone science is to unification? </li>
</ul></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 06:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1701412625047634</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[Today] Talk or similar: De Dieu, des hommes, des instruments. La leçon d'Ivan Illich</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/117413</link>
						<description>Venue: Rue de Poissy 20<br/><br/>Speakers at this event: <br/>Fabio Milana<br/><br/><p>The seminar will be in French.</p>
<p><strong>Zoom Link: https://us06web.zoom.us/j/83114230445</strong></p></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 06:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1701326225242365</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Opportunities Digest – November 29, 2023</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-opportunities-digest-november-29-2023/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Project Opportunities Digest! This week you will find 23 new job opportunities, 5 fellowships, 1 grant, and 3 calls for papers.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 42!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Academic:</h4>



<h4>Postdoctoral Fellow on History of Capitalism (1-year appointment)</h4>



<p>Harvard Business School, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: January 1, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178619862&amp;utm_source=11_28_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">Postdoctoral Fellow – History of Capitalism – HigherEdJobs</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Religion (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Wellesley College, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: December 11, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178619551&amp;utm_source=11_28_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178619551&amp;utm_source=11_28_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Director of Digital Humanities and Undergraduate Learning (Full-time, non-tenure-track)</h4>



<p>University of Florida, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: December 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178619325&amp;utm_source=11_27_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178619325&amp;utm_source=11_27_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Preceptor in Ancient Greek (3-year appointment)</h4>



<p>Harvard University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: December 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178618859&amp;utm_source=11_26_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178618859&amp;utm_source=11_26_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Robert Curvin Postdoctoral Associate in Urban Studies (1-year appointment, possibility of renewal)</h4>



<p>Rutgers, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: February 29, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178618009&amp;utm_source=11_24_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178618009&amp;utm_source=11_24_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor of European History (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Durham University, UK</p>



<p>Deadline: February 5, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://durham.taleo.net/careersection/du_ext/jobdetail.ftl?job=23002046&amp;lang=en&amp;src=JB-10180">https://durham.taleo.net/careersection/du_ext/jobdetail.ftl?job=23002046&amp;lang=en&amp;src=JB-10180</a></p>



<h4>Just Transformations Postdoctoral Fellowship (1-year appointment, possibility of renewal)</h4>



<p>Pennsylvania State University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: January 9, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178617562&amp;utm_source=11_23_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178617562&amp;utm_source=11_23_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>History and NAIS Postdoctoral Fellow (2-year appointment)</h4>



<p>Brown University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: January 15, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178617129&amp;utm_source=11_23_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178617129&amp;utm_source=11_23_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Theology and Religious Studies (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Rosemont College, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178615107&amp;utm_source=11_22_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">Assistant Professor, Theology and Religious S – HigherEdJobs</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor of American Studies (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Kenyon College, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: December 20, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.pageuppeople.com/695/cw/en-us/job/493044/assistant-professor-of-american-studies-tenure-track">https://careers.pageuppeople.com/695/cw/en-us/job/493044/assistant-professor-of-american-studies-tenure-track</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Historian/Archaeologist of Environment in Antiquity (Tenure Track)</h4>



<p>Tufts University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: December 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.historians.org/jobs/19449154/historian-and-or-archaeologist-of-environment-in-antiquity-tenure-track-assistant-professor?utm_source=BTITwitter&amp;utm_medium=Twitter&amp;utm_campaign=BTI%2BTwitter%2BFeed">Historian and/or Archaeologist of Environment in Antiquity, Tenure-Track Assistant Professor in Medford, MA for Tufts University, Classical Studies (historians.org)</a></p>



<h4>Postdoctoral Fellowship: Humanities Without Walls Public Humanities (2-year appointment)</h4>



<p>University of Illinois, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.humanitieswithoutwalls.illinois.edu/about/hww-postdoc-uiuc">https://www.humanitieswithoutwalls.illinois.edu/about/hww-postdoc-uiuc</a></p>



<h4>Minerva Recruitment Job Listings Cite (with areas specifically tailored for Ph.D.)</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://minerva-recruitment.com/">Minerva Recruitment – Higher Education Graduate Jobs, UK &amp; Worldwide (minerva-recruitment.com)</a></p>



<h4>AAR/SBL Job Forum</h4>



<p><a href="https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search">https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search</a></p>



<h4>Non-Academic:</h4>



<h4>Coordinator of Campus Life and Campus Ministry Outreach</h4>



<p>University of St. Thomas, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178620190&amp;utm_source=11_28_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">Coordinator of Campus Life and Campus Ministry Outreach – HigherEdJobs</a></p>



<h4>Bell Museum Curatorial Technician</h4>



<p>University of Minnesota, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: December 13, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178618747&amp;utm_source=11_25_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178618747&amp;utm_source=11_25_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Director of Distance and Online Education (Masters degree required)</h4>



<p>Colorado Mesa University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: January 7, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178618026&amp;utm_source=11_24_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178618026&amp;utm_source=11_24_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Associate Editor (Graduate degree desired)</h4>



<p>Research Foundation CUNY, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/rTWQtvngUI">https://t.co/rTWQtvngUI</a></p>



<h4>Research Associate, US Foreign Policy</h4>



<p>Chicago Council on Global Affairs, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.glassdoor.com/job-listing/research-associate-us-foreign-policy-the-chicago-council-on-global-affairs-JV_IC1128808_KO0,36_KE37,74.htm?jl=1008934657741">https://www.glassdoor.com/job-listing/research-associate-us-foreign-policy-the-chicago-council-on-global-affairs-JV_IC1128808_KO0,36_KE37,74.htm?jl=1008934657741</a></p>



<h4>Global Engagement Strategist</h4>



<p>Institute for Humane Studies, USA (Remote)</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/6Xbz0LQ3LY">https://t.co/6Xbz0LQ3LY</a></p>



<h4>Native American Consultation Specialist (PhD preferred)</h4>



<p>US Army Corps of Engineers, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/7a3sHD6UVl">https://t.co/7a3sHD6UVl</a></p>



<h4>Director of Research &amp; Design (Graduate degree preferred)</h4>



<p>National Center for State Courts, USA (Remote)</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/ggDoJ66G3e">https://t.co/ggDoJ66G3e</a></p>



<h4>Content Assistant</h4>



<p>Paul, Weiss, Rifkind, Wharton &amp; Garrison LLP, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/NHcgINP6T1">https://t.co/NHcgINP6T1</a></p>



<h4>Researcher</h4>



<p>CBS Sports, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/Fc3K8taBSn">https://t.co/Fc3K8taBSn</a></p>



<h4>Education Specialist</h4>



<p>Uban Strategies, Inc., USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/zpbl1JeOZw">https://t.co/zpbl1JeOZw</a></p>



<h2>Fellowships:</h2>



<h4>Charles Eastman Dissertation and Postdoctoral Fellowship (2-year appointment)</h4>



<p>Dartmouth College, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: February 1, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178619141&amp;utm_source=11_26_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178619141&amp;utm_source=11_26_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Sabbatical Fellows Program for Emory Assistant Professors in the Humanities and Social Sciences</h4>



<p>Emory University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: January 31, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178618737&amp;utm_source=11_25_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178618737&amp;utm_source=11_25_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Cesar Chavez Dissertation and Postdoctoral Fellowship (2-year appointment)</h4>



<p>Dartmouth College, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: February 1, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178618197&amp;utm_source=11_24_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178618197&amp;utm_source=11_24_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>American Philosophical Society Museum and Library Fellowships</h4>



<p>Philadelphia Pennsylvania, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: January 19, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.historians.org/jobs/19439141/fellowship-internship-opportunities-at-the-american-philosophical-society-library-museum">https://careers.historians.org/jobs/19439141/fellowship-internship-opportunities-at-the-american-philosophical-society-library-museum</a></p>



<h4>Scholar-in-Residence (Africa/African Diaspora fields of interest)</h4>



<p>New York Public Library, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: December 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.nypl.org/help/about-nypl/fellowships-institutes/schomburg-center-scholars-in-residency/application?utm_campaign=schomburgsocialmedia&amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_medium=social">https://www.nypl.org/help/about-nypl/fellowships-institutes/schomburg-center-scholars-in-residency/application?utm_campaign=schomburgsocialmedia&amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_medium=social</a></p>



<h2>Grants:</h2>



<h4>History of Philosophy Forum at the University of Notre Dame</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 15, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://twitter.com/smrphilosophy/status/1728811590584357107?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw">https://twitter.com/smrphilosophy/status/1728811590584357107?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw</a></p>



<h2>Call for Paper:</h2>



<h4>Religion, State, and Society Journal</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/Y3Tl8JfNCK">https://t.co/Y3Tl8JfNCK</a></p>



<h4>Interpreting the Septuagint in its Greco-Roman Context</h4>



<p>Deadline: January 15, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.academia.edu/109754802/Colloquium_on_Interpreting_the_Septuagint_in_Its_Greco_Roman_Context_June_19_20_2024_">https://www.academia.edu/109754802/Colloquium_on_Interpreting_the_Septuagint_in_Its_Greco_Roman_Context_June_19_20_2024_</a></p>



<h4>Models in Theology: Methodical and Theological Paradigm Shifts Through Model-Building</h4>



<p>Deadline: January 20, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/117285">https://philevents.org/event/show/117285</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1701326225242364</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Morris, Religion, and Myth</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/11/28/morris-religion-and-myth</link>
						<dc:creator>jude_nixon@comcast.net</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, November 28, 2023 - 12:20pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>William Morris Society</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:jnixon@salemstate.edu">jnixon@salemstate.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/poetry">poetry</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/victorian">victorian</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>March 1, 2024</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>MLA New Orleans, 9-12 January 2025</strong></p>
<p><strong>Morris, Religion, and Myth</strong></p>
<p> This MLA guaranteed session invites proposals exploring Morris’s writings on religion and myth. Topics could come from Morris’s Icelandic writings, his fantasy romance, <em>The Earthly Paradise</em>, <em>News from Nowhere</em>, <em>The Defence of Guenevere</em><em>, and </em><em>A Dream of John Ball</em><em>.</em></p>
<p> Please include a 250-word abstract and short bio no later than Friday, 1 March 2024, to <a href="mailto:jnixon@salemstate.edu">jnixon@salemstate.edu</a></p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 08:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1701239822972966</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>American Literary Naturalism and Religion</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/11/26/american-literary-naturalism-and-religion</link>
						<dc:creator>ajball79@icloud.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, November 28, 2023 - 12:19pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>American Religion and Literature Society</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:andrew_ball@emerson.edu">andrew_ball@emerson.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/modernist-studies">modernist studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/science-and-culture">science and culture</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/twentieth-century-and-beyond">twentieth century and beyond</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>January 15, 2024</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p align="center">American Literature Association<br/>35th Annual Conference<br/>May 23-26, 2024<br/>Chicago, IL </p>
<p><strong>American Literary Naturalism and Religion</strong></p>
<p>Canonical and noncanonical American naturalists evinced a complex and ongoing interest in religious matters. For this panel, jointly organized by the Society for the Study of American Literary Naturalism and the American Religion and Literature Society, we invite scholars to examine American literary naturalism’s engagement with religious ideas and practices. The intersection of American literary naturalism and religion presents a rich area for exploration, offering scholars the opportunity to analyze how authors understood the relationship between the deterministic forces of nature and the religious dimensions of American life.</p>
<p>Potential approaches include but are not limited to:</p>
<p>Reevaluation of Naturalist Assumptions – Authors could investigate how American literary naturalism challenges or reinforces traditional religious beliefs, analyzing the ways naturalist narratives engage with questions of morality, free will, and the existence of divinity.</p>
<p>Explore the Religious Dimensions in Naturalist Texts – Authors could examine the presence of religious themes, motifs, and symbolism in naturalistic works, considering how authors negotiated the tension between deterministic natural forces and the religious aspects of human experience.</p>
<p>Authorial Perspectives on Religion – Authors could investigate the beliefs of naturalist authors, exploring how figures such as Stephen Crane, Theodore Dreiser, Jack London, Frank Norris, and Upton Sinclair grapple with or embrace religious ideas in their work.</p>
<p>Comparative Analysis – Authors could compare American literary naturalism with religious texts or explore parallels with religious narratives from other cultural traditions, examining how naturalist perspectives intersect with or diverge from other religious worldviews.</p>
<p>Examine Social and Cultural Contexts – Authors could explore the impact of social and cultural change on the portrayal of religion in American naturalism, investigating how issues such as industrialization, urbanization, and scientific advancements influenced the depiction of religious beliefs in naturalist literature.</p>
<p>Evolution and Religion – Authors could examine how authors engage with religious concepts and practices in the context of evolutionary science, exploring the ways religious ideas are reinterpreted, challenged, or reaffirmed in the face of evolutionary theory. Authors could consider how authors negotiated the tensions between religious faith and the scientific understanding of evolution.</p>
<p>Please submit abstracts of no more than 300 words to <a href="mailto:andrew_ball@emerson.edu">andrew_ball@emerson.edu</a> by <strong>January 15</strong>. Please include a brief biographical note with your submission.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 01:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1701239822972965</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious (In)tolerance and Geopolitics in American Literature</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/11/26/religious-intolerance-and-geopolitics-in-american-literature</link>
						<dc:creator>ajball79@icloud.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, November 28, 2023 - 12:19pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>American Religion and Literature Society</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:anamaria.clawson@snc.edu">anamaria.clawson@snc.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/ethnicity-and-national-identity">ethnicity and national identity</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/general-announcements">general announcements</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>January 15, 2024</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p align="center">American Literature Association<br/>35th Annual Conference<br/>May 23-26, 2024<br/>Chicago, IL</p>
<p><strong>Religious (In)tolerance and Geopolitics in American Literature</strong></p>
<p>This panel seeks to offer a robust and timely discussion about the relationship between religious intolerance and American literature. We are especially interested in papers attuned to transnational and geopolitical frameworks, given the global contexts impacting the resurgence of anti-Semitism and Islamophobia in contemporary U.S. culture. While scholars have long noted how American literature has shaped nativist discourses and shifting conceptions of religious difference within the U.S., they have less often attended to the geopolitical contexts underlying these discourses. And yet, our current moment calls us to this work. In this spirit, our panel asks: how have geopolitical events influenced imaginings of religious “others” within the United States? How have U.S. literary representations of religious difference, pluralism, and (in)tolerance shaped discourses on global politics? And more broadly speaking, how has American literature affirmed and/or challenged the notion of religious “tolerance” in and outside of the U.S.? This panel invites papers from across any period of American literature.</p>
<p>Those interested are asked to submit an abstract of no more than 200-300 words and a brief bio of no more than 100 words to <a href="mailto:anamaria.clawson@snc.edu">anamaria.clawson@snc.edu</a> by <strong>January 15</strong>.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 01:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1701239822972964</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Transcendentalist Legacies of Resilience at Thoreau Annual Gathering 2024</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/11/26/transcendentalist-legacies-of-resilience-at-thoreau-annual-gathering-2024</link>
						<dc:creator>prentissclark@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, November 28, 2023 - 12:19pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Ralph Waldo Emerson Society </div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:bscalia@alumni.lsu.edu">bscalia@alumni.lsu.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/general-announcements">general announcements</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/theory">theory</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>January 12, 2024</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>The Ralph Waldo Emerson Society is sponsoring a panel titled "Transcendentalist Legacies of Resilience" at the Throeau Society Annual Gathering, 2024.</p>
<p>“Resilience” is not a word that Emerson used. Yet, there is much in Emerson’s writings about Nature's restorative power, and essays such as “Self-Reliance,” “Circles,” “Experience,” “Power,” “Fate,” “Courage,” and “Character” contain lines of argument that can be read as analogous and perhaps even foundational to our contemporary notions of resilience. As he states in “Courage,” it  “perfect will, which no terrors can shake, which is attracted by frowns and threats or hostile armies, nay, needs these to awake and fan its reserved energies into a pure flame, and is never quite itself until the hazard is extreme; then it is extreme and fertile, and all its powers play well.”</p>
<p>This panel seeks papers that advocate for a reading of Emersonian resilience and that consider how the Transcendentalists responded to personal, political, societal, and technological change in their own time as well as how they influenced later thinkers and movements. Topics might include, but are not limited to, political and social movements such as abolitionism, civil rights, environmentalism, labor reform, or personal trauma.  </p>
<p>Please send a title and an approximately 250-word abstract to Bill Scalia -- <a href="mailto:bscalia@alumni.lsu.edu">bscalia@alumni.lsu.edu</a> -- by January 12, 2024.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1701239822972963</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Emerson &amp; Varieties of Religious Experience at ALA 2024</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/11/26/emerson-varieties-of-religious-experience-at-ala-2024</link>
						<dc:creator>prentissclark@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, November 28, 2023 - 12:19pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Ralph Waldo Emerson Society </div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:thomas.howard@wustl.edu">thomas.howard@wustl.edu </a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/general-announcements">general announcements</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/theory">theory</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>January 12, 2024</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>The Emerson Society is sponsoring a panel titled "Emerson &amp; Varieties of Religious Experience" at the American Literature Association Annual Conference, May 2024.</p>
<p>Emerson read and thought broadly across religious texts and traditions. He studied the Bhagavad Gita, the Qur’an, the Analects of Confucius, St. Augustine’s Confessions, and the works of Emanuel Swedenborg. He read the Quakers, the Stoics, and the Mystics, and he drew inspiration from individuals as diverse as Mary Moody Emerson, William Ellery Channing, Sampson Reed, Friedrich Schelling, and Germaine de Staël. This panel invites papers on Emerson and varieties of religious experience from the nineteenth-century until now. Topics might include, but are not limited to, texts and traditions that influenced Emerson’s religious thought; Emerson’s influence on later religious thinkers; the scholarly reception of Emerson’s religion; connections between religious experience and aesthetics; and the role of religion in social justice movements.</p>
<p>Please send a title and an approximately 250-word abstract to <a href="mailto:thomas.howard@wustl.edu">thomas.howard@wustl.edu</a> by January 12, 2024.</p>
<p> </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 15:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1701239822972962</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Emerson and William James at ALA 2024</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/11/26/emerson-and-william-james-at-ala-2024</link>
						<dc:creator>prentissclark@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, November 28, 2023 - 12:18pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Ralph Waldo Emerson Society &amp; William James Society</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:thomas.howard@wustl.edu">thomas.howard@wustl.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/general-announcements">general announcements</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/theory">theory</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>January 12, 2024</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>The Emerson Society and the William James Society will co-sponsor a panel titled "Emerson &amp; Varieties of Religious Experience" at the American Literature Association Annual Conference, May 2024.</p>
<p>It is well known that William James considered himself to be Ralph Waldo Emerson’s spiritual heir. Their lives were intertwined: Emerson was James’s godfather, and Emerson was so close with the James family that one room in their New York house was designated as “Mr. Emerson’s room” due to frequent visits. James also took an intellectual interest in Emerson. Even early on, as Robert Richardson describes, Emerson “was certainly vividly present in [James’s] imagination.” While James disagreed with many of Emerson’s more transcendental claims, in 1903 William wrote to his brother Henry to exclaim, “Emerson is exquisite!” </p>
<p>This panel seeks papers exploring the interconnections between Emerson and William James.</p>
<p>Topics may include their shared philosophical, religious, or literary perspectives; their transnational influence; biographical connections; philosophical disagreements; or blended comparisons (e.g. “Emerson’s pragmatism” or “James’s transcendentalism”). Papers with interdisciplinary perspectives—philosophy, psychological, ecology, religious studies, etc.—are especially welcome.</p>
<p>Please send a title and an approximately 250-word abstract to <a href="mailto:thomas.howard@wustl.edu">thomas.howard@wustl.edu</a> by January 12, 2024.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 15:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1701239822972961</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
