<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:20:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:20:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&rid=632bab40e17b9&user=wyattphd-admin&token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>CfP &quot;“Catholic Abolitionisms&quot;, Trier (Germany), June 15-16, 2023</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10953455/cfp-%E2%80%9Ccatholic-abolitionisms-trier-germany-june-15-16-2023</link>
						<dc:creator>Miriam  Franchina</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-15T00:00:00-04:00">June 15, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-16T00:00:00-04:00">June 16, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Germany</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Atlantic History / Studies, Latin American and Caribbean History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Slavery, Spanish and Portuguese History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><div><span><span>Damien Tricoire (Universität Trier), Miriam Franchina (Universität Trier), and Jeremy Popkin (Univ. of Kentucky) are organizing a conference entitled “</span><span><b>Catholic Abolitionisms</b></span><span>.” The conference will be held in </span><span><b>Trier (Germany) on June 15-16, 2023</b></span><span>. </span></span></div><div><span><span>We invite interested scholars to send a <strong>250-word proposal for a 20 minutes presentation </strong>to Miriam Franchina  (</span><a href="mailto:franchina@uni-trier.de"><span>franchina@uni-trier.de</span></a><span>) <strong>by September 30, 2022. </strong></span></span></div><p><span><span>If accepted, speakers will be asked to circulate a draft of their talk shortly before the conference.</span> </span></p><div><span><span>Usually, historiography tends to associate abolitionist movements with Protestant and anglophone movements. Our central question is whether or not, and to what extent, Catholicism inspired abolitionist ideas and movements in the Atlantic world during the early modern era. We use “abolitionisms” in the plural to include instances that may not be connected because of their chronological or geographical distance and to suggest a comparative dimension. We think that a variety of actors (clergymen, indigenous populations, enslaved Africans and Afro-Creoles, members of the Roman Curia, intellectuals in Europe and the Americas, both in colonial times and after independence) may have resorted to Catholic ideas as an argument to criticize the slave trade and colonial slavery fundamentally; and to Catholic networks to concretely reform and possibly abolish the slave trade. </span></span></div><div><span> </span></div><div><span><span>Topics for the conference include (but are not limited to):</span></span></div><ol><li><span><span>The attitude and actions of specific groups of clergy (notably religious orders) to the question of slavery and slave trade, for example, how the Dominicans with Las Casas (16th c.), or the Capuchins with De Jaca and Moirans (17th c.) substantially contested slavery and the slave trade.</span></span></li><li><span><span>The attitude and ensuing actions taken by the Roman Curia based on reports and requests coming from missionaries across the world, both before and after officially condemning slavery in 1839 (for example, the 11 articles issued in 1686 on the enslavement of Africans; or the ad-hoc deliberations on specific “cases of conscience” submitted by missionaries from the Americas).</span></span></li><li><span><span>Catholic-inspired movements of protest and rebellion by indigenous people in the Americas, for example, the rebellion led by the messianic leader Juan Santos Atahualpa in Peru (second half of the 18th c.).</span></span></li><li><span><span>Catholic-inspired movements of protest and rebellion by enslaved Africans and Afro-Creoles in the Americas and West and Central Africa, for example, the messianic and reform Catholicism movement led by the Beatriz Kimpa Vita in the Kingdom of Kongo (early 18th c. ).</span></span></li><li><span><span>Catholic-inspired intellectual circles and networks in Europe and the Americas in the age of abolition, for example, the Abbé Gregoire’s political action and treatises during the French Revolution.</span></span></li><li><span><span>The influence of Catholic-inspired arguments against slavery on intellectuals and politicians who acted in a secular sphere or were personally Protestant, for example, Brissot’s abolitionism.</span></span></li><li><span><span>Trans-confessional networks that debated abolitionism with religious arguments, for example, King Christophe of Haiti and the English abolitionist Thomas Clarkson</span></span></li></ol><div><span><span>Please note that we do not have a precise overview of the funding available at this stage. It would be helpful if you could kindly let us know whether you had any traveling funds available. Online attendance can also be arranged. To learn more about the venue, check out </span><a href="https://nam04.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fmy.matterport.com%2Fshow%2F%3Fm%3D3MiYmELXfpw&amp;data=05%7C01%7Cpopkin%40uky.edu%7Cf5dd6d041403468b9ec008da93ff1e21%7C2b30530b69b64457b818481cb53d42ae%7C0%7C0%7C637985021188587918%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=r131DAEp1Rf3JkOPt4K4KrqOXOPOhBeimRLCBehFovk%3D&amp;reserved=0" rel="nofollow"><span>this virtual tour of the Schatzkammer</span></a><span> of the City Library of Trier.</span></span></div><div><span> </span></div><div><span><span>I am looking forward to hearing from you.</span></span></div><div><span> </span></div><div><span><span>Do not hesitate to contact me for any further queries.</span></span></div><div> </div><div><span><span>Miriam Franchina</span></span></div><p><span><span><a href="mailto:franchina@uni-trier.de">franchina@uni-trier.de</a></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Miriam Franchina</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:franchina@uni-trier.de">franchina@uni-trier.de</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 20:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663738629996306</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FEATURED JOB: Postdoctoral Fellow in Humanities (Andrew W. Mellon Fellows)- Asian University for Women</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10948597/featured-job-postdoctoral-fellow-humanities-andrew-w-mellon</link>
						<dc:creator>Kendra Fuller</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Home Office Notices (Jobs, Reviews)</div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Bangladesh</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Humanities, History Education, Literature, Philosophy, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><strong>Postdoctoral Fellow in Humanities (Andrew W. Mellon Fellows)</strong></p><p>The Andrew W. Mellon Foundation has announced a major grant to the Asian University for Women in Chittagong (Bangladesh) to create and support a new Humanities major that will combine Literature, History, Philosophy and Comparative Religion, supported by extracurricular activities in music, dance, photography and the visual arts.</p><p>AUW is seeking applications from candidates who have recently acquired PhDs from reputable universities in the fields of History, Literature, Philosophy, or Comparative Religious Studies for appointment as Andrew W. Mellon Fellows at AUW. The appointments, based in Chittagong, will be for two years on completion of which the Fellows may be considered for appointment as Assistant Professors.</p><p>We seek candidates who are rooted in their disciplines and at the same time passionate about the potential of interdisciplinary work; who can inspire students with an understanding of the relationship of theory and practice in understanding the world; who can engage creatively with the students to understand multiple forms of oppression and resistance, whether through written texts or through religious practices. Past courses taught at AUW <strong>include Literature of Social Reflection; Banned Books; Shakespeare; Literature as Resistance to Oppression; Poetry of Faiz, Darwish, and Neruda; Greek Tragedies</strong>; History of Empires; South Asian History; South East Asian History; Women’s History; History of Those Without History; Labor Movement History; History of Industrialization; Socially Engaged Buddhism; Asexuality in Contemporary Global Fiction; and Islam and Gender.</p><p>Fellows in History will most likely have interests in topics that relate to hegemony and resistance; in  Literature in postcolonial and comparative literature; in Comparative Religion in people’s lived religious experience, for example sufism, rather than textual analysis; in Philosophy in moral philosophy, philosophy of science and critical theory.</p><p>The Andrew W. Mellon Fellows will work as a team with the Dean of Humanities and colleagues in Bangladesh and internationally to develop a Humanities major at AUW.</p><p><strong>Vacancies: </strong>Nine</p><p><strong>Areas of interest</strong>: History, Literature, Philosophy and Comparative Religious Studies</p><p><strong>Employment Status: </strong>Full-time contractual</p><p><strong>Job Location: </strong>Chittagong, Bangladesh</p><p><strong>Job Context:</strong> Developing AUW’s capacity to teach the humanities from an Asian perspective and to generate fresh and exciting ideas</p><p><strong>Core Responsibilities</strong>:</p><ul><li>Research and publication in the applicant’s area of specialization</li><li>Teaching two courses per term (four per year).</li><li>Program development</li><li>Other duties as assigned by Dean of Humanities</li></ul><p><strong>Qualifications and Experience Required:</strong></p><ul><li>Doctorate from recognized university in relevant field</li><li>Demonstrated ability to think and work outside disciplinary boundaries</li><li>Experience of working in a liberal arts environment in a well-established university or college</li><li>Excellent command of spoken and written English</li><li>Experience of working in a multicultural environment with excellent communication skills</li><li>Appropriate IT skills</li><li>Excellent interpersonal skills and capacity to work collaboratively, build constructive partnerships and to engage in effective teamwork</li><li>Ability to represent the University in a professional manner and to communicate effectively and persuasively</li></ul><p>Female candidates are strongly encouraged to apply.</p><p>Andrew W. Mellon Fellowships will come with funds for research and travel. Each Andrew W. Mellon Fellow will have the opportunity to continue his or her research and to identify a mentor to work with them. Selected candidates will receive a salary of $30,000 per annum, tax-free in Bangladesh (except for Bangladeshi citizens) plus free housing and access to meals at the AUW dining halls at no cost. Local transportation between the residential accommodation and the campus runs on a regular schedule.</p><p><strong>Candidates with spouses who have similar intellectual pedigrees and interests are encouraged to apply. Similarly, candidates with particular connections or interests in the region are emphatically encouraged to apply.</strong></p><p><strong>Start Date:</strong> 1 July 2023. Earlier or later start dates are negotiable.</p><p><strong>Application Deadline:</strong> Applications should be submitted by January 15, 2023.</p><p><strong>To Apply:</strong></p><p>Interested applicants should send their CVs along with a Cover Letter detailing how their qualifications, skills, abilities and experience meet the specific requirements of the role, as outlined in the job description; teaching and research statements; and three references (Name &amp; Contact Information), addressing to <strong><a href="mailto:jobs@auw.edu.bd">jobs@auw.edu.bd</a></strong>. In addition to the other documents, applicants should also send an illustrative course description and syllabus. <strong>Please mention the position applied for in the subject line.</strong> The review of applications will begin immediately. Only short-listed candidates will be contacted.</p><hr/><p>To submit YOUR job posting, please visit the H-Net Job Guide:<a href="https://www.h-net.org/jobs" rel="nofollow"> https://www.h-net.org/jobs</a></p><p>Featured jobs receive an added boost on H-Announce and H-Net’s social media channels.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><a href="mailto:jobs@auw.edu.bd">jobs@auw.edu.bd</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php" target="_blank">https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php?id=64023</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 17:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663738629996305</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Art of Ruling: Ancient Conceptions of Leadership in a Global Context</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/09/19/the-art-of-ruling-ancient-conceptions-of-leadership-in-a-global-context</link>
						<dc:creator>gkaravitis</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, September 20, 2022 - 9:34pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Gerasimos Karavitis</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:gk59@nyu.edu">gk59@nyu.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/classical-studies">classical studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/theory">theory</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>September 19, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Call for Papers
</p><p>Comparative Political Theory Conference</p>
<p>Title: “The Art of Ruling: Ancient Conceptions of Leadership in a Global Context”</p>
<p>Date: December 3, 2022</p>
<p>Location: New York University, Liberal Studies (726 Broadway, 6th Floor)</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Description:</strong></p>
<p>The conference invites submissions on ancient conceptions of political leadership. It intends to be global in scope, bringing together perspectives that emerged in multiple ancient civilizations. Examples of such civilizations include the Babylonian, Chinese, Egyptian, Greek, Judean, Indian, Mayan, Nubian, Persian, and Roman civilizations. How did thinkers in ancient times understand the qualities of a good leader? How did they conceptualize the relationship between rulers and ruled? What challenges did they think leadership entails? From what lived experiences did their conceptions emerge? Did a conception of leaderless politics appear anywhere in the ancient world? How do ancient conceptions of leadership differ from those of the modern era? And how might ancient conceptions of leadership continue to inform our views of leadership today? We invite direct commentaries on the works of ancient thinkers (e.g., Confucius, Plato) as well as papers on later thinkers who interpreted the ancients (e.g., Arendt, Foucault). While the conference relates to a central theme in political theory, we welcome papers that explore ancient conceptions of leadership from multiple disciplinary standpoints (e.g., history, biography, literature, mythology).</p>
<p><strong>Format:</strong></p>
<p>The conference will take place in person. Presentations should be no longer than twenty-five minutes in length.  </p>
<p><strong>Abstracts:</strong></p>
<p>Please submit a two hundred fifty word abstract for papers here <a href="https://www.cptls.org/" target="_blank" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.cptls.org/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1663684409698000&amp;usg=AOvVaw2zzYvkyETcpOxpI-1w5meq">https://www.cptls.org</a>   </p>
<p>The deadline for submitting abstracts is October 15, 2022. Please include the proposed title of your paper along with the abstract.</p>
<p><strong>Correspondence:</strong></p>
<p>Notification of acceptance will be sent no later than November 1.</p>
<p><strong>Inquiries:</strong></p>
<p>Please direct all inquiries to <a href="mailto:cptlsinfo@gmail.com" target="_blank">cptlsinfo@gmail.com</a></p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 15:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663738629996304</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Special Issue &quot;Religion and the Working Class in Film&quot;</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/09/19/special-issue-religion-and-the-working-class-in-film</link>
						<dc:creator>sdiasbranco@fl.uc.pt</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, September 20, 2022 - 9:24pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Religions</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:sdiasbranco@fl.uc.pt">sdiasbranco@fl.uc.pt</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/film-and-television">film and television</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/popular-culture">popular culture</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>March 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Special Issue "Religion and the Working Class in Film"</p>
<p>edited by Sérgio Dias Branco (University of Coimbra)</p>
<p> </p>
<p>This Special Issue, entitled “Religion and the Working Class in Film”, aims to combine the latest developments in the study of religion and film with new approaches in working-class studies. Recently, research within the study of religion and film has produced more concrete studies regarding precise topics and works. At the same time, new working-class studies have given special importance to the cultural expressions that emerge from working-class people and evoke their complex, multifaceted, and intersectional experiences. The main purpose of this Special Issue is to publish contributions that investigate the links between religion and the working class in film grounded in these current discussions.</p>
<p>Scholarship on religion and film—from philosophical, theological, and cultural perspectives—has increased in quantity and quality in recent years. Publications by Inge Kirsner (Komm und sieh: Religion im Film, 2020), Stefanie Knauss (Religion and Film: Representation, Experience, Meaning, 2020), S. Brent Plate (Religion and Film: Cinema and the Re-Creation of the World, 2nd ed., 2017), as well as those by M. Gail Hamner, Terry Lindvall, Gerard Loughlin, John C. Lyden, Joel W. Martin, and Melanie Wright, among others, have promoted and advanced discussions regarding the complex relations between film and religion. Additionally, some researchers have concentrated on specific religious traditions—e.g., Nathan Abrams (The New Jew in Film: Exploring Jewishness and Judaism in Contemporary Cinema, 2012), Francisca Cho (“Imagining Nothing and Imaging Otherness in Buddhist Film”, 1999), Christopher Deacy (Screen Christologies: Redemption and the Medium of Film, 2002), and Kristian Petersen (edited, New Approaches to Islam in Film, 2021)—and others have focused on filmmakers—e.g., Christopher B. Barnett and Clark J. Elliston (edited, Theology and the Films of Terrence Malick, 2018) or Joel Mayward (The Dardenne Brothers’ Cinematic Parables: Integrating Theology, 2022). This effort to limit the scope of research within the study of religion and film has produced more concrete studies regarding precise topics and works.</p>
<p>A topic that may be fruitfully paired with religion in the study of film is the representation of the working class. Recently, researchers such as John Russo and Sherry Lee Linkon (edited, New Working-Class Studies, 2005) have identified and sought to define new trends in working-class studies. A feature of these tendencies is the way they place the working class at the center of inquiry, rather than as a subsequent topic that surfaces from research into social and economic history. The working class works differently in the workplace, in the household, and in communities, and it is shaped by race, gender, sexuality, ethnicity, and place, but also religion. These new studies have given special importance to the cultural expressions that emerge from working-class people and evoke their experiences.</p>
<p>This Special Issue seeks research that considers the developments in the study of religion and film and the new methodological approaches in the working-class studies outlined above. Authors should investigate the links between religion and the working class in film grounded in these current discussions.</p>
<p>Research topics may include (but are not limited to) the following, articulated with specific or comparative analyses of films, individually or in a group:</p>
<ul>
<li>Religion and labor activism;</li>
<li>Religion and the migration and displacement of workers;</li>
<li>Religion and colonialism;</li>
<li>Religion and working-class environments and backgrounds;</li>
<li>Class conflicts in religious settings and contexts;</li>
<li>Cooperation and antagonism between working-class people from different religions;</li>
<li>Cultural politics of the working class as shaped by religion;</li>
<li>Labor unions and progressive politics linked with religious doctrine and organizations;</li>
<li>Intersectional readings that relate religion and class with race, gender, sexuality, ethnicity, and place;</li>
<li>Religions and their connections with disadvantaged social strata.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p>More information here: <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/journal/religions/special_issues/ELT133384M">https://www.mdpi.com/journal/religions/special_issues/ELT133384M</a></p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 10:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663738629996303</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Applications: Thriving in Diverse Contexts</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10943788/call-applications-thriving-diverse-contexts</link>
						<dc:creator>Clifford Anderson</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Fellowship</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-01T00:00:00-04:00">June 1, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2025-05-31T00:00:00-04:00">May 31, 2025</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>New Jersey</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>“What makes for human thriving?” If you are a researcher in the field of Christian theology working on the question of human thriving in the contemporary era, we invite you to apply for this exciting program at the Center of Theological Inquiry in Princeton, NJ (USA).</p><p>This question about the concept and conditions of human flourishing around the world is at the core of the Center’s new cross-training program in the psychological sciences for researchers in any branch of Christian theology, including systematic, philosophical, moral, practical, biblical, and postcolonial theologies. CTI invites theologians who are conducting research on human thriving in their context, or on related themes, to apply for a two-year study program on psychological science and its critical evaluation and application in theologies of thriving.</p><p>Successful applicants will join one of the two peer groups of six theologians in the study and research phases of this cross-training program in psychology, June 2023 - May 2025.</p><p>Applicants should hold an advanced degree in Christian theology or equivalent and a full-time faculty position at an accredited Higher Education Institution. Applications Portal open: October 1, 2022 – January 15, 2023. For more information and to apply, go to <a href="https://www.ctinquiry.org/apply" rel="nofollow">ctinquiry.org/apply</a>.</p><p>This program is made possible by a grant from the John Templeton Foundation.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Clifford B. Anderson, PhD</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Director of Digital Research</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Center of Theological Inquiry</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/>50 Stockton Street<br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Princeton, NJ 08540</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:clifford.anderson@ctinquiry.org">clifford.anderson@ctinquiry.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.ctinquiry.org/" target="_blank">https://www.ctinquiry.org/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 20:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663652228945949</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Newcombe Fellowships--Deadline 11/15</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10943346/newcombe-fellowships-deadline-1115</link>
						<dc:creator>Lindsay Smith</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Fellowship</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-15T00:00:00-05:00">November 15, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Social Sciences, Graduate Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Newcombe Fellows are late-stage Ph.D. students in the humanities and social sciences whose research in some way attends to those commitments and ideals and seeks to understand the communities, social practices, and political arrangements that embody them</p><h2>The Fellowship Award</h2><p>Newcombe Fellows receive $30,000 for 12 months of full-time dissertation writing. (No half-year or partial awards are allowed.)</p><ul><li>20 non-renewable fellowships of $30,000 will be awarded in the spring of 2023.</li><li>Fellows’ graduate schools will be asked to waive tuition and fees while maintaining health insurance for Newcombe Fellows.</li><li>Fellows become part of a network of more than 1,300 Newcombe Fellows leading the way in their various fields.</li></ul><p> </p><h2>Eligibility</h2><p>Eligible applicants for the 2023 Charlotte W. Newcombe Doctoral Dissertation Fellowship must:</p><ul><li>be candidates for Ph.D. degrees in any field of study in the humanities and social sciences at accredited graduate schools in the United States. Candidates working on D.Min., law, Psy.D., Ed.D. and other professional degrees are not eligible.</li><li>have completed all pre-dissertation requirements fulfilled by the application deadline November 15, 2022, including approval of the dissertation proposal.</li><li>be in the writing stage of the dissertation. Usually, this means that fieldwork or other research is complete and writing has begun by the time of the award.</li><li>must expect to complete the dissertation between April 1, 2024 and August 31, 2025.</li><li>have never held a similar national award for the final year of dissertation writing. Applicants who have won such awards as the AAUW, Ford, NAEd/Spencer, Mellon/ACLS, or Mellon-CES fellowship are not eligible.</li><li>be in a humanities or social science department, writing on topics where ethical or religious values are a central concern.</li><li>Prior applicants who did not receive the award when they first applied may reapply if their revised timeline meets Newcombe Fellowship guidelines for completion and defense.</li></ul></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Jere Hogans, Program Officer</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:newcombe@citizensandscholars.org">newcombe@citizensandscholars.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://citizensandscholars.org/fellowships/for-scholars-education-leaders/charlotte-w-newcombe-fellowship/" target="_blank">https://citizensandscholars.org/fellowships/for-scholars-education-leaders/charlotte-w-newcombe-fellowship/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 20:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663652228945948</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Temple Cultures and Traditions of India</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10918385/temple-cultures-and-traditions-india</link>
						<dc:creator>SWATI  GOEL</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-09-30T00:00:00-04:00">September 30, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>India</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Art, Art History &amp; Visual Studies, Intellectual History, Literature, Religious Studies and Theology, South Asian History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Braj Sanskriti Shodh Sansthan (A Research Academy for History, Archaeology, Art, Literature and Folk Culture of Braj)</p><p>Mandir Shri Dham Goda Vihar Premises, Vrindavan, Mathura-281121</p><p><u><strong>Invites</strong></u></p><p>Abstracts for Three Day National Conference: <em><strong>Temple Cultures and Traditions of India</strong></em></p><p>25th to 27th November 2022</p><p><strong>Call For Papers: </strong>Braj Sanskriti Shodh Sansthan, Vrindavan, invites proposals for an interdisciplinary conference.</p><p>The papers and subsequent presentations should connect broadly with our aim to understand the temple culture and traditions of India from multiple standpoints. Please send in your Abstracts of about 500 words by <strong>30th of September, 2022</strong> to <strong><em><a href="mailto:Bsssseminar@gmail.com">Bsssseminar@gmail.com</a></em></strong> The selected participants would be informed by the 15th of October, 2022 and will be required to submit their full papers by the 15th of November, 2022. The conference is scheduled to be held on<strong> 25th, 26th and 27th of November 2022.</strong> The institute will also organise a Heritage Walk on the Historical temples of Vrindavan (detailed schedule of the conference to be released later) .</p><p><strong>Format </strong> The language of the Abstract and respective papers can be either Hindi or English.  They should be typed in Times New Roman font in case of English and Kruti Dev 10 font for Hindi and must be thoroughly proofread.  The Abstracts must include the Name of the Scholars and their professional affiliation. </p><p><strong>Concept Note</strong></p><p>Temples have been an inextricable part of Indian society; within the diversity of the cultures, they have often served the society in multiple faceted ways. In the textual traditions, temples have been perceived as Purush and Prakriti, both immutably depicting the cosmos. The connection with the divine, whether as an individual, group or community, is as personal as it is shared. Temples encapsulate this spirit by acting as sites of sacred space where the revered is the supreme and the devotee a participant in its grandeur. Historically temples have always had a central role to play in the normal functioning of society. Within the several hierarchies of temples being dedicated from Gram devta, Kul devta, Tirtha sthal to Dham, temples have served as public spaces with a binding factor. Therefore, it also gives rise to the material and non-material cultures around themselves.</p><p>The Indian Temple has been hailed as a ‘Monument of Manifestation’ by the eminent art historian Stella Kramrisch. This statement has not even a modicum of fiction in it. Hinduism certainly has a hoary history, and its antiquity could be traced back at least to the Rig Vedic Period. Yajña or the institution of sacrifice, was the core of the Vedic Religion. The Yajur Veda and the Brāhmaṇa texts contain mantras or sacrificial formulae and elaborate injunctions pertaining to the performance of Yajñas. These Vedic Yajñas would be conducted in specially constructed Vedic altars known as chitis. The construction of these chitis was an architectural science, and in their simplest forms, the chitis were a pile of bricks. As time advanced, there was marked shift from Yajñas to worship images in specially built enclosures or temples. However, despite the Yajña rituals gradually waning into the background, the structures of temples owe their origins to the Vedic chitis. The act of temple construction was considered equivalent to a Yajña and was to be initiated in strict confirmation of the prescribed set of rituals. The emergence and dissemination of Bhakti and the ever-growing prominence of sects like Bhāgavata and Śaiva added to the functional and spiritual relevance of temples. The Dharmaśāstra texts incorporated the building of temples in the category of Pūrta Dharmas, and a person belonging to any varṇa could undertake the tasks which were included in the Pūrta Dharma.</p><p>The Epics and Purāṇas comprise many references to temples, and those like the Agni and Matsya Purāṇas provide detailed instructions about the creation of temples and consecration of images in them. Moreover, texts specially dedicated to the science of temple building were written and widely used by the sthapatis. Speaking from an 3 archaeological perspective, the history of temples goes back to the Mauryan Period. We find a depiction of small shrines in the reliefs from the Buddhist Stupa sites of Bharhut and Sanchi in Madhya Pradesh and Mathurā. Epigraphical evidences from the Śuṅga Period onward also provide testimony to the construction of shrines which archaeological evidences have to a great extent corroborated. The structures of temples became more elaborate and codified from the Gupta Period onward. Apart from the Guptas, dynasties like the Vākāṭakas in central India and the Badami Cālukyas and Pallavas in Karnataka and Tamil Nadu respectively pioneered the creation of temples- both rock-cut and structural. During the Gupta period we find a systematic categorization of temples based on their shapes and dimensions. Around the same time, temple architecture manifested itself in three principal idioms- Nāgara, Draviḍa, and Vesara. Apart from these three major architectural styles, several regional styles of temple building originated and matured in various parts of India. From simple shrine like structures, temples now assumed colossal forms equipped with a garbhagṛha (sanctum sanctorum), a line of maṇḍapas or halls, massive śikharas, and shrines of parivāra devatas.</p><p>By the early medieval period, individual temples metamorphosed into temple complexes, and these temple complexes grew into the cultural hubs of contemporary society. It was mainly through the institution of temples that performing arts like music and dance, fine arts like sculpture and paintings, and culinary traditions of bhoga were inextricably connected. Temples no longer remained purely religious establishments- they took on multi-dimensional roles as educational, economic, social, and political epicentres shaping the aesthetic expression of the then societies. Many dynasties, merchants, and common people contributed munificently towards the construction of temples. Hinduism came to be almost completely identified with temples, and art historian George Michell has opined that the Hinduism that developed around the start of the 1st millennium CE is, to a great extent, ‘Temple Hinduism’. This statement aptly summarizes the vital position of temples in the gamut of Hinduism. The temples of India not merely evoke a profound veneration towards a deity through various ritual enactments and festivals but also have been subjected to a magnificent oeuvre of cultures when devotees throng its premises from parts of the country. They facilitate intercultural dialogue and circulate the idea of multiplicity of cultures with deeply rooted human values of shared experiences, respect, and togetherness.</p><p>The conference therefore, aims to bring together researchers from all disciplines to deliberate upon the philosophical, religious, social, economic, technical, artistic, ethnographic, traditional, landscape, material, and non-material aspects of temples.</p><p><strong>Broad Themes of the conference:</strong> The topics may include, but are not restricted to:  Art and Architecture of the temples</p><p> Temples as centres of learning: Textual Traditions of the temples</p><p> Economic and political patronage of the temples</p><p> Temple Pilgrimage, Ecology and the Environment</p><p> Urbanism and the Temples</p><p> Temples as Economic spaces</p><p> Temple Food culture: Bhoga &amp; Śṛṅgāra Paramparā</p><p> Rāga Paramparā : Musical traditions associated with the temples</p><p> Folklore and Oral narratives shaping the temple cultures</p><p> Conservation and Preservation of the temples</p><p> Mobility of the temples</p><p> Social justice: Caste, Untouchability, and access to temples</p><p> House temples and the idea of service</p><p> Temple without deities</p><p> Sampradāyas and the temples</p><p> Temple Festivals and feasts</p><p> Temples and the colonial state</p><p> Performative temple arts</p><p>A nominal amount of Rs. 800/- can be paid online or on arrival. The institute will provide accommodation and food facilities; however, the travel expenses will solely be the responsibility of the participants. Selected Scholars will have to get themselves registered through Emails.</p><p>Please feel free to contact conference organizers for any queries on the above-given Email Id </p><p>Braj Sanskriti Shodh Sansthan Shri Dham Goda Vihar Temple Premises, Gopeshwar Marg,Vrindavan -281121, Mathura, U.P, India</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><a href="mailto:Bsssseminar@gmail.com">Bsssseminar@gmail.com</a>, <a href="mailto:swativenki90@gmail.com">swativenki90@gmail.com</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:Bsssseminar@gmail.com">Bsssseminar@gmail.com</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 19:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663652228945947</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ October 28, 2022 -  October 29, 2022] Conference or similar: Ipoteze religioase în studiul naturii umane</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103106</link>
						<description>Venue: Bulevardul Vasile Pârvan 4<br/><br/><p><strong>Ipoteze Religioase în Studiul Naturii Umane</strong></p>

<p>Universitatea de Vest din Timișoara, 28-29 octombrie 2022</p>

<p>Amfiteatrul A01, Bd. Vasile Pârvan Nr. 4, Timișoara</p>

<p><a href="https://religioushypotheses.com/conference">https://religioushypotheses.com/conference</a></p>


<p>Această conferință face parte din proiectul de cercetare „Religious Hypotheses and the Study of Human Nature” și este realizată în colaborare cu Universitatea de Vest din Timișoara (UVT), programul de masterat „Practica Asistenței Sociale Centrate pe Valori” și Centrul Areopagus din Timișoara. Conferința se concentrează pe întrebarea dacă Scripturile și tradițiile religioase (în special cea creștină) pot furniza ipoteze testabile și care anume sunt rezultatele testării acestor ipoteze. Conferința reunește cercetători dintr-o gamă largă de discipline, inclusiv teologie, filosofie, medicină, lingvistică, informatică, psihologie, istorie și studii literare. Printre vorbitorii confirmați se numără:</p>


<p><strong>Alexandru Neagoe (Universitatea de Vest, Timișoara)</strong></p>

<p><strong>Charles White (Spring Arbor University, SUA)</strong></p>

<p><strong>Emanuel Țundrea (Universitatea Emanuel, Oradea)</strong></p>

<p><strong>Dan Aurel Botică (Universitatea Emanuel, Oradea)</strong></p>

<p><strong>Marius Clim (Academia Română, Filiala Iași)</strong></p>

<p><strong>Ovidiu Hanc (Universitatea Emanuel, Oradea)</strong></p>

<p><strong>Ioan Chirilă (Institutul Național de Sănătate Publică, Iași)</strong></p>

<p><strong>Denise (Daniela) Vasiliu (Universitatea Alexandru Ioan Cuza, Iași)</strong></p>

<p><strong>Ștefan Frenț (Universitatea de Medicină și Farmacie Victor Babeș, Timișoara)</strong></p>

<p><strong>Filip Popovici (Universitatea din București)</strong></p>

<p><strong>Iulia-Teodora Drișcu (Universitatea Alexandru Ioan Cuza, Iași)</strong></p>

<p><strong>Alin Christoph Cucu (Universitatea din Lausanne, Elveția)</strong></p>
<p><strong><br/></strong></p>


<p><strong>Conferința se va desfășura aproape exclusiv în limba română.</strong></p>


<p>Participarea este gratuită, nu este necesară înregistrarea.</p>


<p><strong>Burse pentru studenți</strong>: Oferim până la 6 burse de 250 USD pentru studenți români (cu excepția UVT, inclusiv doctoranzi) pentru călătorie și cazare. Pentru a aplica, vă rugăm să trimiteți următoarele documente la adresa <a href="mailto:info@religioushypotheses.com">info@religioushypotheses.com</a><strong> până la data de 30 septembrie 2022:</strong></p>

<p>·      Un CV actualizat</p>

<p>·      O scurtă scrisoare motivațională (max. 1 pagină A4)</p>

<p>Câștigătorii vor fi anunțați la câteva zile după termenul limită. De asemenea, beneficiarii burselor sunt invitați să participe la dineurile de conferință de vineri și sâmbătă seara.</p>


<p>Informații actualizate, precum și programul conferinței vor fi disponibile la:</p>

<p><a href="https://religioushypotheses.com/conference">https://religioushypotheses.com/conference</a>.  </p>


<p>„Religious Hypotheses and the Study of Human Nature” este un subproiect din cadrul programului mai amplu „<a href="https://cee.ianramseycentre.ox.ac.uk/">New Horizons for Science and Religion in Central and Eastern Europe</a>”, finanțat de Fundația John Templeton. Partenerii noștri locali sunt Fundația Agora Christi din Iași (organizare) și Academia Română din Iași (auspicii academice). </p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 05:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663479426076763</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ September 23, 2022] Conference or similar: PASOLINI AND PHILOSOPHY</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103082</link>
						<description>Venue: Cinemateca Portuguesa<br/><br/><p>This event is organized in collaboration with Cinemateca Portuguesa-Museu do Cinema and will take place within the scope of the activities of the research group Thinking Documentary Film and the research project PhilDoc – Philosophy and Documentary Film. Mediating the Real, both coordinated by Stefanie Baumann (CineLab/IFILNOVA).</p>





PROGRAMME

23/09/2022

17:00 – 20:00
Stefanie Baumann (CineLab/IFILNOVA, Universidade NOVA de Lisboa)
Introduction


Toni Hildebrandt (Department of Modern and Contemporary Art History, Institute of Art History, University of Bern)
Pasolini, une pensée


Giovanbattista Tusa (CultureLab/IFILNOVA, Universidade NOVA de Lisboa)
The Pasolinian Century


Panel discussion
With Stefanie Baumann, Toni Hildebrandt, and Giovanbattista Tusa, moderated by João Coimbra Oliveira, followed by a Q&amp;A with the audience.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 05:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663393035300894</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ September 23, 2022] Conference talk or similar: The Pasolinian Century</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103086</link>
						<description>Venue: Cinemateca Portuguesa<br/><br/>Speakers at this event: <br/>Giovanbattista Tusa (Universidade Nova de Lisboa)<br/><br/>Giovanbattista Tusa (CultureLab/IFILNOVA, Universidade NOVA de Lisboa)
The Pasolinian Century</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 05:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663393035300893</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>JOURNAL TOC&gt; The Eastern Buddhist, Third Series, volume 2, number 1</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10909086/journal-toc-eastern-buddhist-third-series-volume-2-number-1</link>
						<dc:creator>John LoBreglio</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Journal</div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Japan</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Chinese History / Studies, East Asian History / Studies, Japanese History / Studies, Korean History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Dear H-Buddhism Members,</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>We would like to announce the publication of the latest issue of <i>The Eastern Buddhist</i>, Third Series, volume 2, number 1.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><i><span><span><span>The Eastern Buddhist</span></span></span></i></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Third Series, vol. 2, no. 1, 2022</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>June 2022</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Prince Shōtoku at Age Two <i>frontispiece</i></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>ARTICLES</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Nuns and Convents in the Eison Order and the Provenance of the</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Sedgwick Shōtoku Taishi Sculpture at the Harvard Art Museums</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span><span>Matsuo Kenji</span></span></i><span><span><span>・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・ </span></span></span><span><span>1</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Reading D. T. Suzuki Anew</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span><span>Andō Reiji</span></span></i><span><span><span>・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・</span></span></span><span><span>17</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>On the Absence of Buddhist Ethics: An Examination of Interwar </span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span>Shin Writings on the Two Truths</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span><span>Jeff Schroeder</span></span></i><span><span><span>・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・</span></span></span><span><span>35</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Nāgārjuna’s Tetralemma in Yamauchi Tokuryū’s Philosophy </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span><span>Romaric Jannel</span></span></i><span><span><span>・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・</span></span></span><span><span>55</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>REVIEW ARTICLE</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span><span>Chūsei Zenseki Sōkan </span></span></i><span><span>and Issues in the Study of Medieval Zen</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span><span>Sueki Fumihiko</span></span></i><span><span><span>・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・ </span></span></span><span><span>69</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>BOOK REVIEWS</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Georgios T. Halkias and Richard K. Payne, editors. <i>Pure Lands</i></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span><span>in Asian Texts and Contexts: An Anthology </span></span></i><span><span>(<i>Ryoze Wada</i>)</span></span><span><span><span>・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・ </span></span></span><span><span>93</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Funayama Tōru. <i>Rikuchō, Zui, Tō bukkyō tenkaishi </i>(The Evolution of</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Chinese Buddhism during the Six Dynasties, Sui, and Tang</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Periods) (<i>Sangyop Lee</i>)</span></span><span><span><span>・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・ </span></span></span><span><span>97</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Yamamoto Satomi. <i>Chūsei bukkyō kaiga no zuzōshi: Kyōsetsu emaki, </i></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span><span>rokudōe, kusōzu </span></span></i><span><span>(A Genealogy of Imagery in Medieval Buddhist</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Paintings: From Six Realms of Rebirth to Nine Stages of Decay)</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>(<i>Miriam Chusid </i>)</span></span><span><span><span>・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・</span></span></span><span><span>100</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>James C. Dobbins. <i>Behold the Buddha: Religious Meanings of Japanese </i></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><i><span><span>Buddhist Icons</span></span></i></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>(<i>Sinéad Vilbar</i>)</span></span><span><span><span>・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・</span></span></span><span><span>105</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Kusunoki Junshō. <i>Jōkei sen “Yuishikiron jinshishō” no kenkyū: Butsudō</i></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span><span>hen </span></span></i><span><span>(Study of the “<i>Yuishikiron</i>” <i>Jinshishō </i>Compiled by Jōkei: </span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span>Volume on the Buddha Way)</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>(<i>Robert F. Rhodes</i>)</span></span><span><span><span>・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・</span></span></span><span><span>114</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Sujung Kim. <i>Shinra Myōjin and Buddhist Networks of the East Asian</i></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span><span>“Mediterranean”</span></span></i></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>(<i>Anna Andreeva</i>)</span></span><span><span><span>・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・  </span></span></span><span><span>119</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>BOOKS RECEIVED.</span></span><span><span><span>・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・・ </span></span></span><span><span>125</span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><b><span>Free Access</span></b><span> to past volumes of <i>The Eastern Buddhist</i> is available online both via The Eastern Buddhist Society website at </span><a href="https://ebs.otani.ac.jp/backissues.html" rel="nofollow">https://ebs.otani.ac.jp/backissues.html</a><span> and via the Otani University research repository at </span><a href="https://otani.repo.nii.ac.jp/index.php?action=pages_view_main&amp;active_action=repository_view_main_item_snippet&amp;index_id=690&amp;pn=1&amp;count=50&amp;order=17&amp;lang=japanese&amp;page_id=13&amp;block_id=28" rel="nofollow"><span>https://otani.repo.nii.ac.jp/index.php?action=pages_view_main&amp;active_action=repository_view_main_item_snippet&amp;index_id=690&amp;pn=1&amp;count=50&amp;order=17&amp;lang=japanese&amp;page_id=13&amp;block_id=28</span></a><span>.</span></span></span></p><p><span><span> </span></span><span><span><span>Please share this information with your colleagues and students.</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Subscription information can be found at </span><a href="https://ebs.otani.ac.jp/subscriptions.html" rel="nofollow">https://ebs.otani.ac.jp/subscriptions.html</a><span>.</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Volumes of <i>The Eastern Buddhist</i>, New Series and Third Series, may also be found on JSTOR in the Arts &amp; Sciences XV collection.</span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span>With our best wishes,</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>The Editorial Team of <i>The Eastern Buddhist</i></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>John LoBreglio</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Editor</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><a href="https://ebs.otani.ac.jp/" rel="nofollow">https://ebs.otani.ac.jp/</a></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:john.lobreglio@sch.otani.ac.jp">john.lobreglio@sch.otani.ac.jp</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://ebs.otani.ac.jp/" target="_blank">https://ebs.otani.ac.jp/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663393035300892</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ October 3, 2022 -  October 6, 2022] Conference or similar: The ancient Greeks and their knowledge (Los griegos antiguos y el conocimiento)</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103074</link>
						<description>Venue: Avenida Juárez 976<br/><br/><p>To participate send en email to </p>
<p>(para participar previa inscripcion enviar email a):</p>
<p><strong>Pietro Montanari </strong></p>
<p><strong>pietro.montanari@academicos.udg.mx </strong></p>
<p><strong>pietromontanari@hotmail.it </strong></p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 05:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663306637875626</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ February 28, 2023] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103050</link>
						<description>Publication Name: National Taiwan University Philosophical Review: Special Issue on Arguments in Philosophy of Religion<br/><br/><p><strong><em>National Taiwan University Philosophical Review</em></strong></p>
<p><strong>Call for Papers for Special Issue on <em>Arguments in Philosophy of Religion</em></strong></p>
<p><strong>Guest editors: Graham Oppy, Lok-Chi Chan</strong></p>
<p><strong><br/></strong></p>
<p>This special issue accepts original articles or commentaries on Graham Oppy's lead article, "Good Argument". Short commentaries on the lead article are welcome.<br/><br/></p>
<p><strong>I.             </strong><strong>Introduction </strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Established in 1971, the <em>National Taiwan University Philosophical Review</em> is a peer-reviewed journal published by the department of philosophy at National Taiwan University ( http://review.philo.ntu.edu.tw/?hl=en ). This special issue on <em>Arguments in Philosophy of Religion </em>is co-organized by the journal<em> </em>and the Center for Traditional and Scientific Metaphysics (TSM) at National Taiwan University, and is originated from the latter’s <em>Analytic Philosophy of Religion in Asia</em> (APRA) project. The APRA project aims to promote the development of the Asian community of the analytic philosophy of religion and its connection with the rest of the globe, and it has organized multiple international conferences, seminar series, and publication projects.</p>
<p>The topic of religion has been debated extensively in analytic philosophy by believers and nonbelievers alike, such as Russell, Wittgenstein, Ayer, and their successors and opponents. But an important question in philosophy, especially analytic philosophy, is what really constitutes a genuine philosophical argument. Some possible relevant questions include (but are not exclusive to):</p>
<p>(a)  Why should we expect that an argument could convince a philosophical opponent or a neutral bystander, no matter how reasonable and sound it seems to ourselves?</p>
<p>(b)  What are the conditions that must be met by a convincing argument, especially when your targets have fundamental disagreements with your basic worldview and methodology?</p>
<p>(c)  Do the cosmological arguments, teleological arguments, arguments from evil, arguments from hiddenness, and the like, even if apparently sound, really work as intended?</p>
<p>(d)  Can we expect the success of any such argument? </p>
<p>(e)  Does the consideration of religion or the transcendent make the case special?</p>
<p>Several internationally renowned philosophers of religion were invited to contribute to this special issue.</p>
<p><strong><br/>II.            </strong><strong>Submission</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>1.    This special issue accepts <strong>English submissions</strong> only.</p>
<p>2.    This special issue accepts two kinds of submissions:<strong> <u>(a) original articles</u></strong> and <strong><u>(b) commentaries on Graham Oppy’s lead article</u></strong>.</p>
<p>3.    For Oppy’s lead article, ‘Good Argument’, see: <a href="https://reurl.cc/x9GXRV">https://reurl.cc/x9GXRV</a>  . If there are a sufficient number of commentaries, Graham Oppy will offer a response to commentators.</p>
<p>4.    The word limit is <strong><u>7000 words</u></strong>. <strong><u>Short commentaries on the lead article</u></strong> are welcome.</p>
<p>5.    Submission deadline: <strong><u>28 Feb 2023</u></strong>.</p>
<p>6.    Submissions should be sent in Microsoft Word format to <a href="mailto:ntuphilreview@gmail.com"><strong>ntuphilreview@gmail.com</strong></a><strong><u> and </u></strong><a href="mailto:tsmntu@gmail.com"><strong>tsmntu@gmail.com</strong></a><strong><u> , with the title ‘Submission to Arguments in Philosophy of Religion’.</u></strong></p>
<p>7.    Please send you submission along with a title, an abstract of 500 words, a maximum of 5 keywords, together with a separate document containing your name, brief CV, institute, position, address, phone number, and email.</p>
<p>8.    Apart from the instructions outlined above, any submission should in principle follow the regulations of a standard journal submission.</p>
<p>9.    If the submission number exceeds the possible slots of this CFP, the editorial board of the <em>NTU Philosophical Review</em> may assign a submitted article to another issue upon the author’s agreement.</p>
<p>10.For any questions, please contact Lok-Chi Chan at <a href="mailto:lokchan@ntu.edu.tw">lokchan@ntu.edu.tw</a></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>III.          </strong><strong>The guest editors</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Graham Oppy is Professor of Philosophy at Monash University, Australia and a Fellow of the Australian Academy of the Humanities, and served as the chair and CEO of the Australasian Association of Philosophy. He is currently the chief editor of the <em>Australasian Philosophical Review</em>, and serves on the editorial boards of<em> Australasian Journal of Philosophy</em>, <em>Philosophy Compass</em>, <em>Religious Studies, International Journal for Philosophy of Religion </em>and <em>Sophia.</em></p>
<p>Lok-Chi Chan is Associate Professor of Philosophy at National Taiwan University. He currently serves as the CEO of the NTU Center for Traditional and Scientific Metaphysics (TSM) and the Secretary-General of the Taiwan Association for Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science and Technology (LMPST Taiwan).</p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 05:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663306637875625</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Newberry Seminar on Religion and Culture in the Americas. Phantom Luminaries: Frederick Willis, Spiritualism, and Paranormal Investigators in the Age of Disruption,  Daniel Gorman, Jr., University of Rochester</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10894199/newberry-seminar-religion-and-culture-americas-phantom</link>
						<dc:creator>Malachy R. McCarthy</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Seminar</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-09-14T00:00:00-04:00">September 14, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-01T00:00:00-04:00">October 1, 2022</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Illinois</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology, American History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>Religion and Culture in the Americas Seminar</span></span></span></b></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span>Friday, September 30, 2022 </span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span>3:00-5:00 pm Central Time</span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span>Virtual Seminar, Register for link</span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>Phantom Luminaries: Frederick Willis, Spiritualism, and Paranormal Investigators in the Age of Disruption, </span></span></span></b></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>Daniel Gorman, Jr., University of Rochester</span></span></span></b></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span>This excerpt from my dissertation addresses Frederick Willis’s suspension from Harvard Divinity School in spring 1857. Willis was accused of fraud because he hosted Spiritualist séances off-campus in the Boston–Cambridge area. Drawing on Willis’s writings and internal documents from Harvard, this paper considers why, exactly, Harvard’s largely Unitarian faculty found Willis’s extracurricular occultism so concerning.</span></span></p><p><span><span><strong>Respondent:</strong> Christopher Allison, Dominican University</span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>This event is free, but all participants must register in advance and space is limited. To register and request a copy of the pre-circulated paper, contact <a href="mailto:scholarlyseminars@newberry.org">scholarlyseminars@newberry.org</a>.</span></span></span><span><span><span>. Please do not request a paper unless you plan to attend.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>Sponsors</span></span></span></b><span><span><span>: the Cushwa Center for the Study of American Catholicism at the University of Notre Dame, the McGreal Center at Dominican University, the History Department at Loyola University, the University of Chicago Divinity School, University of Illinois at Chicago, and Wheaton College</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><a href="mailto:scholarlyseminars@newberry.org">scholarlyseminars@newberry.org</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:scholarlyseminars@newberry.org">scholarlyseminars@newberry.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://newberry.org/09302022-daniel-gorman-jr-university-rochester" target="_blank">https://newberry.org/09302022-daniel-gorman-jr-university-rochester</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 17:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663306637875624</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Spring Academy 2023 at the Heidelberg Center for American Studies</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10889324/spring-academy-2023-heidelberg-center-american-studies</link>
						<dc:creator>Julia Patricia Nohle</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-15T00:00:00-05:00">November 15, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Germany</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>American History / Studies, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Political Science, Popular Culture Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><b><span><span>Call for Papers</span></span></b></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span>The Heidelberg Center for American Studies (HCA) invites applications for its annual Spring Academy on American Culture, Economics, Geography, History, Literature, Politics, and Religion to be held from <strong>March 20-24, 2023. </strong></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>The HCA Spring Academy provides 20 international Ph.D. students with the opportunity to present and thoroughly discuss their Ph.D. projects. Additionally, it offers workshops held by visiting scholars. </span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>We encourage applications that range broadly across the arts, humanities, and social sciences and pursue an interdisciplinary approach. Participants can present thesis projects on any subject relating to the study of the United States of America. Possible topics include American identity, issues of ethnicity, gender, transatlantic relations, U.S. domestic and foreign policy, economics, and various aspects of American history, literature, religion, geography, law, musicology, and culture. The accepted projects will be arranged into ten panel groups.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Participants are requested to prepare a 20-minute presentation of their research project, which will be followed by a 40-minute discussion. </span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>The Spring Academy aims to create a congenial atmosphere for scholarly exchange in order to inspire future collaborations and foster networking opportunities for participants. </span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>The Heidelberg Center for American Studies is prepared to provide accommodation during the conference week. </span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Thanks to a small travel fund, the Spring Academy can subsidize travel expenses for participants registered and residing in developing and soft-currency countries. Applicants for the travel fund must document the necessity for financial aid and explain how they plan to cover any potentially remaining expenses. Additionally, a letter of recommendation from their doctoral advisor is required.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Due to the ongoing pandemic the HCA reserves the right to adapt the conference structure and host the event online if necessary.</span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Jules Nohle and Virginia Zentgraf</p><p>Spring Academy Organizing Team</p><p>University of Heidelberg</p><p>Heidelberg Center for American Studies</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:springacademy@hca.uni-heidelberg.de">springacademy@hca.uni-heidelberg.de</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.hca.uni-heidelberg.de/spring/applicationspring_en.html" target="_blank">https://www.hca.uni-heidelberg.de/spring/applicationspring_en.html</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663220229954138</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Alevi Pasts Contested: Call for Papers to Workshop on Alevi Historiography</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10889323/alevi-pasts-contested-call-papers-workshop-alevi</link>
						<dc:creator>markus dressler</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-09-15T00:00:00-04:00">September 15, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-08T00:00:00-05:00">November 8, 2022</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Germany</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Cultural History / Studies, Ethnic History / Studies, Islamic History / Studies, Middle East History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>We would like to extend an invitation to submit papers to a workshop on Alevi historiography at Leipzig University on 5-7 October 2023.</p><p>The workshop is a first step towards the publication of an edited volume on Alevi<br/>historiography and all participants are expected to present drafts of chapters for the<br/>publication at the workshop. The invitation is extended to all scholars on Alevis and Alevism<br/>who are interested in critically engaging with historiographies surrounding Alevi communities<br/>and the field of Alevi studies.<br/>The specific focus on historiography for this workshop directs our attention to accounts and<br/>narratives on (the) Alevi past(s) and relevant discussions on the role and function of these<br/>accounts. Such accounts of the past are shared and communicated within Alevi communities,<br/>between Alevi communities and in dialogue or opposition to various others – such as Sunni<br/>Muslims, Turkish state agencies, or scholars of Alevism. There may be questions of labelling,<br/>representation, visibility, authenticity, legitimation as well as material interests, such as the<br/>distribution of resources and access to social and political power involved in the creation and<br/>communication of such accounts of the past.<br/>Thus, we are looking for contributions that present new empirical material or novel researchbased<br/>perspectives on Alevi historiography and focus either on<br/>• historiography as the Alevi emic processes of understanding, negotiating and<br/>demarcating Alevi history, or<br/>• historiography as the academic study of the history of, and discourses on, Alevism<br/>and Alevi communities</p><p>If you are interested in presenting at the workshop, please send a 300-500 word abstract and<br/>a 150-word bio by November 8, 2022 to <a href="mailto:Hege.Markussen@ctr.lu.se">Hege.Markussen@ctr.lu.se</a>. Selections will be<br/>finalised by December 16, 2022 and the final deadline for submitting draft of the articles for<br/>the workshop is August 15, 2023. Limited funding for travel and accommodation is available<br/>for those without institutional support.</p><p>Markus Dressler, Institute for the Study of Religions, Leipzig University</p><p>Hege Markussen, Centre for Theology and Religious Studies, Lund University</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:Hege.Markussen@ctr.lu.se">Hege.Markussen@ctr.lu.se</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.gkr.uni-leipzig.de/fileadmin/Fakult%C3%A4t_GKR/Religionswissenschaftliches_Institut/Dokumente/Alevi_Pasts_-_call_for_papers.pdf" target="_blank">https://www.gkr.uni-leipzig.de/fileadmin/Fakult%C3%A4t_GKR/Religionswissenschaftliches_Institut/Dokumente/Alevi_Pasts_-_…</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 17:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663220229954137</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Anglican and Episcopal History reexamines Absalom Jones, discovers Anglican-Huguenots in Virginia, and considers the Royal Society</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10886149/anglican-and-episcopal-history-reexamines-absalom-jones</link>
						<dc:creator>Matthew Payne</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Journal</div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Wisconsin</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>African American History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span>The autumn issue of <i>Anglican and Episcopal History</i> considers 3 vastly different influences in the Anglican tradition: the Black freedom struggle, French Huguenots, and King Charles II’s Royal Society.</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>“The Episcopal Church was born in a racialized context visible to the Black population of the early republic,” writes D.A. Dunkley. He invites readers to recontextualize celebrated priest Absalom Jones within the Black freedom struggle and culture of Black enslaved people to understand better the influences on Jones’ leadership and ministry shaping the Episcopal Church and becoming its first Black American priest in 1802.</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>The study is titled, “Black Radicalism in the Episcopal Church: Absalom Jones and Slave Resistance, 1746-1818.” Dunkley is associate professor of history and chair of Black Studies at the University of Missouri-Columbia.</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Lonnie H. Lee’s “Huguenot-Anglicans in Seventeenth Century Virginia” then draws on county court records to show ways the “Anglican Church played a more pivotal role in the Huguenot migration to America than historians have previously understood.” Lee, a retired Presbyterian minister, discovers a hidden Rappahannock Refuge for Huguenot Christians.</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>In the final essay, William Brown Patterson examines the Royal Society formed under King Charles II. “Religionists of a broad range of backgrounds were attracted to and welcomed by the membership in the years that followed [its founding in 1663]” and that “Faith and reason were thus joined in a cultural revolution in the early years of the [monarchy’s] Restoration.”</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>The essay is titled, “Religion and the Royal Society in Early Restoration England.” Patterson is professor of history emeritus at Sewanee: The University of the South.</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Readers are also treated to 3 church reviews. </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Church review editor J. Barrington Bates highlights a rare service presided over by 3 women bishops at Christ Church Cathedral in Vancouver, part of the Anglican Church of Canada’s Diocese of New Westminster.</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Other church reviews include Ash Wednesday at St. Edward the Confessor in Lugano, Switzerland, and the Easter Triduum at St. Margaret’s Anglican-Episcopal Church in Budapest, Hungary. Both churches are part of the Church of England’s Diocese in Europe.</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>As always, <i>AEH </i>boasts numerous book reviews related to recent church history and Anglican scholarship. Among them:</span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><i>Justifying Revolution: The American Clergy’s Argument for Political Resistance, 1750–1776</i> by Gary L. Steward | reviewed by Suzanne Geissler of William Paterson University</span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><i>The Dissolution of the Monasteries: A New History </i>by James G. Clark | Reviewed by Norman Jones of Utah State University</span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><i>Mystic Moderns: Agency and Enchantment in Evelyn Underhill, May Sinclair, and Mary Webb</i> by James H. Thrall | Reviewed by Molly James of the Episcopal Church Center</span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><i>Reclaiming the Lives of Britain’s First Mission to West Africa: Three Lives Lost and Found </i>by Fiona Leach | Reviewed by Kyle Welty of University of Texas Rio Grande Valley</span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><i>Faith and Foreign Policy in the American Century</i> by Mark Thomas Edwards | Reviewed by Justus D. Doenecke of New College of Florida</span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span>###</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><strong><span><span>About <i>Anglican and Episcopal History</i></span></span></strong><br/><span><span><em><span>Anglican and Episcopal History</span></em> (ISSN 0896-8039), formerly <em><span>The Historical Magazine of the Protestant Episcopal Church</span></em>, seeks to raise the level of discussion, provide a forum for exchange of ideas, and review books of real worth and of interest to educated Anglicans. It is published quarterly in March, June, September, and December. Full text articles are available through JSTOR.org and for members of the Historical Society of the Episcopal Church at </span></span><a href="https://hsec.us/AEH" rel="nofollow"><span><span>hsec.us/AEH</span></span></a><span><span>.</span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Matthew P. Payne, Director of Operations</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:administration@hsec.us">administration@hsec.us</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://hsec.us/news/12918242" target="_blank">https://hsec.us/news/12918242</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 17:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663220229954136</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Opportunities Digest – September 14th, 2022</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-opportunities-digest-september-14th-2022/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find several full-time and tenure track job postings, several applications for fully funded Ph.D. studentships, and one call for papers.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 37!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs</h2>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Art and Visual Culture (Emphasis on Religious Culture)</h4>



<p>Bates College, Lewiston, ME, US</p>



<p>Deadline: November 1, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.historians.org/jobs/17423174/assistant-professor-of-art-and-visual-culture">https://careers.historians.org/jobs/17423174/assistant-professor-of-art-and-visual-culture</a></p>



<h4>Modern Jewish History – Tenured Faculty</h4>



<p>Johns Hopkins University, US</p>



<p>Deadline: October 17<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.historians.org/jobs/17422508/modern-jewish-history">https://careers.historians.org/jobs/17422508/modern-jewish-history</a></p>



<h4>Lecturer in Religion and the Environment for 2023-2024 Academic Year – (Possibility of Renewal)</h4>



<p>University of Vermont, US</p>



<p>Deadline: November 1, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.uvmjobs.com/postings/56435">University of Vermont Employment Opportunities | Lecturer in Religion and the Environment (uvmjobs.com)</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Theology: New Testament – Full-Time Tenure-Track</h4>



<p>Providence College, US</p>



<p>Deadline: December 15<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.providence.edu/postings/7261">Providence College Portal | Assistant Professor of Theology-New Testament</a></p>



<h2>Studentships</h2>



<h4>2 Fully Funded Ph.D. Studentships Through the Department of Sociology</h4>



<p>University of Surrey, UK</p>



<p>Deadline: December 9<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://eur03.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.surrey.ac.uk%2Ffees-and-funding%2Fstudentships%2Fdepartment-sociology-doctoral-studentships-2023&amp;data=05%7C01%7Cisabella.kasselstrand%40abdn.ac.uk%7Cc25df1fe8f3949705acb08da90b44d33%7C8c2b19ad5f9c49d490773ec3cfc52b3f%7C0%7C0%7C637981401315743182%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=PCpVaNJ7Aawe8NnsY2H1IRnLVvNejIjojgnjI9PW304%3D&amp;reserved=0">https://eur03.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.surrey.ac.uk%2Ffees-and-funding%2Fstudentships%2Fdepartment-sociology-doctoral-studentships-2023&amp;data=05%7C01%7Cisabella.kasselstrand%40abdn.ac.uk%7Cc25df1fe8f3949705acb08da90b44d33%7C8c2b19ad5f9c49d490773ec3cfc52b3f%7C0%7C0%7C637981401315743182%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=PCpVaNJ7Aawe8NnsY2H1IRnLVvNejIjojgnjI9PW304%3D&amp;reserved=0</a></p>



<h4>5 Full-Time Ph.D. Studentships at Leeds Trinity University</h4>



<p>Leeds Trinity University, UK</p>



<p>Deadline: September 30<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.leedstrinity.ac.uk/research/research-degrees/phd-studentships/">Ph.D. studentships – Research Degrees – Research – Leeds Trinity University</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers</h2>



<h4>Princeton Conference on Ritual &amp; Materiality in Buddhism</h4>



<p>Deadline: November 1<sup>st</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/6060/discussions/10856427/cfp-due-nov-1-2022-princeton-conference-ritual-materiality#:~:text=Ritual%20and%20Materiality%20in%20Buddhism%20and%20Asian%20Religions,conference%20hosted%20by%20Princeton%20University%2C%20Buddhist%20Studies%20Workshop.">CFP&gt; Princeton Conference on Ritual &amp; Materiality in Buddhism (due Nov. 1, 2022) | H-Buddhism | H-Net</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663220229954135</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
