<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 12:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 12:25:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>Elders in Religions of Antiquity 2023 : REMINDER: Call For Papers - Elders in Religions of Antiquity</title>
			<link>http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=170259&amp;copyownerid=173363</link>
						<description>REMINDER: Call For Papers - Elders in Religions of Antiquity</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 06:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1669271829501588</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ December 10, 2022] Conference or similar: Online internationaler Workshop  &quot;Comenius’ Angelus Pacis im Kontext der Frühmoderne und dessen Beitrag zur heutigen Friedensethik&quot;</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/105297</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p><strong>Online internationaler Workshop</strong></p>
<p><strong>Comenius’ <em>Angelus Pacis</em> im Kontext der Frühmoderne und dessen Beitrag zur heutigen Friedensethik</strong></p>
<p><strong>10. Dezember 2022</strong></p>
<p>Anders als seine Pädagogik ist Johann Amos Comenius’ <em>Angelus Pacis</em> (1667) wenig rezipiert worden. Der Workshop will das Werk in einer philosophischen Perspektive darstellen, die es sowohl in der Tradition der frühneuzeitlichen Theorien des gerechten Krieges einordnet als auch systematisch analysiert. Denn die Erschließung dieser Schrift kann zur heutigen Debatte der Friedensethik einen wichtigen Beitrag leisten.<em> Angelus Pacis</em> beschränkt sich nicht auf die These, dass der ewige bzw. stabile Friede nur auf einer religiösen aufrechten Motivation beruhen dürfe, noch darf sich die Lektüre dieser Schrift auf eine theologisch orientierte Interpretation beschränken. Denn <em>Angelus Pacis</em> integriert rechtliche, rational-motivationale und teleologisch-geschichtliche Dimensionen des Friedensprozesses auf detaillierte Weise, weshalb es nicht nur aus religiöser Perspektive interessant, sondern auch für eine Auseinandersetzung mit den traditionellen vorherrschenden rechtsphilosophischen bzw. friedensethischen Theorien anschlussfähig ist. Der Workshop besteht aus sechs Beiträgen von internationalen Forschern jeweils mit anschließender Diskussion.</p>
<p><strong>Programm</strong>: https://philosophie-vechta.org/veranstaltungen/aktuell/</p>
<p><strong>Koordination</strong>:</p>
<p>Prof. Dr. Jean-Christophe Merle (Universität Vechta)</p>
<p>Dr. Anna Szyrwińska-Hörig (Universität Vechta)</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Freie Teilnahme, Voranmeldung erforderlich:</strong></p>
<p>jean-christophe.merle@uni-vechta.de</p>
<p>anna.szyrwinska@uni-vechta.de</p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 06:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1669185431787871</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Non-Cloistered Religious Women and Rome at the Aftermath of the Council of Trent. Journey in Archives (ISHWRA)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11813088/non-cloistered-religious-women-and-rome-aftermath-council</link>
						<dc:creator>Sarah Barthélemy</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Seminar</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-25T00:00:00-05:00">November 25, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Belgium</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Early Modern History and Period Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Cultural History / Studies, Italian History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>This coming Friday, 25 November at 4pm, we’ll be hosting in Brussels (Université Saint-Louis Bruxelles - room P30) this month’s ISHWRA seminar, when we’ll be joined by Dr Isabel Harvey (UCLouvain / GEMCA).</p><p>Recent historiography about non-cloistered religious women is based above all on the punctual luck of archives, as the wealth of an Inquisition trial or an autobiography, or on notarial institutional documentation of mainly economic nature. This documentation allows to reconstruct interesting cases, to contextualize them, but it is difficult to move away from the exceptionality of a person, a situation, or an institution rich enough to accumulate a number of notarial archives. I propose to look at another archive, the voluminous documentation of the Congregation of Bishops and Regulars, which will allow us to identify and hear the voices of others, those non-cloistered religious women who are considered neither saints nor heretics, and who did not live in a wealthy community in a large urban center. This presentation will detail the archival and methodological path to identify them and to gather information about their singular existences and experiences.</p><p>D﻿r Isabel Harvey is FNRS postdoctoral fellow at the Université catholique de Louvain.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><strong>T﻿his hybrid event will take place online and at Université Saint-Louis Bruxelles, 43 Boulevard du Jardin Botanique, Bruxelles, 1000 (room P30).</strong></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:sarah.barthelemy@durham.co.uk">sarah.barthelemy@durham.co.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/ishwra-seminar-november-2022-tickets-438918977477" target="_blank">https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/ishwra-seminar-november-2022-tickets-438918977477</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1669185431787870</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Book of Qohelet in its Hellenistic Jewish context</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11768049/book-qohelet-its-hellenistic-jewish-context</link>
						<dc:creator>Sara Ben-Isaac</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-22T00:00:00-05:00">November 22, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Humanities, Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span>Online lecture (Zoom) by Professor Lili Samet.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>The research of the book of Qohelet in the light of extra-biblical materials has traditionally been focused on three main arenas, all representing the book’s indirect context: Mesopotamia, Egypt and Greece. Qohelet’s immediate environment, that is, the book’s relationship to the Jewish discourse of its time, has scarcely been studied.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>This lecture attempts to explore some of the unexhausted potential of studying Qohelet within its Hellenistic Jewish context. Two test cases, one belonging to the legal realm and the other involving theological and philosophical concerns, will be used to exemplify the ways in which innovative interpretations of Qohelet’s words and ideas can be proposed in light of the intellectual history of its time and place.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Nili</span></span><span><span> Samet is a professor of Bible and Assyriology at Bar-Ilan University, and currently a visiting professor at UCL and at Oxford University. She is the author of a book and several dozens of articles in the fields of wisdom literature in Israel and Mesopotamia, with a focus on the Book of Qohelet; Biblical Hebrew, with a focus on linguistic dating; and comparative study of the Bible and the Ancient Near East, with a focus on Sumerian literature. One of her main current projects is a commentary on Qohelet in the series <i>Miqra Le-Yisrael</i></span></span><span><span>.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>The research of the book of Qohelet in the light of extra-biblical materials has traditionally been focused on three main arenas, all representing the book’s indirect context: Mesopotamia, Egypt and Greece. Qohelet’s immediate environment, that is, the book’s relationship to the Jewish discourse of its time, has scarcely been studied.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Institute of Jewish Studies, UCL</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ijs@ucl.ac.uk">ijs@ucl.ac.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/424489017077" target="_blank">https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/424489017077</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 18:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1668839832550742</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Editorial Members</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11760553/call-editorial-members</link>
						<dc:creator>Dina Ripsman Eylon</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Journal</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-12-31T00:00:00-05:00">December 31, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Canada</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Ontario</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Cultural History / Studies, Humanities, Jewish History / Studies, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><i>Women in Judaism: A Multidisciplinary e-Journal</i> is seeking new members to join our editorial board. Scholars in any field in the Humanities and/or Social Sciences are invited to apply.</span></span></p><p><span><span>This refereed, biannual, open access, e-journal is published solely on the Internet and is devoted to an exploration of gender issues in Jewish religion, culture, society and history. Now in its 26th year of publication, the journal features articles, essays, book and film reviews, bibliographies, conference proceedings and more.</span></span></p><p><span><span><i>Women in Judaism: A Multidisciplinary e-Journal</i> is indexed by Érudit, Ulrich's International Periodicals Directory, RAMBI- The Index of Articles on Jewish Studies by the Jewish National and University Library, Index of Jewish Periodicals, and Contemporary Women’s Issues by the Gale Group. In addition, the journal is indexed and linked to by dozens of electronic directories and web sites. [For more details, check our About section.]</span></span></p><p><span><span>New editorial members will be asked to review 1-3 submitted articles a year. The materials fall within the members’ areas of expertise. Members will be asked to promote the journal within their respective academic communities. As members of the editorial board, they could also</span></span><span><span> </span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span>Refer to the journal in their course outlines, bibliographies and even mundane chats in their departments. </span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span>Assign readings from the journal to students. </span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span>Suggest to colleagues and graduate students to write book (and other media) reviews for the journal. </span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span>Solicit colleagues, graduate students to submit articles and other materials. </span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span>Current and previous issues are freely available at <a href="http://www.womeninjudaism.org/" rel="nofollow">www.womeninjudaism.org</a></span></span></p><p><span><span>Please include your CV with your electronic application. We would greatly appreciate your participation in our journal, and thank you for your consideration.</span></span></p><p><span><span>For more info and details, email Dr. Dina Ripsman Eylon, Editor-in-Chief at</span></span></p><p><span><span><a href="https://networks.h-net.org/subject-fields/dina.eylon@alum.utoronto.ca">dina.eylon@alum.utoronto.</a></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr. Dina Ripsman Eylon, Eedtor-in-Chief</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:dina.eylon@alum.utoronto.ca">dina.eylon@alum.utoronto.ca</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://wjudaism.library.utoronto.ca/index.php/wjudaism/index" target="_blank">https://wjudaism.library.utoronto.ca/index.php/wjudaism/index</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 18:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1668839832550741</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
