<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 12:20:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 12:20:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ October 27, 2023 -  May 24, 2024] Conference or similar: Monthly Phenomenology, New Season (2023–2024)</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/115414</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p>We are very pleased to announce the new season (2023–2024) of:     <br/><br/>MONTHLY PHENOMENOLOGY <br/>An online forum of discussion on recent work in phenomenology  </p>
<p><u>Description</u>: This series of talks gathers together scholars interested in phenomenology and its relation to contemporary issues in philosophy, especially in the philosophy of mind. It establishes a forum of discussion where people can meet on a regular basis and present their work-in-progress or recent publications. The topics addressed will stretch from the history of early phenomenology to the systematic application of phenomenological insights in recent debates in analytic philosophy.   <br/><br/><u>Schedule</u>: The talks will take place once a month on a Friday from October to May. Time: 10:15am ET, 3:15pm GMT/GMT+1, 4:15pm CET. (Exceptions are the talks of February and March, which will take place at 7:15am ET, 12:15pm GMT, 1:15pm CET.) Talks last 90 minutes, including a 45 minutes Q&amp;A.   <br/><br/><u>Participation</u>: Talks are held on <a href="http://zoom.us/">zoom</a>. To participate, please send an email to <a href="mailto:hamid.taieb@hu-berlin.de">hamid.taieb@hu-berlin.de</a> with the heading "Registration Monthly Phenomenology". A zoom link will be sent to you the day preceding each talk.     <br/><br/><br/><u>Programme</u>:   <br/><br/>Robin Muller (California State University, Northridge) <br/>Critical Phenomenology and Phenomenological Critique: Ambiguities in the Legacy of Merleau-Ponty <br/>27 October 2023<br/><br/> Bruno Langlet (University of Bordeaux) <br/>On the Controversial Status of Meinongian Assumptions <br/>24 November 2023   <br/><br/>Moritz von Kalckreuth (University of Wuppertal) <br/>Connecting Value, Culture and History – The Approach of Nicolai Hartmann <br/>15 December 2023   <br/><br/>W. Clark Wolf (Marquette University) <br/>In Defense of Pure Concepts <br/>19 January 2024   <br/><br/>Takuya Niikawa (Kobe University) <br/>Atmosphere and Mood <br/>23 February 2024   <br/><br/>Kengo Miyazono (Hokkaido University) <br/>Dissociations between Sensory and Presentational Phenomenology <br/>8 March 2024   <br/><br/>Marie Guillot (University of Essex) <br/>Phenomenal Concepts of Time, Space and Self <br/>5 April 2024   <br/><br/>Elisa Magrì (Boston College) <br/>TBA  <br/>24 May 2024</p>
<p><br/><u>Convenors</u>: <br/>Guillaume Fréchette (University of Geneva) <br/>Marta Jorba (Pompeu Fabra University) <br/>Alessandro Salice (University College Cork) <br/>Hamid Taieb (Humboldt University Berlin) <br/>Íngrid Vendrell-Ferran (Philipps University Marburg)   <br/><br/>Organized on behalf of the <a href="https://netw-phenom-research.wixsite.com/nfpr">Network for Phenomenological Research</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 05:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1697002639576212</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ November 21, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Imam Reza (PBUH) and Interreligious Dialogue</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/115426</link>
						<description><p><strong>The International Conference on Imam Reza (PBUH) and Interreligious Dialogue</strong></p>
<p>Astan Quds Razavi’s Foundation of Islamic Researches in collaboration with Imam Sadiq University and various Iranian and international academic and religious centers will hold the international conference on “Imam Reza (PBUH) and Interreligious Dialogue” from 16 to 18 January 2024. This conference aims to create an atmosphere for dialogue and peaceful coexistence between the followers of different religions and denominations, to strengthen scientific interaction between the scholars of different religions and denominations, to strengthen the scientific interaction between Iranian and International religious institutions, to laying a groundwork for Intellectual cooperation between different religions and denominations on contemporary social challenges, and to emphasize the role of the family as a sacred institution from the perspective of religions and denominations. Laying the groundwork for the conference, the scientific secretariat has planned to hold numerous virtual/in-person pre-con meetings in Persian, Arabic, and English at the different Iranian and international academic/religious centers.</p>
<p>Chairman: Mohammad Hadi Abdkhodaei (Professor, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Iran)</p>
<p>Scientific Secretary: Ahad Faramarz Qaramaleki (Professor, University of Tehran, Iran)</p>
<p>Executive Secretary: Mohsen Sharfaei (Ph. D Graduate, Astan Quds Razavi’s Foundation of Islamic Researches, Iran)</p>
<p>Executive Manager: Roohollah Fadaei (Ph. D Graduate, Tarbiat Modares University, Iran)</p>
<p>Venue: Mashhad, Iran</p>
<p>Conference issues:</p>
<p>1. Theory and Method in Interreligious Dialogue:</p>
<p>- Philosophical Approaches: Phenomenology, Epistemology, Narrative, Intercultural Philosophy, etc.</p>
<p>- Sociological Approaches</p>
<p>- Empirical Approaches</p>
<p>- Psychological Approaches</p>
<p>…</p>
<p>2. Family and Interreligious Dialogue</p>
<p>- Theological Attitudes Towards Family Relationships</p>
<p>- Religions and the Threats to Family Life</p>
<p>- Religions and the Mental Images of Family</p>
<p>- Theology of Gender</p>
<p>- Religions and the Rival Institutions to the Family</p>
<p>- Religions and the Family Roles</p>
<p>We are honored to host some of the well-known scholars in interfaith studies in the scientific board:</p>
<p>·       Rahim Acar: Marmara University, Turkey</p>
<p>·       Ahad Faramarz Qaramaleki: University of Tehran, Iran</p>
<p>·       Lucinda Allen Mosher: Hartford International University for Religion and Peace, USA</p>
<p>·       Seyyed Hossein Nasr: The George Washington University, USA</p>
<p>·       Rasoul Rasoulipour: Kharazmi University, Iran</p>
<p>·       Mohammad Saeedi Mehr: Tarbiat Modares University, Iran</p>
<p>·       Mun'im Sirry: Notre Dame University, USA</p>
<p>·       Amy Yu Fu: Hangzhou City University, China</p>
<p>….</p>
<p>Important Dates</p>
<p>·       Abstract submission deadline: November 21, 2023</p>
<p>·       Notification of acceptance: November 26, 2023</p>
<p>·       Paper submission deadline: December 27, 2024</p>
<p>·       Announcement of the selected papers and presentations’ schedule: January 2, 2024</p>
<p>·       Conference date: January 16-18, 2024</p>
<p>Only Ph. D holders and postgraduate students may submit abstracts and papers independently. Undergraduates' submissions should be coauthored by a professor.</p>
<p>Abstract Features:</p>
<p>·       Abstracts should be no less than 250 words in length and no more than 300.</p>
<p>·        Abstracts should be followed by 3 to 5 keywords.</p>
<p>Paper Features:</p>
<p>·       Papers should be no less than 1500 words in length and no more than 2000 (the abstract and bibliography are not counted).</p>
<p>·       Whole text should be typed in Times New Roman font (font-size: 11 for body and 9 for endnotes and bibliography).</p>
<p>·       All titles and subtitles in the paper should be arranged numerically (English numbers not Roman).</p>
<p>·       All marginal but useful and important notes should be mentioned as endnotes, not footnotes.</p>
<p>·       All references (in-text and reference list) should follow the 16th edition of Chicago citation style.</p>
<p>The conference will be held totally in-person.</p>
<p>The conference registration is free of charge. For those professors and researchers interested in participating in the conference in-person, conference organizers tried to decrease the costs of attendance by finding some funds. Accordingly, the attendance cost for any international participant would be 500 USD (which will be received in cash) including:</p>
<p>•        A 5to7-day stay in Iran (from about 13 to 19 January 2024) at a five-star hotel</p>
<p>•        Complete food services at the hotel</p>
<p>•        Local transportation in Tehran from Imam Khomeini Airport to Mehrabad Airport and vice versa</p>
<p>•        A roundtrip flight ticket from Tehran to Mashhad</p>
<p>•        Local Transportation in Mashhad</p>
<p>It is kindly requested from those who want to attend the event to register on the conference website and to submit their abstracts. Moreover, due to the official process of visa issuance, the secretariat of the conference (irirdialogue@gmail.com) needs the following documents:</p>
<p>1. Passport first two pages</p>
<p>2.  A biometric photo</p>
<p>3. Form 1 (just fill out the English column)</p>
<p>Conference website, submissions and registration:  https://irirdialogue.ir/</p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 05:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1697002639576211</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>THE SACRED, THE SPIRITUAL AND THE RELIGIOUS  IN CONTEMPORARY GLOBAL SOCIETIES</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/10/09/the-sacred-the-spiritual-and-the-religious-in-contemporary-global-societies</link>
						<dc:creator>frederic.lefrancois@univ-antilles.fr</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, October 10, 2023 - 2:23pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>NaKaN Learned Society</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:nakanjournal@gmail.com">nakanjournal@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/international-conferences">international conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/online-conferences">online conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>October 31, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p align="center"><strong>THE SACRED, THE SPIRITUAL AND THE RELIGIOUS </strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>IN CONTEMPORARY GLOBAL SOCIETIES</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p align="center"><strong>INTERNATIONAL ONLINE STUDY DAY</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>December 14, 2023</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Presentation</strong></p>
<p>Universalized, secular and democratic post-modern societies, under the aegis of unbridled freedom and limitless growth, are leading us today, more than ever, to reinterrogate man's relationship with his beliefs in his biocenosis. Thinking of the sacred, the spiritual, the religious, from an absolute point of view, involves a semantic, semiotic and implex mental hierarchy understood in a dichotomous relationship focused on paradigmatic dyads:</p>
<p> city / countryside</p>
<p> nature / culture</p>
<p> civilization / barbarism</p>
<p> deep country / imaginary country</p>
<p> dream country / real country</p>
<p> autochthony / universality</p>
<p> universal / diversel (pluriversal)</p>
<p> emic point of view (from within the social group) / etic point of view (from the observer's point of view)</p>
<p>The relationship between these terms depends on one's perspective. We must recognize that there is a differentiation between the terms sacred/spiritual/religious, but also that it is difficult to establish a boundary between them.</p>
<p>To begin with, we know that the sacred is a particular status linked to myths that refers to the subject, to essence, to ontological depth and its relationship to the divine sphere, to the notion of interiority, of nature, of innateness; it is characterized by the active power of divinity, that feeling of absolute presence, of divine presence. It is both mystery and terror. It is the being of nature, living in the present moment, whereas religion, inseparable from society, brings us back to the concept of culture, of what has been acquired, keeping us in the past and projecting us into the future. It is thought of as a human experience, an external construct, it becomes an object of knowledge, part of collective worship, and in the light of historical evolution, it leads to a cosmetic approach to the world (colonialist, transhumanist...), a dispossession of the characteristics of the human being, or even a projection of the human ideal into an imaginary world.</p>
<p>Spirituality, the preferred domain of the human sciences, also concerns all those who survey the territory of the mind, and is approached with circumspection, with the difficult neutrality that falls to rational, Cartesian minds. In such matters, any system of thought, any attempt at conceptualization is confronted with the irreducible complexity of a protean reality that transcends the field of discourse.</p>
<p>As for religion, it can be understood as any specific system of belief, worship, etc., often implying a moral code, whereas spirituality - which is not exclusive of religion, since atheistic, secular or pagan spirituality can be found - focuses on things and the immaterial world, the world of spirits. It implies a quest, a questioning, a path, a reason. That said, this belief system is rarely unanimous, and in the history of mankind has regularly been involved in conflicts whose intensity demonstrates that the sharing of the sacred does not always overlap with the "sharing of the sensible". In regions of the world where various cultural practices come into contact, exchanges and new creations resulting from appropriations and re-appropriations offer a most interesting subject for study, and invite us to rethink the paradigms of syncretism and super-syncretism (Benítez-Rojo, 2010).</p>
<p>Conceptually, these notions - sacred, spiritual, religious - are associated with a diversity of representations which, in the collective imagination, rarely carry the same semantic, semiological or even gnostic weight in literature, science, the arts and cultural practices. Do they refer to the same meanings in terms of the scholarly observer's reception of the cult communities and cultural ethopoeias, of the theocratic ecosystems he is targeting? From a civilizational point of view, what cultural shocks, or relational ecologies, do they provide access to?</p>
<p>The worlds of literary and artistic creation in the South are precisely scriptural, oracular, sonic, hermetic or heterogeneous worlds where language, the Word, resonance, cosmic energy... are created, and where we tend to reconfigure these terminologies. What, then, of literature and the arts? How do novelists, poets and artists reintegrate or re-appropriate these lost frequential spaces of the Republic of Human Sciences? Are aesthetic strategies, however minimal, perceptible, conceivable or tangible?</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>How to contribute</strong></p>
<p>As these lines of inquiry are not intended to be exhaustive, contributors are encouraged to explore other aspects of the issue along the conceptual lines indicated. Interdisciplinary and comparative approaches to this theme are strongly encouraged.  Contributions at the intersection of literature, the arts and anthropology (among others) will also be particularly appreciated.  With this in mind, proposals may be drawn from related disciplinary, interdisciplinary and transdisciplinary fields. To this end, contributors may draw inspiration from the following areas:</p>
<p> literary studies;</p>
<p> visual and performing arts: painting, sculpture, graphic arts, performance art, etc. ;</p>
<p> philosophy, psychology and theology;</p>
<p> human and social sciences: history, sociology, anthropology, ethnology, political science;</p>
<p> the study of life, pharmacopoeia and the resurgence of ancestral practices;</p>
<p> a diversity of related and diasporic fields: cultural studies, migration studies, etc.</p>
<p>Proposals for contributions should include a title and an abstract of no more than 400 words, accompanied by 5 keywords. They should be accompanied by a brief biobibliographical note, not exceeding 150 words.</p>
<p>Proposals in English, French or Spanish, accompanied by a short bio-bibliographical note, should be sent by October 30, 2023 at the latest. For further information, please send an email to the same address. Please send your abstract (300 words maximum) + 5 keywords to <a href="mailto:nakanJE1contributions@gmail.com">nakanJE1contributions@gmail.com</a> and <a href="mailto:nakanjournal@gmail.com">nakanjournal@gmail.com</a>, together with a brief bio-bibliographical note specifying your institutional affiliation. Contributions will take the form of a 20-minute academic paper followed by a 10-minute discussion.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Selection and programming process</strong></p>
<p> Until October 30, 2023: submission of abstracts and biobibliographical notes</p>
<p> November 1 to November 9, 2023: selection of proposals.</p>
<p> November 10, 2023: notification of authors.</p>
<p> December 1, 2023: distribution and publication of the study day program.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Publication</strong></p>
<p>Please note that the study day will take place online. Contributions likely to be recorded on video may be uploaded - with the panelists' explicit agreement - to AMC's Canal-U channel. A recording and broadcast authorization will be sent to all contributors whose proposals have been selected. Following the event, they will be invited to submit a full article to <em>NaKaN, a Journal of Cultural Studies</em>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Organization</strong></p>
<p>NaKaN Learned Society, University of the French West Indies &amp; University of Mayotte.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Timetable and terms of participation</strong></p>
<p>Please send your abstract (300 words maximum) + 5 keywords to <a href="mailto:nakanJE1contributions@gmail.com">nakanJE1contributions@gmail.com</a> and <a href="mailto:nakanjournal@gmail.com">nakanjournal@gmail.com</a>, together with a brief biobibliographical note specifying your institutional affiliation. Contributions to this multidisciplinary study day may take the form of a 20-minute academic paper followed by a 10-minute discussion.</p>
<p><strong>Agenda</strong></p>
<p>- Deadline for proposals: October 30, 2023</p>
<p>- Scientific Committee response: November 5, 2023</p>
<p>- Program diffusion: November 15, 2023</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Organizing Committee</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Dr. Nathalie Bouchaut-Kancel, Université des Antilles</p>
<p>Mr. Gérald Désert, Université des Antilles</p>
<p>Dr. Frédéric Lefrançois, Université des Antilles</p>
<p>Prof. Buata Malela, Université de Mayotte</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Scientific Committee</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Pr. John Ayotunde Isola Bewaji (University of the West Indies)</p>
<p>Dr. Anny-Dominique Curtius (University of Iowa, USA)</p>
<p>Dr. D. Amy-Rose Forbes-Erickson (Rutgers University, Bowling Green State University)</p>
<p>Dr. Max Belaise (University of the West Indies)</p>
<p>Pr. Frederick Ochieng'-Odhiambon (University of the West Indies)</p>
<p>Pr. Marc Duby (University of South Africa)</p>
<p>Dr. Christina Oikonomopoulou (University of Peloponnese, Greece)</p>
<p>Dr. Christophe Premat (University of Stockholm, Sweden)</p>
<p>Pr. Jean Bessière (University of Paris III Sorbonne, France)</p>
<p>Pr. Laurence Rosier (Université Libre de Bruxelles, Belgium)</p>
<p>Dr. Linda Rasoamanana (University of Mayotte, France)</p>
<p>Pr. Madhura Joshi (Toulouse - Jean Jaurès University, France)</p>
<p>Dr. Yoporeka Somet (Dedan Kimathi University of Technology, Kenya)</p>
<p>Dr. Yves Chemla (Université Paris Descartes, France)</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL REFERENCES</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Anzaldúa, G., <em>Light in the Dark/Luz en lo Oscuro: Rewriting Identity, Spirituality, Reality</em>. Duke University Press, 2015</p>
<p>Aristote. <em>Métaphysique,</em> E, 1026020, trad. J. Tricot, Vrin, Paris, 1953</p>
<p>Bataille, Georges. <em>La part maudite</em>, Minuit, 1985</p>
<p>Benítez Rojo, Antonio. <em>LA Isla Que Se Repite: El Caribe y Perspectiva Posmoderna</em>. Editorial Plaza Mayor, 2010.</p>
<p>Bergson, Henri. <em>Les deux sources de la morale et de la religion,</em> PUF, Paris, 1995</p>
<p>Besnier, Jean-Michel. <em>Histoire de la Philosophie moderne et contemporaine, Figures et Œuvres,</em> Le Collège de Philosophie, Grasset, 1993</p>
<p>Blay, Michel. <em>Grand dictionnaire de la Philosophie,</em> Larousse, CNRS Éditions, 2012, [2003]</p>
<p>Caillois, Roger. <em>L’Homme et le Sacré</em>, Folio-essais, Gallimard, 1983</p>
<p>Carrette, J. R.  &amp; King, R. <em>Selling spirituality: The silent takeover of religion</em>. Psychology Press, 2015</p>
<p>Chateaubriand, François-René (de). <em>Génie du Christianisme</em>, Garnier-Flammarion, 1990.</p>
<p>Durand, Gilbert. <em>Les Structures anthropologiques de l’imaginaire</em>, Armand Colin, 2020 [1969]</p>
<p>Hegel, Georg Wilhelm Friedrich. <em>Leçons sur la philosophie de la religion,</em> Trd. J. Gibelin, Vrin, Paris, 1975</p>
<p>Durkheim, Emile. <em>Les formes élémentaires de la vie religieuse</em>, Livre de poche1912, rééd. CNRS Éditions, 2008</p>
<p>Eliade, Mircea. <em>Le Sacré et le Profane,</em> Folio-essais, Gallimard, 1957</p>
<p>Eliade,Mircea. <em>Le Mythe de l’éternel retour, </em>Folio-essais, Gallimard, 1969</p>
<p>Eliade,Mircea.<em> Aspects du Mythe, </em>Folio-essais, Gallimard, 1963</p>
<p>Girard, René. <em>La Violence et le Sacré,</em> Hachette, 1994</p>
<p>Grosfoguel, Ramon. « The structure of knowledge in Westernized universities: Epistemic racism/sexism and the four genocides/epistemicides of the long 16th century ». <em>Human Architecture: Journal of the Sociology of Self-Knowledge</em>,<em>11</em>(1), 8, 2013.</p>
<p>Hutchison, E. D. , « Spirituality, Religion, and Progressive Social Movements: Resources and Motivation for Social Change »,  <em>Journal of Religion &amp; Spirituality in Social Work: Social Thought</em>, <em>31</em>(1-2), 105-127, 2012.</p>
<p>Lam, Eskil, D. Tonneau-Ryckelynck &amp; D. Dolega-Ritter, <em>Lam : Catalogue raisonné de l'œuvre gravé</em>, H.C. Editions, 2016.</p>
<p>L’Étang Gerry &amp; J.-Pierre Arsaye, <em>La Peinture en Martinique</em>, Paris, H.C. Éditions, 2007.</p>
<p>Marx, Karl. <em>Contribution à la critique de la philosophie du droit de Hegel,</em> Ellipses, Paris, 2000.</p>
<p>Ochieng'-Odhiambo, Frederick. <em>African Philosophy: An Introduction</em>, Consolata Institute of Philosophy Press, Nairobi, 1995.</p>
<p>Otto, Rudolph. <em>Le Sacré,</em> Payot, 2001</p>
<p>Owen, S. <em>The appropriation of native American spirituality</em>. Bloomsbury Publishing, 2008.</p>
<p>Somé, M. P. <em>The healing wisdom of Africa: Finding life purpose through nature, ritual, and community</em>, JP Tarcher, 1999</p>
<p>Spinoza, Baruch. <em>Traité théologico-politique</em>, Garnier-Flammarion, 1965.</p>
<p>Toumson, Roger (dir.), <em>Anthologie de la peinture en Guadeloupe. Des origines à nos jours</em>, Paris, Hervé Chopin,  2009.</p>
<p>Yung-Hing, Renée-Paule (dir.), <em>Art contemporain de la Caraïbe, Mythes, croyances, religions et imaginaire</em>, Editions Hervé Chopin, 2012.</p>
<p>Whitehead, Alfred North. <em>Le Concept de Nature</em>, Vrin, 1998 [1920].</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 13:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1697002639576210</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Flagship Issue of The Classical Connection: Christian Bogeymen</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/10/07/flagship-issue-of-the-classical-connection-christian-bogeymen</link>
						<dc:creator>mbarros</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, October 10, 2023 - 2:22pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>The Classical Connection</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:m.barros@boiseclassicalacademy.com">m.barros@boiseclassicalacademy.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/classical-studies">classical studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>October 14, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p align="center"><strong>Call for Papers: Flagship Issue of <em>The Classical Connection</em></strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Overview of the journal:</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p><a href="http://www.theclassicalconnection.com/">www.theclassicalconnection.com</a> </p>
<p> </p>
<p>We have launched our new journal, <em>The Classical Connection</em>, and are asking for contributions for our debut issue to be published by the end of this year. The underlying principle of the journal is that “The Great Conversation” is still occurring, and we can participate in it. We hope this is a two-way conversation, simultaneously asking, “What role should the premodern play in the post-postmodern era?” and “What insights do we have now that might speak toward the questions of the past?”</p>
<p> </p>
<p>For example:</p>
<p>-       Can current psychological studies give us insight into events of the past?</p>
<ul>
<li>What is the psyche? What is consciousness?</li>
</ul>
<p>-       Might Augustine have something useful to say about the free will debate?</p>
<p>-       Why is the Battle of Salamis still useful for military study despite the technological disparity?</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Though our perspective is Christian, and we believe that the story of the West is permanently intertwined with Christianity, we accept submissions on a range of topics, both secular and religious, regardless of belief system. Our goal is to facilitate robust, academically rigorous, useful conversation.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Outside of our content, we have some distinctives that separate us from other academic journals:</p>
<p>-       <strong>Unique style guide</strong>: when one reads the academic work of Tolkien or Lewis, or anyone else from the mid-20th century or earlier, it’s clear that the rigid academic structure was less essential than the content itself. We hope to move back toward this and encourage accessible yet intelligent conversational prose. Please review our style guide before submission for further details.</p>
<p>-       <strong>Charitability:</strong> We are not interested in publishing things that strip away meaning from the world rather than adding it. As such, there are many scholarly topics that would not be suitable for our journal. For example, the sort of literary criticism where the impression is given that the critic simply hates literature. Alternatively, any sort of inquiry that only focuses on the evils of a particular person, nation, or thought system without any sort of nuanced counterweight. In short, culture theorists say that we’re past the postmodern mockery and cynicism, so academia needs to begin to reflect that.</p>
<p>-       <strong>Streamlined Review:</strong> Contributors to most special issues will be asked to review 1-2 other papers being published in that issue, with a 2-week turnaround time. We will also solicit from our network of reviewers to provide outside expertise as necessary along the same timeline. We don’t want the publication process to be delayed by the review process, and we’ve never gotten (or given) a review so comprehensive that it couldn’t have been done in 2 weeks.</p>
<p>-       <strong>Free to publish, free to view:</strong> We are an institutionally funded open-access journal that does not charge a publication fee. Publication costs and viewing costs are academic barriers to entry that simply should not exist in the digital age.</p>
<p>-       <strong>Special issue only</strong>: Currently, we are a special issue-only journal and do not accept open submissions. If you’re interested in pitching a special issue and serving as a guest editor for it, please contact the managing editor Michael Barros at <a href="mailto:m.barros@boiseclassicalacademy.com">m.barros@boiseclassicalacademy.com</a></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Information about the flagship issue:</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>The theme of our flagship issue is “Christian Bogeymen,” and the articles will explore the compatibility/relationship of various hot-button topics with Christianity. More precisely, this issue will investigate controversial topics that have either been claimed to be incompatible with Christianity or been used in polemics against Christianity. Topics like evolution, the Big Bang, and so on have become bogeymen to the Christian community when they need not be. These major topics, as well as many that are periphery to Christian thought, are what we’re categorizing as “bogeymen” for this issue.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Note: The goal is not for this to be an apologetic issue but rather a communique to the Christian community.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Currently, we have commitments for the following topics:</p>
<p> </p>
<p>-       The history of the Big Bang theory and its compatibility with Christianity.</p>
<p>-       The utility of contemporary Halloween celebrations.</p>
<p>-       The problem of evil: Augustine and Jonothan Edwards</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Some other possible topics might be:</p>
<p> </p>
<p>-       Do Christians need to be comfortable with all Christian doctrine?</p>
<p>-       How damning is the problem of evil?   </p>
<p>-       Can Christians celebrate Halloween?</p>
<p>-       The history and development of Halloween.</p>
<p>-       Why Christians can and should read pagan literature.</p>
<p>-       Why Christians shouldn’t get hung up on the evolution debate when reading Genesis.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Publication timeline:</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Note: This is an experimental issue that is also serving as a proof of concept for our board, so we’ve condensed the timeline. As a result, the peer review process will not be distributed. Instead, we’ll use reviewers in our network who’ve already agreed. This means we will be rather limited on articles we can accept, so it’ll have to be a first come, first served sort of thing. </em></p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p><em>We also have a Christmas issue planned with a longer deadline. Please check the website for more information.</em></p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p>-       Manuscripts (3,500-4,500 words) due Saturday, 14 October</p>
<p>-       Papers returned with reviewer comments Friday, 20 October</p>
<p>-       Revised papers due Friday, 27 October</p>
<p>-       Final editorial review will take place on Sunday, 29 October</p>
<ul>
<li>Please check your e-mail that night just in case there are some last-minute changes</li>
</ul>
<p>-       Publication date: 31 October</p>
<p> </p>
<p>@font-face {font-family:Wingdings; panose-1:5 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0; mso-font-charset:77; mso-generic-font-family:decorative; mso-font-pitch:variable; mso-font-signature:3 268435456 0 0 -2147483647 0;}@font-face {font-family:"Cambria Math"; panose-1:2 4 5 3 5 4 6 3 2 4; mso-font-charset:0; mso-generic-font-family:roman; mso-font-pitch:variable; mso-font-signature:-536870145 1107305727 0 0 415 0;}@font-face {font-family:Calibri; panose-1:2 15 5 2 2 2 4 3 2 4; mso-font-charset:0; mso-generic-font-family:swiss; mso-font-pitch:variable; mso-font-signature:-536859905 -1073697537 9 0 511 0;}p.MsoNormal, li.MsoNormal, div.MsoNormal {mso-style-unhide:no; mso-style-qformat:yes; mso-style-parent:""; margin:0in; mso-pagination:widow-orphan; font-size:12.0pt; font-family:"Calibri",sans-serif; mso-ascii-font-family:Calibri; mso-ascii-theme-font:minor-latin; mso-fareast-font-family:Calibri; mso-fareast-theme-font:minor-latin; mso-hansi-font-family:Calibri; mso-hansi-theme-font:minor-latin; mso-bidi-font-family:"Times New Roman"; mso-bidi-theme-font:minor-bidi; mso-ansi-language:EN-GB;}p.MsoListParagraph, li.MsoListParagraph, div.MsoListParagraph {mso-style-priority:34; mso-style-unhide:no; mso-style-qformat:yes; margin-top:0in; margin-right:0in; margin-bottom:0in; margin-left:.5in; mso-add-space:auto; mso-pagination:widow-orphan; font-size:12.0pt; font-family:"Calibri",sans-serif; mso-ascii-font-family:Calibri; mso-ascii-theme-font:minor-latin; mso-fareast-font-family:Calibri; mso-fareast-theme-font:minor-latin; mso-hansi-font-family:Calibri; mso-hansi-theme-font:minor-latin; mso-bidi-font-family:"Times New Roman"; mso-bidi-theme-font:minor-bidi; mso-ansi-language:EN-GB;}p.MsoListParagraphCxSpFirst, li.MsoListParagraphCxSpFirst, div.MsoListParagraphCxSpFirst {mso-style-priority:34; mso-style-unhide:no; mso-style-qformat:yes; mso-style-type:export-only; margin-top:0in; margin-right:0in; margin-bottom:0in; margin-left:.5in; mso-add-space:auto; mso-pagination:widow-orphan; font-size:12.0pt; font-family:"Calibri",sans-serif; mso-ascii-font-family:Calibri; mso-ascii-theme-font:minor-latin; mso-fareast-font-family:Calibri; mso-fareast-theme-font:minor-latin; mso-hansi-font-family:Calibri; mso-hansi-theme-font:minor-latin; mso-bidi-font-family:"Times New Roman"; mso-bidi-theme-font:minor-bidi; mso-ansi-language:EN-GB;}p.MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle, li.MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle, div.MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle {mso-style-priority:34; mso-style-unhide:no; mso-style-qformat:yes; mso-style-type:export-only; margin-top:0in; margin-right:0in; margin-bottom:0in; margin-left:.5in; mso-add-space:auto; mso-pagination:widow-orphan; font-size:12.0pt; font-family:"Calibri",sans-serif; mso-ascii-font-family:Calibri; mso-ascii-theme-font:minor-latin; mso-fareast-font-family:Calibri; mso-fareast-theme-font:minor-latin; mso-hansi-font-family:Calibri; mso-hansi-theme-font:minor-latin; mso-bidi-font-family:"Times New Roman"; mso-bidi-theme-font:minor-bidi; mso-ansi-language:EN-GB;}p.MsoListParagraphCxSpLast, li.MsoListParagraphCxSpLast, div.MsoListParagraphCxSpLast {mso-style-priority:34; mso-style-unhide:no; mso-style-qformat:yes; mso-style-type:export-only; margin-top:0in; margin-right:0in; margin-bottom:0in; margin-left:.5in; mso-add-space:auto; mso-pagination:widow-orphan; font-size:12.0pt; font-family:"Calibri",sans-serif; mso-ascii-font-family:Calibri; mso-ascii-theme-font:minor-latin; mso-fareast-font-family:Calibri; mso-fareast-theme-font:minor-latin; mso-hansi-font-family:Calibri; mso-hansi-theme-font:minor-latin; mso-bidi-font-family:"Times New Roman"; mso-bidi-theme-font:minor-bidi; mso-ansi-language:EN-GB;}.MsoChpDefault {mso-style-type:export-only; mso-default-props:yes; font-family:"Calibri",sans-serif; mso-ascii-font-family:Calibri; mso-ascii-theme-font:minor-latin; mso-fareast-font-family:Calibri; mso-fareast-theme-font:minor-latin; mso-hansi-font-family:Calibri; mso-hansi-theme-font:minor-latin; mso-bidi-font-family:"Times New Roman"; mso-bidi-theme-font:minor-bidi; mso-ansi-language:EN-GB;}div.WordSection1 {page:WordSection1;}ol {margin-bottom:0in;}ul {margin-bottom:0in;}</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 06:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1697002639576209</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religion in the Global Age: The Irreplicable Human/-ities?</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/10/06/religion-in-the-global-age-the-irreplicable-human-ities</link>
						<dc:creator>avincent</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, October 10, 2023 - 2:16pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>International Society for Religion, Literature and Culture</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:alana.vincent@umu.se">alana.vincent@umu.se</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/ecocriticism-and-environmental-studies">ecocriticism and environmental studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/international-conferences">international conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>December 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Religion in the Global Age
</p><p>The Religion in the Global Age panel at the International Society for Religion, Literature and Culture seeks papers that address the conference theme of "The Irreplacable Human/-ities?" within the framework of the analytic, scientific, or critical study of religion. In this panel, preference is given to papers focussed on comparative studies <strong>or</strong> on specific religions in the Global Age not otherwise represented by existing ISRLC panels. </p>
<p>The ir/replicability of the human is a restatement of a much older question of human distinctiveness, in which the human stands in contrast to “nature” or “the natural”, and religion has played a key role in creating and maintaining the discursive separation between the two. With technological advances introducing “the mechanical”, the binary relationship between the human and the natural has been reconfigured. Religious responses to this reconfiguration have varied widely, and for the 2024 conference, we invite papers which consider this reconfiguration from any vantage point within the remit of ISRLC. We are particularly interested in papers which address:</p>
<ul>
<li>religion and online culture, particularly with reference to</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li>religious subcultures which coalesce through social media</li>
<li>inter-religious dialogue and/or dispute in the digital space</li>
<li>conspiracy thinking </li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>pre-digital imaginations of the post-human </li>
<li>approaches to or depictions of the relationship between “humanity” and “nature” which reach beyond the historical binary configuration</li>
</ul>
<p>Queries and abstract proposals of no more than 350 words should be sent to Alana Vincent (Umeå University) at <a href="mailto:alana.vincent@umu.se">alana.vincent@umu.se</a> no later than 15 December 2023</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 07:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1697002639576208</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ March 15, 2024 -  March 16, 2024] Conference or similar: Second Annual Max Stirner Symposium</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/115314</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p><strong>Stirner and the Theory of Anarchism</strong></p>
<p>Max Stirner has been largely excluded from traditional academic discourse, with much of the work on him being produced within the anarchist tradition. This year’s annual Max Stirner Symposium seeks to rectify this academic exclusion while simultaneously respecting the non-academic contributions to Stirner scholarship by setting the theme of the conference as “Stirner and Anarchist Theory.” This includes a variety of approaches from purely philosophical questions related to anarchism, to the ways in which anarchist theory expands or restricts possible anarchist praxis. </p>
<p>We seek to investigate questions like: What can Stirner say about the metaphysical or ontological basis of anarchism? Does Stirner provide us with a sufficient theoretical grounding for his anarchist praxis? Can Stirner’s theory of subjectivity withstand the 20th Century critiques of the subject? Does Stirner instead prefigure some of these critiques of subjectivity? What is the status of the legitimacy of metaphysics for Stirner? Does he reject or rely on metaphysics? Do the developments of phenomenology pose problems for Stirner’s notion of property? What is the status of the subject-object dichotomy for Stirner? Can the centrality of the self as an egoist be defended? What are the advantages and disadvantages of a theoretical individualism for political praxis? Is theory even important to Stirner? Is his philosophy instead an atheoretical approach to ethics? What is the basis for organization for Stirner if any? Does the notion of the Unique problematize organizing, or does it aid it? Is organizing possible for an individualist theory?</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 05:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1696657028890338</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ January 14, 2024] CFP for conference or similar: Second Annual Max Stirner Symposium</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/115318</link>
						<description><p>Stirner and the Theory of Anarchism</p>
<p>Max Stirner has been largely excluded from traditional academic discourse, with much of the work on him being produced within the anarchist tradition. This year’s annual Max Stirner Symposium seeks to rectify this academic exclusion while simultaneously respecting the non-academic contributions to Stirner scholarship by setting the theme of the conference as “Stirner and Anarchist Theory.” This includes a variety of approaches from purely philosophical questions related to anarchism, to the ways in which anarchist theory expands or restricts possible anarchist praxis. </p>
<p>We seek to investigate questions like: What can Stirner say about the metaphysical or ontological basis of anarchism? Does Stirner provide us with a sufficient theoretical grounding for his anarchist praxis? Can Stirner’s theory of subjectivity withstand the 20th Century critiques of the subject? Does Stirner instead prefigure some of these critiques of subjectivity? What is the status of the legitimacy of metaphysics for Stirner? Does he reject or rely on metaphysics? Do the developments of phenomenology pose problems for Stirner’s notion of property? What is the status of the subject-object dichotomy for Stirner? Can the centrality of the self as an egoist be defended? What are the advantages and disadvantages of a theoretical individualism for political praxis? Is theory even important to Stirner? Is his philosophy instead an atheoretical approach to ethics? What is the basis for organization for Stirner if any? Does the notion of the Unique problematize organizing, or does it aid it? Is organizing possible for an individualist theory?</p>
<p>We are happy to announce that this year’s symposium will have an award of $200 for the best presentation from a member of a marginalized group in philosophy. This includes anyone marginalized on the basis of gender, race, ethnicity, sexuality, class, and ability.</p>
<p><strong><br/></strong></p>
<p>Submission information:</p>
<p><strong><br/></strong></p>
<p>Please include the following information in your submission:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Name &amp; institutional affiliation</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Your abstract (Maximum of 500 words)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A short (2-3 line) author bio</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Indication if you are eligible for the award for best presentation from a member of a marginalized group</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Include the above in an email with the subject line of “Symposium Submission” to stirnersymposium@gmail.com by January 14th, 2024.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 05:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1696657028890337</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ June 20, 2024 -  June 21, 2024] Conference or similar: Homo religiosus &amp; homo technicus: discontinuities and congruencies. Theological, philosophical and psychological approaches</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/115298</link>
						<description>Venue: Aleea Universității, no. 1<br/><br/><p>Homo religiosus and homo technicus define two contextual paradigms of man in the course of history: man who lives in the religious horizon, a constant of his existence, and man who coordinates his life in the quotidian references of technological development. In essence, his life is strongly impacted by new technologies. The same man in the same society, but a society in constant transformation in all its aspects.</p>
<p>The conference intends a multilateral approach to the relationship between the religious dimension of man and the techno-scientific conditions of quotidian life. What is the relationship between homo religiosus and homo technicus and what are the perspectives of this relationship? Does current scientific development invalidate religious truth? What are the challenges of new technologies, especially artificial intelligence, for religious and ethical integrity?</p>
<p>Panels</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Homo religiosus and homo technicus - definitions, interpretations, contextualizations </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The validity of religious truth and new technologies: antagonism or congruence?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The impact of new technologies on man from a theological, ethical, philosophical and psychological perspective</p>
</li>
</ul></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1696657028890336</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ November 24, 2023] Conference or similar: Integritate și redefinire. Omul în orizontul multi-dimensional al societății contemporane</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/115302</link>
						<description>Venue: Aleea Universității, no. 1<br/><br/><p>O simplă analiză asupra realității lumii de astăzi, a anului 2023, ne confirmă faptul că într-un interval de câțiva zeci de ani morfologia societății s-a schimbat radical: localul a devenit global în sensul vizibilității și a comprimării spațiului prin noile tehnici de comunicare, granițele dintre culturi și religii au devenit fluide prin relațiile dialogice și dinamica migrației, tendințele economice au creat rețele trans-naționale, care au generat noi reconfigurări politice, iar dezvoltările tehnologice au impulsionat noi arhitecturi ale ritmului cotidian. În acest context multi-dimensional, omul se simte mult mai pregnant pe sine însuși, simte mai intens relația cu celălalt și cu mediul înconjurător și caută să-și definească mult mai bine situarea în societate.</p>
<p>Omul este o identitate care sintetizează în sine un complex de experiențe cotidiene: religioase, sociale, psihologice, tehnice, medicale, economice, culturale. Iar riscul fragmentarizării vieții poate genera uitarea de sine, care este una dintre cele mai tragice forme de anxietate. Din acest considerent, miza integrității și a redefinirii de sine a devenit o coordonată esențială în registrul vieții. </p>
<p>Conferința își propune să fie un forum de dezbateri asupra unor întrebări care mizează pe faptul existențial: Cum ne păstrăm integritatea într-o societate multi-dimensională care ne provoacă printr-o serie de riscuri? Cum ne redefinim valorile axiologice în complexul experiențelor cotidiene contemporane? Ce aport are religia, filosofia, psihologia, medicina, cultura în articularea integrității umane?   </p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 05:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1696657028890335</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ November 1, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Toronto Philosophy of Religion Workshop</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/115274</link>
						<description><p>The Toronto Philosophy of Religion Work-in-Progress Group will hold a virtual conference on December 14th and 15th, 2023. The event will take place on Zoom, and will feature two keynote speakers: Meghan D. Page (Loyola University Maryland) and Matthew A. Benton (Seattle Pacific University).</p>
<p>There will be 6-8 slots available for other presenters. There is no theme; all topics in analytic philosophy of religion are welcome.</p>
<p>If you would like to be considered for one of these slots, please submit an abstract of 300 words or less, prepared for blind review, to porwipconference@gmail.com. Deadline: 11:59pm Eastern on November 1st, 2023.</p>
<p>(Questions can be directed to any of the conference co-organizers: Liz Jackson (lizjackson111@torontomu.ca), Klaas Kraay (kraay@torontomu.ca), and Daniel Rubio (danielkfrubio@gmail.com).)</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 05:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1696570623675276</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ December 14, 2023 -  December 15, 2023] Conference or similar: Toronto Philosophy of Religion Workshop</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/115270</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p>The Toronto Philosophy of Religion Work-in-Progress Group will hold a virtual conference on December 14th and 15th, 2023. The event will take place on Zoom, and will feature two keynote speakers: Meghan D. Page (Loyola University Maryland) and Matthew A. Benton (Seattle Pacific University).</p>
<p>There will be 6-8 slots available for other presenters. There is no theme; all topics in analytic philosophy of religion are welcome.</p>
<p>If you would like to be considered for one of these slots, please submit an abstract of 300 words or less, prepared for blind review, to porwipconference@gmail.com. Deadline: 11:59pm on November 1st, 2023.</p>
<p>(Questions can be directed to any of the conference co-organizers: Liz Jackson (lizjackson111@torontomu.ca), Klaas Kraay (kraay@torontomu.ca), and Daniel Rubio (danielkfrubio@gmail.com).)</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 05:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1696570623675275</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – October 4, 2023</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-october-4-2023/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find 31 new job opportunities, 1 Fellowship, 1 Grant, 6 Calls for Papers, 6 Conferences/Speakers, and 1 other event/submission.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 31!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Academic:</h4>



<h4>Instructor in Native American Studies (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Mendocino College, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: November 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178557639&amp;utm_source=10_03_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178557639&amp;utm_source=10_03_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor in Ancient Greek and Roman Philosophy</h4>



<p>University of California Berkeley, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: October 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178557573&amp;utm_source=10_03_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178557573&amp;utm_source=10_03_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor in the Department of Biblical Studies and Christian Ministries</h4>



<p>Gordon College, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: November 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178557489&amp;utm_source=10_03_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178557489&amp;utm_source=10_03_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Alexander Grass Chair in Jewish Studies (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>University of Florida, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: December 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178557377&amp;utm_source=10_03_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178557377&amp;utm_source=10_03_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor in Asian Philosophy</h4>



<p>University of Maryland, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: November 10, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://apply.interfolio.com/128918">https://apply.interfolio.com/128918</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Modern Unites States Jewish History</h4>



<p>Syracuse University, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178556880&amp;utm_source=10_03_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178556880&amp;utm_source=10_03_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Associate Professor of Biblical Studies</h4>



<p>Liberty University, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178556601&amp;utm_source=10_02_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178556601&amp;utm_source=10_02_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Yang Visiting Scholars in World Christianity (1-year appointment)</h4>



<p>Harvard University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: October 10, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178556466&amp;utm_source=10_02_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178556466&amp;utm_source=10_02_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Sociology</h4>



<p>Bryant University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: November 1. 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://employment.bryant.edu/postings/3821">https://employment.bryant.edu/postings/3821</a></p>



<h4>Postdoctoral Fellow in Near Eastern Studies</h4>



<p>Cornell University, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178555895&amp;utm_source=09_30_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178555895&amp;utm_source=09_30_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Associate Professor of Holocaust and Comparative Genocide Studies (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Binghampton University, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178555644&amp;utm_source=09_30_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178555644&amp;utm_source=09_30_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Chair/Professor of History, Philosophy, &amp; Religious Studies</h4>



<p>Eastern Kentucky University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: November 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178555125&amp;utm_source=09_30_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178555125&amp;utm_source=09_30_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor in Anthropology (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Eastern Kentucky University, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178555124&amp;utm_source=09_30_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178555124&amp;utm_source=09_30_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Religious Studies (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>North Carolina State University, USA</p>



<p>More Information:  <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178553503&amp;utm_source=09_29_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178553503&amp;utm_source=09_29_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor in the Medieval World (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Barnard College, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: December 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178552188&amp;utm_source=09_28_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178552188&amp;utm_source=09_28_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Associate Professor of Divinity – Old Testament/Hebrew (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Samford University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: November 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178549668&amp;AAEmail=133626&amp;MatchType=2&amp;utm_source=09_26_2023&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=AAEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178549668&amp;AAEmail=133626&amp;MatchType=2&amp;utm_source=09_26_2023&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=AAEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor in Islam (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Northwestern University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: November 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.historians.org/jobs/19198974/assistant-professor-in-islam">https://careers.historians.org/jobs/19198974/assistant-professor-in-islam</a></p>



<h4>Presidential Postdoctoral Fellowship “Race, Ethnicity, and Gender in Western Borderlands”</h4>



<p>Arizona State University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: October 28, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.historians.org/jobs/19215308/presidential-postdoctoral-fellowship-in-history">https://careers.historians.org/jobs/19215308/presidential-postdoctoral-fellowship-in-history</a></p>



<h4>Lecturers for University Writing Program (Non-tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Brandeis University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: November 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://academicjobsonline.org/ajo/jobs/25983?fbclid=IwAR2Os_PsTi2EVRoGDDGHkfcHsj1Xhjgs03uKqOC29hNEE10jHpXSIsU2chw">https://academicjobsonline.org/ajo/jobs/25983?fbclid=IwAR2Os_PsTi2EVRoGDDGHkfcHsj1Xhjgs03uKqOC29hNEE10jHpXSIsU2chw</a></p>



<h4>Minerva Recruitment Job Listings Cite (with areas specifically tailored for Ph.D.)</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://minerva-recruitment.com/">Minerva Recruitment – Higher Education Graduate Jobs, UK &amp; Worldwide (minerva-recruitment.com)</a></p>



<h4>AAR/SBL Job Forum</h4>



<p><a href="https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search">https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search</a></p>



<h4>Non-Academic:</h4>



<h4>University Archivist and Records Manager</h4>



<p>Lincoln University, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178557773&amp;utm_source=10_03_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178557773&amp;utm_source=10_03_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Associate Editor – Comparative Religion: Encyclopedia Britannica (Graduate Degree required)</h4>



<p>Chicago, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178554578&amp;utm_source=10_03_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178554578&amp;utm_source=10_03_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Director of Graduate Theological Programs in Spanish</h4>



<p>Indiana Wesleyan University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: October 29, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178557284&amp;utm_source=10_03_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178557284&amp;utm_source=10_03_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Middle East Project Specialist (2-year appointment)</h4>



<p>Harvard College Library, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178555381&amp;utm_source=09_30_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178555381&amp;utm_source=09_30_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Director of the Institute of Faith and Learning</h4>



<p>Baylor University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: December 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178553103&amp;utm_source=09_28_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178553103&amp;utm_source=09_28_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Dean of the College of Theology, Arts, &amp; Humanities</h4>



<p>Concordia University Chicago, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178553030&amp;utm_source=09_28_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178553030&amp;utm_source=09_28_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Director of Research, Evaluation &amp; Innovation</h4>



<p>Jewish Federation of San Diego, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/R1LwGIw2cG">https://t.co/R1LwGIw2cG</a></p>



<h4>University of North Carolina Press Intern (Paid)</h4>



<p>Deadline: Until filled</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://twitter.com/unc_press/status/1706679012192567320?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw">https://twitter.com/unc_press/status/1706679012192567320?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw</a></p>



<h4>Cultural Anthropologist (PhD encouraged)</h4>



<p>National Park Service</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.usajobs.gov/job/751658900">https://www.usajobs.gov/job/751658900</a></p>



<h4>Director of the Hall Center for the Humanities</h4>



<p>University of Kansas, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: November 6, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.historians.org/jobs/19210109/director-hall-center-for-the-humanities?utm_source=BTITwitter&amp;utm_medium=Twitter&amp;utm_campaign=BTI%2BTwitter%2BFeed">https://careers.historians.org/jobs/19210109/director-hall-center-for-the-humanities?utm_source=BTITwitter&amp;utm_medium=Twitter&amp;utm_campaign=BTI%2BTwitter%2BFeed</a></p>



<h4>Coordinator of Religious and Spiritual Life Initiatives – Student Affairs (Masters degree preferred)</h4>



<p>Carnegie Mellon University, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178552710">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178552710</a></p>



<h4>Editorial Assistant</h4>



<p>Society for Industrial &amp; Applied Mathematics, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/jobs/view/3730700261/">https://www.linkedin.com/jobs/view/3730700261/</a></p>



<h2>Fellowships:</h2>



<h4>“Time, Place, Everywhen” Visiting Fellowships</h4>



<p>Humanities Research Center – Australian National University</p>



<p>Deadline: October 20, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/xX5mJO9Ouh">https://t.co/xX5mJO9Ouh</a></p>



<h2>Grants:</h2>



<h4>AAR Undergraduate Research Grant</h4>



<p>Deadline: November 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/WZj3uvpYD8">https://t.co/WZj3uvpYD8</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>The Secular Paradox: On the Religiosity of the Not-Religious</h4>



<p>Deadline: December 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/QEbaYNbaSN">https://t.co/QEbaYNbaSN</a></p>



<h4>Contemporary Pagans in Public Interaction: Constructing Religion in Central and Eastern Europe</h4>



<p>Deadline: December 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/09/26/contemporary-pagans-in-public-interaction-constructing-religion-in-central-and">https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/09/26/contemporary-pagans-in-public-interaction-constructing-religion-in-central-and</a></p>



<h4>U.S. Catholic Historian: Archeology and Material Culture</h4>



<p>Deadline: August 1, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://twitter.com/monicalmercado/status/1707738262146519523?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw">https://twitter.com/monicalmercado/status/1707738262146519523?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw</a></p>



<h4>Reimagining Relationality Graduate Student Conference</h4>



<p>Deadline: December 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/ASPECT_Conference_2024_CfP.pdf">https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/ASPECT_Conference_2024_CfP.pdf</a></p>



<h4>Between Power and Authority: Arendt on the Constitution and the Courts</h4>



<p>Deadline: December 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/115142">https://philevents.org/event/show/115142</a></p>



<h4>Challenging Concepts Debating Conceptualism and Non-Conceptualism in Epistemology and Metaphysics</h4>



<p>Deadline: December 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/115110">https://philevents.org/event/show/115110</a></p>



<h2>Conferences/Speakers</h2>



<h4>Legal and Theological Theory of the Doctrine of Christian Discovery</h4>



<p>Syracuse University, USA</p>



<p>Date: December 8-10, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://artsandsciences.syracuse.edu/religion/news/university-to-host-conference-that-addresses-legal-and-theological-theory-of-the-doctrine-of-christian-discovery/">https://artsandsciences.syracuse.edu/religion/news/university-to-host-conference-that-addresses-legal-and-theological-theory-of-the-doctrine-of-christian-discovery/</a></p>



<h4>European Research Council Grants for Top Researchers from Anywhere in the World</h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>Date: October 12, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://twitter.com/euraxess_ausnz/status/1707181015763181864?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw">https://twitter.com/euraxess_ausnz/status/1707181015763181864?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw</a></p>



<h4>Beyond Doubt: The Secularization of Society Lecture</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/j8e8kgb78G">https://t.co/j8e8kgb78G</a></p>



<h4>Cultivating Food Justice in Christian Community</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://twitter.com/westarinstitute/status/1707881258519502969?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw">https://twitter.com/westarinstitute/status/1707881258519502969?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw</a></p>



<h4>New Directions in the Study of Religion, and Public Life</h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>Date: October 19, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/RSP-NW.jpg">https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/RSP-NW.jpg</a></p>



<h4>Davis Colloquium on Christianity and Economy</h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>Date: October 27, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/QtnMWjF4X2">https://t.co/QtnMWjF4X2</a></p>



<h2>Miscellaneous:</h2>



<h4>Through the Looking Glass – How to Incorporate Visual Material within Research</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/iXlzQGgmiy">https://t.co/iXlzQGgmiy</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1696484226232399</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Spiritual Responses to American Literary Modernism--Call for Chapter Proposals</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/10/02/spiritual-responses-to-american-literary-modernism-call-for-chapter-proposals</link>
						<dc:creator>wpetrie</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Wednesday, October 4, 2023 - 11:06am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Windy Counsell Petrie / Azusa Pacific University</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:wpetrie@apu.edu">wpetrie@apu.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/modernist-studies">modernist studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>January 8, 2024</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong><em>Spiritual Responses to American Literary Modernism~ Call for Chapter Proposals</em></strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>At the end of 1920, F. Scott Fitzgerald’s first novel, <em>This Side of Paradise</em>, explored the crises of a new generation who had “grown up to find all Gods dead… all faiths in man shaken.” Scholars and theologians concur that American literature, like the culture at large, was undergoing a passage from a spiritual to a secular outlook throughout the 1920s and 30s. This transition was so dramatic and widespread that that the years between 1925-1935 have been termed “the American Religious Depression.” Indeed, many texts from these two decades present their own version of the larger cultural secularization thesis.</p>
<p>But while the secularization thesis is not wrong, it does not provide a complete picture of American literary history between the World Wars. This project seeks to fill this gap by examining the role of spiritual discourse in the literature of the era. It is true that many modernist texts convey a sense of cultural decay or spiritual darkness through cynicism, iconoclasm, or unintelligibility. However, there were a number of American writers who, despite the zeitgeist in which they lived and worked, still insisted on extending either hope, faith, or charity to their readers.</p>
<p>A number of scholars, critics, and editors called for a “spiritual readjustment” in American literature during the 1920s and 30s, and a cadre of writers were working towards this "readjustment" in their fiction or poetry. Some wrote using spiritually coded terms such as transcendence, surrender, sacrifice, or mystery. Others wrote within Judeo-Christian traditions, but were focused on righting injustices within those traditions. There were some who understood faith--although not necessarily religious faith-- as a human necessity. In this expanded sense, faith can mean belief in humanity, meaning, or commitment to progress. </p>
<p>This volume will consist of readings of American texts from the 1920s and 1930s which foreground the presence or impact of the following spiritually-inflected terms in conversation with the ethos of literary modernism:</p>
<p> </p>
<p> Hope</p>
<p> Belief</p>
<p>Transcendence</p>
<p>Mystery</p>
<p>Compassion</p>
<p>Connectedness or Community</p>
<p>Sacrifice</p>
<p>Redemption, among other spiritually-inflected terms</p>
<p> </p>
<p>This edited collection will trace the resurgence of these metaphysical concepts in the work of American writers who were not identified with formal religion as well as those who were. I am happy to receive proposals for chapters which reconsider the work of canonical authors, but would especially welcome proposals treating lesser known or neglected writers of the 20s and 30s. </p>
<p>Please submit chapter proposals of 300-500 words by January 8, 2024 to Windy Petrie at <a href="mailto:wpetrie@apu.edu">wpetrie@apu.edu</a>. Potential contributors will receive a response by January 26. Complete chapters of between 7,000- 10,000 words will be due July 15.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1696484226232398</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
