<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:56:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:56:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ September 15, 2022 -  September 16, 2022] Conference or similar: Rethinking Privacy after this Pandemic</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/102594</link>
						<description>Venue: Poppelsdorfer Allee 28<br/><br/><p>Symposium Rethinking Privacy after this Pandemic, September 15 &amp; 16 2022 at the University of Bonn and online<br/><br/>The ways societies handled the COVID-19 pandemic from early 2020 on has shed light onto a topic that concerns us all: privacy. Having to use online meeting, learning and teaching software to be able to take part in social, school and work life, gave the providers of these services and products an even greater market power alongside with increased spying and surveillance opportunities into peoples’ daily lives. Opting-out of using these tools became impossible. Using smartphones that are ubiquitous listening devices anyhow for governmental Corona tracing did raise many data protection concerns, leading in several countries to trying to build “privacy by design”- applications and take ethical issues into consideration. Being forced to stay at home, not having a dedicated space for work, as “room of one’s own”, nor for leisure, not being able to choose freely with whom to spend one’s free time, (intellectual) property rights of vaccines, rise of domestic violence, non-access to medical care and contraception for women etc. have put into focus questions of the privacy debate many people conceived of as discussed – or even solved – decades ago.</p>
<p>At this conference we will undertake an interdisciplinary reconsideration of privacy, asking how we do want our society to look like based on what we saw, experienced and hopefully learned from the current present and recent past.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 05:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1662010631593662</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Opportunities Digest – 31 August 2022</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-opportunities-digest-31-august-2022/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! You will find two job postings for this week.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 37!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs</h2>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Theology and Religious Studies with a specialization in New Testament</h4>



<p>The University of San Diego in California, US</p>



<p>Deadline: September 16<sup>th,</sup> 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/e1DLmdpmUT">https://t.co/e1DLmdpmUT</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Religious Studies (Tenure Track)</h4>



<p>Eckerd College, US</p>



<p>Deadline: October 7<sup>th,</sup> 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://eckerd.hirecentric.com/jobs/219076.html?fbclid=IwAR2BnYDGiemO464ajAzuDHVq8MuGFqHfpVzI9UYtvRow9BKCLt7nnKc6Vqc">https://eckerd.hirecentric.com/jobs/219076.html?fbclid=IwAR2BnYDGiemO464ajAzuDHVq8MuGFqHfpVzI9UYtvRow9BKCLt7nnKc6Vqc</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1662010631593661</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Dobbs Decision: Religious and Theological Reflections in the Post-Roe Context</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10767014/dobbs-decision-religious-and-theological-reflections-post-roe</link>
						<dc:creator>Wendell Johnson</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-01T00:00:00-04:00">November 1, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Illinois</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Health and Health Care, Library and Information Science, Public Health, Religious Studies and Theology, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>“The Dobbs Decision: Religious and Theological Reflections in the Post-Roe Context”</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span><span><span>The Journal of Religious and Theological Information</span></span></span></i><span><span><span>, published by Taylor and Francis, seeks articles for a special issue devoted to the post-Roe v. Wade environment. We seek a variety of viewpoints (from all faith traditions) and disciplines, both critical of the Dobbs decision and in support of it. Our primary audience consists of librarians and information professionals interested in religious issues and theological bibliography. </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Abstracts due: November 1, 2022</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Articles due: March 1, 2022</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Publication: Volume 22, (January 1, 2024)</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Articles will be uploaded to the journal's online platform upon receipt of proofs (in advance of publication date)</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>We ask that all articles include an English-language bibliography of readily available resources (both print and digital). More information about the Journal of Religious and Theological Information can be found on the journal’s website:</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/toc/wrti20/current" rel="nofollow">https://www.tandfonline.com/toc/wrti20/current</a></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Please contact Wendell G. Johnson, General Editor <i>Journal of Religious and Theological Information </i>(<a href="mailto:wjohnso1@niu.edu">wjohnso1@niu.edu</a>)</span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:wjohnso1@niu.edu">wjohnso1@niu.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 16:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1661972393783940</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Journal Article Publication</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10761377/journal-article-publication</link>
						<dc:creator>Abimbola Adelakun</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Journal</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>African History / Studies, Digital Humanities, Immigration &amp; Migration History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, World History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Dear Colleagues,</p><p>I like to announce the publication of my new article titled, <em>"Thank God for Amazon.com”: Spiritual Warfare, African Theology, and Prayer Merch</em>, published in the Journal of World Christianity. The article is centered around religious merchandising and Christian missionary initiatives through the online marketplace of Amazon.</p><p>Pls., find the link to the article and the abstract below. </p><p><strong>Abstract: </strong>This essay explores the ongoing formations of global Pentecostalism by tracing a route through which some of the practices of exchange travel: Amazon.com. Noting that the “spirits” of globalization, modernity, and capitalism now enable a rapid move of the religious spirit, I spotlight the experiences of four Nigerian ministers who list merchandise of prayer (or “prayer merch”) in the form of books and spiritual warfare prayer manuals for sale on the online marketplace. With personal interviews and a content analysis of the reviews and ratings of their works, I consider the commodification of the practical African theology of prayers, the tactics of promotion, the ethos of Black spirituality that facilitates sales, and the balancing of divine encounter and enterprise.</p><p><a href="https://scholarlypublishingcollective.org/psup/world-christianity/article-abstract/12/2/280/317006/Thank-God-for-Amazon-com-Spiritual-Warfare-African" rel="nofollow">https://scholarlypublishingcollective.org/psup/world-christianity/articl...</a></p><p>Thank you.</p><p>Abimbola A. Adelakun, Ph.D.<br/>African and African Diaspora Studies<br/>University of Texas at Austin<br/>210 W. 24th Street <br/>Mailcode E3400<br/>Austin, TX 78712<br/>(512) 471-4362.</p><p><a href="mailto:adelakun@austin.utexas.edu">adelakun@austin.utexas.edu</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>African and African Diaspora Studies,</p><p>University of Texas at Austin</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:adelakun@austin.utexas.edu">adelakun@austin.utexas.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 17:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1661972393783939</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FEATURED JOB: Das Chair in South Asian Studies- Brown University</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10734415/featured-job-das-chair-south-asian-studies-brown-university</link>
						<dc:creator>Kendra Fuller</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Home Office Notices (Jobs, Reviews)</div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Rhode Island</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>South Asian History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Brown University's Department of Religious Studies invites applications for an open rank appointment in Hindu Studies to fill the Das Chair in South Asian Studies.  We seek a colleague well-versed in Hindu worlds of South Asia in close conversation with the study of religion. Applicants' work may be historical, philological, literary, or ethnographic, pertaining to any region and research language in South Asia. A topical specialization in the study of gender in the period since 1500 CE is preferred. Applicants must have the PhD by the beginning of the appointment.  The application must include: cover letter; curriculum vitae; the names of three references whom the department may contact; and a writing sample.  Diversity, equity and inclusion are integral to the commitment of the Religious Studies Department and Brown University.  Accordingly, Religious Studies seeks qualified candidates who can contribute to racial and gender equity, diversity and inclusion in their scholarship and professional activities.  Further, Religious Studies is keenly interested in diversifying higher education and encourages applications from historically underrepresented groups in higher education. Separate documents describing teaching philosophy and research are optional.  Please submit all materials online via Interfolio (<a href="https://apply.interfolio.com/111396" rel="nofollow">https://apply.interfolio.com/111396</a>).  The deadline for applications is October 15, 2022. </p><hr/><p>To submit YOUR job posting, please visit the H-Net Job Guide:<a href="https://www.h-net.org/jobs" rel="nofollow"> https://www.h-net.org/jobs</a></p><p>Featured jobs receive an added boost on H-Announce and H-Net’s social media channels.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Apply via Interfolio: <a href="https://apply.interfolio.com/111396" rel="nofollow">https://apply.interfolio.com/111396</a> </p><p>For questions, please email <a href="mailto:Religious_Studies@brown.edu?subject=Das%20Chair%20in%20South%20Asian%20Studies&amp;body=Thank%20you%20for%20your%20interest%20in%20the%20Das%20Chair%20in%20South%20Asian%20Studies%20at%20Brown%20University.%20%20Someone%20will%20inquiry%20within%201-3%20business%20days.%0A%0A">Religious_Studies@brown.edu</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php" target="_blank">https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php?id=63819</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 16:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1661972393783938</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Papers Twelfth Annual REFORC Conference on Early Modern Christianity</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10722803/call-papers-twelfth-annual-reforc-conference-early-modern</link>
						<dc:creator>Karla Boersma</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-05-11T00:00:00-04:00">May 11, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-05-13T00:00:00-04:00">May 13, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Belgium</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Early Modern History and Period Studies, Economic History / Studies, European History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span>The Twelfth Annual REFORC Conference on Early Modern Christianity will be hosted by the KU Leuven, and will take place May 11-13, 2023. We welcome short paper proposals related to the topic of the plenary lectures, as well as on all other subjects dealing with Early Modern Christianity.</span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><b><span>Topic Plenary Lectures</span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Early Modern Christianity, Economic Entrepreneurship, and Social Welfare</span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span>The REFORC conference in Leuven takes the four-hundredth anniversary of the death of the Jesuit Leonard Lessius — one of the founders of modern contract law and free economic initiative — as an occasion to open up the discussion to include the Jewish tradition and the various Christian confessions. Questions that can be discussed at the conference include: How did early modern Jewish and Christian thinkers see the relationship between theology of salvation, economic entrepreneurship, and social welfare? How did they view interest on borrowed money? And how did they define the responsibility of successful Christian entrepreneurs for the poor and destitute? What were the internal discussions within the various confessional groups – also with their own institutional authorities – and with other confessions? And how does all this relate to Max Weber’s now hundred-year-old theory of the spirit of Protestantism and the emergence of capitalism in Western Europe?</span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><b><span>Plenary Speakers</span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Wim Decock (UC Louvain), Nina Javette Koefoed (Aarhus University), Germano Maifreda (University of Milan), Brian P. Owensby (University of Virginia, History Department), Eleonora Rai (KU Leuven), Keith Stanglin (Heritage Christian University, Florence, AL).</span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><b><span>Short Papers, Panels, and General Attendance</span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>The (in-person) conference is open to individual short paper presentations (20 minute presentations) and to thematic sessions of two or three short papers. Papers can focus on all disciplines related to Early Modern Christianity, ca. 1400-1700, such as philosophy, law, history, theology, etc., independent of the theme of the plenary papers.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>It is also possible to attend the conference without giving a paper.</span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><b><span>Deadline Short Paper Submission</span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>March 1, 2023.</span></span></span></span></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Karla Boersma</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:info@reforc.com">info@reforc.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://reforc.com/events/twelfth-annual-reforc-conference-on-early-modern-christianity/" target="_blank">https://reforc.com/events/twelfth-annual-reforc-conference-on-early-modern-christianity/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 17:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1661972393783937</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Football and Religion: Tales of Hope, Play and Passion</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10716310/football-and-religion-tales-hope-play-and-passion</link>
						<dc:creator>Layal Mohammad</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Event</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-09-01T00:00:00-04:00">September 1, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-12-04T00:00:00-05:00">December 4, 2022</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Art, Art History &amp; Visual Studies, Cultural History / Studies, Fine Arts, Religious Studies and Theology, Sport History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Join us on 1 September for a panel discussion on our upcoming exhibition "Football and Religion: Tales of Hope, Play and Passion". The event will take place at the Aga Khan Centre, London, as well as online and will be followed by a viewing of the exhibition.</p><p><strong>About the Exhibition</strong></p><p>Presented by the Aga Khan University’s Institute for the Study of Muslim Civilisations (AKU-ISMC) and the Aga Khan Centre Gallery, this exhibition explores the relationship between football and religion and how the two are often connected, with players praying on the pitch and fans observing religious rituals in tandem. The wider narrative across the exhibition examines football’s ability to champion social causes, promote marginalised voices, and create opportunities for inclusion and diversity in ways no other sport can.</p><p>The exhibition provides a narrative on the subject through a snapshot of social history and contemporary commentary with a selection of books, magazines and newspaper articles, relevant objects, and artefacts. This narrative provides the contextual backdrop for a series of new artworks created by visual artist, illustrator, and animator Ed Merlin Murray.</p><p>The exhibition, Football and Religion, includes something for everyone — from eye-catching immersive illustrated animations to interactive art and a host of inspirational media that allow visitors to delve into the subject as much as they wish.</p><p>Visit the Aga Khan Centre Gallery for more details about the exhibition: <a href="https://l.facebook.com/l.php?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.agakhancentre.org.uk%2Fgallery%2F%3Ffbclid%3DIwAR00McuAQb7NQtz2VivNUajAK5cfHgbQljcWnveSmGW3k9USGG3Bd9iuP7k&amp;h=AT2j2Vbbw71SyAKMSrD8LMDoxnuajiHpE2foIbdi11BPdsxQu3SkBrS7GdaMaSPNi60oVuL0LQ1Jv-IPnTIdQBmWWlt-UMFaLW_3BbWmwB1ok25PYcp7X0-VrrPVhj2EJ2mH&amp;__tn__=q&amp;c%5B0%5D=AT2LHDizljvunDMcKgtUrTP2fF6L_ei6xOnPXNFilUbeySVwjVMmjGfSmGNbcUisPmNbYvCrIpOcOd6IskQM9MktY7V50hV9j2_0LZZmNuUc03UhpwMt71uo1fq7XiLdfyqgalbQG4R13terCWb18dwTbAocPi6q-cv-q3qkiRgUoN4" rel="nofollow">www.agakhancentre.org.uk/gallery/</a></p><p><strong>Speakers</strong></p><p>• Kevin Coleman: Formerly of Brentford FC (Chair).</p><p>• Ed Merlin Murray: Visual artist and animator.</p><p>• Karshima Inayat: Gilgit League Pakistan.</p><p>• Dr Zafar Iqbal: Head of Sports Medicine, Crystal Palace FC.</p><p>• Matt Baker: Director of Sports Chaplaincy UK and Chaplain for Charlton Athletic FC.</p><p>• Linvoy Primus: Former Portsmouth and Charlton FC.</p><p>• Yasmin Abukar: Founder Sisterhood FC.</p><p><strong>Dates and Times</strong></p><p>Panel Discussion: 1 September 2022, 18:00-19:00 (London Time)</p><p>Exhibition Viewing: 1 September 2022, 19:00-20:00</p><p>Exhibition Viewing: 2 September - 4 December 2022</p><p><strong>Venue</strong></p><p>Aga Khan Centre (Atrium Conference Room and Gallery),<br/>10 Handyside Street,<br/>London N1C 4DN</p><p><strong>Booking</strong></p><p>The event is free, but booking is essential:</p><p>To attend in person, register via Eventbrite: <a href="https://fal.cn/3r4zn?fbclid=IwAR255eyfF9UAFw7cRq4JU2viHURuiKfqo34Q3zqHhjUgX1g_5QDXtF9AsRo" rel="nofollow">https://fal.cn/3r4zn</a></p><p>To attend online, register via Zoom: <a href="https://fal.cn/3r4zo?fbclid=IwAR2a-n1ShDHEJEwN9Xk_DDNSPSC_XqDIKnCBemF5ndeUvM-64WsUfgEEIA4" rel="nofollow">https://fal.cn/3r4zo</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Layal Mohammad</span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span>Senior Coordinator, Marketing &amp; Communications</span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span>Institute for the Study of Muslim Civilisations</span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span>The Aga Khan University (International)</span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span>Aga Khan Centre, 10 Handyside Street, London N1C 4DN</span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span>Tel: +44 [0] 20 7380 3839</span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span>Incorporated in England as a company limited by guarantee no. 4448389 | </span></span></span><span><span><span>Registered Charity Number 1179136</span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:layal.n.mohammad@aku.edu">layal.n.mohammad@aku.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.aku.edu/ismc/events/pages/event-detail.aspx" target="_blank">https://www.aku.edu/ismc/events/pages/event-detail.aspx?EventID=2179&amp;Title=Football%20and%20Religion%3A%20Tales%20of%20H…</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 18:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1661972393783936</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>After Earth? Religion and Technology on a Changing Planet</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10710923/after-earth-religion-and-technology-changing-planet</link>
						<dc:creator>Evan Berry</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-02T00:00:00-05:00">February 2, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-05T00:00:00-05:00">February 5, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Arizona</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Environmental History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Anthropology, Humanities, Social Sciences</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><strong>2023 ISSRNC Conference | Call for Papers</strong></p><p><b>February 2-5, 2023 @ Arizona State University and Beyond</b></p><p>Human-induced changes to the Earth system are happening at an unprecedented rate. At the same time that human activity is disrupting the climate, igniting mega-fires, depleting natural resources, and triggering mass extinctions, we are witnessing renewed interest in space exploration and extra-bodily aspirations. Religion and spirituality, in myriad forms, are present in calls to restore nature and respect natural limits, as well as in excitement about transgressing traditional earthly boundaries and creating new futures. Pressing global-scale environmental and social problems are increasingly met with technological responses that can foster greater intimacy and entanglement with nature, but also detachment from nature and material processes. </p><p>Hyperconnectivity and alienation simultaneously define our social lives and interactions with nature. Can the same technologies that potentially enable humans to decouple from Earth be deployed to save it? Can emerging technologies be a vehicle for positive change or religious transformation? How, if at all, do techno-solutions address the underlying cultural, social, and religious causes of global crises? Do emerging technologies fundamentally alter the human-nature relationship, or are they merely the latest version of longstanding religious or secular-scientific interpretations of the human? Is there an implied theological anthropology embedded in techno-social and techno-environmental projects? How do technologies at the horizons of planetary limits—from space exploration to renewable energy—intersect with matters of race, gender, and justice? Does a global-scale response to these interconnected, escalating crises demand a shared, common vision of the human?</p><p>We welcome proposals from scholars across the arts and humanities, sciences and social sciences, inviting all researchers broadly engaged with the nexus of religion, nature, and culture. The conference theme of “Religion and Technology on a Changing Planet” is a direct invitation to those scholars working on the following:</p><ul><li>Religious and spiritual aspects of emerging technologies, including rewilding, virtual reality, artificial intelligence, space exploration, etc.;</li><li>Theological and ethical critiques of emerging technologies including climate engineering, de-extinction, synthetic biology, space exploration (e.g. settlement, empire, extraction, colonization, terraforming); </li><li>Inquiries into the intersection of religion, gender, sexuality, and embodiment with the construction of scientific and technological forms of knowledge;</li><li>Religious and spiritual dimensions of planetary models (Gaia, Earth System Science, Spaceship Earth, cybernetics, animism, autopoiesis and ecopoiesis); </li><li>Compatibility or conflict of emerging technologies with environmental justice, Indigenous rights and perspectives, religious/ethical perspectives on animals or nature;</li><li>Engagement of religious and spiritual groups with post-truth technologies (social media, misinformation, science denial, conspiracy); </li><li>Futurevisions and worldmaking, religion in/and/of science fiction, dystopia, utopia, apocalypticism, Afro-futurism, Afro-pessimism, religion and ethics in promised, unrealized, and emerging human and non-human futures;</li><li>Machine intelligence, AI, and transhumanism; sapient technologies, techno-transcendence, religious, spiritual and ethical dimensions of human augmentation and organic-synthetic fusions, technologically facilitated spiritual experiences; cybernetics, disability, queerness; </li><li>Intersections of religion and spirituality with extractivism, disposability, necropolitics, and ‘throw-away culture’; the theology and ethics of energy transition; climate change belief and denial in a digitally mediated political economy; </li><li>We also invite reflection on theory and method in the study of religion and the environment; barriers to interdisciplinary inquiry; and/or discussion of methods and practices for engaging across disciplines. </li></ul><p><strong>Format:</strong></p><p>The 2023 ISSRNC Conference will employ a hybrid format. Assuming that coronavirus protocols allow it, our  primary modality will be an in-person gathering at the Tempe campus of Arizona State University. Remote participation will be possible, especially for presenters who pre-arrange their virtual participation and for presenters from the Global South whose participation will be enabled by remote technologies. Our hybrid format will also include “satellite” locations, which will facilitate in-person participation for smaller groups who wish to limit their carbon emissions by gathering at a site nearer to home. Satellite locations and details for these regional gatherings will be announced soon. </p><p><strong>Proposal Submission and Deadlines:</strong> </p><p>We invite proposals from all researchers working at the nexus of religion, nature, and culture. </p><p>Proposals may take the form of individual papers or pre-arranged panel sessions. <b>Paper </b>proposals must include two documents: The first should be a 150-word abstract that includes the Title, as well as the name and contact information of the Participant. The second should be a 500-word (or less) description of the paper that includes the title, and indicates the methods, argument, and findings as well as the relevant literature engaged. <b>Session proposals</b> should include paper proposals for each participant as well as an overview document describing the session title, theme, participants, and order of presentation.</p><p>Proposals for sessions or events that would not fit the traditional session format are also encouraged. For instance, we invite proposals for an experimental online session that would enable ISSRNC members to present at the conference without physically attending. This session would consist of pre-recorded video presentations that would be available to all conference participants. The presenters would be expected to participate in an asynchronous online discussion of the presentation throughout the conference. We also plan to reserve space for a number of panels developed through new or existing ISSRNC <a href="https://www.issrnc.org/working-groups/" rel="nofollow">online working groups</a>.</p><p>Please use the submission form provided on the <a href="https://www.issrnc.org/conferences/2023-conference/" rel="nofollow">ISSRNC 2023 Conference page</a> to submit your proposal by <b>September 30, 2022</b>. Papers will be anonymously peer-reviewed by an international scholarly committee and decisions made by late October 2022. All presenters will be required to <a href="https://www.issrnc.org/membership-account/membership-levels/" rel="nofollow">join or renew as members</a> in good standing of the International Society for the Study of Religion, Nature and Culture. Presenters and session organizers are encouraged to submit their articles for publication, or their sessions for special issues, to the official publication of the ISSRNC, the <a href="https://journals.equinoxpub.com/index.php/JSRNC/index" rel="nofollow">Journal for the Study of Religion, Nature, and Culture</a> (<em>JSRNC</em>).</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:secretary@issrnc.edu">secretary@issrnc.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.issrnc.org/conferences/2023-conference/2023-asu-cfp/" target="_blank">https://www.issrnc.org/conferences/2023-conference/2023-asu-cfp/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 17:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1661972393783935</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP: Esotericism, Occultism, and Magic at Southwest Popular/American Culture Association 2023 (Albuquerque, New Mexico, Feb. 22-25)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10662027/cfp-esotericism-occultism-and-magic-southwest-popularamerican</link>
						<dc:creator>George Sieg</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-31T00:00:00-04:00">October 31, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>New Mexico</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Cultural History / Studies, Humanities, Intellectual History, Popular Culture Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>Call for Papers</span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>ESOTERICISM, OCCULTISM, AND MAGIC</span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>Southwest Popular / American Culture Association (SWPACA)</span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p>                                         <span><span><span><span><span>44th Annual Conference, February 22-25, 2023</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Marriott Albuquerque</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Albuquerque, New Mexico</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><a href="http://www.southwestpca.org/" rel="nofollow"><span><span>http://www.southwestpca.org</span></span></a></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Submissions open on <b>August 15, 2022</b></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Proposal submission deadline: <b>October 31, 2022</b></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Proposals for papers and panels are now being accepted for the 44th annual SWPACA conference. One of the nation’s largest interdisciplinary academic conferences, SWPACA offers nearly 70 subject areas, each typically featuring multiple panels.  For a full list of subject areas, area descriptions, and Area Chairs, please visit </span></span><a href="http://southwestpca.org/conference/call-for-papers/" rel="nofollow"><span><span>http://southwestpca.org/conference/call-for-papers/</span></span></a></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Esotericism, Occultism, and Magic invites proposals relating to magical worldviews, practices, and representations, as well as consciousness transformation, hidden meanings, the power of transmutation, and related phenomena. Characteristic beliefs and practices include: arcane symbolism, imagery, and aesthetics; unseen forces and spiritual intermediaries; synchronous patterns, non-ordinary causation, and anomalous processes. Examples of concepts and systems include Theosophy, Freemasonry, Rosicrucianism, Hermeticism, Gnosticism, Sufism, Satanism, Tantra, witchcraft, sorcery, demonology, astrology, alchemy, shamanism, yoga, parapsychology, and psychic and paranormal phenomena, along with beliefs and practices relating to altered states of consciousness, overlapping with the study of mysticism as well as New Age spirituality, channeling, positive thinking, manifest intention, guardian angels, and Ascended Masters. Esoteric, occult, and magical ideas, beliefs, and practices appear in every culture and civilization; contemporary media and popular culture have embraced them enthusiastically, yet at times have reacted against them. The impact of esotericism, occultism, and magic on genre formation/content and popular cultural perceptions has been profound.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><a name="m_-7259256431519726101__Hlk56944543"><span><span><span>Individual papers, organized panels, and roundtable discussions welcomed. Please contact the </span></span></span></a><span><span><span>area chair with questions/suggestions. Special themes discussed for 2023 may include the following, but all proposals suitable to the Area will be considered:</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>EOM and augmented reality, virtual reality, metacognition, metanarrative, artifice, and the uncanny (valley); Gnostic metafiction and mythology; ontological pressure, self-similarity, meta-textuality and fourth-wall-breaking as technique and representation in EOM; EOM and the (anti)cosmic weird; EOM, the inhuman, the unhuman, the abhuman, the monstrous, and the abject; conception, creation, conjuration, and animation of artificial life, unlife, the undead, spirits, servitors, familiars, elementals, homunculi, and constructs; EOM and the paranormal; EOM representations in alternative media; EOM, tradition, traditionalism, and metapolitics; EOM and sectarianism, radicalism, deviance, reactionary movements, extremisms, “extremes” and “the extreme”; crime, violence, and transgression; the demonic, the diabolic, and EOM anti-religion; Cross-cultural intersections and syncretisms; Islamic esotericism and magic in reception and representation; reconstructed/speculated historical practices in popular culture and fiction; scientistic representations in esotericism, occultism, and magic; the crossroads and the in-between; the symbolic significance and function of place, location, and locality; the mainstreaming of EOM; the intersection of EOM with popular spirituality, including popular numerology and astrology, angel beliefs, self-help, popular witchcraft and spellcasting; EOM across, within, between, and <i>as </i>genre; archives, archaicism, and nostalgia; canonicity in representations and transmissions; fantasy and escapism in worldview, practice, and representation; scrying, divination, surveillance, the “seer” and conceptions/representations of the “watchers”, EOM , the erotic, and the ecstatic; EOM, love, romance, and romanticism; EOM and aesthetics; EOM, transcendence, the mystical, and altered/nonordinary consciousness; theurgy, theosis, deification, alchemy, transmutation, the transpersonal, and the transhuman; EOM as transdisciplinary </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Sample Ideas for topics categorized by media:</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Literature: Fiction by practitioners, such as Philip K. Dick, William S. Burroughs, C. S. Friedman. Books by practitioners (for example, Evola, Gurdjieff, Crowley, Anton LaVey, Gerald Gardner, Peter Carroll, Edgar Cayce). Influences and themes in magical realism, speculative fiction, gothic fiction, weird fiction, historical fiction, urban fantasy, paranormal romance and adventure. Fiction influential on practitioners, such as <i>Zanoni</i>, Goethe’s <i>Faust</i>, The <i>Illuminatus! </i>Trilogy. Historical representations of magicians, witches, and wizards, including stylized and mythic figures (Merlin, Morgan La </span></span></span><span>Fey</span><span><span><span>, Circe, Medea, Kostchie the Deathless, etc.), in genre fiction (contemporary Arthurian adaptations) or modernizations (Neil Gaiman, Tim Powers, Jim Butcher), indigenous futurism and fantasy (Octavia Butler, Rebecca Roanhorse).  New Age and/or popular manifestation guides, such as The Secret. Conspiracist and/or extra-terrestrial cosmologies related to esoteric concepts (David Icke, the Seth transmissions to Jane Roberts, the Michael channelings, etc.).</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Visual Art: Examples: Wassily Kandinsky, Austin Spare, Rosaleen Norton, Michael Bertiaux.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Film: Content as in <i>Dune, The Color Out of Space, The VVitch</i>, <i>Hereditary</i>, <i>Midsommar</i>, <i>The Skeleton Key</i>, <i>The Serpent and the Rainbow</i>, <i>The Ninth Gate</i>, <i>The Conjuring </i>series, <i>The Wicker Man</i>; Gnostic allegories such as <i>The Matrix</i>, <i>Dark City</i>, <i>The Truman Show</i>; explorations of consciousness such as <i>eXistenZ</i>, <i>Altered States</i>, <i>2001 Space Odyssey</i>; representations of occult aesthetic, such as <i>Eyes Wide Shut</i>, or traumatic initiation, such as the <i>Saw</i> series; stylized depictions of magicians, wizards, and witches (<i>Dr. Strange, Shazam, Maleficent, Oz, Warlock, Thulsa Doom </i>of<i> Conan, Jafar</i> of <i>Aladdin</i>) ; esoteric/occult films such those by Kenneth Anger and Alejandro Jodorowsky; pseudo- and crypto-history in fiction (<i>Tomb Raider, National Treasure</i>); New Age documentaries, such as <i>The Secret</i>; conspiracist receptions of esoteric and occult history, such as <i>Zeitgeist</i>.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Television: Theme and/or content examples <i>Westworld, Stranger Things, Brand New Cherry Flavor, Sandman, Wandavision, Game of Thrones/House of the Dragon, The Witcher, The Magicians, Shadowhunters, The Man in the High Castle, The Chilling Adventures of Sabrina, Twin Peaks, Westworld, Penny Dreadful, DaVinci’s Demons, American Horror Story, American Gods, Lucifer, True Detective</i> (season one), <i>Strange Angel</i> (fictionalized biography of occultist/magician Jack Parsons.) Significant protagonists and anti-heroes; fourth-wall-breaking or uncanny figures, presented with esoteric, occult, or quasi-ritualistic aesthetics (Dr. Hannibal Lecter, Frank Underwood of <i>House of Cards</i>). </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Comics / Graphic Novels: Contain esoteric, occult, and magical motifs and tropes. Some are actively esoteric; Grant Morrison claims <i>The Invisibles </i>and <i>Promethea </i>as personal magical workings; the graphic novels of Neil Gaiman embrace esoteric, occult, magical themes and characters.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Music: Specific artists (e.g.,Genesis P-Orridge, David Bowie, Coil, Marilyn Manson, Ghost, Watain, Dissection, Behemoth, Wardruna, Tori Amos, Loreena McKennitt, Gustav Holst), genres (dark ambient, dungeon synth, black metal, viking/Nordic ambient, apocalyptic folk, witch house).</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Video Games: Theme and content, e.g., <i>Cult of the Lamb, Hunt: Showdown, Dead Synchronicity, The Witcher, Silent Hill, Darkest Dungeon, Cultist Simulator, Eldritch, SOMA, Deus Ex, Dark Souls, Xenogears, Devil May Cry,</i> <i>Curious Expedition, Murdered: Soul Suspect, Arcana, Shadow Hearts, Arx Fatalis</i>; pseudo-history <i>Assassin’s Creed, Tomb Raider</i>; historical worldviews, <i>Civilization VI </i>(secret societies), <i>Crusader Kings </i>(cults, witchcraft, demonolatry).</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Tabletop Roleplaying Games: <i>The Esoterrorists </i>and <i>Yellow King </i>(Pelgrane Press)<i>, Esoterica </i>(Fire Ruby Designs), <i>Kult: Divinity Lost </i>(rebooted by Modiphius Games), <i>Liminal </i>(Modiphius),<i> Sigil &amp; Shadow </i>(Osprey Games), <i>Esoteric Enterprises </i>(Dying Stylishly Games), White Wolf’s <i>Mage</i> (classic <i>World of Darkness</i>) and <i>Demon: The Descent </i>(<i>Chronicles of Darkness</i>), <i>World of Darkness </i>generally, Atlas Games <i>Unknown Armies</i>, Monte Cook’s <i>Invisible Sun, </i>Kevin Crawford's <i>Silent Legions.</i> RPGs have influenced the conception of magic in popular culture across media, and present extensive representation of magical figures.  Esoteric and gnostic themes intersect with transhumanism in examples such as <i>Eclipse Phase</i>.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Other possible topics:</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Influence of esoteric/occult/magical/New Age beliefs, practices, symbols on popular culture and aesthetics (e.g., memes, clothing, tattoos, jewelry).</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Influence of popular culture on esoteric/occult/magical beliefs, practices, and practitioners (e.g., Lovecraft mythos as actual magical practice, fictional gods of chaos in Chaos Magic, and real vampire communities using concepts from <i>Vampire:The Masquerade</i>).</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Popular beliefs about esotericism/occultism/magic: fads, trends, moral panics, witch-hunts, witch-crazes, conspiracy theories (e.g., anti-occult-conspiracism in QAnon; Illuminati paranoia, bloodline of the Holy Grail beliefs, Satanic Ritual Abuse scandals).</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Reactions and polemics against esoteric/occult/magical beliefs and practices.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>All proposals must be submitted through the conference’s database at </span></span></b><a href="http://register.southwestpca.org/southwestpca" rel="nofollow"><b><span><span>http://register.southwestpca.org/southwestpca</span></span></b></a></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>For details on using the submission database and on the application process in general, please see the Proposal Submission FAQs and Tips page at </span></span><a href="http://southwestpca.org/conference/faqs-and-tips/" rel="nofollow"><span><span>http://southwestpca.org/conference/faqs-and-tips/</span></span></a></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Individual proposals for 15-minute papers must include an abstract of approximately 200-500 words. Including a brief bio in the body of the proposal form is encouraged, but not required.   </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>For information on how to submit a proposal for a roundtable or a multi-paper panel, please view the above FAQs and Tips page.   </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>The deadline for submissions is October 31, 2022.   </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>SWPACA offers monetary awards for the best graduate student papers in a variety of categories. Submissions of accepted, full papers are due January 1, 2023.  SWPACA also offers travel fellowships for undergraduate and graduate students. For more information, visit </span></span><a href="http://southwestpca.org/conference/graduate-student-awards/" rel="nofollow"><span><span><span>http://southwestpca.org/conference/graduate-student-awards/</span></span></span></a></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Registration and travel information for the conference will be available at </span></span><a href="http://southwestpca.org/conference/conference-registration-information/" rel="nofollow"><span><span><span>http://southwestpca.org/conference/conference-registration-information/</span></span></span></a></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><a name="_Hlk110273473"><span><span>For 2023, we are excited to be at a new venue, the Marriott Albuquerque (2101 Louisiana Blvd NE, Albuquerque, NM 87110), which boasts free parking and close proximity to dining, shopping, and other delights. </span></span></a></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>In addition, please check out the organization’s peer-reviewed, scholarly journal, <i>Dialogue: The Interdisciplinary Journal of Popular Culture and Pedagogy</i>, at </span></span><a href="http://journaldialogue.org/" rel="nofollow"><span><span><span>http://journaldialogue.org/</span></span></span></a></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>If you have any questions about the Esotericism, Occultism, and Magic area, please contact its Area Chair, Dr. George J. Sieg, Southwestern Indian Polytechnic Institute, <a href="mailto:georgejsieg@gmail.com">georgejsieg@gmail.com</a> (505-440-2105). </span></span><span><span>If you have general questions about the conference, please contact us at </span></span><a href="mailto:support@southwestpca.org"><span><span>support@southwestpca.org</span></span></a><span><span>, and a member of the executive team will get back to you.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>We look forward to receiving your submissions!</span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr. George J. Sieg</p><p>Southwest Popular/American Culture Association (Area Chair: Esotericism, Occultism, and Magic)</p><p>Southwestern Indian Polytechnic Institute (Liberal Arts: Philosophy and English)</p><p><a href="mailto:georgejsieg@gmail.com">georgejsieg@gmail.com</a> / (505) 440-2105</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:georgejsieg@gmail.com">georgejsieg@gmail.com</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 17:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1661972393783934</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Authors on the Doctrine of Discovery</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10643988/call-authors-doctrine-discovery</link>
						<dc:creator>Adam DJ Brett</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-08-11T00:00:00-04:00">August 11, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>New York</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>American History / Studies, Humanities, Indigenous Studies, Race / Ethnic Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>We are now accepting applications for partnership and collaboration with The Doctrine of Discovery Project. We are interested in publishing original essays roughly 1,000-3,000 words in length for <a href="https://doctrineofdiscovery.org/" rel="nofollow">doctrineofdiscovery.org</a>. Applicants must have specific knowledge pertaining to Indigenous Peoples issues and/or graduate level training in religious studies, law, humanities, social sciences, or ecology. This partnership is open to faculty, independent scholars, graduate students and Haudenosaunee and Indigenous knowledge sharers. Stipends are available.</p><p>Interested authors should submit a 150-300 word abstract, a 150–300 word biography, your resume/cv (if available), and a sample of a previous published article no later than September 31, 2022. The goal of this partnership is to support and amplify Indigenous voices pertaining to the Doctrine of Discovery, so priority will be given to Indigenous Peoples working in this area.</p><p>Each essay should be geared towards an interested and engaged public and undergraduate audience. Our first high-priority interest is in the following core topics:</p><ul><li>200 Years of Johnson v. M’Intosh (JvM): Indigenous Responses to the Religious Foundations of Racism</li><li>The Doctrine of Discovery and Law</li><li>The religious dimensions of the Doctrine of Discovery</li><li>The Doctrine of Discovery as a global phenomenon (international)</li><li>The environmental impact of the Doctrine of Discovery</li><li>Doctrine of Discovery and Indian Boarding/Residential Schools</li><li>And other Doctrine of Discovery related topics.</li></ul><p>Authors will be notified whether their proposals are accepted by October 1, 2022. First drafts or full essays are due by December 1, 2022, and final versions are due January 15, 2022. All authors must note their educational and social background in their biographies. Only original previously unpublished works will be considered. Authors implicitly agree to the terms of our <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en" rel="nofollow">Creative Commons License</a>. <strong>We seek to amplify and prioritize submissions from Indigenous Peoples of Turtle Island/Abya Yala. We also interested in an international range of scholarly contributions.</strong></p><h2><strong>About the Project</strong></h2><p>The Doctrine of Discovery Project (<a href="https://doctrineofdiscovery.org/" rel="nofollow">doctrineofdiscovery.org</a>) is a collaborative interdisciplinary open educational resource designed for use in higher education. It is being funded by the Henry Luce Foundation Grant, <a href="https://www.hluce.org/grants/?programs=4&amp;years=314&amp;sort=newest&amp;date_day=&amp;date_month=&amp;date_year=&amp;keyword=" rel="nofollow">“200 Years of Johnson v. McIntosh: Indigenous Responses to the Religious Foundations of Racism,”</a> for 3 years (2022-24).</p><h2><strong>About the Principal Investigator</strong></h2><p>Prof. Philip P. Arnold (<a href="https://thecollege.syr.edu/people/faculty/arnold-philip-p/" rel="nofollow">Religion, Syracuse University</a>) has been writing and working on Indigenous issues for over 30 years. With Sandy Bigtree (Akwesasne Mohawk Nation), they founded the not-for-profit <a href="https://indigenousvalues.org/" rel="nofollow">Indigenous Values Initiative</a> where they launched the Doctrine of Discovery Project site in 2009-2010. To learn more see: “<a href="https://thecollege.syr.edu/news-all/news-from-2022/examining-the-history-and-consequences-of-the-doctrine-of-christian-discovery/" rel="nofollow">Examining the History and Consequences of the Doctrine of Christian Discovery.</a>”</p><h2><a href="https://indigenousvalues.org/call-for-authors-on-the-doctrine-of-discovery/" rel="nofollow">Apply Now</a></h2></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Philip P. Arnold is Associate Professor and Chair of the Department of Religion at Syracuse University, as well as a core faculty member of Native American and Indigenous Studies. </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:pparnold@syr.edu">pparnold@syr.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://doctrineofdiscovery.org/blog/call-for-authors-doctrine-of-discovery/" target="_blank">https://doctrineofdiscovery.org/blog/call-for-authors-doctrine-of-discovery/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 17:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1661972393783933</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFA: The Robert H. N. Ho Family Foundation Program in Buddhist Studies is calling for new Applications!</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10642131/cfa-robert-h-n-ho-family-foundation-program-buddhist-studies</link>
						<dc:creator>Ryan Cuthbert</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Fellowship</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-16T00:00:00-05:00">November 16, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Asian History / Studies, East Asian History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, South Asian History / Studies, Southeast Asian History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><table><tr><td><span><span><span><span><span><strong><span>The Robert H. N. Ho Family Foundation </span></strong><br/><b><strong><span>Program in Buddhist Studies</span></strong><br/><br/><em><span>Now Accepting Applications for 2022-23 </span></em><br/><i><em><span>Fellowship and Grant Competitions</span></em></i></b></span></span></span></span></span></td></tr></table><table><tr><td><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS) invites applications for </span></span></span></span><a href="https://www.acls.org/programs/robert-h-n-ho-family-foundation-in-buddhist-studies/" rel="nofollow"><span><span><span><span>The Robert H. N. Ho Family Foundation Program in Buddhist Studies</span></span></span></span></a><span><span><span><span> 2022-23 competitions. In cooperation with the Foundation, ACLS awards fellowships and grants supporting work that will expand the understanding and interpretation of Buddhist thought in scholarship and society, strengthen international networks of Buddhist scholars, and increase the visibility of new knowledge and research on Buddhist traditions.   </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p></td></tr></table><table><tr><td><p><span><span><span><strong><span><span><span><span>Worldwide Scope</span></span></span></span></strong><br/><span><span><span><span>These are global competitions.  All scholars – anywhere in the world – who are engaged in the study of any aspect of Buddhist traditions are welcome to apply. There are no restrictions as to the location of work proposed or the citizenship of applicants. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span><span><span>Eligible scholars at Asian universities and monastic institutions are especially encouraged to apply.</span></span></span></span></b><br/><br/><span><span><span><span>Applications must be submitted in English, but the written work produced by the fellow or grantee can be in any language. Work proposed must be in </span></span></span></span><a href="https://www.acls.org/faqs/acls-faq/" rel="nofollow"><span><span><span><span>the humanities and interpretive social sciences</span></span></span></span></a><span><span><span><span> and must employ humanistic approaches and methods.</span></span></span></span><br/><br/><strong><span><span><span><span>Awards</span></span></span></span></strong>  </span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span><a href="https://www.acls.org/competitions/the-robert-h-n-ho-family-foundation-dissertation-fellowships-in-buddhist-studies/" rel="nofollow"><strong><span><span><span><span>Dissertation Fellowships</span></span></span></span></strong></a><span><span><span>: One-year stipends to PhD candidates for full-time preparation of dissertations.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><a href="https://www.acls.org/competitions/robert-h-n-ho-early-career/" rel="nofollow"><strong><span><span><span><span>Early Career Research Fellowships</span></span></span></span></strong></a><span><span><span>: One-year stipends to pre-tenure scholars for research and writing.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><a href="https://www.acls.org/competitions/the-robert-h-n-ho-family-foundation-translation-grants-in-buddhist-studies/" rel="nofollow"><strong><span><span><span><span>Translation Grants in Buddhist Studies</span></span></span></span></strong></a><span><span><span>: One-year awards supporting collaborative or individual projects for translations of important texts in order to make them available to communities of scholarship and Buddhist practice. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><a href="https://www.acls.org/competitions/the-robert-h-n-ho-family-foundation-new-professorships-in-buddhist-studies/" rel="nofollow"><strong><span><span><span><span>New Professorships</span></span></span></span></strong></a><span><span><span>: Multiyear grants to colleges and universities to establish new teaching positions in Buddhist studies.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><strong><a href="https://www.acls.org/competitions/the-robert-h-n-ho-family-foundation-buddhism-public-scholars/" rel="nofollow"><span><span><span><span>Buddhism Public Scholars</span></span></span></span></a></strong><b><span><span><span><span>:</span></span></span></span></b><span><span><span><span> Awards of up to two years to place early career scholars in positions at museums and publishers. These positions are initially one-year placements that are renewable for a second year. Host institutions will be announced in the fall.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><strong><span><span><span><span>Deadlines</span></span></span></span></strong> </span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span><strong><span><span><span>Fellowships and Grants - November 16, 2022</span></span></span></strong></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><strong><span><span><span>New Professorships Awards to Institutions and Buddhism Public Scholars - January 11, 2023</span></span></span></strong></span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><br/><span><span><span><i><span><span><span><span>The Robert H. N. Ho Family Foundation Program in Buddhist Studies, administered by ACLS, is committed to inclusion, equity, and diversity as integral components of merit that enhance the scholarly enterprise. It is a</span></span></span></span></i><span><span><span><span> <i>priority of this program that cohorts of fellows and grantees be broadly inclusive of different backgrounds and cultures, as well as in languages of study, topics, Buddhist traditions, and locations of research.</i></span></span></span></span><br/><strong> </strong><br/><strong><span><span><span><span>Questions?  Contact us at </span></span></span></span></strong><a href="mailto:BuddhistStudies@acls.org?subject=Questions%20About%20the%20Buddhist%20Studies%20Program"><span><span><span>BuddhistStudies@acls.org</span></span></span></a><strong><span><span><span><span>.</span></span></span></span></strong> </span></span></span></p></td></tr></table><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:BuddhistStudies@acls.org">BuddhistStudies@acls.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.acls.org/programs/robert-h-n-ho-family-foundation-in-buddhist-studies/" target="_blank">https://www.acls.org/programs/robert-h-n-ho-family-foundation-in-buddhist-studies/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 18:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1661972393783932</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>PRIVACY, SECRECY, &amp; ESOTERICISM</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10641700/privacy-secrecy-esotericism</link>
						<dc:creator>Natacha Klein Käfer</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-14T00:00:00-05:00">November 14, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-15T00:00:00-05:00">November 15, 2022</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Denmark</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Cultural History / Studies, History of Science, Medicine, and Technology, Intellectual History, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Esoteric traditions and associated currents have, through many centuries, developed and employed a number of strategies connected with secrecy. One important dimension of this has been to secure privacy for their practices, transmission, and survival. People needed safe spaces to procure esoteric knowledge, and secrecy was at the core of how much of this knowledge was protected. Secrecy and privacy have also served functions in esotericism related to discourses about higher knowledge, access to the divine, the secrets of nature, didactics and identity construction. The <strong>Centre for Privacy Studies</strong> and the <strong>Copenhagen Centre for the Study of Theosophy and Esotericism</strong> of the University of Copenhagen invite scholars interested in the intersection of esotericism and privacy in a broader historical perspective to continue the exploration of this area in November 2022. </p><p> </p><p>Topics of interest include (but are not restricted to):</p><ul><li>Secrecy and concealment: practices and strategies;</li><li>Privacy in the transmission of knowledge - correspondence, training, and traditions;</li><li>Private circles: initiations, codes, insiders and outsiders;</li><li>Texts as private vehicles of esotericism - cryptic writings, symbolism, and languages;</li></ul><p> </p><p><strong>Keynote speakers:</strong></p><p>Professor <a href="https://www.kockuvonstuckrad.com/" rel="nofollow">Kocku von Stuckrad</a>, University of Groningen: “Secrecy, Concealment, and Privacy: Three Different Modes of Esoteric Tradition”</p><p>Professor <a href="https://www.gu.se/en/about/find-staff/henrikbogdan" rel="nofollow">Henrik Bogdan</a>, University of Gothenburg: “Secrecy and Early Eighteenth-Century Freemasonry”</p><p> </p><p><strong>Paper proposals:</strong></p><p>Everyone is welcome to submit a paper proposal. Please use the form below to submit an abstract of no more than 500 words and a short biography under 150 words in length.</p><p><strong>DEADLINE FOR SUBMISSIONS:</strong> <strong>September 18, 2022 via the site: </strong></p><p><strong><a href="https://teol.ku.dk/privacy/events/events-2022/seminar-privacy-secrecy--esotericism/" rel="nofollow">https://teol.ku.dk/privacy/events/events-2022/seminar-privacy-secrecy--e...</a></strong></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:nkk@teol.ku.dk">nkk@teol.ku.dk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://teol.ku.dk/privacy/events/events-2022/seminar-privacy-secrecy--esotericism/" target="_blank">https://teol.ku.dk/privacy/events/events-2022/seminar-privacy-secrecy--esotericism/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 18:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1661972393783931</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ November 15, 2022] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/102530</link>
						<description>Publication Name: "Occultism and Politics in Central and Eastern Europe"<br/><br/><p>"<strong>The Polish Journal of the Arts and Culture. New Series</strong>" invites scholars to submit their articles to a special issue "<strong>Occultism and Politics in Central and Eastern Europe</strong>".</p>
<p>Since the nineteenth century, Central and Eastern Europe has experienced rapid social, political, and economic changes, which caused transformation and upheavals in local societies. Rising nationalism culminating in the Revolutionary year 1848, echoes of the Romantic movement, ongoing industrialisation, First World War, the emergence of national states and disintegration of the Austro-Hungarian Empire, later followed by World War Two and the establishment of the socialist regimes represent some of the key milestones the region went through. New sciences emerged, and intellectuals of the region also tried to cope with the impetus of new discoveries in the Orient. Since mid-nineteenth century, the rise of occultism and its further spread throughout Europe represented a peculiar reaction to these conditions. Central and Eastern European states dealt with these occult and esoteric movements in various ways, from suppression to silent support, and the movements themselves had various ideas about the meaning and aims of the nation. We wish to investigate the links between state, power, and occult and esoteric ideas, movements, and key figures.</p>
<p>Focusing on occultism and esotericism in Central and Eastern Europe since the mid-nineteenth-century until now, we invite scholars to share their articles in a special issue of "The Polish Journal of the Arts and Culture". The scope of the issue includes the following topics:<br/>- Tensions between or calls for nationalism and/or transnationalism in the occult and esoteric movements;<br/>- Attitudes of various state bodies (republics, empires or totalitarian regimes) to occultism and esotericism, from suppression to support;<br/>- Practising occultism or esotericism under socialist regimes;<br/>- Case studies of influential movements, persons, or ideas either originating or being adopted in Central and Eastern Europe;<br/>- Critical reflection of the scholarship concerning occultism and esotericism in Central and Eastern Europe.</p>
<p>The guest editors of the issue are Dr. Karolina Maria Hess (Centre for Comparative Studies of Civilisations, Jagiellonian University) and Dr. Pavel Horák (Institute of Ethnology, Czech Academy of Sciences).</p>
<p>The editors will consider all manuscripts prepared according to the following criteria:<br/>- Length: 20 000 – 40 000 characters with spaces<br/>- Language: English<br/>- Deadline: November 15th, 2022</p>
<p>Please send your proposed contribution to: karolina.maria.hess@uj.edu.pl and horak@eu.cas.cz</p>
<p>For further guidelines see: https://www.ejournals.eu/PJACNS/menu/574/</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 05:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1661665027225615</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ March 31, 2023] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/102526</link>
						<description>Publication Name: "Society, Art, and Culture in the Face of War"<br/><br/><p>"<strong>The Polish Journal of the Arts and Culture. New Series</strong>" invites scholars to submit their articles to a special issue "<strong>Society, Art, and Culture in the Face of War</strong>". <br/><br/>From 24 February 2022, the eyes of not only Europe, but also the whole world, turned to Ukraine. The military operations that Russia had long conducted world-wide, and which escalated on that day in the eruption of the Russian-Ukrainian war, are a reminder of the armed, cultural and social conflict that has been growing in this region for years. The heroic Ukrainian mobilisation not only relates to the conduct of intense military operations but also to the self-organisation of society under the difficult circumstances of war. An essential element of this mobilisation is activity in the sphere of culture and art, focusing on the internal integration of Ukrainian society and acquiring external allies. <br/><br/>Focusing on the issues related to the cultural front, cultural policy, and cultural diplomacy during the Russo-Ukrainian war that has been ongoing since 2014, we invite scholars to share their articles in a special issue of The Polish Journal of The Arts and Culture. New Series. <br/><br/>Our goal is to examine the problems arising from the Russian invasion of Ukraine, genocide, war crimes, and international politics, especially from a philosophical and cultural perspective. The scope of the issue includes the following topics: <br/>- artistic and cultural opposition to war crimes (murals, performances, and others),<br/>- modern language of propaganda and communication (including the issue of hybrid war, social media, and the Internet),<br/>- cultural policy and cultural diplomacy in circumstances of war,<br/>- documentation and analysis of cultural crimes,<br/>- durability and objectivity of ethical values in the post-modern world,<br/>- post-memory as a tool for the categorisation and understanding of the present day,<br/>- development of intellectual culture and physical culture in new national/patriotic narratives. <br/><br/>We are also happy to announce that this issue opens academic cooperation between the Centre for Comparative Studies of Civilisations and the National University of Veterinary Medicine and Biotechnology in Lviv. <br/><br/>The editors of the special issue are Dr Elżbieta Olzacka, Dr Paulina Tendera (Krakow, Centre for Comparative Studies of Civilisations, Jagiellonian University), Taras Mazur MA (Lviv, National University of Veterinary Medicine and Biotechnology), and Dr Sergii Rusakov (Kyiv, National Pedagogical Drahomanov University). <br/><br/>The editors will consider all manuscripts prepared according to the following criteria: <br/>- Length: 30,000–40,000 characters with spaces.<br/>- Language: Polish and English<br/>- Deadline: March 2023 Please send your proposed contribution to: elzbieta.olzacka@uj.edu.pl &amp; paulina.tendera@uj.edu.pl<br/><br/>For further guidelines see: https://www.ejournals.eu/PJACNS/menu/574/</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 05:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1661665027225614</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ November 15, 2022] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/102530</link>
						<description>Publication Name: "Occultism and Politics in Central and Eastern Europe"<br/><br/><p>"<strong>The Polish Journal of the Arts and Culture. New Series</strong>" invites scholars to submit their articles to a special issue "<strong>Occultism and Politics in Central and Eastern Europe</strong>".</p>
<p>Since the nineteenth century, Central and Eastern Europe has experienced rapid social, political, and economic changes, which caused transformation and upheavals in local societies. Rising nationalism culminating in the Revolutionary year 1848, echoes of the Romantic movement, ongoing industrialisation, First World War, the emergence of national states and disintegration of the Austro-Hungarian Empire, later followed by World War Two and the establishment of the socialist regimes represent some of the key milestones the region went through. New sciences emerged, and intellectuals of the region also tried to cope with the impetus of new discoveries in the Orient. Since mid-nineteenth century, the rise of occultism and its further spread throughout Europe represented a peculiar reaction to these conditions. Central and Eastern European states dealt with these occult and esoteric movements in various ways, from suppression to silent support, and the movements themselves had various ideas about the meaning and aims of the nation. We wish to investigate the links between state, power, and occult and esoteric ideas, movements, and key figures.</p>
<p>Focusing on occultism and esotericism in Central and Eastern Europe since the mid-nineteenth-century until now, we invite scholars to share their articles in a special issue of "The Polish Journal of the Arts and Culture". The scope of the issue includes the following topics:<br/>- Tensions between or calls for nationalism and/or transnationalism in the occult and esoteric movements;<br/>- Attitudes of various state bodies (republics, empires or totalitarian regimes) to occultism and esotericism, from suppression to support;<br/>- Practising occultism or esotericism under socialist regimes;<br/>- Case studies of influential movements, persons, or ideas either originating or being adopted in Central and Eastern Europe;<br/>- Critical reflection of the scholarship concerning occultism and esotericism in Central and Eastern Europe.</p>
<p>The guest editors of the issue are Dr. Karolina Maria Hess (Centre for Comparative Studies of Civilisations, Jagiellonian University) and Dr. Pavel Horák (Institute of Ethnology, Czech Academy of Sciences).</p>
<p>The editors will consider all manuscripts prepared according to the following criteria:<br/>- Length: 20 000 – 40 000 characters with spaces<br/>- Language: English<br/>- Deadline: November 15th, 2022</p>
<p>Please send your proposed contribution to: karolina.maria.hess@uj.edu.pl and horak@eu.cas.cz</p>
<p>For further guidelines see: https://www.ejournals.eu/PJACNS/menu/574/</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 05:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1661665027225613</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ October 7, 2022] Talk or similar: Conceptual Reverse-Engineering, Teleology and Concepts of God</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/102498</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/>Speakers at this event: <br/>Christos Kyriacou (University of Cyprus)<br/><br/><p>I argue that if there has been a divine creation act, then we can build on such a divine act to conceptually reverse-engineer the possible nature of God by (a) constructing possible models of the nature of God and by (b) comparing them for explanatory power (and other theoretical virtues). That is, I argue that, by analogy with human rational action, divine rational action must be constrained by certain requirements of practical rationality, such as: intentionality, voluntariness, purposefulness, instrumentality, responsibility, morality and providence. Of course, the analogy is loose and imperfect and should take into account the Anselmian proviso that, unlike feeble humans, God is a perfect being and fully rational, otherwise we will fall prey to crude anthropomorphism. Conceptual reverse-engineering of the nature of God must also be constrained by certain independently motivated metaphysical facts, such as the causal closure of the physical and the apparent necessity of the laws of nature. I then examine how different concepts of God (theism, deism, pantheism) fare with regard to the projected properties of divine rational agency and the metaphysical facts of causal closure and natural necessity. As it turns out, different concepts of God fare better with some aspects and worse with some others. Our task is to compare different models of the nature of God and search for the more explanatorily fruitful and overall more theoretically virtuous theory. </p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 05:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1661578625764934</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
