<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 12:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 12:18:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ October 1, 2024] CFP for conference or similar: Society for Philosophy of Religion</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/123254</link>
						<description><p>I write to solicit papers for the 2025 meeting of the Society for the Philosophy of Religion to be held in New Orleans from March 6—8, 2025 at the Hyatt Centric French Quarter.</p>
<p>The deadline for receiving submissions is October 1, 2024. The Society is especially pleased to announce that Yujin Nagasawa (University of Oklahoma) will deliver the keynote address and Richard Swinburne (Oxford University) and James Sterba (University of Notre Dame) will present on a special panel for their upcoming book, <em>Could a Good God Permit So Much Suffering?</em></p>
<p>Please submit your paper via email to <u><a target="_blank">Joshua.Horn@uwsp.edu</a></u></p>
<p>To be considered, your paper ought to be prepared for blind review and be no more than 6000 words. Papers read at the meeting should not deviate from the accepted paper. If you wish to propose a panel discussion, please send a proposal explaining the topic, with the names of those who have agreed to participate on the panel.</p>
<p>If you would be willing to serve as a commentator or a session chair, please send me an e-mail indicating your interest.</p>
<p>“The Society for Philosophy of Religion Rising Scholar Award” will be granted to the best essay written by a philosopher who earned their Ph.D. in the last 5 years. The Society reserves the right not to name a winner in the event that none of the submissions is deemed to be of sufficient quality or suitability for the award.</p>
<p>I look forward to receiving your submissions.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1715319425572105</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ March 6, 2025 -  March 8, 2025] Conference or similar: Society for Philosophy of Religion</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/123250</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1715319425572104</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ June 21, 2024] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/123186</link>
						<description>Publication Name: Conceptualising the Abyss in religion<br/><br/><p><em><strong>Conceptualising the Abyss in religion</strong></em></p>
<p>As a common expression and proverb, "the abyss calls to the abyss" is intended to signify both a chain reaction and a deeper, potentially endless or bottomless fall: one excess leads to another excess, one crime leads to another crime, one evil throws us into a greater evil. However, in its original biblical sense, taken from <em>Psalm</em> 41:8, it has less pejorative connotations, in that it expresses the indefectible bond that exists between the believer and God, especially when the latter tends to merge with the invisible. <em>The abyss that calls (Abyssus)</em>, on the other hand, is that of the apostle insofar as he represents all believers, because he is aware of the road ahead and the trials that will face him in his quest for God. <em>The abyss that is called (Abyssum),</em> on the other hand, is that of God, unfathomable, abstruse we might also say, eluding all human knowledge/understanding, both in his answers and in his presence. As for the verb to call (<em>invocare</em>), this invites us to think of a call to ourselves, close to ourselves, which is above all a call for help: the distress of a fallen and sinful creature. The abyss of man asks, and therefore hopes, that the divine abyss will answer his call and save him from an inner battle that he is not certain of winning alone. From then on, the act of calling is not devoid of hope, in which anxiety and the desire for a response are intertwined. Finally, the certainty expressed in <em>Psalm</em> 41:12: "He is my saviour and my God" indicates the noblest attitude to adopt, even when God remains silent and absent. Commenting on this psalm, Augustine multiplies this already twofold abyss, since the abyss refers not only to God's incomprehensible judgements, the divine ways and God himself, but also to the human heart - the deepest abyss, so subject is it to inner distortion - to mankind in general, to human weakness, to sin, or even to the depth of the sea. For the Bishop of Hippo, the notion of the abyss refers to the mysterious depths of man and God, because each in its own way is an inexhaustible source of incomprehension that we must try to unravel and grasp (1). The <em>Confessions</em> themselves could be read as a human attempt to approach the abyss that we are in the face of a second, much nobler abyss, which is God, into which we must try to plunge ... to sink. And yet the silence and absence of God nonetheless open up an abyss of meaning that never ceases to question and is conducive to doubt. The absence of God is perceived as a void, if not a vacancy to be filled by something else: where Job remains faithful to God despite trials and afflictions, the contradictory existence of evil and suffering, the "death of God" leaves man alone in the face of an abyss, faced with the challenge of creating new values that are no longer hostile to life (the superhuman/the nihilism of the last man) (2).</p>
<p>The multi-faceted nature of the abyss is at the root of these diverse and even opposing reactions. Indeed, the abyss has a properly topological meaning: it refers to a concrete physical place, but one that has the particularity of always being unfathomable. As the Greek etymology <em>ἄβυσσος</em> "bottomless" testifies, venturing into it is already losing oneself in it. The abyss is therefore characterised by an impossibility of being identified in its depth and totality since it escapes, by definition, any attempt at understanding and mastery. With its pejorative connotations, it often gives rise to fear and anxiety (3) and is associated with Hell and sin. The same is true of the verb abîmer, which refers to the action of altering, degrading or even destroying something. However, it can also mean to <em>damage</em>, in the sense of <em>modifying</em>, in particular to make something better. To "fall into God" is not so much a fall as an elevation to him, but one that no one can accomplish and from which no one emerges unscathed. Finally, the abyss is a concept close to the infinite (4), in that they both refer to the idea of the unfathomable, so much so that the abyss becomes the other name for God himself (5). That this abyss escapes man is then a sign, even a proof, of God's existence and of a greatness to be respected and admired (6). On this point, the humility of not wanting to understand/know God outside the abyss that defines him implies assigning limits to theological discourse, to the very possibility and legitimacy of theology. In short, we need to ask what can be said about the abyss in religion, since it seems from the outset, by virtue of its definition, to escape discourse.</p>
<p>This issue of <em>ThéoRèmes</em> is an interdisciplinary issue, inviting epistemological and comparative reflection on the uses of the concept of the abyss in religion. The dossier is particularly open to studies of the notion in other religions: is there or is there not such a concept or its equivalent? How is it translated? What exactly is the religious conceptual framework in which it is used? The articles may deal with the notion in one or more authors or in the corpus of a tradition of thought or religion. Similarly, it is possible to approach the concept from other fields or disciplines, such as phenomenology, but it is important to make the link with the abyss 'in religion'. Proposals for articles may fit into one or more of the following areas of reflection:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>The theological axis:</strong> how have different religions and philosophies conceptualised the abyss in religion? How are the different abysses (God's abyss, man's abyss, hell's abyss, sin's abyss) thought of, and in relation to each other? What does the abyss have to offer in relation to neighbouring concepts such as infinity?</li>
<li><strong>The epistemological axis</strong>: what are the conditions of possibility and truth of all discourse and thought on the abyss? Should the faculties of knowledge mobilised to immerse themselves in the abyss reject reason in favour of intuition (sensitive, intellectual, mystical)? Does a theology of the abyss necessarily imply a doctrinal impoverishment?</li>
<li><strong>The moral and political axis</strong>: what normativity can a theology of the abyss exercise, particularly for an ecclesial institution? Does a theology of the abyss imply doctrinal tolerance, given the unfathomability of God?</li>
<li><strong>The literary and aesthetic axis:</strong> how can the abyss be depicted or represented artistically? What are the recurring metaphors used to evoke it? How is the sublime the aesthetic experience of the abyss?</li>
<li><strong>The psychological axis:</strong> what emotions or affects does the abyss arouse (fear, admiration, fascination, humility)? How can we deal with the abyss within us? To what extent is the human interior, the heart or conscience, the abyss of his being?</li>
</ul>
<p><u>How to submit :</u></p>
<p>Deadline for sending proposals, 500 words: 10/06/2024 at manon.gibot@ephe.psl.eu <strong>and</strong> andy.serin@univ-paris1.fr<br/>Reply to authors: 20/06/2024 at the latest.<br/>Deadline for articles, 40,000 characters including spaces: 20/12/2024</p>
<p>Articles will then be submitted to the journal's evaluation procedure (https://journals.openedition.org/theoremes/116): double-blind expertise, then submitted to the Scientific Committee for validation</p>
<p><u>Notes:</u></p>
<p>(1) Georgiana Huian writes of Augustine's commentary that it "does not engage in a game of personifications of the abyss, but a breakthrough of the mystery that calls into question the constitution of the 'subject' by referring to intersubjectivity", <em>Augustin. Le cœur et la crise du sujet</em>, Paris, Cerf Patrimoines, 2020, p. 187. See also: Françoise Vinel, "L'abîme appelle l'abîme... (Ps. 41 (42), 8). Plaidoyers pour l'allégorie dans quelques commentaires du psautier, d'Eusèbe à Augustin", in Pierre Maraval (ed.), <em>Le psautier chez les Pères</em>, Strasbourg, Centre d'Analyse et de Documentation Patristiques, 1994, p. 251.</p>
<p>(2) All of Dostoyevsky's thought is also haunted by this question of the death of God, of his absence, of the abyss of incomprehension in the face of the violence of the world. For example, the "Revolt" chapter of The <em>Brothers Karamazov.</em></p>
<p>(3) Kierkegaard, faced with the anguish that freedom can provoke in man, compares anguish to vertigo: "when the eye plunges into an abyss, one has vertigo, which comes as much from the eye as from the abyss, because one might not have looked", Le concept d'angoisse, Paris, Gallimard, 1935, p. 90.</p>
<p>(4) In his fragment "Disproportion", Pascal mentions the term abyss several times in connection with infinity, explaining that he wants "to make him see a new abyss in there" (emphasis added).</p>
<p>(5) Apophatic and mystical theology more generally have taken seriously this definition of a God who can neither be named nor defined, by associating him, for example, with nothingness, and by placing experience itself at the heart of their thinking. See, for example, Maitre Eckhart.</p>
<p>(6) The notion of the sublime in Kantian aesthetics holds together this idea of a positive abyss that arouses fascination and respect, as well as fear. The sublime, as abyss, absolute immensity and transgression of limits, exceeds the human scale. As Paulette Carrive explains, "the analysis of the sublime is undoubtedly at the heart of the entire Kantian system, for it reveals man in the interiority of his greatness and humility" ("le sublime dans l'esthétique de Kant", in<em> Revue d'Histoire littéraire de la France,</em> 86e année, no. 1, Le sublime (Jan.-Feb., 1986), pp. 78-79. See <em>Critique of the Faculty of Judgement,</em> II, "Analysis of the Sublime", § XXIII to XXVIII.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1715233027793662</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Opportunities Digest – May 8, 2024</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-opportunities-digest-may-8-2024/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Project Opportunities Digest! This week, you will find 31 new job opportunities, 1 fellowship, 1 award, 10 calls for papers, and 4 conferences/speakers.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 43!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Academic:</h4>



<h4>Assistant Professor of History/Political Science (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Morehead State University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: June 3, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178781134&amp;utm_source=05_07_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178781134&amp;utm_source=05_07_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Visiting Assistant Professor of History (1-year appointment, Master’s degree required)</h4>



<p>College of the Mainland, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: Until filled</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178780981&amp;utm_source=05_07_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178780981&amp;utm_source=05_07_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Professor of History (Full-time, Master’s degree required)</h4>



<p>Miami Dade College, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: Until filled</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178780912&amp;utm_source=05_07_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178780912&amp;utm_source=05_07_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Visiting Assistant Professor of Sociology (1-year appointment)</h4>



<p>Oglethorpe University, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178780792&amp;utm_source=05_07_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178780792&amp;utm_source=05_07_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor in American Politics (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Claremont McKenna College, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: September 30, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178780385&amp;utm_source=05_06_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178780385&amp;utm_source=05_06_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Nancy Schaenen Endowed Visiting Scholar of Ethics (2-year appointment)</h4>



<p>DePauw University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: May 17, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178779756&amp;utm_source=05_05_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178779756&amp;utm_source=05_05_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Visiting Assistant Professor of Holocaust and Genocide Studies (1-year appointment, possibility of renewal)</h4>



<p>University of Cincinnati, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178779442&amp;utm_source=05_05_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178779442&amp;utm_source=05_05_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Visiting Assistant Professor of Philosophy (1-year appointment, possibility of renewal)</h4>



<p>Dominican University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: Until filled</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178777943&amp;AAEmail=140263&amp;MatchType=2&amp;utm_source=05_04_2024&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=AAEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178777943&amp;AAEmail=140263&amp;MatchType=2&amp;utm_source=05_04_2024&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=AAEmail</a></p>



<h4>Visiting Assistant Professor of Anthropology (1-year appointment)</h4>



<p>Scripps College, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: May 13, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178779311&amp;utm_source=05_04_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178779311&amp;utm_source=05_04_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Visiting Assistant Professor of Anthropology (2-year appointment)</h4>



<p>Berry College, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: Until filled</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178778892&amp;utm_source=05_04_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178778892&amp;utm_source=05_04_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Associate Provost for Undergraduate Education (1-year appointment)</h4>



<p>Lincoln University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: May 23, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178778700&amp;utm_source=05_04_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178778700&amp;utm_source=05_04_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Visiting Assistant Professor of Philosophy</h4>



<p>Hope College, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: Until filled</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178777219&amp;AAEmail=140238&amp;MatchType=2&amp;utm_source=05_03_2024&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=AAEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178777219&amp;AAEmail=140238&amp;MatchType=2&amp;utm_source=05_03_2024&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=AAEmail</a></p>



<h4>Adjunct Professor of Religion &amp; Theology (Master’s degree required)</h4>



<p>La Salle University, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178777767&amp;utm_source=05_03_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178777767&amp;utm_source=05_03_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Professor of American Jewish History and Director of the Goldstein-Goren Center for American Jewish History</h4>



<p>New York University, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178777758&amp;utm_source=05_03_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178777758&amp;utm_source=05_03_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Teaching Professor of Sociology (1-year appointment)</h4>



<p>Georgetown University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: May 15, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178777615&amp;utm_source=05_03_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178777615&amp;utm_source=05_03_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Visiting Assistant Professor of International History (1-year appointment, possibility of renewal)</h4>



<p>New York University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: Until filled</p>



<p>More Information:  <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178776153&amp;utm_source=05_02_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178776153&amp;utm_source=05_02_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Associate Professor of History of Philosophy (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>New York University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: Until filled</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178776131&amp;utm_source=05_02_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178776131&amp;utm_source=05_02_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Systematic Theology</h4>



<p>Mount St. Mary’s University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: Until filled</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178776118&amp;utm_source=05_02_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178776118&amp;utm_source=05_02_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor in Indigenous Studies (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>New York University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: Until filled</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178776048&amp;utm_source=05_02_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178776048&amp;utm_source=05_02_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Global Sociology (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>University of California, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: June 15, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178775519&amp;utm_source=05_02_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178775519&amp;utm_source=05_02_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Minerva Recruitment Job Listings Site (with areas specifically tailored for Ph.D.)</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://minerva-recruitment.com/">Minerva Recruitment – Higher Education Graduate Jobs, UK &amp; Worldwide (minerva-recruitment.com)</a></p>



<h4>AAR/SBL Job Forum</h4>



<p><a href="https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search">https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search</a></p>



<h4>Non-Academic:</h4>



<h4>Associate Editor</h4>



<h4>University of Notre Dame, USA</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178781303&amp;utm_source=05_07_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178781303&amp;utm_source=05_07_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Director of Research and Policy</h4>



<p>United States Commission on International Religious Freedom</p>



<p>Deadline: May 14, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://lnkd.in/ewvpeh7g">https://lnkd.in/ewvpeh7g</a></p>



<h4>Digital Collections Manager</h4>



<p>Washington and Lee University, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178756879&amp;AAEmail=140283&amp;MatchType=2&amp;utm_source=05_04_2024&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=AAEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178756879&amp;AAEmail=140283&amp;MatchType=2&amp;utm_source=05_04_2024&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=AAEmail</a></p>



<h4>Copy Editor and Editorial Coordinator</h4>



<p>Harvard University, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178778613&amp;utm_source=05_04_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178778613&amp;utm_source=05_04_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Museum Preparator</h4>



<p>Palmer Museum of Art at Penn State, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178778427&amp;utm_source=05_04_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178778427&amp;utm_source=05_04_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Career and Professional Development Program Manager for Postdoctoral Fellows</h4>



<p>University of Michigan, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: May 22, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178777105&amp;utm_source=05_03_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178777105&amp;utm_source=05_03_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Archivist for Public Services (Graduate degree required)</h4>



<p>Tufts University, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178776994&amp;utm_source=05_03_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178776994&amp;utm_source=05_03_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Collections Archivist (Graduate degree required)</h4>



<p>Johns Hopkins University, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178776613&amp;utm_source=05_03_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178776613&amp;utm_source=05_03_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Publication and Special Projects Coordinator</h4>



<p>Appalachian State University, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178776395&amp;utm_source=05_02_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178776395&amp;utm_source=05_02_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Managing Editor/Project Manager (Researcher) at NYU’s Ethics &amp; Journalism Initiative</h4>



<p>New York University, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178776267&amp;utm_source=05_02_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178776267&amp;utm_source=05_02_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Director of Graduate Career Services</h4>



<p>Penn State University, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178774526&amp;utm_source=05_01_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178774526&amp;utm_source=05_01_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h2>Fellowships:</h2>



<h4>Postdoctoral Fellowship (1-year appointments, possibility of renewal for up to 4 years)</h4>



<p>Auburn University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: May 30, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178780376&amp;utm_source=05_06_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178780376&amp;utm_source=05_06_24&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h2>Awards:</h2>



<h4>2025 Boniuk Institute Senior Scholar Award</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 20, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://boniuk.rice.edu/nominate-senior-scholar">https://boniuk.rice.edu/nominate-senior-scholar</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>Routledge Companion to Superhero Studies</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 24, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://popularcultureandtheology.com/2024/04/22/cfp-routledge-companion-to-superhero-studies-final-call/">https://popularcultureandtheology.com/2024/04/22/cfp-routledge-companion-to-superhero-studies-final-call/</a></p>



<h4>Maimon, Cohen, Cassirer. Kantianism in its Relationship to Judaism</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 30, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/123026">https://philevents.org/event/show/123026</a></p>



<h4>The Use of GenAI Tools in Education Research</h4>



<p>Deadline: December 12, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://think.taylorandfrancis.com/article_collections/cogent-education-the-use-of-genai-tools-in-education-research/?_gl=1*xcnt8q*_ga*MTUzMDY1OTg5Mi4xNjc4ODU0OTYw*_ga_0HYE8YG0M6*MTcxNDczMzY1OS4xMTMuMS4xNzE0NzMzODc0LjU3LjAuMA..*_gcl_au*MTExNzI4NTM5NS4xNzE0MzAwODgz&amp;_ga=2.39240483.1640012001.1714645834-1530659892.1678854960">Cogent Education: The Use of GenAI Tools in Education Research (taylorandfrancis.com)</a></p>



<h4>The Orthodox Canon Law Society of North America</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 31, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.oclsna.org/conference">https://www.oclsna.org/conference</a></p>



<h4>Climate Change, Religion, and Responsibility</h4>



<p>Deadline: June 30, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://commons.lib.jmu.edu/ijr/news.html">https://commons.lib.jmu.edu/ijr/news.html</a></p>



<h4>Religion and Politics: Historical Developments and Contemporary Transformations</h4>



<p>Deadline: August 1, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/journal/religions/special_issues/6SJ92EF75U">https://www.mdpi.com/journal/religions/special_issues/6SJ92EF75U</a></p>



<h4>Re-Imagining the Woman’s “Curse”: Redemptive Readings of Genesis 3:16</h4>



<p>Deadline: September 1, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/journal/religions/special_issues/B024B4716Q">https://www.mdpi.com/journal/religions/special_issues/B024B4716Q</a></p>



<h4>Catholic Modernity in the Americas: Land, Culture, and Politics</h4>



<p>Deadline: September 15, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://cushwa.nd.edu/news/call-for-papers-catholic-modernity-in-the-americas/">https://cushwa.nd.edu/news/call-for-papers-catholic-modernity-in-the-americas/</a></p>



<h4>Conference on the History of Women Religious: Lives and Archives</h4>



<p>Deadline: August 15, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://cushwa.nd.edu/news/call-for-papers-conference-on-the-history-of-women-religious/">https://cushwa.nd.edu/news/call-for-papers-conference-on-the-history-of-women-religious/</a></p>



<h4>Situating Religious Cognition</h4>



<p>Deadline: October 1, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/journal/religions/special_issues/7Q488424D1">https://www.mdpi.com/journal/religions/special_issues/7Q488424D1</a></p>



<h2>Conferences/Speakers:</h2>



<h4>Hot to Get A Great Job Outside Academia</h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://twitter.com/fromphdtolife/status/1787803483581677991?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw">https://twitter.com/fromphdtolife/status/1787803483581677991?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw</a></p>



<h4>Exploring Indic Traditions</h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>Date: July 8-12, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/uberoi-teacher-training_teachertraining-workshop-hinduism-activity-7187532417023328256-C0WK/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_ios">https://www.linkedin.com/posts/uberoi-teacher-training_teachertraining-workshop-hinduism-activity-7187532417023328256-C0WK/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_ios</a></p>



<h4>Religious Communities and Higher Education in Tumultuous Times</h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>Date: May 10, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://rraweb.us10.list-manage.com/track/click?u=55bb1644f88e9457d182915ac&amp;id=7681b0546c&amp;e=c7b3861607">https://rraweb.us10.list-manage.com/track/click?u=55bb1644f88e9457d182915ac&amp;id=7681b0546c&amp;e=c7b3861607</a></p>



<h4>Forum on Architecture, Spirituality, and Culture</h4>



<p>Date: June 5-9, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://acsforum.org/symposium/2024-symposium/">https://acsforum.org/symposium/2024-symposium/</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1715233027793661</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>OT 2024 : Open Theology - call for Section Editors</title>
			<link>http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=180431&amp;copyownerid=173363</link>
						<description>Open Theology - call for Section Editors</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 05:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1715146626133937</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ May 30, 2024] CFP for conference or similar: Maimon, Cohen, Cassirer. Kantianism in its relationship to Judaism</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/123026</link>
						<description><p><strong>- Deutschsprachiger Aufruf siehe unten -</strong></p>
<p>In recent years there has been a renewed interest in the work of Solomon Maimon especially in research on the history of philosophy—evident from a whole series of recent monographs and the new historical-critical edition of his works. In light of this newer research the conference would like to look back at and draw a comparison with the philosophical constellation at the beginning of the 20th century in which Solomon Maimon first received greater interest in the history of philosophy and modern philosophial appropriations — namely in the Marburg school of neo-Kantianism represented in particular by Hermann Cohen and later Ernst Cassirer. Cassirer was the first major independent philosopher to make Salomon Maimon’s rationalist dissolution of Kant’s doctrine of the given known to a wider public in his work „Das Erkenntnisproblem in der Philosophie und Wissenschaft der neueren Zeit“. Thanks to Cassirer, Maimon was no longer perceived as a mere footnote in the work of Fichte, who had been provoked by Maimon’s scepticism. While Hermann Cohen initially developed his interpretation of Kant independently of Salomon Maimon and while Cohen only rarely mentioned Maimon, his contemporaries soon noticed the great affinity of both philosophers with regard of their fundamental philosophical insights. Cohen’s interpretation of Kant and his systematic philosophy subsequently provided a decisive orientation for the early research on Salomon Maimon, which was mostly conducted in neo-Kantian circles (Albert Zubersky, Salomon Atlas, Hugo Bergmann). The conference shall enable a reappraisal of the neo-Kantian contribution to the understanding of Maimon and put the thoughts of Maimon, Cohen and Cassirer in a productive dialogue, but also shed light on the limitations of this early reception of Maimon and help to understand the role of similar philosophical thoughts within the very different contexts of an understanding of philosophy departing from the theory of sciences in neo-Kantianism on the one hand, and a philosophy very much attached to the 17th and 18th century understanding of metaphysics in Maimon on the other hand.</p>
<p>Beyond the affinities concerning philosophical doctrines and the interpretation of Kant, Maimon, Cohen and Cassirer are also united with respect to the importance of their role as Jewish intellectuals for their works: Despite their aim of contributing to the progress of the one, universal philosophy (which belongs neither to a religious denomination, nor a national origin), building upon the revolutionary advancements brought by Immanuel Kant, all three philosophers consciously reflected on their position as Jewish thinkers within the field of philosophy, drawing on rabbinical, Jewish intellectual traditions that were indispensable to them for their interventions into Kantianism. At the same time, they all attempted to develop a philosophical understanding of Jewish religion based on Kant’s philosophy, but against Kant’s own understanding of Judaism. Alluding to Ernst Cassirer’s lecture „Hermann Cohens Philosophie in ihrem Verhältnis zum Judentum“, in the year of Kant’s 300th birthday and Cassirer’s 150th birthday, we try to create a dialogue between research contributions on Maimon, Cohen and Cassirer in the fields of theoretical philosophy as well as ethics and philosophy of religion and broader Jewish intellectual history, which together are able to shed light on the historical drafts of a relationship between Kantianism and Judaism.</p>
<p>Possible questions for the conference in the field of theoretical philosophy include: What interpretative decisions with regard to Kant lead Maimon and the Marburg School to their conceptualist reading of Kant? How does Cohen’s limitation to a theory of knowledge relate to Maimon’s metaphysical aims — rooted in the rationalist tradition of the 17th and 18th century — in their conceptions a new logic? Based on today’s understanding of the history of mathematics, how do we assess the key role of the infinitesimal calculus—on which both philosophers wrote historiographic works—in Cohen’s and Maimon’s criticism of Kant’s doctrine of the given? How did Cassirer’s „Erkenntnisproblem“ shape the understanding of Maimon's position in the history of post-Kantian philosophy?</p>
<p>Possible questions for the conference in the field of ethics include: How does the independence of the reality of the pure will that grounds ethics from experience and psychology on the one hand, and religious authority on the other—a fundamental principle of Cohen’s ethics—, relate to Maimon’s scepticism about the real efficaciousness of the moral law? How do Maimon’s and Cohen’s definitions of the relationship between morality and religion relate to Kant’s own multiple revisions of his doctrine of postulates of pure practical reason? What do Maimon’s and Cohen’s understanding of natural law and positive law provide to counter Hegel’s criticism of a supposedly Jewish, merely abstract Kantian legality? How does Cassirer late work on the “Myth of the State” react to the authoritarian-fascist criticism directed against the practical philosophy of the Marburg School for example by Carl Schmitt?</p>
<p>Possible questions for the conference in the field of philosophy of religion include: What independent status can a religion or a rational religion have vis-à-vis ethics for Maimon and also for Cohen, who revised his philosophy of religion from 1914 onwards, still subordinating religion to ethics but no longer understanding it as a mere historic fact? How do Maimon and Cohen independently from each other approach Maimonides’ doctrine of divine attributes to the Kantian critique of rational theology?</p>
<p>What similarities exist between Maimon’s and Cassirer’s foundation of philosophy of religion in a certain theory of language, with both Maimon and Cassirer’s „Philosophie der symbolischen Formen“ building upon 17th and 18th century philosophical debates on language? What understanding of the law allows Maimon, Cohen and Cassirer, to no longer see Judaism as an outdated, deficient religion compared to the Christian religion with respect to the approachment of reason, as Kant did? In which anti-Jewish political contexts do the philosophers articulate their philosophical understanding of Jewish religion—from hostility towards Maimon as a result of his split with Reinhold to anti-Semitic resentment against neo-Kantianism among National Socialist philosophers such as Max Wundt or Martin Heidegger?</p>
<p>At the heart of works of the three philosophers we wish to recognise the struggle for understanding the Kantian texts. The lecture programme will thereby be supplemented by three joint reading sessions which, based on the interpretations of Kant’s Analytic of Principles, the doctrine of postulates in the Critique of Practical Reason and the reflections on Judaism in the Religious Writings and Anthropology, will open up central questions of the conference for joint discussion by the experts. Finally, all participants will have the opportunity to visit Hermann Cohen’s grave at the Jewish cemetery in Berlin-Weißensee. Working languages will be English and German.</p>
<p>For enquiries please contact Jonathan Schmidt-Dominé and Yehuda Oren, schmidt-domine@em.uni-frankfurt.de. Abstracts can be submitted in either English or German until May 30th.</p>
<p><strong>Maimon, Cohen, Cassirer</strong></p>
<p>Der Kantianismus in seinem Verhältnis zum Judentum</p>
<p>Angesichts eines in den letzten Jahren erneuerten Interesses der philosophiegeschichtlichen Forschung am Werk Salomon Maimons – für das eine ganze Reihe jüngerer Monographien sowie die neue historisch-kritische Werkausgabe stehen, deren erster Band soeben erschienen ist – möchte die Konferenz nach jener philosophischen Konstellation zu Beginn des 20. Jahrhunderts zurückfragen, in welcher Salomon Maimon erstmals größeres philosophiegeschichtliches Interesse und eine erneute Aneignung erfuhr: Für diese Konstellation stehen maßgeblich die beiden Namen Hermann Cohen und Ernst Cassirer. Ernst Cassirer war der erste große eigenständige Philosoph, der mit seinem „Erkenntnisproblem in der Philosophie und Wissenschaft der neueren Zeit“ Salomon Maimons rationalistische Auflösung der Kant’schen Lehre der Gegebenheit wieder neu bekannt machte. Dank Cassirer wurde Maimon nicht mehr länger bloß als Fußnote im Werk des von Maimons Skeptizismus provozierten Fichte wahrgenommen. Während Hermann Cohen zu Beginn der Entwicklung seiner Kant-Interpretation unabhängig von Salomon Maimon betrieb und Cohen Maimon nur selten erwähnte, bemerkten seine Zeitgenossen bald die große Übereinstimmung der beiden Philosophen bezüglich entscheidender Einsichten. Cohens Kant-Interpretation und seine systematische Philosophie prägten in der Folge die zumeist aus neukantianischen Kreisen betriebene frühe Forschung zu Salomon Maimon (Albert Zubersky, Salomon Atlas, Hugo Bergmann). Die Konfefrenz versucht den neukantianischen Beitrag zum Verständnis Maimons neu zu würdigen und das Denken Maimons, Cohens und Cassirers in einen produkitven Dialog zu bringen, aber auch Beschränkungen der frühen Rezeption aufzuzeigen und die unterschiedliche Rolle ähnlicher philosophischer Gedankengänge in ganz verschiedenen Kontexten zu verstehen, sprich: im Kontext eines maßgeblich wissenschaftstheoretisch orientierten neukantianischen Philosophieverständnisses einerseits, und einem stark am Metaphysikverständnis des 17. und 18. Jahrhunderts orientierten Philosophie im Falle Maimons andererseits.</p>
<p>Über die Affinitäten ihrer philosophischen Lehren und ihrer Kant-Interpretationen vereint Maimon, Cohen und Cassirer auch die Bedeutung ihrer Rolle als jüdische Intellektuelle für ihre Werke: Bei allem Anspruch, von Konfession und Herkunft unabhängig der einen Philosophie im Anschluss an die philosophische Revolution Kants zum Fortschritt zu verhelfen, reflektieren alle drei Philosophen bewusst ihre Position als jüdische Denker im philosophischen Diskurs, wobei sie auf für ihre Innovationen unverzichtbare jüdische, einschließlich rabbinische intellektuelle Traditionen zurückgreifen. Gleichzeitig versuchten sie allesamt, ausgehend von Kant, aber gegen Kants eigenes Verständnis des Judentums ein philosophisches Verständnis der jüdischen Religion zu entwickeln. Anschließend an Ernst Cassirers Vortrag „Hermann Cohens Philosophie in ihrem Verhältnis zum Judentum“ laden wir im Jahr des 300. Geburtstags Kants und des 150. Geburtstags Cassirers dazu ein, Forschungsbeiträge zu Maimon, Cohen und Cassirer sowohl im Gebiet der theoretischen Philosophie als auch der Ethik und der Religionsphilosophie zu präsentieren, welche gemeinsam ein Licht auf die historischen Entwürfe eines Verhältnisses des Kantianismus zum Judentum zu werfen vermögen.</p>
<p>Mögliche Fragen der Konferenz im Bereich der theoretischen Philosophie: Welche interpretatorischen Entscheidungen mit Blick auf Kant führen Maimon bzw. die Marburger Schule zu ihrer konzeptualistischen Kant-Lesart? Wie verhält sich Cohens Beschränkung auf eine Erkenntnistheorie zu Maimons stark in der Tradition des Rationalismus des 18. Jahrhunderts stehenden Metaphysik-Anspruchs in ihren Entwürfen für eine neue Logik? Wie beurteilen wir ausgehend vom heutigen mathematikhistorischen Verständnis die Schlüsselrolle der – von beiden Philosophen auch ausführlich historisch behandelten – Infinitesimalrechnung für Cohens wie Maimons Kritik an Kants Lehre der Gegebenheit? Wie prägte Cassirers „Erkenntnisproblem“ das Verständnis von Maimons Position in der Geschichte der nachkantischen Philosophie?</p>
<p>Mögliche Fragen der Konferenz im Bereich der Ethik: Wie verhält sich die für Cohen zentrale Unabhängigkeit der Realität des die Ethik begründenden reinen Willens von Erfahrung und Psychologie einerseits, religiöser Autorität andererseits zu Maimons Skeptizismus gegenüber der Realität der Wirkung des moralischen Gesetzes? Wie verhalten sich Maimons und Cohens Verhältnisbestimmungen zwischen Moral und Religion zu Kants eigener mehrfach aufgenommenen Postulatenlehre? Was haben Maimons und Cohens Verständnis von Naturrecht und positivem Recht etwa der Hegel’schen Kritik an einer vermeintlich jüdischen bloß abstrakten kantischen Gesetzlichkeit entgegenzusetzen? Wie reagiert Cassirer mit seinem „Mythos des Staates“ auf die autoritaristisch-faschistische Kritik etwa seitens Carl Schmitts an der praktischen Philosophie der Marburger Schule?</p>
<p>Mögliche Fragen der Konferenz im Bereich der Religionsphilosophie: Welchen eigenständigen Stellenwert kann eine Religion bzw. eine Vernunftreligion gegenüber der Ethik für Maimon bzw. Cohen, der ab 1914 eine der Ethik zwar untergeordnete, aber doch nicht bloß historisch-orientierte Religionsphilosophie entwickelte? Wie nähern Maimon und Cohen unabhängig voneinander Maimonides’ Attributenlehre an die kantische Kritik der rationalen Theologie an?</p>
<p>Welche Gemeinsamkeiten bestehen zwischen Maimons und Cassirers sprachphilosophischer Fundierung der Religionsphilosophie, wobei Maimon ebenso wie Cassirers „Philosophie der symbolischen Formen“ maßgeblich auf Debatten des Sprachdenkens des 17. und 18. Jahrhunderts aufbauen? Welches Gesetzesverständnis erlaubt es den Maimon, Cohen und Cassirer das Judentum anders als Kant nicht als eine gegenüber dem sich der Vernunft annähernden christlichen Religion überholte, defizitäre Religion aufzufassen? In welchen antijüdischen politischen Kontexten artikulieren die Philosophen ihr philosophisches Verständnis der jüdischen Religion – angefangen bei Anfeindungen gegen Maimon infolge seiner Entzweiung mit Reinhold bis hin zum antisemitischen Ressentiment gegen den Neukantianismus bei nationalsozialistischen Philosophen wie Max Wundt oder Martin Heidegger?</p>
<p>Als einen Kern des Werks der drei Philosophen wünschen wir das Ringen ums Verständnis des kantischen Textes würdigen. Das Vortragsprogramm wird daher ergänzt durch drei gemeinsame Lektüresitzungen, welche ausgehend von den Interpretationen von Kants Analytik der Grundsätze, der Postulatenlehre in der Kritik der praktischen Vernunft bzw. der Betrachtungen zum Judentum in der Religionsschrift und der Anthropologie zentrale Fragen der Konferenz für die gemeinsame Diskussion der Fachleute öffnet. Abschließend steht allen Teilnehmenden ein gemeinsamer Besuch des Grabs von Hermann Cohen auf dem jüdischen Friedhof Berlin-Weißensee offen.</p>
<p>Für Nachfragen kontaktieren Sie gerne Jonathan Schmidt-Dominé and Yehuda Oren, schmidt-domine@em.uni-frankfurt.de. Abstracts können bis zum 30. Mai auf Deutsch oder Englisch eingereicht werden.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 05:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1714887423933223</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ December 15, 2024 -  December 17, 2024] Conference or similar: Maimon, Cohen, Cassirer. Kantianism in its relationship to Judaism</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/123022</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p><strong>- Deutschsprachiger Aufruf siehe unten -</strong></p>
<p>In recent years there has been a renewed interest in the work of Solomon Maimon especially in research on the history of philosophy—evident from a whole series of recent monographs and the new historical-critical edition of his works. In light of this newer research the conference would like to look back at and draw a comparison with the philosophical constellation at the beginning of the 20th century in which Solomon Maimon first received greater interest in the history of philosophy and modern philosophial appropriations — namely in the Marburg school of neo-Kantianism represented in particular by Hermann Cohen and later Ernst Cassirer. Cassirer was the first major independent philosopher to make Salomon Maimon’s rationalist dissolution of Kant’s doctrine of the given known to a wider public in his work „Das Erkenntnisproblem in der Philosophie und Wissenschaft der neueren Zeit“. Thanks to Cassirer, Maimon was no longer perceived as a mere footnote in the work of Fichte, who had been provoked by Maimon’s scepticism. While Hermann Cohen initially developed his interpretation of Kant independently of Salomon Maimon and while Cohen only rarely mentioned Maimon, his contemporaries soon noticed the great affinity of both philosophers with regard of their fundamental philosophical insights. Cohen’s interpretation of Kant and his systematic philosophy subsequently provided a decisive orientation for the early research on Salomon Maimon, which was mostly conducted in neo-Kantian circles (Albert Zubersky, Salomon Atlas, Hugo Bergmann). The conference shall enable a reappraisal of the neo-Kantian contribution to the understanding of Maimon and put the thoughts of Maimon, Cohen and Cassirer in a productive dialogue, but also shed light on the limitations of this early reception of Maimon and help to understand the role of similar philosophical thoughts within the very different contexts of an understanding of philosophy departing from the theory of sciences in neo-Kantianism on the one hand, and a philosophy very much attached to the 17th and 18th century understanding of metaphysics in Maimon on the other hand.</p>
<p>Beyond the affinities concerning philosophical doctrines and the interpretation of Kant, Maimon, Cohen and Cassirer are also united with respect to the importance of their role as Jewish intellectuals for their works: Despite their aim of contributing to the progress of the one, universal philosophy (which belongs neither to a religious denomination, nor a national origin), building upon the revolutionary advancements brought by Immanuel Kant, all three philosophers consciously reflected on their position as Jewish thinkers within the field of philosophy, drawing on rabbinical, Jewish intellectual traditions that were indispensable to them for their interventions into Kantianism. At the same time, they all attempted to develop a philosophical understanding of Jewish religion based on Kant’s philosophy, but against Kant’s own understanding of Judaism. Alluding to Ernst Cassirer’s lecture „Hermann Cohens Philosophie in ihrem Verhältnis zum Judentum“, in the year of Kant’s 300th birthday and Cassirer’s 150th birthday, we try to create a dialogue between research contributions on Maimon, Cohen and Cassirer in the fields of theoretical philosophy as well as ethics and philosophy of religion and broader Jewish intellectual history, which together are able to shed light on the historical drafts of a relationship between Kantianism and Judaism.</p>
<p>Possible questions for the conference in the field of theoretical philosophy include: What interpretative decisions with regard to Kant lead Maimon and the Marburg School to their conceptualist reading of Kant? How does Cohen’s limitation to a theory of knowledge relate to Maimon’s metaphysical aims — rooted in the rationalist tradition of the 17th and 18th century — in their conceptions a new logic? Based on today’s understanding of the history of mathematics, how do we assess the key role of the infinitesimal calculus—on which both philosophers wrote historiographic works—in Cohen’s and Maimon’s criticism of Kant’s doctrine of the given? How did Cassirer’s „Erkenntnisproblem“ shape the understanding of Maimon's position in the history of post-Kantian philosophy?</p>
<p>Possible questions for the conference in the field of ethics include: How does the independence of the reality of the pure will that grounds ethics from experience and psychology on the one hand, and religious authority on the other—a fundamental principle of Cohen’s ethics—, relate to Maimon’s scepticism about the real efficaciousness of the moral law? How do Maimon’s and Cohen’s definitions of the relationship between morality and religion relate to Kant’s own multiple revisions of his doctrine of postulates of pure practical reason? What do Maimon’s and Cohen’s understanding of natural law and positive law provide to counter Hegel’s criticism of a supposedly Jewish, merely abstract Kantian legality? How does Cassirer late work on the “Myth of the State” react to the authoritarian-fascist criticism directed against the practical philosophy of the Marburg School for example by Carl Schmitt?</p>
<p>Possible questions for the conference in the field of philosophy of religion include: What independent status can a religion or a rational religion have vis-à-vis ethics for Maimon and also for Cohen, who revised his philosophy of religion from 1914 onwards, still subordinating religion to ethics but no longer understanding it as a mere historic fact? How do Maimon and Cohen independently from each other approach Maimonides’ doctrine of divine attributes to the Kantian critique of rational theology?</p>
<p>What similarities exist between Maimon’s and Cassirer’s foundation of philosophy of religion in a certain theory of language, with both Maimon and Cassirer’s „Philosophie der symbolischen Formen“ building upon 17th and 18th century philosophical debates on language? What understanding of the law allows Maimon, Cohen and Cassirer, to no longer see Judaism as an outdated, deficient religion compared to the Christian religion with respect to the approachment of reason, as Kant did? In which anti-Jewish political contexts do the philosophers articulate their philosophical understanding of Jewish religion—from hostility towards Maimon as a result of his split with Reinhold to anti-Semitic resentment against neo-Kantianism among National Socialist philosophers such as Max Wundt or Martin Heidegger?</p>
<p>At the heart of works of the three philosophers we wish to recognise the struggle for understanding the Kantian texts. The lecture programme will thereby be supplemented by three joint reading sessions which, based on the interpretations of Kant’s Analytic of Principles, the doctrine of postulates in the Critique of Practical Reason and the reflections on Judaism in the Religious Writings and Anthropology, will open up central questions of the conference for joint discussion by the experts. Finally, all participants will have the opportunity to visit Hermann Cohen’s grave at the Jewish cemetery in Berlin-Weißensee. Working languages will be English and German.</p>
<p>For enquiries please contact Jonathan Schmidt-Dominé and Yehuda Oren, schmidt-domine@em.uni-frankfurt.de. Abstracts can be submitted in either English or German until May 30th.</p>

<p><strong>Maimon, Cohen, Cassirer</strong></p>
<p>Der Kantianismus in seinem Verhältnis zum Judentum</p>

<p>Angesichts eines in den letzten Jahren erneuerten Interesses der philosophiegeschichtlichen Forschung am Werk Salomon Maimons – für das eine ganze Reihe jüngerer Monographien sowie die neue historisch-kritische Werkausgabe stehen, deren erster Band soeben erschienen ist – möchte die Konferenz nach jener philosophischen Konstellation zu Beginn des 20. Jahrhunderts zurückfragen, in welcher Salomon Maimon erstmals größeres philosophiegeschichtliches Interesse und eine erneute Aneignung erfuhr: Für diese Konstellation stehen maßgeblich die beiden Namen Hermann Cohen und Ernst Cassirer. Ernst Cassirer war der erste große eigenständige Philosoph, der mit seinem „Erkenntnisproblem in der Philosophie und Wissenschaft der neueren Zeit“ Salomon Maimons rationalistische Auflösung der Kant’schen Lehre der Gegebenheit wieder neu bekannt machte. Dank Cassirer wurde Maimon nicht mehr länger bloß als Fußnote im Werk des von Maimons Skeptizismus provozierten Fichte wahrgenommen. Während Hermann Cohen zu Beginn der Entwicklung seiner Kant-Interpretation unabhängig von Salomon Maimon betrieb und Cohen Maimon nur selten erwähnte, bemerkten seine Zeitgenossen bald die große Übereinstimmung der beiden Philosophen bezüglich entscheidender Einsichten. Cohens Kant-Interpretation und seine systematische Philosophie prägten in der Folge die zumeist aus neukantianischen Kreisen betriebene frühe Forschung zu Salomon Maimon (Albert Zubersky, Salomon Atlas, Hugo Bergmann). Die Konfefrenz versucht den neukantianischen Beitrag zum Verständnis Maimons neu zu würdigen und das Denken Maimons, Cohens und Cassirers in einen produkitven Dialog zu bringen, aber auch Beschränkungen der frühen Rezeption aufzuzeigen und die unterschiedliche Rolle ähnlicher philosophischer Gedankengänge in ganz verschiedenen Kontexten zu verstehen, sprich: im Kontext eines maßgeblich wissenschaftstheoretisch orientierten neukantianischen Philosophieverständnisses einerseits, und einem stark am Metaphysikverständnis des 17. und 18. Jahrhunderts orientierten Philosophie im Falle Maimons andererseits.</p>
<p>Über die Affinitäten ihrer philosophischen Lehren und ihrer Kant-Interpretationen vereint Maimon, Cohen und Cassirer auch die Bedeutung ihrer Rolle als jüdische Intellektuelle für ihre Werke: Bei allem Anspruch, von Konfession und Herkunft unabhängig der einen Philosophie im Anschluss an die philosophische Revolution Kants zum Fortschritt zu verhelfen, reflektieren alle drei Philosophen bewusst ihre Position als jüdische Denker im philosophischen Diskurs, wobei sie auf für ihre Innovationen unverzichtbare jüdische, einschließlich rabbinische intellektuelle Traditionen zurückgreifen. Gleichzeitig versuchten sie allesamt, ausgehend von Kant, aber gegen Kants eigenes Verständnis des Judentums ein philosophisches Verständnis der jüdischen Religion zu entwickeln. Anschließend an Ernst Cassirers Vortrag „Hermann Cohens Philosophie in ihrem Verhältnis zum Judentum“ laden wir im Jahr des 300. Geburtstags Kants und des 150. Geburtstags Cassirers dazu ein, Forschungsbeiträge zu Maimon, Cohen und Cassirer sowohl im Gebiet der theoretischen Philosophie als auch der Ethik und der Religionsphilosophie zu präsentieren, welche gemeinsam ein Licht auf die historischen Entwürfe eines Verhältnisses des Kantianismus zum Judentum zu werfen vermögen.</p>
<p>Mögliche Fragen der Konferenz im Bereich der theoretischen Philosophie: Welche interpretatorischen Entscheidungen mit Blick auf Kant führen Maimon bzw. die Marburger Schule zu ihrer konzeptualistischen Kant-Lesart? Wie verhält sich Cohens Beschränkung auf eine Erkenntnistheorie zu Maimons stark in der Tradition des Rationalismus des 18. Jahrhunderts stehenden Metaphysik-Anspruchs in ihren Entwürfen für eine neue Logik? Wie beurteilen wir ausgehend vom heutigen mathematikhistorischen Verständnis die Schlüsselrolle der – von beiden Philosophen auch ausführlich historisch behandelten – Infinitesimalrechnung für Cohens wie Maimons Kritik an Kants Lehre der Gegebenheit? Wie prägte Cassirers „Erkenntnisproblem“ das Verständnis von Maimons Position in der Geschichte der nachkantischen Philosophie?</p>
<p>Mögliche Fragen der Konferenz im Bereich der Ethik: Wie verhält sich die für Cohen zentrale Unabhängigkeit der Realität des die Ethik begründenden reinen Willens von Erfahrung und Psychologie einerseits, religiöser Autorität andererseits zu Maimons Skeptizismus gegenüber der Realität der Wirkung des moralischen Gesetzes? Wie verhalten sich Maimons und Cohens Verhältnisbestimmungen zwischen Moral und Religion zu Kants eigener mehrfach aufgenommenen Postulatenlehre? Was haben Maimons und Cohens Verständnis von Naturrecht und positivem Recht etwa der Hegel’schen Kritik an einer vermeintlich jüdischen bloß abstrakten kantischen Gesetzlichkeit entgegenzusetzen? Wie reagiert Cassirer mit seinem „Mythos des Staates“ auf die autoritaristisch-faschistische Kritik etwa seitens Carl Schmitts an der praktischen Philosophie der Marburger Schule?</p>
<p>Mögliche Fragen der Konferenz im Bereich der Religionsphilosophie: Welchen eigenständigen Stellenwert kann eine Religion bzw. eine Vernunftreligion gegenüber der Ethik für Maimon bzw. Cohen, der ab 1914 eine der Ethik zwar untergeordnete, aber doch nicht bloß historisch-orientierte Religionsphilosophie entwickelte? Wie nähern Maimon und Cohen unabhängig voneinander Maimonides’ Attributenlehre an die kantische Kritik der rationalen Theologie an?</p>
<p>Welche Gemeinsamkeiten bestehen zwischen Maimons und Cassirers sprachphilosophischer Fundierung der Religionsphilosophie, wobei Maimon ebenso wie Cassirers „Philosophie der symbolischen Formen“ maßgeblich auf Debatten des Sprachdenkens des 17. und 18. Jahrhunderts aufbauen? Welches Gesetzesverständnis erlaubt es den Maimon, Cohen und Cassirer das Judentum anders als Kant nicht als eine gegenüber dem sich der Vernunft annähernden christlichen Religion überholte, defizitäre Religion aufzufassen? In welchen antijüdischen politischen Kontexten artikulieren die Philosophen ihr philosophisches Verständnis der jüdischen Religion – angefangen bei Anfeindungen gegen Maimon infolge seiner Entzweiung mit Reinhold bis hin zum antisemitischen Ressentiment gegen den Neukantianismus bei nationalsozialistischen Philosophen wie Max Wundt oder Martin Heidegger?</p>
<p>Als einen Kern des Werks der drei Philosophen wünschen wir das Ringen ums Verständnis des kantischen Textes würdigen. Das Vortragsprogramm wird daher ergänzt durch drei gemeinsame Lektüresitzungen, welche ausgehend von den Interpretationen von Kants Analytik der Grundsätze, der Postulatenlehre in der Kritik der praktischen Vernunft bzw. der Betrachtungen zum Judentum in der Religionsschrift und der Anthropologie zentrale Fragen der Konferenz für die gemeinsame Diskussion der Fachleute öffnet. Abschließend steht allen Teilnehmenden ein gemeinsamer Besuch des Grabs von Hermann Cohen auf dem jüdischen Friedhof Berlin-Weißensee offen.</p>
<p>Für Nachfragen kontaktieren Sie gerne Jonathan Schmidt-Dominé and Yehuda Oren, schmidt-domine@em.uni-frankfurt.de. Abstracts können bis zum 30. Mai auf Deutsch oder Englisch eingereicht werden.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 05:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1714887423933222</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
