<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 12:19:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 12:19:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ May 15, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Merleau-Ponty and Embodiment: Between the Cognitive, Aesthetic, and Socio-Political</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/109901</link>
						<description><p><strong>Merleau-Ponty and Embodiment: Between the Cognitive, Aesthetic, and Socio-Political</strong></p>
<p>47th Annual Meeting of the International Merleau-Ponty Circle</p>
<p>In-person and virtual (hybrid)</p>
<p>4-6 December 2023</p>
<p>Deakin University, Melbourne (Narrm), Australia </p>
<p><em>“Le corps est notre moyen général d’avoir un monde</em>. / <em>The body is our general means of having a world.”</em></p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p>Merleau-Ponty's seminal work on embodiment has been of enduring interest and influence in a wide range of fields. It has, for example, played a significant role in research on embodied cognition and enactivism, subjectivity and intersubjectivity, affectivity, movement, art, place, and more. Although sometimes criticised for providing an account of embodiment that is too general, Merleau-Ponty’s philosophical foregrounding of embodiment has also facilitated critical phenomenological studies attending to the specificities of how particular bodies inhabit social and political environments, through considerations of race, gender, disability, ageing, and illness. This year’s meeting of the IMPC seeks to bring together these rich and varied strands of enquiry, in order to think with, against, and beyond Merleau-Ponty’s own contributions on the lived body. </p>
<p>Only its third time outside North America, this year’s meeting will take place in Melbourne (Narrm), Australia, on the traditional and unceded lands of the Kulin Nation. The conference is being directed by Helen Ngo and Jack Reynolds, with support from Andrew Inkpin and others. Keynote and plenary speakers will be announced shortly. The conference will be held at the centrally located and accessible Deakin Downtown campus, and recommended accommodation options will be provided nearer the date. </p>
<p><strong>Full paper submissions</strong> of no more than 3,500 words should be prepared for anonymous review and sent to <em>both</em> the directors at helen.ngo@deakin.edu.au and jack.reynolds@deakin.edu.au with the subject heading "IMPC submission" <strong>by May 15, 2023</strong>. As is custom, submissions on any aspect of Merleau-Ponty’s work, in addition to the conference theme, are also welcome.</p>
<p>This year’s event will include a thematic stream on <em>Race, place, and bodies</em> curated by Helen Ngo for a research project funded by the Australian Research Council (DE220100329). A small number of bursaries will be available for students and unwaged early career researchers presenting in-person in this stream. Participants wishing to be considered for this are asked to indicate so on the cover letter of your submission. </p>
<p>The conference features the M. C. Dillon prize and lecture for the best graduate student paper submission (https://www.merleauponty.org/m-c-dillon-memorial/). To be considered for this prize, please indicate so on the cover letter of your submission. This year’s conference will also inaugurate a second graduate student prize, the Morstyn prize, which recognises our late colleague, from Sydney, Australia, Ron Morstyn, who contributed to and attended the IMPC over many years, with special interests in psychology and psychiatry. Details for consideration for this prize will be announced between now and the submission deadline.  </p>
<p>Finally, as this conference will be held as a hybrid event, please indicate whether, upon acceptance, you plan to attend in-person or virtually. In order to host the conference at a physical location, a certain percentage of talks will need to be presented in person, and this will be factored in during the anonymous review process. If you plan to attend virtually because doing so physically presents insurmountable accessibility issues (of whatever sort, including economic ones), you are welcome (but not required) to include that information. You are also welcome to include any anticipated accessibility needs, which will greatly assist in planning.</p>
<p>Helen Ngo and Jack Reynolds, on behalf of International Merleau-Ponty Circle.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 05:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680586628555805</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ December 4, 2023 -  December 6, 2023] Conference or similar: Merleau-Ponty and Embodiment: Between the Cognitive, Aesthetic, and Socio-Political</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/109897</link>
						<description>Venue: Deakin Downtown<br/><br/><p>47TH ANNUAL CONFERENCE OF THE INTERNATIONAL MERLEAU-PONTY CIRCLE</p>
<p>Dec 4th – Dec 6th 2023 | Deakin University, Melbourne (Narrm), Australia | In-person and virtual (hybrid)</p>
<p><em>“Le corps est notre moyen général d’avoir un monde</em>. / <em>The body is our general means of having a world.”</em></p>
<p>Merleau-Ponty’s seminal work on embodiment has been of enduring interest and influence in a wide range of fields. It has, for example, played a significant role in research on embodied cognition and enactivism, subjectivity and intersubjectivity, affectivity, movement, art, place, and more. Although sometimes criticized for providing an account of embodiment that is too general, Merleau-Ponty’s philosophical foregrounding of embodiment has also facilitated critical phenomenological studies attending to the specificities of how particular bodies inhabit social and political environments, through considerations of race, gender, disability, ageing, and illness. This year’s meeting of the IMPC seeks to bring together these rich and varied strands of enquiry, in order to think with, against, and beyond Merleau-Ponty’s own contributions on the lived body.</p>
<p>Only its third time outside North America, this year’s meeting of IMPC will take place in Melbourne (Narrm), Australia, on the traditional and unceded lands of the Kulin Nation.</p>
<p>The conference is being directed by Helen Ngo and Jack Reynolds.</p>
<p>Keynote and plenary speakers will be announced shortly. The conference will be held at the centrally located and accessible Deakin Downtown campus, and recommended accommodation options will be provided nearer the date. Registration will be required; this page will be updated when registration deadlines have been set.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 05:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680586628555804</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Methodist Studies Seminar (in person and online)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12640999/methodist-studies-seminar-person-and-online</link>
						<dc:creator>Geordan Hammond</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-05-12T00:00:00-04:00">May 12, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Methodist Studies Seminars provide an opportunity for established and emerging scholars of Methodist Studies to present the findings of their research. We conceive of Methodist Studies broadly and aim to provide opportunities for students of history, theology, literature, art, material culture and other fields related to Methodism.</p><p>The next seminar will be hosted by the Manchester Wesley Research Centre and Cliff College at Nazarene Theological College in Manchester and online on Friday 12 May 2023. There is no cost to attend, but registration is required. The registration link and seminar schedule can be found at: <a href="https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/methodist-studies-seminars" rel="nofollow">https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/methodist-studies-seminars</a>. </p><p>The conference will be on Friday 12 May from 10:00am to 4pm BST</p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Nazarene Theological College</p><p>Dene Road, Didsbury</p><p>Manchester M20 2GU</p><p>UK</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ghammond@nazarene.ac.uk">ghammond@nazarene.ac.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/methodist-studies-seminars" target="_blank">https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/methodist-studies-seminars</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 17:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680154627898615</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CfP: Baltic Orthodoxy: People, Practices, Places</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12639618/cfp-baltic-orthodoxy-people-practices-places</link>
						<dc:creator>James White</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Area Studies, Humanities, Religious Studies and Theology, Russian or Soviet History / Studies, Eastern Europe History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span>From the nineteenth century, Orthodox practices, identities, and institutions in the Baltic region have continually been rewoven to form a truly intriguing tapestry reflecting the particular perspectives and interests of a dazzling number of weavers. Initially the religion of Russian settlers, Orthodoxy attracted indigenous lower-class adherents during complex social manoeuvring between local elites and the imperial authorities. In the process, both rural and urban locales were transformed by the presence of Orthodox clergy, churches, charities, schools, and sacred narratives, some imposed from above, others created by agents on the ground. Following the devastation unleashed by the First World War and revolution, Baltic Orthodox churches and believers faced not only the formidable task of creating new institutions embodying both late imperial reform movements and new democratic trends, but also negotiating their position as minorities within avowedly secular republics. Following yet another round of destructive conflict in the Second World War, Orthodoxy in parts of the Baltic region had to confront yet another challenge, that of the militantly atheistic Soviet state, which shuttered churches, persecuted clergy and believers, and imposed strict regulations on religious activities. Today, Orthodoxy and its adherents continue to play an important role in the multicultural landscape of the modern Baltic region, adapting their faith and practices to a world thoroughly changed by digital revolution. </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Throughout this period, the Baltic region has been at the avant-garde of the changes associated with modernity. The population enjoyed levels of literacy that were impressively high compared to many countries of the time. Its transport and communication systems rapidly developed, as did the sciences, arts, and culture</span></span>: <span><span>Orthodoxy in the Baltic region has interacted with and reflected these developments. At the same time, Orthodoxy in the Baltic region was diverse, including representatives not only from ‘official Orthodoxy', but also varied Old Believer groups. </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>The study of Orthodoxy in the Baltic region has typically focused on the religion’s place within overarching political narratives – within imperial russification, as a minority faith in secular states, or as a target of Soviet persecution. Such a focus is certainly justified, but it has often led to the neglect of the everyday religious experiences of Orthodox parishioners, communities, and institutions within this multiconfessional, multiethnic, and multilinguistic region in the throes of modernization. Equally, it has led to a neglect of the agency of a variety of local groups and peoples, as such actors tend to be viewed as the recipients of projects and policies rather than active participants in them. </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Taking as its starting point a microhistorical perspective/Geertzian deep description, this proposed volume will decentralise narratives of Orthodoxy in the Baltic region and restore agency to local Orthodox actors, demonstrating how believers and communities, although not in isolation, have experienced and transformed Orthodoxy in the context of a variety of political regimes (empire, republic, Soviet federal unit, post-Soviet state) and in a period marked by modernization. <b>Contributing authors representing a variety of academic disciplines and national backgrounds will be asked to provide micro examinations of Orthodoxy in the Baltic region (Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, and Finland), choosing as their case studies individual people, communities, and practices from the nineteenth century to the present day</b>. </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>In presenting this research, this book will, for the first time in English, demonstrate the dizzying array of Orthodox experiences from a bottom-up perspective, understanding Orthodox identities as, at least in part, generated not only by central institutions but also by believers, clergymen, and communities. Orthodoxy in this volume will not be understood within a vacuum: the authors will be expected to demonstrate how individuals, communities, and practices influenced and were influenced by broader social, cultural, political, and economic trends, and how Orthodoxy affected and was affected by actors and institutions from other groups. Finally, the volume will also stress the fluid and penetrable nature of both state borders and various imagined communities, emphasising links not only between the Orthodox communities of four Baltic countries, but also connections with groups, people, and institutions in other parts of the globe. These links had and continue to have transformative potential, changing perspectives, attitudes, and the allocation of resources. </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>The contributions should consider the following questions:</span></span></b></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span>How have Baltic Orthodox actors and institutions (individuals, parish communities, schools, ecclesiastical institutions, etc.) developed (and continue to develop) in the context of religious and ethnic diversity? </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>How did/do aspects of modernity affect Orthodox communities and identities?</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>What was/is the impact of central policy (for instance, nationalizing imperial practices or Soviet anti-religious policy) on Orthodox individual and collective identities?</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>What role did/does women and gender issues play in Orthodox communities?  </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>What role has/does monasticism play in the image, identity, and attractiveness of Orthodoxy in the region?</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>How did/do connections with communities (Orthodox or otherwise) across the world transform Baltic Orthodox identities and practices?   </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>How did/do local environmental conditions affect the development of Baltic Orthodox communities? </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>How did/do Orthodox practices of conciliarity, such as the rituals and practices of self-government, develop on the level of the parish, deanery, and diocese? What conflicts did/do they provoke? </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>How did Orthodox theology change and develop in the Baltic context? How did such thought influence Baltic Orthodox praxis? </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>How did music and musical practices reflect developments in Baltic Orthodoxy?</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>In what distinctive ways did Old Believer communities, practices, and institutions develop from the nineteenth to the twenty-first centuries? How did Old Belief’s relationship with ‘official Orthodoxy’ change over this period? </span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>These questions could be studied through the following lenses: </span></span></b></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span>Biographical approaches to individuals, be they clergy or laity, Orthodox or connected with Orthodoxy; </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Focusing on an individual parish or group of parishes from a historical or anthropological/sociological perspective; </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Historical or sociological case studies examining religious institutions, including schools, parish institutions, missions, monasteries, archives, bureaucratic organs, and jurisdictions; </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Historical, ethnographic/anthropological, theological, and musicological approaches to the study of religious practices, including singing, pilgrimage, charity, cross processions, naming practices, etc. </span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span><span>This book is expected to appeal to specialists in the history and politics of states in the Baltic region, specialists in the history and contemporaneity of European religions, specialists in the lives of minority groups, interested members of the general public, and university students. </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>English-language editorial assistance will be provided to non-native speakers. </span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>Timetable for contributors</span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>1 June 2023 – Deadline for proposals (title, author details, abstracts of no more than 500 words, keywords)</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>1 July 2023 – Editorial decisions on contributors and contributions</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>30 January 2024 – Submission of draft articles</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Spring 2024 – Workshop for contributors to be held at the University of Tartu</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>1 April 2024 – Requests for revisions</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>1 September 2024 – Submission of second drafts</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>1 January 2025 – Submission of the book to the press</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>Please submit your proposal to the editors at </span></span></b><a href="mailto:irina.paert@ut.ee"><b><span><span>irina.paert@ut.ee</span></span></b></a><b><span><span>, </span></span></b><a href="mailto:liina.eek@ut.ee"><b><span><span>liina.eek@ut.ee</span></span></b></a><b><span><span>, and </span></span></b><a href="https:///C:/Users/James/Downloads/james.matthew.white@ut.ee"><b><span><span>james.matthew.white@ut.ee</span></span></b></a></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>Irina Paert (general)</span></span></b><i> </i><span><span>is an associate professor at the School of Theology and Religious Studies, University of Tartu. She has two books: <i>Old Believers, Religious Dissent and Gender in Russia, 1760-1850</i> (Manchester, 2003) and <i>Spiritual Elders: Charisma, Tradition and Orthodoxy in Imperial Russia</i> (DeKalb, 2010). She edited the collective monograph (in Russian) <i>Orthodoxy in the Baltic: Religion, Politics, Education 1840-1930 </i>(Tartu, 2018). She is PI in the research project “Orthodoxy as Solidarity: Conciliar and Popular Orthodoxy in Estonia”, funded by the Estonian Research Council. Email address: <a href="mailto:irina.paert@ut.ee">irina.paert@ut.ee</a>. </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>Liina Eek (sociology) </span></span></b><span><span>is a programme manager in Estonian Research Council and part-time researcher at the University of Tartu, School of Theology and Religious Studies, where she also defended her PhD in 2017 (“Catechesis and Beliefs among Contemporary Estonian-Speaking Orthodox”). Her research focus is contemporary Estonian-speaking Orthodox, their beliefs and views on Orthodoxy and Orthodox theology. She has edited a collection of articles about Orthodoxy in Estonia, <i>Mitut usku Eesti IV. Õigeusu eri</i>. Email address: <a href="mailto:liina.eek@ut.ee">liina.eek@ut.ee</a></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>James M. White (history)</span></span></b><i> </i><span><span>is a research fellow in church history at the University of Tartu. He published his first book,<i> Unity in Faith? Edinoverie, Russian Orthodoxy, and Old Belief, 1800-1918</i>, with Indiana University Press in 2020. His article "Russian Orthodox Monasticism in Riga Diocese, 1881-1917" won the Canadian Association of Slavists Article of the Year Award in 2020. He is the creator and runner of <a href="https:///C:/Users/James/Downloads/www.balticorthodoxy.com">www.balticorthodoxy.com</a>. Contact email address: <a href="mailto:james.matthew.white@ut.ee">james.matthew.white@ut.ee</a></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:james.matthew.white@ut.ee">james.matthew.white@ut.ee</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 17:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680154627898614</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Opportunities Digest – March 29, 2023</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-opportunities-digest-march-29-2023/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find 6 new job opportunities, 2 fellowships, 1 training, 3 awards, 3 grants, 9 Call for Papers, and 9 upcoming conferences/speakers.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 33!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Head of School: School of Humanities and Languages (Full-time,  5 yr. appointment)</h4>



<p>University of New South Wales, Australia</p>



<p>Deadline: April 11, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://external-careers.jobs.unsw.edu.au/cw/en/job/514826/head-of-school-school-of-humanities-and-languages">https://external-careers.jobs.unsw.edu.au/cw/en/job/514826/head-of-school-school-of-humanities-and-languages</a></p>



<h4>Teaching Specialist (Experiential Learning)</h4>



<p>University of Melbourne, Australia (Full-time)</p>



<p>Deadline: April 4, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=8f52a2c49f&amp;e=ea2dc4a949">https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=8f52a2c49f&amp;e=ea2dc4a949</a></p>



<h4>Union Organizer</h4>



<p>Melbourne, Australia</p>



<p>Deadline: April 4, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=57fcd63efc&amp;e=ea2dc4a949">https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=57fcd63efc&amp;e=ea2dc4a949</a></p>



<h4>University Assistant (Prae-doc) (1.5-year commitment, can be extended to 3 years)</h4>



<p>University of Vienna, Austria</p>



<p>Deadline: April 9, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://vdtr.univie.ac.at/en/admission/open-positions/">https://vdtr.univie.ac.at/en/admission/open-positions/</a></p>



<h4>Postdoctoral Research Associate (1-year term, possibility of renewal)</h4>



<p>Princeton University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: April 10, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://csr.princeton.edu/news/2023/apply-postdoc">https://csr.princeton.edu/news/2023/apply-postdoc</a></p>



<h4>Teaching Associate in Islamic Studies (Fixed term, part-time)</h4>



<p>University of Nottingham, UK</p>



<p>Deadline: April 28, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://jobs.nottingham.ac.uk/vacancy.aspx?ref=ARTS103323&amp;fbclid=IwAR18Cqj_AyOSJ2SLKhSkKV6F98RhSNpzbMUe2NGAd05QRkBwngUIRyjoJwU">https://jobs.nottingham.ac.uk/vacancy.aspx?ref=ARTS103323&amp;fbclid=IwAR18Cqj_AyOSJ2SLKhSkKV6F98RhSNpzbMUe2NGAd05QRkBwngUIRyjoJwU</a></p>



<p></p>



<h4>AAR/SBL Job Forum</h4>



<p><a href="https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search">https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search</a></p>



<h2>Fellowships:</h2>



<h4>Feinstein Center for American Jewish History</h4>



<p>Temple University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: March 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12553828/summer-fellowship-feinstein-center-american-jewish-history">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12553828/summer-fellowship-feinstein-center-american-jewish-history</a></p>



<h4>E. H Boundy Ph.D. Fellowship</h4>



<p>University of Exeter, UK</p>



<p>Deadline: June 5<sup>th</sup>, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.jobs.ac.uk/job/CYF535/eh-boundy-phd-studentship-theology-and-religion">https://www.jobs.ac.uk/job/CYF535/eh-boundy-phd-studentship-theology-and-religion</a></p>



<h2>Trainings:</h2>



<h4>Sacred Writes Summer Training Cohort (Online)</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 17, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/8Db5pa1taL">https://t.co/8Db5pa1taL</a></p>



<h2>Grants:</h2>



<h4>Outstanding Applied Research Award</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://rraweb.us10.list-manage.com/track/click?u=55bb1644f88e9457d182915ac&amp;id=a20d9da844&amp;e=c7b3861607">https://rraweb.us10.list-manage.com/track/click?u=55bb1644f88e9457d182915ac&amp;id=a20d9da844&amp;e=c7b3861607</a></p>



<h4>Constant H. Jacquet Research Awards</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://rraweb.us10.list-manage.com/track/click?u=55bb1644f88e9457d182915ac&amp;id=cbd632370a&amp;e=c7b3861607">https://rraweb.us10.list-manage.com/track/click?u=55bb1644f88e9457d182915ac&amp;id=cbd632370a&amp;e=c7b3861607</a></p>



<h4>RRA/SSSR Annual Meeting Travel</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://rraweb.us10.list-manage.com/track/click?u=55bb1644f88e9457d182915ac&amp;id=8c7664e1af&amp;e=c7b3861607">https://rraweb.us10.list-manage.com/track/click?u=55bb1644f88e9457d182915ac&amp;id=8c7664e1af&amp;e=c7b3861607</a></p>



<h2>Awards:</h2>



<h4>Excellence in the Study of Religion</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 12, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/ByvUjmGQ5r">https://t.co/ByvUjmGQ5r</a></p>



<h4>Best First Book in the History of Religions</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 12, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/ByvUjmGQ5r">https://t.co/ByvUjmGQ5r</a></p>



<h4>Religion and the Arts Book Award</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 12, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/ByvUjmGQ5r">https://t.co/ByvUjmGQ5r</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>The Afterlife in Popular Culture: <em>The Ausralasian Journal of Popular Culture</em></h4>



<p>Deadline: October 13, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12556769/cfp-afterlife-popular-culture-special-issue-australasian">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12556769/cfp-afterlife-popular-culture-special-issue-australasian</a></p>



<h4>Emerging Religious Geography of Australia</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="mailto:miriamdb@blanquerna.url.edu">miriamdb@blanquerna.url.edu</a></p>



<h4>Situating Religious Cognition</h4>



<p>Deadline: October 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/journal/religions/special_issues/7Q488424D1">https://www.mdpi.com/journal/religions/special_issues/7Q488424D1</a></p>



<h4>Society for Reformation Research: “Intercultural Reformations”</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 17, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12604235/society-reformation-research-intercultural-reformations">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12604235/society-reformation-research-intercultural-reformations</a></p>



<h4>Open Success!? Research and Publishing in Religion, Film, and Media</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://open-success.uni-graz.at/de/welcome/">https://open-success.uni-graz.at/de/welcome/</a></p>



<h4>Religion in Motion: Between Borders and Belonging</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/CfP-Religion-in-motion-NGG-conference-1.pdf</p>



<h4>New Moderate Narratives in Times of Extremism</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/109329">https://philevents.org/event/show/109329</a></p>



<h4>International Conference on the Middle Ages: Religion in Medieval Urban Europe</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12535058/international-conference-middle-ages-2023-religions-medieval">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12535058/international-conference-middle-ages-2023-religions-medieval</a></p>



<h4>Environmental Endings and Religious Futures</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 19, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://basr.ac.uk/2023/03/03/basr-annual-conference-2023-2/">BASR Annual Conference 2023</a></p>



<h2>Conferences:</h2>



<h4>Caught in the Current: British and Canadian Evangelicals in an Age of Self-Spirituality</h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>Date: April 18, 2023, 3 pm EST</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSc69xZ740Njz1g3y1_K4GljB3GMdfAHeHRpCqVX458Zi0j0cQ/viewform">“Caught in the Current: British and Canadian Evangelicals in an Age of Self-Spirituality” CSSR/CCSR Webinar Registration – Inscription pour le webinaire de la SCÉR/CCSR (google.com)</a></p>



<h4>Beyond the Black/White binary: Research on Race &amp; Congregations</h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>Date: April 13, 2023, 3 pm EST</p>



<h4>Shaping the Anthropos: Cosmologies, Mythologies, and Logics of Subjecthood</h4>



<p>Zoom or Columbia University USA</p>



<p>Date: April 7, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/0Rhvs3vfzl">https://t.co/0Rhvs3vfzl</a></p>



<h4>Colloquium on “Interreligious Interactions in South Asia”</h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>Date: April 3-12 10-11: EST</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Program_Interreligious-Interactions-in-South-Asia-1.pdf">https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Program_Interreligious-Interactions-in-South-Asia-1.pdf</a></p>



<h4>Learning Islam and Craft: Muslim Artisans’ Embodied &amp; Textual Knowledge in Colonial India</h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>Date: April 11, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/sKRb7buMtG">https://t.co/sKRb7buMtG</a></p>



<h4>Postsecular Studies, Literature, and Care</h4>



<p>University of Granada, Spain</p>



<p>Date: May 25-26, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/109513">https://philevents.org/event/show/109513</a></p>



<h4>Open Success!? Research and Publishing in Religion, Film, and Media</h4>



<p>University of Graz, Austria</p>



<p>Date: September 14-15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://open-success.uni-graz.at/de/welcome/">https://open-success.uni-graz.at/de/welcome/</a></p>



<h4>Unsettling Normality</h4>



<p>University Heidelberg, Germany</p>



<p>Deadline: September 20-22, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/109141">https://philevents.org/event/show/109141</a></p>



<h4>2023 Silber-Obrecht Lecture in Interreligious and Interfaith Studies with Francis X. Clooney, S.J.</h4>



<p>Loyola University Maryland, USA</p>



<p>Date: April 25-26, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12553960/2023-silber-obrecht-lecture-interreligious-and-interfaith">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12553960/2023-silber-obrecht-lecture-interreligious-and-interfaith</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680154627898613</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CALL FOR PAPERS | Asian Catholic Materialities</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12635051/call-papers-asian-catholic-materialities</link>
						<dc:creator>Minghua Tay</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-05-02T00:00:00-04:00">May 2, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Singapore</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology, Southeast Asian History / Studies, Anthropology, Urban Design and Planning, East Asian History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><strong>DATE OF EVENT : 30 August - 1 September 2023<br/>VENUE : Hybrid (National University of Singapore &amp; Online via Zoom)<br/>WEBSITE : <a href="https://ari.nus.edu.sg/events/catholic-materialities/" rel="nofollow">https://ari.nus.edu.sg/events/catholic-materialities/</a></strong></p><p><br/><span><strong>CALL FOR PAPERS DEADLINE: 2 MAY 2023</strong></span></p><p>This conference investigates the material forms through which Asian Catholics manifest their liturgical concerns, ecological commitment, and institutional presence, and how these material translations and negotiations participate in the making of contemporary Asia.</p><p>Historically, Asian Catholics have built outstanding hospitals, schools, and churches which have reshaped the visual landscape and material flows of Asian social spaces (Arimura 2014, Coomans 2018, Hudd 2019). Often, Asian Catholics and their objects have questioned the ways in which their surrounding society related to and conceptualized the material world. During the multi-secular Chinese rite controversy (1582-1936), Catholics have challenged the ways East Asian authorities materially perform a wide range of ritual practices which structured their political order (Mungello 1994).</p><p>But under different circumstances, Asian Catholics have also integrated and preserved indigenous understandings of the material world and its agency (Bovensiepen 2018). In parallel, Catholic networks and institutions have played a major role in introducing and circulating new knowledge and techniques about physics, botanic, agriculture, chemistry and medicine which have questioned the ways Asian societies relate to the material environment (Galipeau 2021).</p><p>Today, Asian Catholics continue to materially translate their social presence, ecological concerns, economic efforts, and religious commitments. Through the erection of new sites of devotions, cemeteries, and public institutions, Asian Catholics mobilize particular materials and designs to make their priorities tangible. Echoing to Global Catholicism conversations and elaborating on their own locally-informed cultural resources, Asian Catholics join actions to prevent climate change and preserve the environment (Palmer 2015). And the material experience, concerns, and sensibilities of Asian Catholics have far reaching influences – they participate in the contemporary production of Asian societies and Global Catholicism.</p><p>In dialogue with the material turn in religious studies and the <a href="https://www.isac-research.org/" rel="nofollow">Initiative for the Study of Asian Catholics</a>, this hybrid conference probes conceptions of Catholic materialities in contemporary Asia (Fleming 2014; Reinhardt 2016). While considering the relevance of geography, history, politics, and economy in the study of the material ideologies of Asian Catholics (Chambon 2020), the conference seeks to question the ways in which Asian Catholics participate in the material production of contemporary Asia and world Catholicism. Without essentializing and homogenizing Asian Catholic beliefs and practices, the conference will investigate ways to conceptualize Catholic cultural productions and materialities and their relations with other Asian religious traditions, economic flows, and political ideologies.</p><p>Selected papers should address one or more of the following questions:</p><ul><li>What are the materially informed practices and discourses that Asian Catholics promote today? Which worldviews about the material environment, the body, and human sociability do they encourage?</li><li>How are the architectural features of Asian Catholic hospitals, schools, cemeteries, and churches, producing various forms of Asian Catholicism and inter-religious coexistences?</li><li>Who are the individual and institutional actors involved in the production and circulations of Asian Catholic objects? How are the material translation of Asian Catholicism intersecting with on-going negotiations of gender ideologies, class, and racial identities?</li><li>How are Asian Catholics taking parts in economic flows as well as in responses to ecological crisis and climate change?</li><li>How are digital tools impacting the ways in which Asian Catholics relate to the material world and the body? How are online technologies mobilized to spread Catholic understandings of the nature?</li><li>To what extent does the flow of material objects participate in and shape the worldwide integration of Asian Catholics into global economy and world Catholicism? What are the objects circulating in and out of Asian Catholic networks? How do they shape economic flows and religious aesthetics beyond Asian Catholicism?</li></ul><p><br/>BIBLIOGRAPHY</p><p>Arimura, Rie. 2014. “The Catholic Architecture of Early Modern Japan: Between Adaptation and Christian Identity.” Japan Review 27 (27): 53–76.<br/>Judith M. 2018. <a href="https://anchor.fm/isac06/episodes/Episode---7---Judith-Bovensiepen-on-her-book---The-Land-of-Gold-Post-Conflict-Recovery-and-Cultural-Revival-in-Independent-Timor-Leste-e19094q" rel="nofollow">The Land of Gold.</a> Cornell University Press.<br/>Chambon, Michel. 2020. Making Christ Present in China: Actor-Network Theory and the Anthropology of Christianity. Cham: Palgrave Macmillan.<br/>Coomans, Thomas. 2018. “East Meets West on the Construction Site. Churches in China, 1840s-1930s.” Construction History: Journal of the Construction History Group 33 (2): 63–84.<br/>Fleming, Benjamin J. 2014. Material Culture and Asian Religions: Text, Image, Object. New York: Routledge, Taylor &amp; Francis Group.<br/>Galipeau, Brendan A. 2021. “Free in the Mountains or Home in the Vineyard: Institutional Changes in Agriculture and Negotiating Between Contract Farm Labour and Valuable Fungi Collection in Tibet.” Journal of Agrarian Change 21 (1): 143–59.<br/>Hudd, Sandra. 2019. “Revisiting Christian Missionaries in the Straits Settlements: Blurring the Boundaries Between Empire, Mission and Development.” Journal of the Malaysian Branch of the Royal Asiatic Society 92 (1): 21–39.<br/>Mungello, D. E. 1994. The Chinese Rites Controversy: Its History and Meaning. Nettetal: Steyler Verlag.<br/>Palmer, Lisa. Water Politics and Spiritual Ecology Custom, Environmental Governance and Development. New York: Routledge, 2015.<br/>Reinhardt, Bruno. “‘Don’t Make It a Doctrine’: Material Religion, Transcendence, Critique.” Anthropological Theory 16, no. 1 (2016): 75-97.</p><p><br/><strong>SUBMISSION OF PROPOSALS</strong></p><p>Paper proposals should include a title, an abstract (300 words maximum), and a brief personal biography of 150 words for submission by <strong>2 May 2023</strong>. Please also include a statement confirming that your paper has not been published or committed elsewhere, and that you are willing to revise your paper for potential inclusion in an edited book publication (in collaboration with the workshop organizers and other participants).</p><p>Please submit your proposal using the provided <a href="https://ari.nus.edu.sg/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/CFP-Proposal-Form-Catholic-Materialities-4.docx" rel="nofollow">template</a> to <a href="mailto:minghua.tay@nus.edu.sg">minghua.tay@nus.edu.sg</a>. Successful applicants will be notified by the <strong>end of May</strong>. Panel presenters will be required to submit drafts of papers (4,000-6,000) words by <strong>15 August 2023</strong>. These drafts will be circulated to fellow panelists and discussants in advance. Drafts need not be fully polished. Indeed, we expect that presenters will be open to feedback from fellow participants.</p><p>This hybrid conference will accommodate both in-person and online participants, as needed. If possible, the Asia Research Institute will provide overseas participants with full or partial airfare as well as three nights of accommodation. Please indicate in the proposal form if you require funding support.</p><p><br/><strong>CONFERENCE CONVENOR</strong></p><p><strong>Dr Michel Chambon </strong><br/>Asia Research Institute, National University of Singapore</p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><strong>Ms Minghua TAY</strong><br/>Asia Research Institute, National University of Singapore<br/>AS8 Level 7, 10 Kent Ridge Crescent, Singapore 119260<br/>Email: <a href="mailto:minghua.tay@nus.edu.sg">minghua.tay@nus.edu.sg</a><br/>Tel: (65) 6516 4224<br/>Fax: (65) 6779 1428</p><p>URL: <a href="https://ari.nus.edu.sg/upcoming-events/" rel="nofollow">https://ari.nus.edu.sg/upcoming-events/</a></p></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 20:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680068236384637</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Confraternities in the Early Modern World - CFP for sessions at 16th Century Studies Conference (Baltimore - 26-29 October 2023)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12615031/confraternities-early-modern-world-cfp-sessions-16th-century</link>
						<dc:creator>Nicholas Terpstra</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-04-10T00:00:00-04:00">April 10, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Maryland</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Early Modern History and Period Studies, Cultural History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Social History / Studies, World History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The <b>Society for Confraternity Studies </b>(SCS) invites proposals for individual papers or sessions at the 2023 annual meeting of the Sixteenth Century Society and Conference (SCSC), <b>26-29 October 2023</b> at the <b>Renaissance Baltimore Harborplace Hotel</b>.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>We are particularly interested in papers and panels that deal with the following themes: </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><i><span><span>Confraternities in the Development of Global Catholicism </span></span></i><span><span>(e.g., confraternal sociability, ritual, charity, and spirituality in Asian, African, and American settings)</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><i><span><span>Confraternities as Brokers of Collective Identities</span></span></i><span><span> (including occupational, gendered, and ‘national’ confraternities, indigenous confraternities, confraternities of the enslaved, etc.)</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><i><span><span>Artistic, Musical, or Theatrical Patronage in Confraternities</span></span></i></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><i><span><span>Open Topics</span></span></i></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Papers are limited to 20 minutes and should not have been previously published or presented at a different scholarly meeting.  Panels normally include 3 presenters.  All presenters must register for the conference if accepted.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>If you would like to submit a paper or panel or need additional information, please contact:  Nicholas Terpstra (<a href="mailto:nicholas.terpstra@utoronto.ca"><span>nicholas.terpstra@utoronto.ca</span></a>);  we’re happy to work with you as you refine your proposal.  The deadline for submission (via email) of paper and panel proposals is <b>10 April 2023</b>.  The SCS will then review papers and panels and inform applicants of its decisions before the SCSC deadline (17 April 2023).</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><i><span><span>Paper </span></span></i><span><span>proposals should include:</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span>Paper Title</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Abstract (150 words maximum)</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Presenter’s name, affiliation, and email address</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Presenter’s biography or brief CV (3-4 sentences, maximum 150 words, including rank and most important publications or evidence of scholarship)</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Whether audiovisual equipment is needed and what kind</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Whether you wish to have your paper considered for the Carl Meyer prize</span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><i><span><span>Panel</span></span></i><span><span> proposals should include:</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span>Panel title</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Abstract of the panel (300 words maximum)</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Organizer’s name, affiliation, and email address</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Chair / commentator’s name, affiliation, and email address</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>List of papers / presenters with relevant paper proposals, including all of the information noted above for each individual paper in the panel.</span></span></span></span></span></li></ul></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Nicholas Terpstra, Professor of History, University of Toronto</p><p>President, Society for Confraternity Studies</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:nicholas.terpstra@utoronto.ca">nicholas.terpstra@utoronto.ca</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 19:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680068236384636</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>35th  Annual Symposium on Jewish Civilization:    The Jewish Diaspora and  the  Promised Land</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12626824/35th-annual-symposium-jewish-civilization-jewish-diaspora-and</link>
						<dc:creator>Leonard Greenspoon</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-05-01T00:00:00-04:00">May 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The Klutznick Chair (Creighton University), the  Kripke Center (Creighton University), the  Harris  Center  (University  of  Nebraska-Lincoln), and  the Schwalb  Center (University  of  Nebraska at Omaha) announce  their 35th  Annual Symposium  on Jewish Civlization, October  22-23, 2023,  in Omaha, Nebraska.   The  title is "The  Jewish Diaspora and the  Promised Land: Origins, Developments,  Future Prospects."</p><p>Taken together, accepted  presentations will cover many time periods from  the  biblical  era to  the modern world and a range of media,  genres,  and approaches.</p><p>Support for presenters'  transportation  and accommodation will  be  provided.  Presenters  will also submit a written version  of  their presentation for  an  edited, thematic volume as part  of  the  Studies in Jewish Civilization Series  (Purdue  University  Press).</p><p>Proposals should contain a 250-word  abstract and  a CV  and be submitted by  May 1 to  Leonard  Greenspoon,  Klutznick Chair, at  <a href="mailto:ljgrn@creighton.edu">ljgrn@creighton.edu</a>.</p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Leonard  Greenspoon</p><p>Klutznick Chair  in  Jewish Civilization</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ljgrn@creighton.edu">ljgrn@creighton.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 19:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680068236384635</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
