<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 21:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 21:57:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ February 29, 2024] CFP for conference or similar: International Conference &quot;Environmental Ethics and Vulnerability in Western and/or Buddhist Philosophy&quot;</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/114690</link>
						<description><p>Call for abstracts:</p>
<p>This conference aims to explore new paths in environmental ethics by bringing into dialogue Western and Buddhist philosophical traditions. Global issues such as environmental ones require global answers that need to elaborate a wide perspective.</p>
<p>Given the popularity of Buddhism as well as the growth of Buddhist studies in the West, this conference looks for intercultural contributions on environmental ethics that embrace both Western and Buddhist philosophical traditions.</p>
<p>In this respect, vulnerability may play a key role in bridging East and West. Its prominent position in contemporary ethics and global bioethics could contribute to transcending the view of a self-referential modern subjectivity in favor of a fully relational conception of subjectivity. This conception aligns closely with the Buddhist perspective on reality as the interconnectedness of everything that exists.</p>
<p>The main objective of this conference is to provide a platform for bringing together scholars in environmental ethics, vulnerability, and global bioethics from both Western and Buddhist philosophical traditions, fostering potential dialogues between them. Contributions from either the Western or Buddhist perspective alone are also welcome.</p>
<p>Possible topics for papers can include, but are not limited to: environmental ethics in Western or Buddhist philosophical traditions, comparative perspectives on environmental ethics between Western and Buddhist philosophical traditions, historical encounters between Western and Buddhist philosophical traditions regarding environmental ethics, vulnerability and global bioethics from either the Western or Buddhist perspectives, comparative perspectives on vulnerability and global bioethics between Western and Buddhist philosophical traditions, future challenges in environmental ethics, vulnerability and global bioethics.</p>
<p>Keynote speakers: Henk ten Have (Duquesne University, USA), Marion Hourdequin (Colorado College, USA), Claudia Navarini (European University of Rome, Italy), William Edelglass (Emerson College, USA), Benedetta Giovanola (University of Macerata, Italy), Janet Donohoe (University of West Georgia, USA), Graham Parkes (University of Vienna, Austria). </p>
<p>The conference is funded by the European Commission through its Marie Skłodowska-Curie Actions  and sponsored by the following academic societies: International Society for Environmental Ethics (ISEE), International Association for Environmental Philosophy (IAEP), Italian Society for Moral Philosophy (SIFM), International Association for Education in Ethics (IAEE), XXV World Congress of Philosophy Rome 2024 (WCP 2024), Society for Asian and Comparative Philosophy (SACP).</p>
<p>Abstracts (of max 300 words) and CV should be submitted to: Laura Langone (laura.langone@univr.it) and Carlo Chiurco (carlo.chiurco@univr.it). Abstracts can be submitted in either English or Italian.</p>
<p>In the email subject line please write: Environmental Ethics and Vulnerability Conference.</p>
<p>Deadline for proposals: 29 February 2024.</p>
<p>Notification of acceptance: by 10 May 2024.</p>
<p>_____________________________________________________________</p>
<p>(Versione italiana)</p>
"Etica ambientale e vulnerabilità in dialogo tra Occidente e Oriente"
<p>Call for abstracts:</p>
<p>La natura globale dei problemi ambientali richiede risposte globali e ad ampio spettro. Data la popolarità del buddismo e la diffusione dei corsi universitari dedicati allo studio del buddismo in Occidente, la conferenza invita a proporre contributi a carattere interculturale intorno ai temi dell’etica ambientale che abbraccino le filosofie occidentali e buddiste.</p>
<p>In questo contesto, la vulnerabilità appare come una categoria-ponte capace di svolgere un ruolo chiave nel dialogo tra Est e Ovest. La sua posizione di rilievo nell’etica contemporanea e nella bioetica globale potrebbe contribuire a superare la visione di una soggettività moderna autoreferenziale a favore di una concezione compiutamente relazionale, in armonia con la visione buddista della realtà come interconnessione di tutto ciò che è.</p>
<p>L’obiettivo principale di questa conferenza è favorire il dialogo tra le tradizioni filosofiche occidentali e quelle buddiste sui temi dell’etica ambientale, della vulnerabilità e della bioetica globale. Sono benvenuti anche contributi che esplorino questi temi esclusivamente dalle prospettive occidentali oppure da quelle buddiste.</p>
<p>Possibili argomenti: etica ambientale nelle filosofie occidentali oppure nelle filosofie buddiste, dialogo sull’etica ambientale tra le filosofie occidentali e buddiste, storia degli incontri tra le filosofie occidentali e buddiste sull'etica ambientale, vulnerabilità e bioetica globale nelle filosofie occidentali oppure nelle filosofie buddiste, dialogo sulla vulnerabilità e la bioetica globale tra le filosofie occidentali e quelle buddiste, sfide future dell’etica ambientale, della vulnerabilità e della bioetica globale.</p>
<p>Keynote speakers: Henk ten Have (Duquesne University, USA), Marion Hourdequin (Colorado College, USA), Claudia Navarini (Università Europea di Roma, Italia), William Edelglass (Emerson College, USA), Benedetta Giovanola (Università degli Studi di Macerata, Italia), Janet Donohoe (University of West Georgia, USA), Graham Parkes (University of Vienna, Austria).</p>
<p>La conferenza è finanziata dalla Commissione Europea attraverso i fondi Marie Skłodowska-Curie Actions  ed è patrocinata dalle seguenti associazioni accademiche: International Society for Environmental Ethics (ISEE), International Association for Environmental Philosophy (IAEP), Società Italiana di Filosofia Morale (SIFM), International Association for Education in Ethics (IAEE), XXV World Congress of Philosophy Rome 2024 (WCP 2024), Society for Asian and Comparative Philosophy (SACP).</p>
<p>Abstract di massimo 300 parole e un curriculum vitae devono essere inviati a Laura Langone (laura.langone@univr.it) e Carlo Chiurco (carlo.chiurco@univr.it). Gli abstract possono essere inviati in inglese oppure in italiano.</p>
<p>Nell’oggetto della mail bisogna scrivere: Conferenza etica ambientale e vulnerabilità.</p>
<p>Scadenza per le proposte: 29 febbraio 2024.</p>
<p>Notifica di accettazione: entro il 10 maggio 2024.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 05:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1695101828401787</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ October 24, 2024 -  October 26, 2024] Conference or similar: International Conference &quot;Environmental Ethics and Vulnerability in Western and/or Buddhist Philosophy&quot;</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/114686</link>
						<description>Venue: Cà Vignal 3, Str. le Grazie, 15, 37134 <br/><br/><p>Call for abstracts:</p>
<p>This conference aims to explore new paths in environmental ethics by bringing into dialogue Western and Buddhist philosophical traditions. Global issues such as environmental ones require global answers that need to elaborate a wide perspective.</p>
<p>Given the popularity of Buddhism as well as the growth of Buddhist studies in the West, this conference looks for intercultural contributions on environmental ethics that embrace both Western and Buddhist philosophical traditions.</p>
<p>In this respect, vulnerability may play a key role in bridging East and West. Its prominent position in contemporary ethics and global bioethics could contribute to transcending the view of a self-referential modern subjectivity in favor of a fully relational conception of subjectivity. This conception aligns closely with the Buddhist perspective on reality as the interconnectedness of everything that exists.</p>
<p>The main objective of this conference is to provide a platform for bringing together scholars in environmental ethics, vulnerability, and global bioethics from both Western and Buddhist philosophical traditions, fostering potential dialogues between them. Contributions from either the Western or Buddhist perspective alone are also welcome.</p>
<p>Possible topics for papers can include, but are not limited to: environmental ethics in Western or Buddhist philosophical traditions, comparative perspectives on environmental ethics between Western and Buddhist philosophical traditions, historical encounters between Western and Buddhist philosophical traditions regarding environmental ethics, vulnerability and global bioethics from either the Western or Buddhist perspectives, comparative perspectives on vulnerability and global bioethics between Western and Buddhist philosophical traditions, future challenges in environmental ethics, vulnerability and global bioethics.</p>
<p>Keynote speakers: Henk ten Have (Duquesne University, USA), Marion Hourdequin (Colorado College, USA), Claudia Navarini (European University of Rome, Italy), William Edelglass (Emerson College, USA), Benedetta Giovanola (University of Macerata, Italy), Janet Donohoe (University of West Georgia, USA), Graham Parkes (University of Vienna, Austria). </p>
<p>The conference is funded by the European Commission through its Marie Skłodowska-Curie Actions and sponsored by the following academic societies: International Society for Environmental Ethics (ISEE), International Association for Environmental Philosophy (IAEP), Italian Society for Moral Philosophy (SIFM), International Association for Education in Ethics (IAEE), XXV World Congress of Philosophy Rome 2024 (WCP 2024), Society for Asian and Comparative Philosophy (SACP).</p>
<p>Abstracts (of max 300 words) and CV should be submitted to: Laura Langone (laura.langone@univr.it) and Carlo Chiurco (carlo.chiurco@univr.it). Abstracts can be submitted in either English or Italian.</p>
<p>In the email subject line please write: Environmental Ethics and Vulnerability Conference.</p>
<p>Deadline for proposals: 29 February 2024.</p>
<p>Notification of acceptance: by 10 May 2024.</p>
<p>_____________________________________________________________</p>
<p>(Versione italiana)</p>
"Etica ambientale e vulnerabilità in dialogo tra Occidente e Oriente"
<p>Call for abstracts:</p>
<p>La natura globale dei problemi ambientali richiede risposte globali e ad ampio spettro. Data la popolarità del buddismo e la diffusione dei corsi universitari dedicati allo studio del buddismo in Occidente, la conferenza invita a proporre contributi a carattere interculturale intorno ai temi dell’etica ambientale che abbraccino le filosofie occidentali e buddiste.</p>
<p>In questo contesto, la vulnerabilità appare come una categoria-ponte capace di svolgere un ruolo chiave nel dialogo tra Est e Ovest. La sua posizione di rilievo nell’etica contemporanea e nella bioetica globale potrebbe contribuire a superare la visione di una soggettività moderna autoreferenziale a favore di una concezione compiutamente relazionale, in armonia con la visione buddista della realtà come interconnessione di tutto ciò che è.</p>
<p>L’obiettivo principale di questa conferenza è favorire il dialogo tra le tradizioni filosofiche occidentali e quelle buddiste sui temi dell’etica ambientale, della vulnerabilità e della bioetica globale. Sono benvenuti anche contributi che esplorino questi temi esclusivamente dalle prospettive occidentali oppure da quelle buddiste.</p>
<p>Possibili argomenti: etica ambientale nelle filosofie occidentali oppure nelle filosofie buddiste, dialogo sull’etica ambientale tra le filosofie occidentali e buddiste, storia degli incontri tra le filosofie occidentali e buddiste sull'etica ambientale, vulnerabilità e bioetica globale nelle filosofie occidentali oppure nelle filosofie buddiste, dialogo sulla vulnerabilità e la bioetica globale tra le filosofie occidentali e quelle buddiste, sfide future dell’etica ambientale, della vulnerabilità e della bioetica globale.</p>
<p>Keynote speakers: Henk ten Have (Duquesne University, USA), Marion Hourdequin (Colorado College, USA), Claudia Navarini (Università Europea di Roma, Italia), William Edelglass (Emerson College, USA), Benedetta Giovanola (Università degli Studi di Macerata, Italia), Janet Donohoe (University of West Georgia, USA), Graham Parkes (University of Vienna, Austria).</p>
<p>La conferenza è finanziata dalla Commissione Europea attraverso i fondi Marie Skłodowska-Curie Actions  ed è patrocinata dalle seguenti associazioni accademiche: International Society for Environmental Ethics (ISEE), International Association for Environmental Philosophy (IAEP), Società Italiana di Filosofia Morale (SIFM), International Association for Education in Ethics (IAEE), XXV World Congress of Philosophy Rome 2024 (WCP 2024), Society for Asian and Comparative Philosophy (SACP).</p>
<p>Abstract di massimo 300 parole e un curriculum vitae devono essere inviati a Laura Langone (laura.langone@univr.it) e Carlo Chiurco (carlo.chiurco@univr.it). Gli abstract possono essere inviati in inglese oppure in italiano.</p>
<p>Nell’oggetto della mail bisogna scrivere: Conferenza etica ambientale e vulnerabilità.</p>
<p>Scadenza per le proposte: 29 febbraio 2024.</p>
<p>Notifica di accettazione: entro il 10 maggio 2024.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 05:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1695101828401786</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>International Conference &quot;Play, Masks and Make-believe: Ritual Representations&quot;</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/09/14/international-conference-play-masks-and-make-believe-ritual-representations</link>
						<dc:creator>communication@lcir.co.uk</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Monday, September 18, 2023 - 12:16pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>London Centre for Interdisciplinary Research</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:masks@lcir.co.uk">masks@lcir.co.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/ethnicity-and-national-identity">ethnicity and national identity</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/international-conferences">international conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>November 5, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p lang="en-US" align="justify" xml:lang="en-US">Through the centuries, humans have often shaped their social life by fictional moments and by taking part in fictional events: carnivals, representations, role plays, society plays, structured and semi-structured collective and singular moments where strictly coded contexts organize specific worlds and cultural dimensions. Play, in its wide acception and in its nature of artificial and coded mechanism, reflects historically the symbolic work by which human societies have elaborated, explained and organized the world. Play, fiction, representation and human performance are crucial moments in which categories such as reckoning, planning, ability, strategy, but also turbolence, improvisation, discard and change, are concerned. By organizing fictional moments, plays, rituals and collective experiences, humans bet on the meaning of their social groups. In play and representation, as liminal moments, social groups define relationships, roles, functions and identities. Inside representational and fictional performances, 'normal' time is suspended and a new space of experience is defined. Liminal situations produce the possibility of changes, of new and different symbolic experiences. </p>
<p lang="en-US" align="justify" xml:lang="en-US">By exploring the nature of play and of fictional moments of representation, this conference aims to shape a deeper look into different aspects of an anthropology of performance. A focus will be put on how different discourses, disciplines and art forms interact in the definition of a dynamics of social representations where human experience can be analyzed and discussed. </p>
<p>Proposals are welcome from different research fields such as Literary Studies, Film Studies, History of Theatre, Psychoanalys, Anthropology, Art History, Philosophy, Historiography and Sociology.</p>
<p>Papers are invited on topics related, but not limited, to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Theatre, historical perspectives on representation, representations in time</li>
<li>Carnival</li>
<li>Rituals of remembrance as social representations</li>
<li>Ritual forms of representation</li>
<li>Art forms as social moments of rituality</li>
<li>Masks and masquerades</li>
<li>Cultural history of representation</li>
<li>Anthropology of experience</li>
<li>Time, rituality and representation</li>
<li>Rituals and collectivity</li>
<li>Sacred representations</li>
<li>Representation in society, representation as a social act</li>
<li>Anthropology of performance: meaning and social aspects of representation</li>
<li>Symbolic meanings in representations</li>
</ul>
<p>Paper proposals up to 250 words and a brief biographical note should be sent <strong> </strong>to: <strong><a href="mailto:masks@lcir.co.uk" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">masks@lcir.co.uk</a></strong><em>.</em></p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 06:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1695101828401785</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>International Conference  on Cross-Religious Exchanges in Eastern Indian Cultural and Literary Traditions</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/09/12/international-conference-on-cross-religious-exchanges-in-eastern-indian-cultural-and</link>
						<dc:creator>DEBANJALI ROY</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Monday, September 18, 2023 - 10:31am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>School of Language &amp; Literature, Kalinga Institute of Industrial Technology-Deemed to be University, Bhubaneswar, India</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:conference.ksll@kiit.ac.in">conference.ksll@kiit.ac.in</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/international-conferences">international conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/online-conferences">online conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>October 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>KIIT School of Language &amp; Literature (KSLL)</strong> invites papers for the international conference on the topic of <strong>“Cross-Religious Exchanges in Eastern Indian Cultural and Literary Traditions”</strong> to be held on <strong>February 15-17, 2024</strong> in the <strong>hybrid mode</strong> at Kalinga Institute of Industrial Technology-Deemed to be University. The conference aims to explore the interactions among religion, philosophy, and literary and cultural texts from the Eastern and North Eastern part of the Indian subcontinent.<br/>This conference will look into instances of the cross-cultural and cross-religious interactions reflected in literary and cultural texts of Odisha, Bengal, Jharkhand, Bihar, seven sisters of the North East, Bangladesh, Bhutan, and Nepal. We welcome papers that explore the following themes, but are not limited to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Intersections of religion, philosophy, and literature in the Eastern part of India</li>
<li>Literary Projections of the indigenous myths</li>
<li>Intertextuality between Eastern Indian literature and religious scripture</li>
<li>Religious hybridity as a form of resistance</li>
<li>Transcending religious identity in literary and cultural texts</li>
<li>Indigenous knowledge system and literature</li>
<li>Indigenisation of formalised and institutionalised religious forms</li>
<li>Religion as a tool to proclaim identity</li>
<li>Interaction between religion and biography in the eastern region</li>
<li>Literary genres facilitating dialogues among different religions</li>
<li>Going beyond colonial ideology in the light of Eastern Indian worldview</li>
<li>Interface between religion and Eastern Indian arts</li>
<li>Nature, culture and religion</li>
<li>Cross-Religious exchanges and the cyberspace</li>
<li>Contribution of the global market to the formation of religious and cultural hybridity</li>
<li>The Jagannath mythology in Eastern Indian literature</li>
</ul>
<p>Important Dates &amp; Submission Guidelines<br/>●Abstracts should be no longer than 250 words and should include the paper’s title, objective / purpose, method, novelty / originality of expected finding(s) besides author’s name, affiliation, and email address. The deadline for abstract submission is <strong>October 15, 2023</strong>.<br/>●Please send your abstracts to [<a href="mailto:conference.ksll@kiit.ac.in">conference.ksll@kiit.ac.in</a>]. Selected papers will be considered for publication in proceedings to be published by a reputed international publisher. Some of the selected papers may be considered for inclusion in the inaugural issue of bi-annual journal named KIIT Journal of Language, Literature and Culture.<br/>●Notification of acceptance of abstracts will be sent by <strong>November 15, 2023</strong>.<br/>●Last day of registration with full payment is <strong>November 30, 2023</strong>.<br/>●The deadline for full paper submission is <strong>December 31, 2023</strong>.<br/>Registration Fee Details:<br/>●₹3000/ (Indian / Nepalese / Bhutanese / Bangladeshi faculty participants)<br/>●$ 250 (International participants)<br/>●₹2000 (Indian Students / Researchers)</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 10:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1695101828401784</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ November 15, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Fifth Meeting of the Critical Genealogies Workshop</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/114590</link>
						<description><p>The Critical Genealogies Workshop provides a space of collaboration and experimentation for scholars who deploy genealogy in order to investigate problematizations, possibilizations, and assemblies of the contemporary. The purpose of the event is to present in-progress genealogical work so as to thematize and reflect on larger questions of research design, strategy, and structure and practical questions about conducting genealogical research.</p>
<p><br/></p>
<p>We seek submissions from scholars from any disciplinary or field background who deploy genealogical methods and practices in their work: previous events have included scholars from Philosophy, Political Science, History, Media Studies, and other backgrounds. Approaching genealogy largely through the lens of Foucault and Nietzsche, we also welcome other genealogical approaches of diverse inspiration. Above all, we endeavor to take seriously Foucault’s challenges to inherited practices of philosophical critique by taking up genealogy to interrogate the history of the present.</p>
<p><br/></p>
<p>The format of the workshop involves pre-circulation of in-progress work. This will be a pre-read event; participants are expected to share their papers by mid-March 2024 and are expected to read papers from other participants prior to arrival. Concurrent sessions will feature paper presentations consisting of two sets of brief commentaries (5 minutes each) followed by group discussion (35-40 minutes). </p>
<p><br/></p>
<p>Please send an abstract of no more than 750 words in “.pdf” format to criticalgenealogies@gmail.com by November 15, 2023. Indicate “Critical Genealogies Workshop submission” in the subject line. Decisions will be conveyed within one month of the deadline. If you require an earlier decision in order to secure funding, please write to Verena Erlenbusch-Anderson (vrlnbsch@memphis.edu) and Colin Koopman (koopman@uoregon.edu).</p>
<p><br/></p>
<p>Logistical information about accommodations &amp; transportation will be provided with program decisions. There will be no registration fees associated with this event, and attendees will need to fund their own travel, lodging, and (most) meals. To facilitate interaction in the evening after sessions, attendees are encouraged to stay at the conference hotel, details of which will be announced with program decisions.</p>
<p><br/></p>
<p>For further information see our website (https://sites.google.com/view/criticalgenealogiesworkshop/home) or contact CGW co-founders Verena Erlenbusch-Anderson (vrlnbsch@memphis.edu) and Colin Koopman (koopman@uoregon.edu).</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 05:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1694756231685653</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ April 26, 2024 -  April 27, 2024] Conference or similar: Fifth Meeting of the Critical Genealogies Workshop</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/114586</link>
						<description>Venue: Hall of Languages<br/><br/><p>The Critical Genealogies Workshop provides a space of collaboration and experimentation for scholars who deploy genealogy in order to investigate problematizations, possibilizations, and assemblies of the contemporary. The purpose of the event is to present in-progress genealogical work so as to thematize and reflect on larger questions of research design, strategy, and structure and practical questions about conducting genealogical research.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 05:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1694756231685652</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Critical Essays on &quot;The Righteous Gemstones&quot;</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/09/10/critical-essays-on-the-righteous-gemstones</link>
						<dc:creator>JefferyDennis</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, September 14, 2023 - 4:42pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Jeffery P. Dennis/Minnesota State University, Mankato</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:jeffery.dennis@mnsu.edu">jeffery.dennis@mnsu.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/fan-studies-and-fandom">fan studies and fandom</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/film-and-television">film and television</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/gender-studies-and-sexuality">gender studies and sexuality</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>November 30, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><em>The Righteous Gemstones</em> is a dark comedy about a world-famous megachurch pastor; his three children, who assist with the ministry; and various associates, extended family members, and antagonists.  Each season (2019, 2022, 2023) is self-contained and intricately structured, inviting scene by scene and even frame by frame analysis. Typically the family faces two interconnected outside threats; parallel father-son crises featuring patriarch Eli, his eldest son, and his grandchildren; parallel relationship crises involving the other children and their partners; and a disruptive force.</p>
<p>Abstracts for 5000-7000 word essays are invited for an edited collection on <em>The Righteous Gemstones</em>. Essays should be accessible to both a scholarly and a general audience. Suggested topics include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Sin, forgiveness, and redemption</li>
<li>Deviance and criminality</li>
<li>Mental illness</li>
<li>Sexual identity and coming out</li>
<li>The importance of place</li>
<li>Death and resurrection</li>
<li>Musical backgrounds</li>
<li>Horror and science-fiction tropes</li>
<li>The paranormal and divine intervention</li>
<li>Time and atemporality</li>
<li>Plot misdirections</li>
<li>Fan fiction and fan art</li>
</ul>
<p>Submit a 250-500 word abstract and a 50 word author biography to Dr. Jeffery P. Dennis, Department of Criminal Justice, Minnesota State University, Mankato.  Email: <a href="mailto:jeffery.dennis@mnsu.edu">jeffery.dennis@mnsu.edu</a></p>
<p>Deadline for abstract submission: November 30, 2023</p>
<p>Deadline for submission of selected papers: March 1, 2024</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 21:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1694756231685651</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Bishop Street Journal: &quot;Faith in the Contemporary World&quot;</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/09/08/bishop-street-journal-faith-in-the-contemporary-world</link>
						<dc:creator>ZBourgeois</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, September 14, 2023 - 4:08pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>The Department of Theological Studies at Concordia University</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:bishopstreetconcordia@gmail.com">bishopstreetconcordia@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/graduate-conferences">graduate conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>December 6, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Concordia University's Department of Theological Studies proudly presents the Call for Papers for volume three of the Bishop STreet Journal. This edition's theme is "Faith <em>in</em> the Contemporary World."</p>
<p>In the wake of the COVID-19 pandemic, “faith” has been challenged. Faith in our institutions, in our neighbors, and in the world at large has been questioned or outright abandoned by some, as evidenced by the coups, protests and social media campaigns of conspiracy theorists we’ve witnessed since lockdowns began in the spring of 2020 - and we may also say that faith has been gained in such cases. although in manipulated and weaponized forms. However, faith has also stayed strong as well; a 2022 report found that generosity increased during the pandemic [1], with the lead researcher telling The Washington Post in an interview that such results restore one’s “faith in humanity.” [2]</p>
<p>Bishop Street is interested in articles and creative works that explore faith - its rise and decline - in our post-pandemic world. Subjects may include theological reflection on contemporary religious communities, politics, philosophy, technology, and art, with interdisciplinary perspectives being more than welcomed. Works outside of this theme that are theological in scope will also be considered.</p>
<p>Traditional academic articles should be 5,000-8,000 words long, Times New Roman, 12 pt, using the Chicago Style 17th Edition, Footnotes - Bibliography reference system. Bishop Street accepts submissions in English and French. Authors and artists are requested to submit their work to the editorial team at <a href="mailto:bishopstreetconcordia@gmail.com">bishopstreetconcordia@gmail.com</a> by December 6th. A confirmation email will be sent to the authors whose article has been selected. Articles are peer reviewed, in a double blind process.</p>
<p>[1] See Ariel Fridman, Rachel Gershon, and Ayelet Gneezy, "Increased generosity under COVID-19 threat, Scientific Reports 12, 4886 (2022). <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-022-08748-2">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-022-08748-2</a>.</p>
<p>[2] Tara Parker-Pope, "Did the pandemic make us all a little more generous?" The Washington Post, last modified December 1st, 2022. <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/wellness/2022/12/01/charity-giving-pandemic-generosity/">https://www.washingtonpost.com/wellness/2022/12/01/charity-giving-pandem...</a></p>
<p> </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 16:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1694756231685650</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Esotericism, Occultism, and Magic at Southwest Popular/American Culture Association, Feb 21-24, Albuquerque, New Mexico</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/09/08/esotericism-occultism-and-magic-at-southwest-popularamerican-culture-association-feb</link>
						<dc:creator>georgejsieg@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, September 14, 2023 - 1:54pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Southwest Popular/American Culture Association</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:Georgejsieg@gmail.com">Georgejsieg@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/popular-culture">popular culture</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>October 31, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p align="center"><strong>Call for Papers</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>ESOTERICISM, OCCULTISM, AND MAGIC</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>Southwest Popular / American Culture Association (SWPACA)</strong> </p>
<p align="center">45th Annual Conference, February 21-24, 2024</p>
<p align="center">Marriott Albuquerque</p>
<p align="center">Albuquerque, New Mexico</p>
<p align="center"><a href="http://www.southwestpca.org/">http://www.southwestpca.org</a></p>
<p align="center">Submissions open on <strong>September 1, 2023</strong></p>
<p align="center">Proposal submission deadline: <strong>October 31, 2023</strong></p>
<p>Proposals for papers and panels are now being accepted for the 45th annual SWPACA conference. One of the nation’s largest interdisciplinary academic conferences, SWPACA offers nearly 70 subject areas, each typically featuring multiple panels.  For a full list of subject areas, area descriptions, and Area Chairs, please visit <a href="http://southwestpca.org/conference/call-for-papers/">http://southwestpca.org/conference/call-for-papers/</a></p>
<p><strong>Esotericism, Occultism, and Magic</strong> invites proposals relating to magical worldviews, practices, and representations, as well as consciousness transformation, hidden meanings, the power of transmutation, and related phenomena. Characteristic beliefs and practices include: arcane symbolism, imagery, and aesthetics; unseen forces and spiritual intermediaries; synchronous patterns, non-ordinary causation, and anomalous processes. Examples of ideas and systems include Hermeticism, Gnosticism, Sufism, Tantra, Rosicrucianism, Freemasonry, Satanism,  witchcraft, sorcery, demonology, astrology, alchemy, yoga, shamanism, parapsychology, and psychic and paranormal phenomena, along with beliefs and practices relating to altered states of consciousness, overlapping with the study of mysticism as well as New Age spirituality, channeling, positive thinking, manifest intention, guardian angels, and Ascended Masters. Esoteric, occult, and magical concepts, beliefs, and practices appear in every culture and civilization; contemporary media and popular culture have embraced them enthusiastically, yet at times have reacted against them. The impact of esotericism, occultism, and magic on genre formation/content and popular cultural perceptions has been profound. </p>
<p>Special themes for 2024 may include the following, as well as their various possible intersections and combinations, but all proposals suitable to the Area will be considered: esotericism, occultism, magic, liminality, fluidity, and normative boundaries (cultural, social, intellectual, ethical, moral, spiritual, racial, ethnic, legal etc.) as well as their challenge and transgression -- but also the mainstreaming of EOM; identity, personality, and personification;  metamorphosis and shapeshifting; the sacred and the numinous; EOM and ecology; EOM, nationalism, (geo)politics, espionage, disinformation, and cyberspace; cultural conceptions/constructions of (in)sanity, madness, mania, compulsion, and addiction;  pathology, and pathologization; (un)death, and unlife; antinomianism, immoralism, and conceptions of evil; EOM and crime (as motive, as projection, but also the criminalization/vilification of EOM); the monstrous; artificial life, artificial sentience, and artificial sapience; the supernatural; conceptions of the miraculous and the impossible; thaumaturgy and wonder-working; illusion, deepfake, simulation, and forgery; magical charlatanry and occult fraud; EOM and concepts of "reality", virtual and otherwise; "technomagic", "magical machines", technology, innovation, and inspiration; EOM and memes; creativity, interactive fiction, and metafiction; invented worlds, secondary worlds, myth, magical realism, the fantastic, the weird, and the sublime; theurgy and theosis; mystery cults and theophany; entheogens and nootropics; indigenous worldviews and magical folklore; Tradition and Traditionalism; EOM, nostalgia, retrofuturism, alternate history, and counterfactual scenarios; concepts/models of parallel/alternate dimension, timelines, multiverses/metaverses; the alien and the unknown </p>
<p>Sample Ideas for topics categorized by media: </p>
<p>Literature: Fiction by practitioners, such as Philip K. Dick, William S. Burroughs, C. S. Friedman. Books by practitioners (for example, Evola, Gurdjieff, Crowley, Anton LaVey, Gerald Gardner, Peter Carroll, Edgar Cayce). Influences and themes in magical realism, speculative fiction, gothic fiction, weird fiction, historical fiction, urban fantasy, paranormal romance and adventure. Fiction influential on practitioners, such as <em>Zanoni</em>, Goethe’s <em>Faust</em>, The <em>Illuminatus! </em>Trilogy. Historical representations of magicians, witches, and wizards, including stylized and mythic figures (Merlin, Morgan La Fey, Circe, Medea, Kostchie the Deathless, etc.), in genre fiction (contemporary Arthurian adaptations) or modernizations (Neil Gaiman, Tim Powers, Jim Butcher, Susanna Clarke), indigenous futurism and fantasy (Octavia Butler, Rebecca Roanhorse).  New Age and/or popular manifestation guides, such as <em>The Secret</em>. Conspiracist and/or extra-terrestrial cosmologies related to esoteric concepts (David Icke, the Seth transmissions to Jane Roberts, the Michael channelings, etc.). </p>
<p>Visual Art: Examples: Hilma af Klint, Wassily Kandinsky, Austin Spare, Rosaleen Norton, Michael Bertiaux.</p>
<p>Film: Content as in <em>Hellraiser, The Color Out of Space, The Witch</em>, <em>Hereditary</em>, <em>Midsommar</em>, <em>Apostle, The Endless, A Dark Song, Kill List, Drag Me To Hell, The Skeleton Key</em>, <em>The Serpent and the Rainbow</em>, <em>The Ninth Gate</em>, <em>The Conjuring </em>series, <em>The Wicker Man</em>; Gnostic allegories such as <em>The Matrix</em>, <em>Dark City</em>, <em>The Truman Show</em>; explorations of consciousness such as <em>eXistenZ</em>, <em>Altered States</em>, <em>2001 Space Odyssey, Dune</em>; representations of occult aesthetic, such as <em>Eyes Wide Shut</em>, occult conspiracy, such as <em>Starry Eyes, </em>or traumatic initiation, such as the <em>Saw</em> series; stylized depictions of magicians, wizards, and witches (<em>Dr. Strange, Shazam, Maleficent, Oz, Warlock, Thulsa Doom </em>of<em> Conan, Jafar</em> of <em>Aladdin</em>) ; esoteric/occult films such those by Kenneth Anger and Alejandro Jodorowsky; pseudo- and crypto-history in fiction (<em>Tomb Raider, National Treasure</em>); New Age documentaries, such as <em>The Secret</em>; conspiracist receptions of esoteric and occult history, such as <em>Zeitgeist</em>. </p>
<p>Television: Theme and/or content examples <em>Mayfair Witches, Westworld, Stranger Things, Brand New Cherry Flavor, Yellowjackets, Sandman, Wandavision, Game of Thrones/House of the Dragon, The Witcher, The Magicians, A Discovery of Witches, Midnight Mass, The Devil In Ohio, The Order, Dark, Shadowhunters, The Man in the High Castle, The Chilling Adventures of Sabrina, Twin Peaks, Penny Dreadful, DaVinci’s Demons, American Horror Story, American Gods, Lucifer, True Detective</em> (season one), <em>Strange Angel</em> (fictionalized biography of occultist/magician Jack Parsons.) Significant protagonists and anti-heroes; fourth-wall-breaking or uncanny figures, presented with esoteric, occult, or quasi-ritualistic aesthetics (Dr. Hannibal Lecter, Frank Underwood of <em>House of Cards</em>).  </p>
<p>Comics / Graphic Novels: Contain esoteric, occult, and magical motifs and tropes. Some are actively esoteric; Grant Morrison claims <em>The Invisibles </em>and <em>Promethea </em>as personal magical workings; the graphic novels of Neil Gaiman embrace esoteric, occult, magical themes and characters. </p>
<p>Music: Specific artists (e.g. Genesis P-Orridge, David Bowie, Coil, Marilyn Manson, Ghost, Watain, Dissection, Behemoth, Wardruna, Tori Amos, Loreena McKennitt, Gustav Holst), genres (dark ambient, dungeon synth, black metal, viking/Nordic ambient, apocalyptic folk, military industrial, witch house). </p>
<p>Video Games: Theme and content, e.g., <em>Astrologaster, The Council, Goetia, Hell Is Others, Cyberpunk 2077, Saturnalia, Solium Infernum, A Plague Tale, Cult of the Lamb, Hunt: Showdown, Medium, Potion Craft: Alchemist Simulator, Dead Synchronicity, The Witcher, Silent Hill, Darkest Dungeon, Cultist  Simulator, The Shadow Government Simulator, Secret Government, Secret World, Xenogears, Devil May Cry, Murdered: Soul Suspect, Arcana, Arcanum: Of Steamworks and Magick Obscura, Shadow Hearts, Arx Fatalis, Eternal Darkness</em>; pseudo-history <em>Assassin’s Creed, Tomb Raider, Broken Sword</em>; historical worldviews, <em>Civilization VI </em>(secret societies), <em>Crusader Kings </em>(cults, witchcraft, demonolatry), <em>The Elder Scrolls, Destiny 2, Genshin Impact </em>(Gnosticism &amp; Hermeticism), <em>Curious Expedition </em>(historical occultists as playable characters, occult revival + pulp aesthetic); <em>Deus Ex, SOMA, State of Mind </em>(transhumanism); methodology (<em>Nevermind</em>, when utilizing biofeedback) </p>
<p>Tabletop Roleplaying Games: <em>The Esoterrorists </em>and <em>Yellow King </em>(Pelgrane Press)<em>, Esoterica </em>(Fire Ruby Designs), <em>Kult: Divinity Lost </em>(rebooted by Modiphius Games), <em>Liminal </em>(Modiphius),<em> Sigil &amp; Shadow </em>(Osprey Games), <em>Esoteric Enterprises </em>(Dying Stylishly Games), White Wolf’s <em>Mage</em> (classic <em>World of Darkness</em>) and <em>Demon: The Descent </em>(<em>Chronicles of Darkness</em>), <em>World of Darkness </em>generally, Atlas Games <em>Unknown Armies</em>, Monte Cook’s <em>Invisible Sun, </em>Kevin Crawford's <em>Silent Legions.</em> RPGs have influenced the conception of magic in popular culture across media, and present extensive representation of magical figures.  Esoteric and gnostic themes intersect with transhumanism in examples such as <em>Eclipse Phase</em>. </p>
<p>Other possible topics:</p>
<p>Influence of esoteric/occult/magical/New Age beliefs, practices, symbols on popular culture and aesthetics (e.g., memes, clothing, tattoos, jewelry).</p>
<p>Influence of popular culture on esoteric/occult/magical beliefs, practices, and practitioners (e.g., Lovecraft mythos as actual magical practice, fictional gods of chaos in Chaos Magic, and real vampire communities using concepts from <em>Vampire:The Masquerade</em>).</p>
<p>Popular beliefs about esotericism/occultism/magic: fads, trends, moral panics, witch-hunts, witch-crazes, conspiracy theories (e.g., anti-occult-conspiracism in QAnon; Illuminati paranoia, bloodline of the Holy Grail beliefs, Satanic Ritual Abuse scandals).</p>
<p>Reactions and polemics against esoteric/occult/magical beliefs and practices </p>
<p><strong>All proposals must be submitted through the conference’s database at </strong><a href="http://register.southwestpca.org/southwestpca"><strong>http://register.southwestpca.org/southwestpca</strong></a></p>
<p>For details on using the submission database and on the application process in general, please see the Proposal Submission FAQs and Tips page at <a href="http://southwestpca.org/conference/faqs-and-tips/">http://southwestpca.org/conference/faqs-and-tips/</a></p>
<p>Individual proposals for 15-minute papers must include an abstract of approximately 200-500 words. Including a brief bio in the body of the proposal form is encouraged, but not required.   </p>
<p>For information on how to submit a proposal for a roundtable or a multi-paper panel, please view the above FAQs and Tips page.  </p>
<p>The deadline for submissions is October 31, 2023.   </p>
<p>SWPACA offers monetary awards for the best graduate student papers in a variety of categories. Submissions of accepted, full papers are due January 1, 2024.  SWPACA also offers travel fellowships for undergraduate and graduate students. For more information, visit <a href="http://southwestpca.org/conference/graduate-student-awards/">http://southwestpca.org/conference/graduate-student-awards/</a> </p>
<p>Registration and travel information for the conference will be available at <a href="http://southwestpca.org/conference/conference-registration-information/">http://southwestpca.org/conference/conference-registration-information/</a></p>
<p>For 2024, we are excited to continue again at the Marriott Albuquerque (2101 Louisiana Blvd NE, Albuquerque, NM 87110), which boasts free parking and close proximity to dining, shopping, and other delights.</p>
<p>In addition, please check out the organization’s peer-reviewed, scholarly journal, <em>Dialogue: The Interdisciplinary Journal of Popular Culture and Pedagogy</em>, at <a href="http://journaldialogue.org/">http://journaldialogue.org/</a></p>
<p>If you have any questions about the Esotericism, Occultism, and Magic area, please contact its Area Chair, George J. Sieg, Southwestern Indian Polytechnic Institute, <a href="mailto:georgejsieg@gmail.com">georgejsieg@gmail.com</a>. If you have general questions about the conference, please contact us at <a href="mailto:support@southwestpca.org">support@southwestpca.org</a>, and a member of the executive team will get back to you.</p>
<p><strong>This will be a fully in-person conference.</strong> If you’re looking for an online option to present your work, keep an eye out for details about the 2024 SWPACA Summer Salon, a completely virtual conference to take place in June 2024. However, do keep in mind that the Summer Salon is a smaller conference with limited presentation slots and no student funding assistance.</p>
<p>We look forward to receiving your submissions!</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1694756231685649</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ December 1, 2023] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/114534</link>
						<description>Publication Name: Palgrave Handbook of Phenomenology and Literature<br/><br/><p><strong>Call for Proposals: <em>Palgrave Handbook of Phenomenology and Literature</em></strong></p>

<p><br/> The <em>Palgrave Handbook of Phenomenology and Literature </em>invites scholars and advanced Ph.D. students to submit chapter proposals for inclusion in the two-volume work. While the phenomenological engagement of literature was a major field of inquiry in France, Germany, and North America from the 1930s to the 1960s, the rise of structuralism and then poststructuralism questioned this approach. In recent years, however, phenomenological perspectives on literature have been enjoying a renaissance, one the <em>Handbook</em> seeks to express and advance.</p>

<p>The <em>Handbook </em>seeks to explore a wide range of phenomenological interactions with concrete works of literature, methods of literary theory, and canonical questions of philosophy. In doing so, the <em>Handbook </em>will reflect on the phenomenology <em>of </em>literature, the phenomenology <em>in </em>literature, and the mutually critical relationships <em>between</em> phenomenology, literary theory, and philosophy.</p>

<p>Chapters will be 4000-7000 words, inclusive of bibliography and notes. Successful chapters will be accessible to upper-level undergraduates, graduate students, and faculty in fields of literature and continental philosophy, primarily, but also readers from theology and religious studies who are concerned with sacred literature and analytical philosophers working on aesthetics.</p>

<p>We welcome proposals on any topic of phenomenology and literature, and we are especially on the lookout for chapters in the following areas:</p>
<ul>
<li>chapters on major figures in the field: both those well-known for work on literary questions (e.g. Ingarden, Heidegger) and also those who, while less well-known for their work in this area, still did important work in the field (e.g. Fanon, de Beauvoir);</li>
<li>chapters on how literary topics (e.g. metaphor, plot, genres) can benefit from, and benefit, phenomenological reflection;</li>
<li>chapters on how phenomenology can enter into generative dialogues with movements in literary theory (e.g. new historicism, postcolonial theory, Queer theory, posthumanism);</li>
<li>chapters on how phenomenological intersections with literary phenomena can cast light on broader philosophical problems (e.g. skepticism, tensions between faith and reason, or moral dilemmas).</li>
</ul>

<p>Please submit your title and abstract proposals of no more than 300 words, as well as a current CV, by December 1, 2023, to Jeffrey McCurry (<a href="mailto:mccurryj@duq.edu">mccurryj@duq.edu</a>), whom you can also contact with any questions.</p>

<p>The timeline is below.</p>
<ul>
<li>December 1, 2023 - Abstracts due</li>
<li>February 1, 2024 – Notification of Preliminary Acceptance or Rejection</li>
<li>Feb. 1, 2025 – Completed Chapters Due</li>
<li>July 1, 2025 – Editorial Reviews Completed</li>
<li>Jan. 1, 2026 – Revisions Completed, Final Approval of Chapters, Manuscript Submitted</li>
<li>Spring 2026 – Copy Edits and Proofs</li>
<li>Fall 2026 (hopefully in time for SPEP) – Volume Publication</li>
</ul></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 05:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1694669831994254</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – September 13, 2023</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-september-13-2023/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find 32 new job opportunities, 1 Fellowship, 1 Award, 4 Calls for Papers, 8 Conferences/Speakers, and 1 other event/submission.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 31!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Academic:</h4>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Women’s &amp; Gender Studies (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>University of Missouri, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: November 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178532759&amp;utm_source=09_12_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">Assistant Professor of Women’s &amp; Gender Studies (TT) – HigherEdJobs</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor in Islamic Studies (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Bard College, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: October 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178532658&amp;utm_source=09_12_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">Assistant Professor (Tenure Track) – Islamic Studies – HigherEdJobs</a></p>



<h4>Ethnic Studies Instructor (Part-time, Masters degree accepted)</h4>



<p>Community College of Aurora, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: ASAP</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178532416&amp;utm_source=09_12_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">Ethnic Studies Instructor – HigherEdJobs</a></p>



<h4>Humanities Instructor (Part-time, Masters degree accepted)</h4>



<p>Community College of Aurora, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: ASAP</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178532366&amp;utm_source=09_12_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">Humanities Instructor – HigherEdJobs</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor in Modern East Asian Buddhism (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Boston University</p>



<p>Deadline: October 14, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178531012&amp;utm_source=09_12_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">Assistant Professor in Modern East Asian Buddhism, Religion, College of Arts &amp; Sciences (23599932650908) – HigherEdJobs</a></p>



<h4>Professor of Jewish Studies (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Sarah Lawrence College, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: September 15, 2023, or until filled</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178530882&amp;utm_source=09_12_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">Jewish Studies Tenure Track Faculty Position – HigherEdJobs</a></p>



<h4>Postdoctoral Instructor of Medieval History (2-year appointment)</h4>



<p>California Institute of Technology, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: March 15, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.historians.org/jobs/19117134/postdoctoral-instructor-in-medieval-history?utm_source=BTITwitter&amp;utm_medium=Twitter&amp;utm_campaign=BTI%2BTwitter%2BFeed">Postdoctoral Instructor in Medieval History in Pasadena, CA for California Institute of Technology (historians.org)</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Religious Ethics and Critical Thought (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Oberlin College, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: October 18, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://jobs.oberlin.edu/postings/14414">Oberlin College &amp; Conservatory Applicant Portal | Assistant Professor of Religious Ethics and Critical Thought</a></p>



<h4>Postdoctoral Research Associate (3-year appointment)</h4>



<p>Queen Mary University, UK</p>



<p>Deadline: October 3, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.jobs.ac.uk/job/DCN800/postdoctoral-research-associate">https://www.jobs.ac.uk/job/DCN800/postdoctoral-research-associate</a></p>



<h4>Postdoctoral Researcher (3-year appointment)</h4>



<p>University of Groningen, Netherlands</p>



<p>Deadline: October 5, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.rug.nl/about-ug/work-with-us/job-opportunities/?details=00347-02S000AC5P">Postdoc in history of anthropology or religious studies (0.8 FTE) (V23.0585) | Job opportunities | University of Groningen (rug.nl)</a></p>



<h4>Professor of Sociology (Non-tenure-track, Masters degree accepted)</h4>



<p>Cecil College, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: Until filled</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.jobscore.com/careers/cecilcollege/jobs/full-time-faculty-sociology-dQmZ9VVEzpL7-2vi33WO-e?ref=rss&amp;sid=68">https://careers.jobscore.com/careers/cecilcollege/jobs/full-time-faculty-sociology-dQmZ9VVEzpL7-2vi33WO-e?ref=rss&amp;sid=68</a></p>



<h4>Professor of Philosophy (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>St. Louis University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: November 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178530727&amp;utm_source=09_09_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">Eslick Chair of Philosophy – HigherEdJobs</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Anthropology (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>University of Massachusetts, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: November 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178530612&amp;utm_source=09_09_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">Assistant Professor (Anthropology) – HigherEdJobs</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor in Reformation-Era and Modern Christianities (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Union Theological Seminary, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: October 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://churchhistory.org/tenure-track-position-reformation-era-and-modern-christianities-union-theological-seminary/">Tenure Track Position, Reformation-Era and Modern Christianities – Union Theological Seminary – American Society of Church History</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor in Interreligious Histories (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Union Theological Seminary, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: October 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178529643&amp;utm_source=09_08_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178529643&amp;utm_source=09_08_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Philosophy (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Seton Hill, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: September 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178527382&amp;AAEmail=133113&amp;MatchType=2&amp;utm_source=09_07_2023&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=AAEmail">Assistant Professor of Philosophy – HigherEdJobs</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Journalism: Faith, Religion, and Spirituality Reporting (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>University of Utah, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: October 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178526802&amp;utm_source=09_07_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178526802&amp;utm_source=09_07_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor in Medieval Studies (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Princeton University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: November 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://jobs.chronicle.com/job/37514593/assistant-professor-tenure-track/?TrackID=52800&amp;BatchID=1191&amp;cmpid=JBE_TL_20230824_jobtitle&amp;utm_source=jbe&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JBE_TL_20230824_jobtitle_job1">Assistant Professor, Tenure Track job with Princeton University | 37514593 (chronicle.com)</a></p>



<h4>Dan David Postdoctoral Fellow (2-year appointment)</h4>



<p>Tel Aviv University, Israel</p>



<p>Deadline: December 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.historians.org/jobs/19104807/the-dan-david-society-of-fellows-postdoc">The Dan David Society of Fellows (Postdoc) in Tel Aviv, for Dan David Prize (historians.org)</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Sociology</h4>



<p>University of Arkansas, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: October 6, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178526318&amp;utm_source=09_06_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178526318&amp;utm_source=09_06_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Philosophy (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>University of Denver, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: November 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178526130&amp;utm_source=09_06_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178526130&amp;utm_source=09_06_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Minerva Recruitment Job Listings Cite (with areas specifically tailored for Ph.D.)</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://minerva-recruitment.com/">Minerva Recruitment – Higher Education Graduate Jobs, UK &amp; Worldwide (minerva-recruitment.com)</a></p>



<h4>AAR/SBL Job Forum</h4>



<p><a href="https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search">https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search</a></p>



<h4>Non-Academic:</h4>



<h4>Academic Research Analyst</h4>



<p>Institute for Humane Studies, USA (Remote)</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://us231.dayforcehcm.com/CandidatePortal/en-US/ihs/Posting/View/310">Academic Research Analyst (Remote) – Career Portal (dayforcehcm.com)</a></p>



<h4>Justice Researcher – Security and Extremism Research Program</h4>



<p>RTI International, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.rti.org/jobs/10723?src=JB-10203">Justice Researcher – Security and Extremism Research Program in Multiple Locations | RTI International</a></p>



<h4>Curriculum Manager</h4>



<p>West Shore Home, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.westshorehome.com/position/curriculum-manager/">Curriculum Manager – West Shore Careers (westshorehome.com)</a></p>



<h4>Speechwriter and Researcher</h4>



<p>Gwinnett, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.governmentjobs.com/careers/gwinnett/jobs/4184899/speechwriter-and-researcher">Job Opportunities | Gwinnett County Government (governmentjobs.com)</a></p>



<h4>Conflicts Research Assistant</h4>



<p>Russell Tobin, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://russelltobin.com/job/legal/conflicts-research-assistant-remote-361482/">Conflicts Research Assistant – Remote – Russell Tobin</a></p>



<h4>Senior Research Project Manager</h4>



<p>Fordham University, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.fordham.edu/postings/3974">https://careers.fordham.edu/postings/3974</a></p>



<h4>Museum Collections Manager – Libraries and Museums</h4>



<p>University of Texas at San Antonio, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: October 5, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178527698&amp;utm_source=09_07_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178527698&amp;utm_source=09_07_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Outcomes, Assessment, &amp; Evaluation Analyst (Graduate degree preferred)</h4>



<p>National Association for Continuing Education, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://workforcenow.adp.com/mascsr/default/mdf/recruitment/recruitment.html?cid=9bf93b1d-de86-4212-8903-2df38337c33d&amp;ccId=19000101_000001&amp;jobId=485898&amp;lang=en_US&amp;source=CC2">https://workforcenow.adp.com/mascsr/default/mdf/recruitment/recruitment.html?cid=9bf93b1d-de86-4212-8903-2df38337c33d&amp;ccId=19000101_000001&amp;jobId=485898&amp;lang=en_US&amp;source=CC2</a></p>



<h4>Educational Research Associate</h4>



<p>Pennsylvania Department of Education, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.governmentjobs.com/careers/pabureau/jobs/4176039/educational-research-associate-2">https://www.governmentjobs.com/careers/pabureau/jobs/4176039/educational-research-associate-2</a></p>



<h4>Research Associate (Part-time)</h4>



<p>The Garden Initiative for Black Women’s Religious Activism</p>



<p>Deadline: September 25, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/F5WVdddW0AITnnI.jpg">https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/F5WVdddW0AITnnI.jpg</a></p>



<h4>Curator of Religious Collections</h4>



<p>Indiana University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: Until filled</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178525346&amp;utm_source=09_06_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">Curator of Religious Collections – HigherEdJobs</a></p>



<h2>Fellowships:</h2>



<h4>Beinecke Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library Short-term Research Fellowships</h4>



<p>Yale University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: September 22, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://beinecke.library.yale.edu/programs/fellowships/short-term-research-fellowships">Short-term Research Fellowships | Beinecke Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library (yale.edu)</a></p>



<h2>Awards:</h2>



<h2>Graduate Student Research Award</h2>



<p>Deadline: September 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://associationforiranianstudies.org/awards/graduate-student-research-award?fbclid=IwAR3ykuhx1dyppvE6NFQfdZ-WQTF_VnQUjgGAZqdQFnBKYv_7fzIxu0323iQ">https://associationforiranianstudies.org/awards/graduate-student-research-award?fbclid=IwAR3ykuhx1dyppvE6NFQfdZ-WQTF_VnQUjgGAZqdQFnBKYv_7fzIxu0323iQ</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>Undisciplining Religion and Science: Science, Religion, and Nature</h4>



<p>Deadline: October 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://twitter.com/issrnc/status/1700928228926382419?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw">ISSRNC on X: “CFP for a special issue of #Religions, “Undisciplining Religion and Science: Science, Religion and Nature”, co-edited by Whitney Bauman and Lisa Stenmark! <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f9f5.png" alt="🧵">” / X (twitter.com)</a></p>



<h4>Divine Disasters: Exploring Distressed Landscapes in Literature and Theology</h4>



<p>Deadline: October 27, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/09/07/divine-disasters-exploring-distressed-landscapes-in-literature-and-theology">cfp | call for papers (upenn.edu)</a></p>



<h4>Devils and Justified Sinners</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 1, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/09/04/devils-and-justified-sinners">cfp | call for papers (upenn.edu)</a></p>



<h4>Theology and Religion in Daredevil</h4>



<p>Deadline: September 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://popularcultureandtheology.com/2023/08/05/extended-call-for-papers-theology-and-religion-in-daredevil/">https://popularcultureandtheology.com/2023/08/05/extended-call-for-papers-theology-and-religion-in-daredevil/</a></p>



<h2>Conferences:</h2>



<h4>Beyond Doubt: The Secularization of Society</h4>



<p>Online</p>



<p>Date: September 19, 2023, 12 pm ET</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/ov1aVJbOC0">https://t.co/ov1aVJbOC0</a></p>



<h4>Black Religion and Critical Theory Colloquium</h4>



<p>Harvard University, USA</p>



<p>Date: October 5, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://hds.harvard.edu/news/public-events-calendar?trumbaEmbed=view%3Devent%26eventid%3D167906901%26view%3Devent%26eventid%3D167906901">Public Events Calendar | Harvard Divinity School (HDS)</a></p>



<h4>American Religions in a Global Context Seminars</h4>



<p>Stanford University, USA</p>



<p>Date: Varies</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://argc.stanford.edu/news/2023-24-argc-proseminar-speakers">2023-24 ARGC Proseminar Speakers | American Religions in a Global Context (stanford.edu)</a></p>



<h4>Wollaston Research Seminar: “My whole life was the two suburbs that surrounded the church…”</h4>



<p>Online</p>



<p>Date: September 14, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=d107bbacd9&amp;e=ea2dc4a949">https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=d107bbacd9&amp;e=ea2dc4a949</a></p>



<h4>A Decolonial Turn: Rethinking “Religion” in Australian Research</h4>



<p>Online</p>



<p>Date: September 20, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="mailto:sylvia.ang@monash.edu">sylvia.ang@monash.edu</a></p>



<h4>Western Sydney University Religion and Society Research Cluster Seminar</h4>



<p>Western Sydney University, Australia</p>



<p>Date: September 28, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=bc8414ee2e&amp;e=ea2dc4a949">https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=bc8414ee2e&amp;e=ea2dc4a949</a></p>



<h4>The Problem of the Unthought: Black Studies and the Study of Religion – Past, Present, and Future</h4>



<p>Columbia University,</p>



<p>Date: September 28-29, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://afamstudies.columbia.edu/events/problem-unthought-black-studies-and-study-religion-pastpresent-futures">https://afamstudies.columbia.edu/events/problem-unthought-black-studies-and-study-religion-pastpresent-futures</a></p>



<h4>Beyond Genesis: The Many Creation Stories of the Bible</h4>



<p>University of North Carolina, USA</p>



<p>Date: October 19, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/F5XL4dzaMAA_T37.jpg">https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/F5XL4dzaMAA_T37.jpg</a></p>



<h2>Miscellaneous:</h2>



<h4>St. Gabriel’s Doctoral Scholarship Program</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.cstg.org.uk/scholarship-programmes/doctoral/">Doctoral Scholarship Programme – Culham St Gabriel’s (cstg.org.uk)</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1694669831994253</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ October 7, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Imam Reza (PBUH) and Interreligious Dialogue</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/114494</link>
						<description><p><strong>The International Conference on Imam Reza (PBUH) and Interreligious Dialogue</strong></p>
<p>Astan Quds Razavi’s Foundation of Islamic Researches in collaboration with Imam Sadiq University and various Iranian and international academic and religious centers will hold the international conference on “Imam Reza (PBUH) and Interreligious Dialogue” from 16 to 18 January 2024. This conference aims to create an atmosphere for dialogue and peaceful coexistence between the followers of different religions and denominations, to strengthen scientific interaction between the scholars of different religions and denominations, to strengthen the scientific interaction between Iranian and International religious institutions, to laying a groundwork for Intellectual cooperation between different religions and denominations on contemporary social challenges, and to emphasize the role of the family as a sacred institution from the perspective of religions and denominations. Laying the groundwork for the conference, the scientific secretariat has planned to hold numerous virtual/in-person pre-con meetings in Persian, Arabic, and English at the different Iranian and international academic/religious centers.</p>
<p>Chairman: Mohammad Hadi Abdkhodaei (Professor, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Iran)</p>
<p>Scientific Secretary: Ahad Faramarz Qaramaleki (Professor, University of Tehran, Iran)</p>
<p>Executive Secretary: Mohsen Sharfaei (Ph. D Graduate, Astan Quds Razavi’s Foundation of Islamic Researches, Iran)</p>
<p>Executive Manager: Roohollah Fadaei (Ph. D Graduate, Tarbiat Modares University, Iran)</p>
<p>Venue: Mashhad, Iran</p>
<p>Conference issues:</p>
<p>1. Theory and Method in Interreligious Dialogue:</p>
<p>- Philosophical Approaches: Phenomenology, Epistemology, Narrative, Intercultural Philosophy, etc.</p>
<p>- Sociological Approaches</p>
<p>- Empirical Approaches</p>
<p>- Psychological Approaches</p>
<p>…</p>
<p>2. Family and Interreligious Dialogue</p>
<p>- Theological Attitudes Towards Family Relationships</p>
<p>- Religions and the Threats to Family Life</p>
<p>- Religions and the Mental Images of Family</p>
<p>- Theology of Gender</p>
<p>- Religions and the Rival Institutions to the Family</p>
<p>- Religions and the Family Roles</p>
<p>We are honored to host some of the well-known scholars in interfaith studies in the scientific board:</p>
<p>·       Rahim Acar: Marmara University, Turkey</p>
<p>·       Ahad Faramarz Qaramaleki: University of Tehran, Iran</p>
<p>·       Lucinda Allen Mosher: Hartford International University for Religion and Peace, USA</p>
<p>·       Seyyed Hossein Nasr: The George Washington University, USA</p>
<p>·       Rasoul Rasoulipour: Kharazmi University, Iran</p>
<p>·       Mohammad Saeedi Mehr: Tarbiat Modares University, Iran</p>
<p>·       Mun'im Sirry: Notre Dame University, USA</p>
<p>·       Amy Yu Fu: Hangzhou City University, China</p>
<p>….</p>
<p>Important Dates</p>
<p>·       Abstract submission deadline: October 7, 2023</p>
<p>·       Notification of acceptance: October 22, 2023</p>
<p>·       Paper submission deadline: December 6, 2023</p>
<p>·       Announcement of the selected papers and presentations’ schedule: December 22, 2023</p>
<p>·       Conference date: January 16-18, 2024</p>
<p>Only Ph. D holders and postgraduate students may submit abstracts and papers independently. Undergraduates' submissions should be coauthored by a professor.</p>
<p>Abstract Features:</p>
<p>·       Abstracts should be no less than 250 words in length and no more than 300.</p>
<p>·        Abstracts should be followed by 3 to 5 keywords.</p>
<p>Paper Features:</p>
<p>·       Papers should be no less than 1500 words in length and no more than 2000 (the abstract and bibliography are not counted).</p>
<p>·       Whole text should be typed in Times New Roman font (font-size: 11 for body and 9 for endnotes and bibliography).</p>
<p>·       All titles and subtitles in the paper should be arranged numerically (English numbers not Roman).</p>
<p>·       All marginal but useful and important notes should be mentioned as endnotes, not footnotes.</p>
<p>·       All references (in-text and reference list) should follow the 16th edition of Chicago citation style.</p>
<p>The conference will be held totally in-person.</p>
<p>The conference registration is free of charge. For those professors and researchers interested in participating in the conference in-person, conference organizers tried to decrease the costs of attendance by finding some funds. Accordingly, the attendance cost for any international participant would be 500 USD (which will be received in cash) including:</p>
<p>•        A 5to7-day stay in Iran (from about 13 to 19 January 2024) at a five-star hotel</p>
<p>•        Complete food services at the hotel</p>
<p>•        Local transportation in Tehran from Imam Khomeini Airport to Mehrabad Airport and vice versa</p>
<p>•        A roundtrip flight ticket from Tehran to Mashhad</p>
<p>•        Local Transportation in Mashhad</p>
<p>It is kindly requested from those who want to attend the event to register on the conference website and to submit their abstracts. Moreover, due to the official process of visa issuance, the secretariat of the conference (irirdialogue@gmail.com) needs the following documents:</p>
<p>1. Passport first two pages</p>
<p>2.  A biometric photo</p>
<p>3. Form 1 (just fill out the English column)</p>
<p>Conference website, submissions and registration:  <a href="https://irirdialogue.ir/">https://irirdialogue.ir/</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 05:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1694583423805685</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
