<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 12:19:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 12:19:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ March 15, 2024] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/118365</link>
						<description>Publication Name: Compositing Man: Worldly-ecologies &amp; Life/Death Affirming Perspectives<br/><br/><p>Compositing Man: Worldly-ecologies &amp; Life/Death Affirming Perspectives</p>
<p>Call for Papers: philoSOPHIA 15, pub date est. for Jan/Feb 2025</p>
<p>Guest Editors: Xalli Zúñiga &amp; Stephanie Rivera Berruz</p>
<p>philoSOPHIA: Journal of Transcontinental Philosophy Feminism</p>
<p>The colonial dynamics by which global capitalism asserts its dominance, establishing itself as the Earth’s prevailing economic system, give rise to metabolic rifts that tamper with the relations that make life possible. Through colonization, global capitalism fractures living systems by redefining all elements of life as resources—rendered inanimate, isolated, and mechanized for the sole purpose of extraction and wealth accumulation. As a result, the histories of social and environmental spheres are disjointed, leading to what Anna Tsing poignantly describes as “Earth stalked by Man.” Whether termed the Plantationocene, Capitalocene, or Anthropocene, this age of human exceptionalism is defined by a toxic spread of life-diminishing phenomena: ocean acidification, temperature extremes, ecosystem simplification, deforestation, and rampant ecocide. The era of anthropos, or “Man,” shaped by human activity, implies more than an issue of species, but of racial class disparities. Capitalism relies on the unequal exploitation of individuals, often through racial and sexual discrimination, and the one-sided exploitation of natural landscapes, perpetuating itself through a paradigm of plunder. As a result, living forms (human; non-human alike) are robbed of the wealth they generate without any opportunity for replenishment or reciprocity. </p>
<p>In this context, we invite contributions that critically challenge prevailing anthropocentric narratives of nature and that seek to interrogate the relations between life-affirming practices and the natural cycles of decay, decomposition and regeneration. Drawing inspiration from Malcom Ferdinand (2022), we strive for a wordly-ecology(s) “that recognizes that our existence and our bodies are made up of encounters with a plurality of human beings and a plurality of non-human beings” (20). We welcome projects that resonate with the idea that to be alive is to live and produce worlds through/with others. This includes considerations of ecological caregiving, the building of coalitions and kinships, mutual aid, coevolution, mycorrhizal symbiosis, the formation of alliances and solidarity, transversality, and horizontal relational dynamics, among others. Grounded in notions of belonging, permeability, and the ideological transformation of human exceptionalism, our goal is to to create worlds rooted in cooperation and interconnectedness.</p>
<p>In resonance with current trends in feminist scholarship that explore the dynamics between regional and diasporic linkages across the U.S. South and the Global South, including African, Indigenous, Caribbean, Latin American, Middle Eastern, and Asian perspectives on gender and sexuality and their connections to the U.S. South, this invitation for contributions is guided by questions within transcontinental contexts and practical methodologies that have to do with:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Redefining Belonging: How can we redefine belonging to extend beyond human-centric views, fostering a sense of nurturing dwelling with all forms of life?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Shifting Human Exceptionalism: How can concepts like porosity, mixture, and permeability challenge human exceptionalism, as well as reshape our frames of relation with the living world?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Composting “Nature:” How does human egotism shape our perception of nature as an inert, subdued entity? In what manner does the mechanization of life influence our interaction with and experience of the natural world? Is it possible to reimagine and understand nature from a perspective that transcends mechanistic interpretations?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Revitalizing Life-Affirming Relations: How can coalition-building reconfigure life-affirming relationships, reshaping our understanding of humanity and life itself? In what ways can collaborative alliances redefine the dynamics of human interaction and our collective relationship with the broader tapestry of existence?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Reworlding Non-Capitalist Ecologies: How can we cultivate worlds beyond the reach of colonial-extractive capitalism, promoting global-scale mutualisms and cooperation? In a landscape marred by competition, how can ecological care foster interspecies collaboration?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Spirituality: How do spiritual traditions from globally marginalized communities engage with and interpret the environmental crisis? In what ways can the focus on shadow (often neglected or overlooked) aspects within these practices provide distinct and insightful perspectives in the discourse surrounding environmental challenges?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Sensuousness and Decay: How might we reshape our understanding of the connection between life-affirming practices and the natural processes of death, decay, and decomposition, and in what ways do these insights inform our understanding of sensuousness, the erotic, and relationality?</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Deadline for submission: March 15, 2024</p>
<p>Email submissions to:wordly.ecologies.philosophia@gmail.com</p>
<p>Inquires to Guest Editors: Xalli Zúñiga:xalli.zungia.research@gmail.com </p>
<p>          Stephanie Rivera Berruz:stephanie.riveraberruz@marquette.edu</p>
<p>Format: Submissions should be in the range of 5,000-8,000 words (including a 200 word abstract, author bio, and references) and should follow the formatting guidelines:https://sunypress.edu/content/download/467893/5617709/version/1/file/philoSOPHIA_SubmissionGuidelines.pdf</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 06:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1704523025245944</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ July 1, 2024 -  July 9, 2024] Conference or similar: 2024 Hildebrand Project Summer Residency</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/118353</link>
						<description>Venue: 1235 University Blvd.<br/><br/><p>The annual Hildebrand Project Summer Residency will take place July 1-9, 2024, at Franciscan University of Steubenville, and is free to attend for all accepted participants. <br/><br/>The Residency is an intensive program for advanced students and scholars working on MA theses, Ph.D. dissertations, habilitations, books, chapters, or scholarly articles principally focused on Dietrich von Hildebrand or substantively engaged with his thought. We are especially interested in supporting research that has never been publicly presented.<br/><br/>The Residency is not limited to those working exclusively on Dietrich von Hildebrand. We welcome applications from students and scholars working on kindred spirits, like Max Scheler, Adolf Reinach, and Edith Stein , or on any thinker or set of issues, provided that the work in progress includes Hildebrand as a substantive interlocutor or meaningfully engages the personalist tradition.<br/><br/>Residency participants will have the opportunity to work closely with Hildebrand Project Senior Scholars, Dr. John F. Crosby, Dr. Josef Seifert, and Rocco Buttiglione, each of whom was a student of either Dietrich von Hildebrand or Karol Wojtyla. <br/><br/>The application and travel scholarship deadline is January 31, 2024. For more information and how to apply, please visit https://hildebrandproject.org/event/summer-residency-2024/.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 06:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1704436624843405</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ February 26, 2024 -  February 27, 2024] Conference or similar: Delusions at the Intersection</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/118273</link>
						<description>Venue: University Hospital of Zürich, Rämistrasse<br/><br/><p><strong>Call for participation: </strong>We are looking for participants from any disciplinary as well as experiential background with an interest in the phenomenology of delusions. The workshop will be interactive throughout, and there will be ample opportunity for discussion and work in small groups. Brief optional presentation: participants are encouraged to give brief presentations in any format they wish (e.g., 5-minute flash-talk or provocation, 15-minute work-in-progress paper, data session or any other creative short format). We are especially keen to hear about theoretical and methodological challenges that you may have come across in your own research on delusions, and about transdisciplinary approaches that may help tackle these challenges.</p>
<p>Participation is free but is restricted to max 30 people. <strong>To apply, please send:</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>A short biography (100 words)</li>
<li>A statement of interest (300 words) including whether you would like to give a brief presentation, the topic of the proposed presentation and the format. If you do not wish to present, just tell us a bit more about you and your research interests.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Email the above to:</strong> r.ritunnano.1@pgr.bham.ac.uk &amp; anke.maatz@pukzh.ch (cc: j.m.littlemore@bham.ac.uk). Please use <strong>“Surname - Sandpit Application”</strong> as your email subject line. If you need to make advanced travel arrangements and are seeking an expedited response, please contact the organisers directly. If your application is accepted, you will then be invited to register for the event on Eventbrite: https://www.eventbrite.com/e/delusions-at-the-intersection-tickets-774099431237 </p>
<p><strong>Applications deadline:</strong> January 15, 2024, 9:00am GMT.</p>
<p><strong>EVENT OVERVIEW</strong></p>
<p>Research into delusions poses methodological challenges that stretch and push narrow disciplinary boundaries. Depending on their disciplinary focus, researchers have often focused on individual features of delusional phenomena (e.g., their epistemic features, underlying cognitive biases or their clinical correlates), failing to attend to their complexity.</p>
<p>In contrast, phenomenological psychopathologists have emphasised the role of subjectivity in delusion formation and maintenance. However, much phenomenological work continues to rely on dis-engaged research practices that eschew critical reflection on the cultural, linguistic, historical and political contexts within which delusional phenomena are constituted. The aim of this workshop is to move beyond the traditional conceptualisation of delusion as ‘dysfunctional belief’ and open up a new trans- and inter-disciplinary space for methodological development and theoretical cross-pollination.</p>
<p>We are particularly interested to hear from scholars, practitioners and lived-experience researchers who are/have been involved in exploring delusional phenomena from a multiplicity of perspectives and methods from the psy-sciences, phenomenology, linguistics, social sciences, theology, anthropology, among other disciplines. The sandpit will also lay the groundwork to establish and international network for phenomenological and interdisciplinary approaches to delusion research.</p>
<p><strong>SPEAKERS &amp; CONTRIBUTORS</strong></p>
<p>Anthony Fernandez (Southern Denmark)</p>
<p>Jasper Feyaerts (Ghent; Leuven)</p>
<p>Heiko Hausendorf (Zürich)</p>
<p>Yvonne Ilg (Zürich)</p>
<p>Jeannette Littlemore (Birmingham)</p>
<p>Anke Maatz (Zürich)</p>
<p>Rosa Ritunnano (Birmingham)</p>
<p>Rob Sips (Maastricht)</p>
<p><strong>REGISTRATION INFO</strong></p>
<p><strong>Is registration required?</strong> Yes, successful applicants will be asked to register on Eventbrite.</p>
<p><strong>Accessibility:</strong> Event organisers adhere to the BPA/SWIP Good Practice for Conferences and Seminar Series and the BPA Guidelines for Accessible Conferences.</p>
<p><strong>Queries?</strong> Please email the organisers r.ritunnano.1@pgr.bham.ac.uk, anke.maatz@pukzh.ch &amp; j.m.littlemore@bham.ac.uk</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 06:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1704436624843404</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ July 1, 2024 -  July 9, 2024] Conference or similar: 2024 Hildebrand Project Summer Residency</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/118353</link>
						<description>Venue: 1235 University Blvd.<br/><br/><p>The annual Hildebrand Project Summer Residency will take place July 1-9, 2024, at Franciscan University of Steubenville, and is free to attend for all accepted participants. <br/><br/>The Residency is an intensive program for advanced students and scholars working on MA theses, Ph.D. dissertations, habilitations, books, chapters, or scholarly articles principally focused on Dietrich von Hildebrand or substantively engaged with his thought. We are especially interested in supporting research that has never been publicly presented.<br/><br/>The Residency is not limited to those working exclusively on Dietrich von Hildebrand. We welcome applications from students and scholars working on kindred spirits, like Max Scheler, Adolf Reinach, and Edith Stein , or on any thinker or set of issues, provided that the work in progress includes Hildebrand as a substantive interlocutor or meaningfully engages the personalist tradition.<br/><br/>Residency participants will have the opportunity to work closely with Hildebrand Project Senior Scholars, Dr. John F. Crosby, Dr. Josef Seifert, and Rocco Buttiglione, each of whom was a student of either Dietrich von Hildebrand or Karol Wojtyla. <br/><br/>The application and travel scholarship deadline is January 31, 2024. For more information and how to apply, please visit https://hildebrandproject.org/event/summer-residency-2024/.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 06:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1704436624843403</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Experience of Stone II: Sculpting Comparative Phenomenologies</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/12/29/the-experience-of-stone-ii-sculpting-comparative-phenomenologies</link>
						<dc:creator>alexanderD</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, January 4, 2024 - 12:43am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Christina Cowart-Smith (Durham University, UK) and Alexander D'Alisera (Boston College, USA)</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:christina.e.smith@durham.ac.uk">christina.e.smith@durham.ac.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/ecocriticism-and-environmental-studies">ecocriticism and environmental studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/medieval">medieval</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>February 8, 2024</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>CALL FOR PAPERS -- EAA 2024 -- ROME, ITALY </strong></p>
<p>Christina Cowart-Smith and Alexander D'Alisera invite abstract submission to session #643 ("The Experience of Stone II: Sculpting Comparative Phenomenologies") at the 2024 annual meeting of the European Association of Archaeologists in Rome, Italy. Please see the text below for further details. Any questions may be addressed to the organizers at <a href="mailto:christina.e.smith@durham.ac.uk">christina.e.smith@durham.ac.uk</a> and <a href="mailto:alexander.dalisera@bc.edu">alexander.dalisera@bc.edu</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Session Title and Number</strong><br/>#643. The Experience of Stone II: Sculpting Comparative Phenomenologies</p>
<p><strong>Organizers</strong><br/>Christina Cowart-Smith (Durham University, UK)<br/>Alexander D'Alisera (Boston College, USA)</p>
<p><strong>Deadline</strong><br/>8 February 2024</p>
<p><strong>Submissions</strong><br/><a href="https://submissions.e-a-a.org/eaa2024/">https://submissions.e-a-a.org/eaa2024/</a></p>
<p><strong>Abstract</strong><br/>The Experience of Stone hits Rome! Building upon the success of last year’s all-day panel, this session offers explorations into the phenomenology of stone sculpture and monuments, stone artefacts, stone buildings, and natural landscapes of stone. In the words of Maurice Merleau-Ponty, ‘The body is our general medium for having a world.’ Centred on EAA 2024’s theme ‘persisting with change’, this session explores how stone constructs (and is mediated by) a viewer's sensorial experience. Phenomenology offers a way for thinking about the affective presence of stone, stone monuments, and natural stonescapes, and proves particularly important for periods and places where the textual record is scant.</p>
<p>We invite scholars of all time periods, geographies, and disciplines—but especially archaeologists, historians, and art historians working from the prehistoric to medieval periods—to contribute papers exploring comparative phenomenologies of stone. Papers that examine geographically or temporally cross-border case-studies are particularly welcome. Possible subjects include, but are not limited to: comparative stonescapes; reuse of hewn or sculptured stone; epigraphy through changing viewership; sculpting memory; textual references to the experience of stone; stone and empire; agentive stone; the application of viewsheds in spatial analysis; a theology of stone; multi-media stone monuments; and, landscape archaeology. As with last year’s panel, this session aims to offer a forum through which history, archaeology, and other disciplines may continue to develop further scholarly discourse and collaboration.</p>
<p><strong>Keywords<br/></strong>stone and stone sculpture, phenomenology, comparative studies, landscape archaeology, monumentality, architectures of stone</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 21:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1704350223155950</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Special Issue on Freedom</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/12/28/special-issue-on-freedom</link>
						<dc:creator>natalia.wohar@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, January 4, 2024 - 12:43am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>The Journal of Dialogic Ethics: Interfaith and Interhuman Perspectives</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:dialogicethics@duq.edu">dialogicethics@duq.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/rhetoric-and-composition">rhetoric and composition</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>July 1, 2024</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>This issue will engage the theme of the National Communication Association’s 109th Annual Convention on freedom. The convention’s call recognizes the relationship between human communication and freedom, inquiring into the meaning of freedom and the role of communication in achieving freedom. In response to this theme, the <em>Journal of Dialogic Ethics </em>invites essays that consider connections between and among freedom, dialogue, and ethics, with a special focus on interfaith and interhuman perspectives.<br/> <br/>Topics of contributions may include, but are not limited to, scholarly explorations related to academic freedom, freedom of speech, liberation theology, dialogic perspectives on American democracy, and intercultural/intergroup/interpersonal relations.</p>
<p><strong>Timeline</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Submission deadline: July 1, 2024</li>
<li>Essays will be subject to two blind peer reviews.</li>
<li>Notification of status: September 1, 2024</li>
<li>Publication: <em>The Journal of Dialogic Ethics: Interfaith and Interhuman Perspectives </em>4, no. 1 (Spring 2025)</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Author Instructions</strong></p>
<p>Please submit full manuscripts as Microsoft Word documents to <a href="mailto:dialogicethics@duq.edu">dialogicethics@duq.edu</a>. </p>
<p>Two files should be sent:</p>
<ul>
<li>The first should include a cover page with name, current institutional affiliation, mailing address, email address, and a 75–100-word biography of the author(s).</li>
<li>The second should include the manuscript, a 100–150-word abstract, and 4–6 keywords. The manuscript should be 20–25 double-spaced pages in length, including references. Author name(s) should be completely removed from the manuscript and document properties.</li>
</ul>
<p>Manuscript formatting and citations should conform to the current edition of the <em>Chicago Manual of Style</em> (Author-Date References format). </p>
<p>Manuscripts submitted to the<em> Journal of </em><em>Dialogic Ethics: Interfaith and Interhuman Perspectives</em> should be original manuscripts not under review at another journal or publication.</p>
<p><strong>For more information, visit <a href="https://www.dialogic-ethics.org/submit.html.%C2%A0">https://www.dialogic-ethics.org/submit.html. </a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 21:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1704350223155949</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>5th Annual International Symposium on Festival Culture (ISFC)</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/12/22/5th-annual-international-symposium-on-festival-culture-isfc</link>
						<dc:creator>festival.culture.edu@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, January 4, 2024 - 12:38am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Journal of Festival Culture Inquiry and Analysis</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:festival.culture.edu@gmail.com">festival.culture.edu@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/general-announcements">general announcements</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/international-conferences">international conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/popular-culture">popular culture</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>February 18, 2024</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>Sensing Euphoric and Dysphoric Atmospheres</strong><br/>
</p><p>Our fifth annual event addresses the theme of ‘sensing euphoric and dysphoric atmospheres’ in festive, celebratory, and ritual cultures. Taking an embodied perspective, we focus on the role of corporeal perception in making sense of lived experience.</p>
<p>With regard to atmospheres, we focus on “the ways in which a multiplicity of bodies [are] part of, and entrenched in, a situation that encompasses it” (Riedel 2019:85). We aim to explore what existential phenomenology can reveal about carnivals, festivals, ceremonies, fetes, fairs, rituals, and other celebrations. Thus, exploring the euphoric and/or dysphoric atmospheres associated with these events and celebrations.</p>
<p>Our theme takes into account shared values, practices, customs, heritage, traditions, continuity, uniqueness, and differentiation within festive and celebratory culture. It is also important to consider the degree to which euphoria and dysphoria can be shared and learned, along with the camaraderie and familial aspects related to them.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Proposals may also address, but are not limited to, the following themes:</p>
<p>​</p>
<p>• Art, Craft, and Practice</p>
<p>• Carnivals (including Diasporic Carnivals)</p>
<p>• Celebration and Leisure</p>
<p>• Competition, Adjudication, and Legacy</p>
<p>• Costume and the Body</p>
<p>• Creative Industries</p>
<p>• Culture and Politics</p>
<p>• Dance and Performance </p>
<p>• Education</p>
<p>• Embodiment </p>
<p>• Events </p>
<p>• Food Culture </p>
<p>• Community Making (Re-making)</p>
<p>• Literature</p>
<p>• Medieval Culture</p>
<p>• Night Festivals</p>
<p>• Memory, Nostalgia, and Temporality</p>
<p>• Music and Sound </p>
<p>• Tradition and Heritage </p>
<p>• Religion</p>
<p>• Resistance, Resilience, and Activism</p>
<p>• Sporting Celebrations</p>
<p>• Tourism</p>
<p>​</p>
<p>Abstracts of up to 500-word (only abstracts/papers that have not been previously presented and published will be considered) and biographies of no more than 100 words (in Word .doc format). </p>
<p> </p>
<p>Key Dates: </p>
<p>500-word (Word doc. files only) Abstract Proposal Submission: 18th February 2024</p>
<p>​</p>
<p>Notification of Acceptance: 20th February 2024</p>
<p>​</p>
<p>Completed Presentation (optional) Deadline: 1st April 2024</p>
<p>​</p>
<p>ISFC registration will open in early 2024.</p>
<p>​</p>
<p>Symposium Date:  TBA.</p>
<p>​</p>
<p>Riedel, Friedlind, ‘Atmosphere’, in Affective Societies: Key Concepts, ed. by Jan Slaby and  ‎Christian von Scheve, eds. (New York: Routledge, 2019), pp. 85-95</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 02:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1704350223155948</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>International Conference on Myths, Archetypes and Symbols: &quot;Models and Alternatives&quot;</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/12/21/international-conference-on-myths-archetypes-and-symbols-models-and-alternatives</link>
						<dc:creator>LCIR</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, January 4, 2024 - 12:37am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>London Centre for Interdisciplinary Research</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:myths@lcir.co.uk">myths@lcir.co.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/international-conferences">international conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/online-conferences">online conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/world-literatures-and-indigenous-studies">world literatures and indigenous studies</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>April 15, 2024</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Humankind has always sought to explain its origins and the mysteries of life to map personal and collective boundaries, and to secure its sense of identity through the power of everyday events and occurrences. Exemplary accounts of imaginary happenings and supernatural creatures from a time beyond history and memory explain the genesis of the universe, the making of a living thing, the formation of an attitude or the inception of an institution. The essence of these traditional narratives reflects a certain system of values and code of self-conduct of a group of individuals bound together by social and cultural ties, and the cardinal virtues and vices of human nature captured in a conventional configuration.</p>
<p>Even though the time and place of performance and reception generate numerous variants and a multitude of interpretations, myths encode a universal sensibility and specificity, and propose generic yet unique models of humanity. They reveal a culture’s deepest understanding of its own beginnings, awareness of purpose and destiny, its position in the world, and meaning of existence and experience. A particular culture creates particular characters to embody its spirit and significant traits of personality, and particular images to convey its most representative attributes and attitudes.</p>
<p>The conference aims to explore the mode of organisation, the fundamental patterns and the paradigms of human memory that lie at the root of quintessential stories, tales and beings. It will also focus on the constants and variables of some particular components and their relationship with other fields of study, such as anthropology, arts, cultural history, literature, literary criticism, philosophy, psychology, pedagogy, sociology, theology, etc.</p>
<p>The main objective of the event is to bring together all those interested in examining the intersections between their professions and/or interests and some distinct local, regional, national, or global aspects related to myths and mythology, archetypal characters, situations and symbols, providing an integrative approach to their perception and relevance in the 21st century.</p>
<p>Topics include but are not limited to several core issues:</p>
<ul>
<li>from <em>The Age of Fable</em> to <em>The Golden Bough</em> and beyond</li>
<li>the functions and cultural impact of myths, archetypes and symbols</li>
<li>the locality and universality of myths, archetypes and symbols</li>
<li>monotheism, polytheism, pantheism</li>
<li>gods, demigods and heroes</li>
<li>myth, ritual and the sacred</li>
<li>holy books and early writings</li>
<li>myth-revision from antiquity to the 21st century</li>
<li>mythology and language</li>
<li>mythology and science</li>
<li>mythology and religion</li>
<li>mythology and visual arts</li>
<li>mythology and music</li>
<li>mass-media and myth creation</li>
<li>mythography and mythopesis</li>
<li>euhemerism – history and imagination</li>
<li>patterns, prototypes, stereotypes</li>
<li>ethos and eidos</li>
<li>Jungian archetypes</li>
<li>archetypal characters in literature and film</li>
<li>archetypal symbolism</li>
<li>archetypal psychology</li>
<li>archetypal pedagogy</li>
<li>symbols – context and meaning</li>
<li>major themes, motifs and symbols</li>
<li>the meaning and symbolism of colours</li>
<li>the meaning and symbolism of numbers</li>
<li>signs, emblems and icons</li>
<li>semiotics and symbolism</li>
</ul>
<p>Paper proposals up to 250 words and a brief biographical note should be sent<strong> </strong>to: <a href="mailto:myths@lcir.co.uk"><strong>myths@lcir.co.uk</strong></a>.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 20:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1704350223155947</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Institute on Theology and Disability 2024</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/12/20/institute-on-theology-and-disability-2024</link>
						<dc:creator>InstituteTheologyDisability</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, January 4, 2024 - 12:32am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Institute on Theology and Disability 2024</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:info@theologydisability.org">info@theologydisability.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>January 31, 2024</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>The Institute on Theology and Disability, hosted this year at Boston College and online in hybrid formats, invites submissions in the intersections of theology and disability. Open to academic papers in the intersection of theology, religion, interpretation, religious history, practical theology, HB/OT and NT, ethics, and disability/disability studies in any form (including mental health).<br/>Submissions are also welcome in the form of practical ministry workshops, which may include collaborative practices and group work (unlike traditional paper proposals).</p>
<p>Submission requires a 150 word summary and a 400-500 work abstract. Information can be found at <a href="https://faithanddisability.org/institute/">https://faithanddisability.org/institute/</a> which includes a link to the submission page. Virtual presenters are welcome!</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 03:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1704350223155946</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
