<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 12:19:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 12:19:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>Cambridge Yin-Cheng Distinguished Lecture Series | Professor Elena Valussi [16 May 14:00-15:30 BST]</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12804678/cambridge-yin-cheng-distinguished-lecture-series-professor</link>
						<dc:creator>Junfu Wong</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Event</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Chinese History / Studies, East Asian History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Anthropology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><b>Space, Place and Religious Identities in Sichuan: Two Case Studies of the Chunyang Guan </b><b>純陽觀</b><b> and the Yuwang Gong </b><b>禹王宮</b></p><p> </p><p><b>四川地區的空間、場所與宗教屬性：純陽觀與禹王宮的兩個案例研究</b></p><p><b> </b></p><p> </p><p><b><b>On May 16, Prof. Elena Valussi (Loyola University) will share with us insights from her ongoing research with two case studies of Sichuanese religious spaces. This event is taking place <b><u>in person</u></b> (a recording of the lecture will be made available at a later date). </b><b>Please come and join us!</b></b></p><p><br/><b>Speaker</b>: Elena Valussi (阿琳娜)</p><p> </p><p> </p><p><b>Discussant</b>: Noga Ganany (高諾佳)</p><p><b>Date: </b>May 16<sup>th</sup> (Tuesday) 2023</p><p><b>Time:</b> 14:00 BST</p><p><b>Venue: </b>Room 8-9, Faculty of Asian and Middle Eastern Studies (Sidgwick Avenue, Cambridge, CB3 9DA)</p><p> </p><p> </p><p> </p><p> </p><p><b><u>Abstract</u></b><b>:</b></p><p> </p><p>In investigating the religious traditions of Sichuan (and beyond), the diversity and hybridity of religious practices expressed in texts and rituals have emerged. This talk will address parallel questions of hybridity and religious identity through the historical analysis of two religious spaces. The first is the Chunyang guan 純陽觀 in Xinjin 新津. First imagined and built in the late Qing dynasty as a space devoted to the three religions, in fact it functioned as a fully religious space only for a short time. In the early to mid-twentieth century it was variously used as an orphanage and school, and is now a museum and tea house, while still holding a liminal religious significance. The second example comes from a preliminary investigation of several different guildhalls (huiguan 會館) in Sichuan.  Originally multivalent spaces representing the business interests and religious beliefs of migrant communities entering Sichuan in the mid Qing dynasty, after losing their supporting communities and undergoing various historical vicissitudes, many are now in disrepair, shifting from religious to secular spaces, or being re-assigned to a different religious tradition, often Buddhist. The case of the Yuwang gong 禹王宮 in Lizhuang 李莊, now the Huiguang si 慧光寺 Buddhist monastery, is emblematic. Because of their shifting and fragile identities, their movement from sacralized to secularized or viceversa, the spaces under investigation are undercategorized, thus overlooked, understudied and marginalized. These examples might help in the historical investigation of other shifting religious sites in different parts of China.</p><p> </p><p>在調研四川及其周邊地區宗教傳統的過程中，文本與儀式中的宗教實踐呈現出多樣性與混雜性的特徵。本次講座通過對兩個宗教空間的史料分析，探討混雜性與宗教属性的平行问题。第一個案例是新津的純陽觀。此觀建於晚清，最初被想像為一個尊崇三教的空間，但事實上它只在短時間內完全發揮宗教空間的功能。自二十世紀起，它成為一個多功能的場所，二十世紀初期至中期曾被用作孤兒院兼學校，現在是一個博物館兼茶館，儘管仍具備有限的宗教意義。第二個例子來自對四川幾個不同會館的初步調研。清中期移民群體進入四川，建造了代表他們商業利益和宗教信仰的多功能空間，後來這些空間失去支持群體，又歷經歲月變遷，現在很多都年久失修，從宗教空間轉變為世俗空間，或者重新被賦予另一種宗教傳統，通常是佛教傳統。李莊的禹王宮，現在的佛教聖地慧光寺，就是典型的案例。由於它們多變而脆弱的属性，以及世俗化或神聖化的轉變，我調研的這些空間沒有被合理歸類，因而也被邊緣化，疏於重視和研究。這些例子有助於從歷史學的角度研究中國各地其他處於變化中的宗教場所。</p><p> </p><p><b><u>About the Speaker</u></b><b>:</b></p><p>Elena Valussi is a senior Lecturer in the History Department at Loyola University Chicago. Her research and publications revolve around the intersection of gender, religion and body practices, Republican discourses on gender and religion, the intellectual history of Daoism, and spirit writing in Chinese history. She is also co-editor, with Matthias Schumann, of a soon to be published book: Communicating with the Gods: Spirit-writing in Chinese History and Society, Brill, where she wrote an article on gender and spirit writing. With prof. Stefania Travagnin, she is the co-director of a research project on religious diversity in Sichuan province funded by the CCK foundation. She has been visiting professor at the University of Venice, the Chinese University of Hong Kong and at the University of Erlangen-Nuremberg in Germany. She is the vice President of the Society for the Study of Chinese Religions. Her most recent articles include “Daoist Sexual Practices for Health and Immortality for Women” in Handbook of Chinese Medicine, ed. by Michael Stanley Baker and Vivienne Lo, London, Routledge, 2022;“Men Built Religion, Women Made it Superstitious: Gender and Superstition in Republican China”, Journal of Chinese Religions 48.1, 2020; “Gender as a Useful Category of Analysis in Chinese religions: with two Case Studies from the Republican Period”, in Critical Concepts and Methods for the Study of Chinese Religions III: Key Concepts in Practice, edited by Stefania Travagnin and Paul Katz, Leiden, De Gruyters, 2019.</p><p> </p><p>阿琳娜是芝加哥洛約拉大學歷史系的高級講師。她的研究和發表圍繞性別、宗教和身體實踐的交匯處，民國時期關於性別與宗教的論述，道教思想史，以及中國歷史上的扶乩傳統。她即將同馬蒂亞斯·舒曼一起編著並出版《與神對話：中國歷史與社會中的扶乩》（博睿出版社），此書收錄她一篇關於性別與扶乩的論文。她同史芬妮教授一同擔任四川宗教多樣性研究項目的負責人，該項目由蔣經國基金會贊助。她曾於威尼斯大學、香港中文大學及德國埃爾朗根-紐倫堡大學擔任客座教授。她目前也是中國宗教研究會（SSCR）的副主席。她最近的文章包括“為女性追求健康與長生的道教性實踐”，收錄於徐源、羅維前編《中藥指南》（倫敦：羅德里奇出版社，2022年）；“男子建了宗教而女子去迷信它：民國時期的性別與迷信”，《中國宗教》48卷1期，2020年；“性別作為分析中國宗教的重要範疇：民國時期的兩個案例研究”，收錄於史芬妮、康豹編《中國宗教研究中的學術概念與方法（三）：實踐中的關鍵概念》（萊頓：德古意特出版社，2019年）。</p><p> </p><p><b><u>About the Discussant</u></b><b>:</b></p><p>Noga Ganany is an Assistant Professor in the Study of Late Imperial China at the Faculty of Asian and Middle Eastern Studies at the University of Cambridge and a Fellow of Sidney Sussex College, Cambridge. Her main research interests are Chinese cultural history, religious practice in China, Chinese literature and book culture, travel and pilgrimage, and popular culture. She is currently writing a book titled Origin Narratives: Hagiographic Literature and Religious Practice in Late Ming China, which examines the role of commercial publishing in propagating cultic reverence of saints, gods, and immortals among lay readers. Dr Ganany is a board member of the Society for the Study of Chinese Religions (SSCR) and a board member of the Society for Ming Studies.</p><p> </p><p>高諾佳是劍橋大學亞洲與中東研究系的助理教授，從事明清研究；也是劍橋悉尼·蘇塞克斯學院的研究員。她主要的研究興趣包括中國文化史、中國宗教實踐、中國古代文學與書籍文化、旅行與朝覲、以及流行文化。她目前正在撰寫《出身傳：晚明中國聖人傳記文學與宗教實踐》一書，其中探討了商業出版對於在世俗讀者之間傳播聖、神、仙崇拜所發揮的作用。高博士目前也擔任中國宗教研究會（SSCR）的理事與明史研究會（Society for Ming Studies）的理事。</p><p> </p><p> </p><p>This lecture is part of the Yin-Cheng Distinguished Lecture Series on Buddhism, which is generously supported by the Tzu Chi Foundation and organised at the University of Cambridge by Dr Noga Ganany.</p><p> </p><p>Looking forward to seeing many of you there!</p><p> </p><p>Best wishes,</p><p> </p><p>Junfu Wong</p><p>Yizhuo Li</p><p>Ilay Golan</p><p> </p><p>Faculty of Asian and Middle Eastern Studies</p><p>University of Cambridge</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:jw2034@cam.ac.uk">jw2034@cam.ac.uk</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 20:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1683524234174289</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Currents: Local Practices and Popular Beliefs in Buddhism / 2023 Cambridge Graduate Student Conference on East Asian Studies</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12804398/currents-local-practices-and-popular-beliefs-buddhism-2023</link>
						<dc:creator>Ilay Golan</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-07-06T00:00:00-04:00">July 6, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-07-07T00:00:00-04:00">July 7, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Anthropology, Asian History / Studies, Chinese History / Studies, East Asian History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Like the flow of currents, the dissemination and diffusion of Buddhism in East Asian societies takes place in various directions. Robert E. Buswell Jr. conceptualises currents and countercurrents to describe the diverse regional strands of influence on the East Asian Buddhist tradition. Beside cross-regional developments, currents or subcurrents within a regional Buddhist tradition can manifest in the convergence and divergence between institutionalised teachings and local practices. Dominated mainly by lay people’s experiences of Buddhism, local practices and popular beliefs usually present a considerable degree of religious and cultural hybridity. Moreover, at a local level, religious rituals and liturgical performances are often integrated with vernacular genres of storytelling such as literature and drama. Since the inception of the eastward Buddhist missionary in the second or third century, some of these local currents prosper concomitantly with Buddhist monasteries that have been centres of regional learning and practice, while others are considered illegitimate and constantly banned by political authorities.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>This conference invites graduate students from the UK and Europe to submit proposals for presentations exploring local practices and popular beliefs in East Asian Buddhism. Topics include but are not limited to:</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span> </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>(1) Local practices and rural religions</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>(2) Vernacular literature, drama and ritual performance</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>(3) Lay ritual practices</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>(4) Universal themes underlying local beliefs </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>(5) Deification and the creation of local pantheons</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>(6) Demonisation and demonology in Buddhism</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>…</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>We also welcome submissions on other topics relevant to Buddhism and/or other faiths in East Asia.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span> </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The conference will take place in person at the University of Cambridge. There will be no hybrid arrangements. With the kind support from the Tzu Chi Foundation, we will be able to cover domestic travel costs within the UK and international travel up to 100 GBP, and provide accommodations for two nights at Cambridge.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Please submit your abstract (250-300 words) by <b><u>31 May 2023</u> </b>via </span></span></span><a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfVD5aLv3UxLbZqtZFy6paFCdOfQcEgGx-ib1mXWPqdUXoILg/viewform?usp=share_link" rel="nofollow"><span><span><span><span>this Google form</span></span></span></span></a><span><span><span>. Please include the following information in your proposal:</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span> </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>(1) Author(s)</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>(2) Affiliation</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>(3) Email</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>(4) Title</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>(5) Abstract</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>(6) Keywords (up to five)</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span> </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The final decision will be made by early June. Any queries can be addressed to Ilay Golan at </span></span></span><a href="mailto:ig411@cam.ac.uk"><span><span><span><span>ig411@cam.ac.uk</span></span></span></span></a><span><span><span>. </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The Tzu Chi Foundation's support of Buddhist Studies at the University of Cambridge is managed by Dr Noga Ganany. For more information, contact Dr Ganany at <a href="mailto:ng462@cam.ac.uk">ng462@cam.ac.uk</a>.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span> </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Best wishes,</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The Organizing committee: </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Ilay Golan (University of Cambridge)</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Yizhuo Li (University of Cambridge)</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Junfu Wong (University of Cambridge)</span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ig411@cam.ac.uk">ig411@cam.ac.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1fJTQoCKHQ6NmjNNH0z8vFTkWWcLkX2T2DkbxFoqwFC8/prefill" target="_blank">https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1fJTQoCKHQ6NmjNNH0z8vFTkWWcLkX2T2DkbxFoqwFC8/prefill</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 20:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1683524234174288</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ May 15, 2023] Conference talk or similar: Why is Dialectic Fragile?</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/111158</link>
						<description>Venue: Online<br/><br/>Speakers at this event: <br/>Ivan Boldyrev (Radboud University)<br/>Philipp Weber (Ruhr-Universität Bochum, Ruhr-Universität Bochum)<br/><br/><p><strong>[ONLINE COLLOQUIUM] Ivan Boldyrev (Radboud University of Nijmegen) @ The Athens Colloquium on Kant and German Idealism</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>The Athens Colloquium on Kant and German Idealism</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Department of Philosophy, University of Athens</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Monday <strong>15 May</strong> <strong>2023</strong>, 18:00 p.m. (Athens, Greece time)</p>
<p>(London 16:00, Berlin 17:00, Paris 17:00, Boston 11:00, Los Angeles</p>
<p>08:00)</p>
<p><strong><br/></strong></p>
<p><strong>Ivan Boldyrev (Radboud University of Nijmegen)</strong></p>
<p><em>Why is Dialectic Fragile?</em><em></em></p>
<p>Respondent: Philipp Weber (Bochum)</p>
<p>***To receive the paper to be discussed please contact Ioannis Trisokkas at <strong>idtrisokkas@philosophy.uoa.gr</strong> ***</p>
<p><strong>Organizers</strong>: Ioannis Trisokkas, Sebastian Stein, Stavros Panagiotou</p>
<p><strong>Webpage</strong>:https://sites.google.com/view/theathenscolloquium/home</p>
<p>For any enquiries please contact Ioannis Trisokkas (<strong>idtrisokkas@philosophy.uoa.gr</strong>).</p>
<p><strong>WEBEX LINK</strong></p>
<p>https://uoa.webex.com/uoa/j.php?MTID=m50399c2b5498d3d80f40ba5b1ea07bc8</p>
<p>Meeting number (access code): 2734 963 0088</p>
<p>Meeting password: GqsJjTx8J33</p>
<p><strong><u>IVAN BOLDYREV</u></strong></p>
<p>Ivan Boldyrev is Assistant Professor at Radboud University Nijmegen. He is the author of <em>Ernst Bloch and His Contemporaries</em> (2014); <em>Hegel, Institutions and Economics</em> (with Carsten Herrmann-Pillath, 2014); and <em>Die Ohnmacht des Spekulativen: Elemente einer Poetik von Hegels</em> Phänomenologie des Geistes (2021). He also recently co-edited, with Sebastian Stein, <em>Interpreting</em> <em>Hegel’s</em> Phenomenology of Spirit (2021). Apart from German Idealism and critical theory, he also works on the history and philosophy of economics. </p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 05:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1683437826879795</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>ICHSS 2024 : 2024 10th International Conference on Humanity and Social Sciences (ICHSS 2024)</title>
			<link>http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=173593&amp;copyownerid=13881</link>
						<description>2024 10th International Conference on Humanity and Social Sciences (ICHSS 2024) [Nagoya, Japan] [Jan 5, 2024 - Jan 7, 2024]</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 05:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1683351429757640</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ November 17, 2023 -  November 19, 2023] Conference or similar: Performance: 10th Annual International Conference of the Centre for Phenomenology in South Africa</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/111061</link>
						<description>Venue: University of Johannesburg<br/><br/><p>The conference aims to explore the role of performance in philosophy, psychoanalysis, and the arts, and to examine its relevance in contemporary thought.  </p>

<p>Performance can be viewed in various ways, including in terms of the distinction, common to French authors in the 1960s, between the enunciated statement and the act of enunciation or speech act. This concept is central to the work of Foucault’s archeology, Lacan’s post-structuralist rehabilitation of the psychoanalytic tradition, and feminist theory, especially the work on performativity by Judith Butler and other fourth wave feminist theorists. Performance is also an enduring and crucial topic in dance and theatre studies. In addition, it has attracted significant attention in the philosophy of education.   </p>

<p>This conference will address various topics related to performance, such as the links between performance and gender studies, performance and the unconscious, performance and the body in dance and theatre, and the therapeutic value of performance. It will explore questions like how performance helps to account for the shift from structuralism to post-structuralism, and how performativity constitutes a sufficiently plastic concept in feminist theory. </p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 05:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1683265033286316</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ July 27, 2023 -  August 3, 2023] Conference or similar: Experiencing Liminal Spaces in Feminist Philosophy - Nordic Summer University</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/111085</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p>How to act from a place of not-knowing? Can we take ourselves seriously while not relying on the categories of thought that have repressed and excluded ‘others’? How can we learn to listen to what we don’t already know? These are questions that need to be addressed by feminist philosophy, in order to open up space within an otherwise fixed reality. We question the rigidity of language, of subject-object relations. Instead, we want to ask what is needed to think ‘thinking’ again? What happens when I relate to a(n) (m)Other? What does this othering accomplish, besides reaffirming the concepts of subject and object? Is there a way to be with what is not-me? Can we build bridges to relate to others that will enable us to be in liminal spaces? If we can, would that mean inventing impossible ways to relate that put in question what is knowledge, language, empathy, compassion? How to be present in a place that cannot be named? How to understand, and stay with what Derrida called the impossibility of witnessing what we ourselves survive?</p>
<p>“How is it possible that an event is, and is not? How can any event, properly called, be nothing? And yet… (...) the nature of miscarriage in (...) society. It both is and is not. It is both a source of acknowledged pain and suffering, and one swept easily away with ‘you can always try again’ or ‘it could be worse’.”</p>
<p>Derrida pointed at the “disturbing complicity between fiction and testimony”. Is this why there are so many contemporary speculative fictional accounts of motherhood and pregnancy, because there is no other way to address that particular liminal space? Is this what Hannah Arendt meant when she wrote: “The less we are free to decide who we are or to live as we like, the more we try to put up a front, to hide the facts, and to play roles.”</p>
<p>At the core of this seminar is an invitation to experience the liminal space of the in-between. “Liminal space is a place of ambiguity and anxiety, of no-longer and not-yet”, according to Ronald Carson. It is also a matrixial borderspace, and a witnessing of what cannot be witnessed. A liminal space is something that can emerge between me and you, between me and the world, and between me and myself. How to witness it? How to think it? How to write it? And how to investigate this together?</p>
<p>We especially invite workshops and shared practices to experience these liminal spaces, through listening, writing, being, investigating, thinking together. We look forward to taking the time together to stay with the anxiety of the ambiguity of a liminal space, a threshold that is not taking a position - yet. </p>
<p><strong><br/></strong>About the NSU Summer Session</p>
<p>One week long seminar in a space shared with eight other study circles investigating topics ranging from whiteness to Nordic environmental ethics, from ‘Racialisation, Objectification, Dehumanisation: Missionary and Merchant in the Mongolian Empire’ to ‘What a waste: surplus art, theory and tékhnē’. While we will host our own program during the week, and investigate the liminal space through philosophical workshops organised by the coordinators and participants alike, we will also be able to actively search out collaboration with and join the program of other circles present during the NSU Summer Session. </p>
<p>Please be aware that Nordic Summer University is a horizontal organisation fully run by volunteers and with minimum funding. During the NSU Summer Session members are invited to join the General Assembly to discuss and take decisions regarding the future (study) program of NSU. </p>
<p>Registration and fee</p>
<p>All prices include NSU membership, full accommodation and food for the whole week:</p>
<p>– single rooms for 575 euros per person.</p>
<p>– double/twin rooms for 425 euro per person.</p>
<p>– family rooms for 950 euros (family of 4).</p>
<p>(see https://www.nsuweb.org/activities/summer-session/ for more information)</p>
<p>The rooms are all equipped with their own private bathroom (shared with only the people in the room). All rooms at Vyturys Hotel are of modest to good quality. The rooms include bed linen and towels, and all food is also included in the price. The cost includes accommodation for the week, 3 meals and 2 coffee breaks a day, and access to the full NSU program during the summer session. Participation in the summer session requires NSU membership (included in the prices mentioned above).</p>
<p>Partial scholarships may be available, please contact the coordinators for more information. </p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 05:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1683265033286315</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ August 18, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Performance: 10th Annual International Conference of the Centre for Phenomenology in South Africa</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/111065</link>
						<description><p>The 10th Annual International Conference of the Centre for Phenomenology in South Africa is pleased to invite submissions for its upcoming event on the theme of performance, to be held from 17-19 of November 2023 at the University of Johannesburg, South Africa. The conference aims to explore the role of performance in philosophy, psychoanalysis, and the arts, and to examine its relevance in contemporary thought. </p>
<p>Performance can be viewed in various ways, including in terms of the distinction, common to French authors in the 1960s, between the enunciated statement and the act of enunciation or speech act. This concept is central to the work of Foucault’s archeology, Lacan’s post-structuralist rehabilitation of the psychoanalytic tradition, and feminist theory, especially the work on performativity by Judith Butler and other fourth wave feminist theorists. Performance is also an enduring and crucial topic in dance and theatre studies. In addition, it has attracted significant attention in the philosophy of education.   </p>
<p>This conference will address various topics related to performance, such as the links between performance and gender studies, performance and the unconscious, performance and the body in dance and theatre, and the therapeutic value of performance. It will explore questions like how performance helps to account for the shift from structuralism to post-structuralism, and how performativity constitutes a sufficiently plastic concept in feminist theory.</p>
<p>Topics of the conference include, but are not limited to:</p>
<p>·       Performance, language, and speech act theory;</p>
<p>·       Enunciated/enunciation within Foucault’s archaeology and Lacan’s psychoanalysis;</p>
<p>·       Performance and life in Nietzsche and Artaud and their interpreters;</p>
<p>·       Performance and theatre, including the therapeutic value of performance;</p>
<p>·       The relation between theatre and dance as kinds of performance;</p>
<p>·       Performance and feminisms;</p>
<p>·       Perception and understanding a performance;</p>
<p>·       Performative acts and gender constitution;</p>
<p>·       Rituals and performativity;</p>
<p>·       Performance and pedagogies.</p>
<p><strong><u>Submission</u></strong>:</p>
<p>Please send a 700 word abstract for blind review to <a href="mailto:ujphenomenology@gmail.com">ujphenomenology@gmail.com</a>. The full paper should be no more than 3000-3500 words for a 30-35 min. presentation. Proposals for panel discussion are also welcome.</p>
<p>The deadline for submission of abstracts is Friday the 18th of August 2023.</p>
<p><strong><u>Conference fees</u></strong>:</p>
<p>The conference fee for 3 days is R750 whereas for 1 day it is R300. Students should apply for a bursary or a reduction. The conference will be hybrid.</p>
<p>For more information about the conference, please visit the website of the Centre for Phenomenology in South Africa: <a href="https://saphenomenology.wordpress.com/">https://saphenomenology.wordpress.com</a>. Alternatively, please contact one of the organizers: Rafael Winkler (<a href="mailto:rwinkler@uj.ac.za">rwinkler@uj.ac.za</a>), Catherine Botha (<a href="mailto:cbotha@uj.ac.za">cbotha@uj.ac.za</a>) or Abraham Olivier (<a href="mailto:aolivier@ufh.ac.za">aolivier@ufh.ac.za</a>).  </p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 05:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1683265033286314</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ June 1, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Experiencing Liminal Spaces in Feminist Philosophy - Nordic Summer University</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/111089</link>
						<description><p>How to act from a place of not-knowing? Can we take ourselves seriously while not relying on the categories of thought that have repressed and excluded ‘others’? How can we learn to listen to what we don’t already know? These are questions that need to be addressed by feminist philosophy, in order to open up space within an otherwise fixed reality. We question the rigidity of language, of subject-object relations. Instead, we want to ask what is needed to think ‘thinking’ again? What happens when I relate to a(n) (m)Other? What does this othering accomplish, besides reaffirming the concepts of subject and object? Is there a way to be with what is not-me? Can we build bridges to relate to others that will enable us to be in liminal spaces? If we can, would that mean inventing impossible ways to relate that put in question what is knowledge, language, empathy, compassion? How to be present in a place that cannot be named? How to understand, and stay with what Derrida called the impossibility of witnessing what we ourselves survive?</p>
<p>“How is it possible that an event is, and is not? How can any event, properly called, be nothing? And yet… (...) the nature of miscarriage in (...) society. It both is and is not. It is both a source of acknowledged pain and suffering, and one swept easily away with ‘you can always try again’ or ‘it could be worse’.”</p>
<p>Derrida pointed at the “disturbing complicity between fiction and testimony”. Is this why there are so many contemporary speculative fictional accounts of motherhood and pregnancy, because there is no other way to address that particular liminal space? Is this what Hannah Arendt meant when she wrote: “The less we are free to decide who we are or to live as we like, the more we try to put up a front, to hide the facts, and to play roles.”</p>
<p>At the core of this seminar is an invitation to experience the liminal space of the in-between. “Liminal space is a place of ambiguity and anxiety, of no-longer and not-yet”, according to Ronald Carson. It is also a matrixial borderspace, and a witnessing of what cannot be witnessed. A liminal space is something that can emerge between me and you, between me and the world, and between me and myself. How to witness it? How to think it? How to write it? And how to investigate this together?</p>
<p>We especially invite workshops and shared practices to experience these liminal spaces, through listening, writing, being, investigating, thinking together. We look forward to taking the time together to stay with the anxiety of the ambiguity of a liminal space, a threshold that is not taking a position - yet. </p>
<p><strong><br/></strong>About the NSU Summer Session</p>
<p>One week long seminar in a space shared with eight other study circles investigating topics ranging from whiteness to Nordic environmental ethics, from ‘Racialisation, Objectification, Dehumanisation: Missionary and Merchant in the Mongolian Empire’ to ‘What a waste: surplus art, theory and tékhnē’. While we will host our own program during the week, and investigate the liminal space through philosophical workshops organised by the coordinators and participants alike, we will also be able to actively search out collaboration with and join the program of other circles present during the NSU Summer Session. </p>
<p>Please be aware that Nordic Summer University is a horizontal organisation fully run by volunteers and with minimum funding. During the NSU Summer Session members are invited to join the General Assembly to discuss and take decisions regarding the future (study) program of NSU. </p>
<p>Registration and fee</p>
<p>All prices include NSU membership, full accommodation and food for the whole week:</p>
<p>– single rooms for 575 euros per person.</p>
<p>– double/twin rooms for 425 euro per person.</p>
<p>– family rooms for 950 euros (family of 4).</p>
<p>(see https://www.nsuweb.org/activities/summer-session/ for more information)</p>
<p>The rooms are all equipped with their own private bathroom (shared with only the people in the room). All rooms at Vyturys Hotel are of modest to good quality. The rooms include bed linen and towels, and all food is also included in the price. The cost includes accommodation for the week, 3 meals and 2 coffee breaks a day, and access to the full NSU program during the summer session. Participation in the summer session requires NSU membership (included in the prices mentioned above).</p>
<p>Partial scholarships may be available, please contact the coordinators for more information. </p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 05:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1683265033286313</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Afro-Christian Convention: The Fifth Stream of the United Church of Christ</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12800205/afro-christian-convention-fifth-stream-united-church-christ</link>
						<dc:creator>Lauren Lemley</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Event</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-05-30T00:00:00-04:00">May 30, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>African American History / Studies, American History / Studies, Black History / Studies, Race / Ethnic Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><strong>Join us for a virtual discussion with editor Rev. Dr. Yvonne Delk to celebrate the publication of <a href="https://www.thepilgrimpress.com/products/afro-christian-convention-the-fifth-stream-of-the-united-church-of-christ" rel="nofollow"><em>The Afro-Christian Convention: The Fifth Stream of the United Church of Christ</em></a>.</strong></span></p><p><span><strong>The holy stream of African spirituality that flowed across the Atlantic Ocean and up into the tidewaters of Virginia in 1619—the same stream that overflowed into the worship and work of the United Church of Christ—is celebrated and given its long-overdue place in the canon of UCC history by Rev. Dr. Delk and contributors to this important volume.</strong></span></p><p><span><strong>The story of the Afro-Christian Convention is one of faith, survival, and empowerment in the hostile environment of racism. From 1892 to the 1960s, the Afro-Christian Convention was composed of 150 churches and 25,000 members, located primarily in North Carolina and Virginia. In June 1957, when the founding/merging leaders of the new United Church of Christ processed through Cleveland, representation of the Afro-Christian Convention churches was folded into the representation of the Convention of the South—a 1950s initiative of the Congregational Christian denomination to fold Black churches of the South into a single conference.</strong></span></p><p><span><strong>But the spirit, worldview, worship, and impact of Afro-Christian Convention churches are not appropriately represented under the banner of the Congregational stream of UCC history, a stream informed predominantly by white perspective. The Afro-Christian Convention, born from the wellspring of independent Black churches with deep African rootedness, is rightly understood—and at last shared—as a unique stream.</strong></span></p><p><span><strong>The event is free to all, but registration is required via this link: </strong></span><a href="https://us06web.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_xK9oTvDzSTaMznySibQ2zA" rel="nofollow"><span><strong>https://us06web.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_xK9oTvDzSTaMznySibQ2zA</strong></span></a></p><p><span><strong>After registering, you will receive a confirmation email containing information about joining the webinar.</strong></span></p><p><span><strong>For more information, please email <a href="mailto:info@14beacon.org?subject=The%20Afro-Christian%20Convention">info@14beacon.org</a>.</strong></span></p><p><br/><span><strong>SPEAKER BIO</strong></span></p><p><span><strong>The Rev. Dr. Yvonne V. Delk</strong> has served for sixty years as an educator, preacher, organizer, and prophetic voice leading the fight for human and civil rights for people of color, children, and the poor throughout five continents. She is currently a member of the Board of Trustees for Franklinton Center at Bricks, and lives in Norfolk, Virginia.</span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Lauren Lemley<br/>Communications Manager<br/>Congregational Library &amp; Archives</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:info@14beacon.org">info@14beacon.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.congregationallibrary.org/events/afrochristianconvention" target="_blank">https://www.congregationallibrary.org/events/afrochristianconvention</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 03:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1683265033286312</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ June 14, 2023] Conference or similar: Hyperdigital Designs</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/111009</link>
						<description>Venue: Alison Richards Building, 7 West Road (Sidgwick Site)<br/><br/><p>Digital technologies have become a deeply integrated aspect of our lives. From speaking to friends and ordering food to finding our way around, all our daily acts are now mediated by the digital. This deep integration promises to expand our agency, yet it also shapes and constrains it in ways that we may not recognise or welcome. Increasingly, we are confronted with a dilemma: either to withdraw from or engage with the use of digital technologies, as these often tend to disperse our attention and hinder our self-awareness. In the space of possibilities between anti-technological suspicions and anti-human desires for assimilation, we aim to critically reflect on the creative origins and free use of the cybernetic grammar of digital computers.</p>
<p>The ‘Hyperdigital Designs’ workshop at the University of Cambridge will explore creative reflections upon the grammar of digital computers. Building upon the collaborative ‘How to Play with Fire’ project that began at the 2022 Diverse Intelligence Summer Institute, the ‘Hyperdigital’ announces a higher reflection on the creation and use of digital media for human freedom. Beyond the fixed opposition between the Postdigital and the Digital, the Hyperdigital exceeds so as more radically to enter and accelerate the free use of the digital — whether among the creators of digital systems, or from the oldest creator of the idea of the digital itself.</p>
<p>We invite abstracts of up to 250 words for a one-day workshop on Wednesday 14 June 2023 at the University of Cambridge, Alison Richards Building SG2, hosted by Cambridge Digital Humanities and co-sponsored by the William Temple Foundation, to explore interdisciplinary perspectives on thinking beyond the digital at its highest point. We are interested to host talks that explore the fundamental theoretical questions of philosophy, theology, ethics, and art, as well as applied and practical discussions concerning how technologies or designs, from video games to generative artificial intelligence, can be envisioned to mediate and emancipate human creativity.</p>
<p>Send abstracts 250 words or less to HyperdigitalDesigns@gmail.com</p>
<p>Deadline for abstracts: Saturday 13 May 2023</p>
<p>Notice: Monday 15 May 2023</p>
<p>www.howtoplaywithfire.com </p></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 05:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1683178627986773</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ September 30, 2023] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/111029</link>
						<description>Publication Name: Essay Prize: Is Consciousness Fundamental?<br/><br/><p>Essay Prize: Is Consciousness Fundamental?</p>
<p>Submissions are welcome for an essay prize on the question of whether consciousness is a fundamental feature of the universe that is part of the John Templeton Foundation funded project, “Panpsychism and Pan(en)theism: Philosophy of Mind Meets Philosophy of Relligion,” led by Philip Goff (Durham University) and Andrei A. Buckareff (Marist College) (information about the project can be found here: https://www.templeton.org/grant/panpsychism-and-panentheism-philosophy-of-mind-meets-philosophy-of-religion). We welcome submissions that defend or critique panpsychism (understood broadly to include both micropsychism and cosmopsychism as well as panprotopsychism). Additionally, authors are welcome to submit papers on panpsychism that approach it from within various philosophical sub-disciplines beyond the philosophy of mind, including papers that examine panpsychism in the philosophy of religion, philosophy of physics, and axiology. We also welcome submissions that focus on panpsychism in the history of philosophy. Submissions may be single-authored or co-authored.</p>
<p>The winning submission will appear in a special issue of the <em>Journal of Consciousness Studies </em>and will be made available open-access. Additionally, the author(s) of the prize will be awarded £1000.</p>
<p>Submissions should be no longer than 8000 words (including notes and references). Authors should prepare their submissions for blind review and include a cover sheet with their name, institutional affiliation (if they have one), and contact information.</p>
<p>The deadline for submissions is the 30th of September 2023. The winner will be announced by the 30th of October 2023. Submissions should be sent with “Panpsychism Essay Submission” in the subject line to .</p></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 05:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1683178627986772</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Materializing Transparency</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12795440/materializing-transparency</link>
						<dc:creator>Ruth Ezra</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Workshop</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-05-26T00:00:00-04:00">May 26, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Switzerland</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Art, Art History &amp; Visual Studies, Film and Film History, History of Science, Medicine, and Technology, Medieval and Byzantine History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The history of transparency can be summed up as a progression in materials from the mined to the man-made: by the early modern period, rock crystal and alabaster — celebrated in the ancient and medieval worlds for their vitreousness and translucency — could no longer compete with the increasingly reliable clarity of factory-produced flint glass, which would in turn cede its primacy as see-through matter to that of manufactured plastics, made fully synthetic by 1907. Tracing but also challenging such a narrative of technological change and obsolescence, this workshop investigates the possibilities and limitations of transparency in all its material instantiations, and from perspectives both transhistorical and theoretical. Case studies include gauze, celluloid, varnish, openwork caskets, optical lenses, polaroid film, mordants, and witch balls. Taking these examples as starting points for wide-ranging discussion, we will think together about how the physical properties of a clear substrate, glaze, or surface might prompt reflection on concepts such as in/visibility, opacity, transcendency, distortion, obstinancy (<em>Eigensinn</em>), racialization, disclosure, and access.</p><p>Scheduled to coincide with the release of two important new books on transparency, <a href="https://press.uchicago.edu/ucp/books/book/chicago/V/bo183106455.html" rel="nofollow"><em>The Varnish and the Glaze: Painting Splendor with Oil, 1100-1500</em></a> (Chicago, 2023), by Marjolijn Bol, and <em><a href="https://yalebooks.yale.edu/book/9780300237245/transparency/" rel="nofollow">Transparency: The Material History of an Idea</a></em> (Yale, 2023), by Daniel Jütte, this workshop engages with current scholarship in the history of art, science, architecture, religion, museology, and conservation. </p><p>Supported by eikones, the NOMIS Foundation, and the Paul Mellon Centre for Studies in British Art.</p><p>-------</p><p>Program<strong> </strong></p><p>Location: Forum eikones, Rheinsprung 11, 4051 Basel</p><p>From 08:30 - Welcome - coffee in the foyer</p><p>09:00 - Ruth Ezra, Introduction</p><p>09:20 - Patrick Crowley, ‘The Wrong Side of Things’: Roman Reverse-Engraved Glass</p><p>10:00 - Manuela Beer, Difference in Transparency: Rock Crystal in Medieval Artefacts</p><p>10:40 - Coffee break</p><p>11:00 - Arne Leopold, Veiling the Gaze, Veiling the Material: Openwork Caskets and the Pretence of Transparency in the 13th Century</p><p>11:40 - Leena Crasemann, Veiling Space: Textiles’ Anti-matter</p><p>12:20 - Lunch break</p><p>13:20 - Elizabeth Rice Mattison, Acid, Water, Rust, and Process in Dürer’s Etchings</p><p>14:00 - Phillip Roberts, Richard Reeve and Alice Grove: A Night Language</p><p>14:40 - Coffee break</p><p>15:00 - Jennifer Y. Chuong, Tricky Transparency: Witch Balls in Nineteenth-Century America</p><p>15:40 - Yanning Ma, Can a picture be a terrarium? Transparency, vitality, and confinement in Victorian Britain (presenting online)</p><p>16:20 - Coffee break</p><p>16:40 - Kirsty Sinclair Dootson, Celluloid Skin: Transparency, Sensitivity, and the Racialization of Film</p><p>17:20 - Aïcha Revellat, So Transparent, So Opaque: Hannah Villiger’s Early Polaroid Pictures</p><p>18:00 - Comfort break</p><p>18:15 - Book talk: Marjolijn Bol, The Varnish and the Glaze (Chicago 2023), in conversation</p><p>19:00 - Apéro</p><p>NB. The workshop is open to all and no registration is required to join in person; papers will not be streamed online.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Ruth Ezra, NOMIS Fellow and eikones, University of Basel</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ruth.ezra@unibas.ch">ruth.ezra@unibas.ch</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://eikones.philhist.unibas.ch/en/news/events/event-details/materializing-transparency/" target="_blank">https://eikones.philhist.unibas.ch/en/news/events/event-details/materializing-transparency/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 17:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1683178627986771</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – May 3, 2023</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-may-3-2023/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find 6 new job opportunities, 1 Fellowship, 17 Call for Papers, and 7 upcoming conferences/speakers.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 33!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Postdoc in the Department of Textual, Historic, and Systematic Studies of Judaism and Christianity</h4>



<p>Radbound University Nijmegen, Netherlands</p>



<p>Deadline: May 5, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://twitter.com/nt4ox/status/1649322079484018689?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw">https://twitter.com/nt4ox/status/1649322079484018689?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Curator of Asian Art (Ph.D. not required)</h4>



<p>Princeton University Art Museum</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://puwebp.princeton.edu/AcadHire/apply/application.xhtml?listingId=30001">https://puwebp.princeton.edu/AcadHire/apply/application.xhtml?listingId=30001</a></p>



<h4>Jewish Life Coordinator (MA or Ph.D.)</h4>



<p>Ursinus College, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.ursinus.edu/live/profiles/6534-jewish-life-coordinator">https://www.ursinus.edu/live/profiles/6534-jewish-life-coordinator</a></p>



<h4>Associate Director, Abbasi Program in Islamic Studies (Ph.D. not required)</h4>



<p>Stanford, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careersearch.stanford.edu/jobs/associate-director-abbasi-program-in-islamic-studies-21213">https://careersearch.stanford.edu/jobs/associate-director-abbasi-program-in-islamic-studies-21213</a></p>



<h4>Visiting Assistant Professor – Philosophy and Religion (full-time, 1-year appointment, Ph.D. not required)</h4>



<p>Worcester Polytechnic Institute, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://wpi.wd5.myworkdayjobs.com/WPI_External_Career_Site/job/Worcester/Visiting-Assistant-Professor---Philosophy-and-Religion_R0002397">https://wpi.wd5.myworkdayjobs.com/WPI_External_Career_Site/job/Worcester/Visiting-Assistant-Professor—Philosophy-and-Religion_R0002397</a></p>



<h4>Lecturer in Philosophy/Religion (1-year appointment, possibility of renewal)</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://twitter.com/jlgittinger/status/1653086049650851873?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw">https://twitter.com/jlgittinger/status/1653086049650851873?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw</a></p>



<h4>Minerva Recruitment Job Listings Cite (with areas specifically tailored for Ph.D.)</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://minerva-recruitment.com/">Minerva Recruitment – Higher Education Graduate Jobs, UK &amp; Worldwide (minerva-recruitment.com)</a></p>



<h4>AAR/SBL Job Forum</h4>



<p><a href="https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search">https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search</a></p>



<h2>Fellowships:</h2>



<h4>Marie Skladowska-Curie Actions Fellowships</h4>



<p>Deadline: September 13, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://marie-sklodowska-curie-actions.ec.europa.eu/calls/msca-postdoctoral-fellowships-2023">https://marie-sklodowska-curie-actions.ec.europa.eu/calls/msca-postdoctoral-fellowships-2023</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>Sexual Violence in Muslim Communities: Towards Awareness and Accountability</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/u/1/d/1kwoSCRPwtmPiArcDNHcS7YiziTBQ-BH1Z6cfWQj6m_I/mobilebasic">https://docs.google.com/document/u/1/d/1kwoSCRPwtmPiArcDNHcS7YiziTBQ-BH1Z6cfWQj6m_I/mobilebasic</a></p>



<h4>The Sociological Review</h4>



<p>Date: June 17, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://thesociologicalreview.org/announcements/calls/the-sociological-review-monographs-call-for-expressions-of-interest/">https://thesociologicalreview.org/announcements/calls/the-sociological-review-monographs-call-for-expressions-of-interest/</a></p>



<h4>Religions: Whither Spirituality?</h4>



<p>Deadline: August 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12741975/special-issue-religions-whither-spirituality">Special Issue of Religions: Whither Spirituality? | H-Announce | H-Net</a></p>



<h4>Shifting Perspectives on Muslimness and Islam in Contemporary Fictions</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12746280/shifting-perspectives-muslimness-and-islam-contemporary">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12746280/shifting-perspectives-muslimness-and-islam-contemporary</a></p>



<h4>Theology, Religion, and Watchmen</h4>



<p>Deadline: June 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/xcDsZWvj5y">https://t.co/xcDsZWvj5y</a></p>



<h4>4<sup>th</sup> Graduate Colloquium in Middle Eastern and Ottoman Studies</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 20, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12747560/4th-graduate-colloquium-middle-eastern-and-ottoman-studies">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12747560/4th-graduate-colloquium-middle-eastern-and-ottoman-studies</a></p>



<h4>Jerusalem Studies in Religion and Culture:</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://twitter.com/brill_religious/status/1650439823428050944?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw">https://twitter.com/brill_religious/status/1650439823428050944?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw</a></p>



<h4>9<sup>th</sup> International Conference on Spirituality and Psychology</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=173351&amp;copyownerid=31491">http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=173351&amp;copyownerid=31491</a></p>



<h4>Women in Judaism: Call for Book Reviewers</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12754504/women-judaism-call-book-reviewers">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12754504/women-judaism-call-book-reviewers</a></p>



<h4>Living Islam in Nigeria: Muslim Experiences in a Postcolonial State</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12760612/living-islam-nigeria-muslim-experiences-postcolonial-state">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12760612/living-islam-nigeria-muslim-experiences-postcolonial-state</a></p>



<h4>Review of Religious Research:</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.rraweb.org/journal-review-of-religious-research/call-for-papers/">https://www.rraweb.org/journal-review-of-religious-research/call-for-papers/</a></p>



<h4>Midwest Jewish Studies Association Annual Conference</h4>



<p>Deadline: June 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12769491/call-papers-midwest-jewish-studies-association-annual">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12769491/call-papers-midwest-jewish-studies-association-annual</a></p>



<h4>After Disaster: Southeast Regional Conference on Christianity and Literature</h4>



<p>Deadline: August 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/04/25/after-disaster-southeast-regional-conference-on-christianity-and-literature">https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/04/25/after-disaster-southeast-regional-conference-on-christianity-and-literature</a></p>



<h4>Zero-Hour: Rethinking 1945 from Jewish Transnational Perspectives – An Interdisciplinary Workshop</h4>



<p>Deadline: July 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12774390/call-papers-zero-hour-rethinking-1945-jewish-transnational">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12774390/call-papers-zero-hour-rethinking-1945-jewish-transnational</a></p>



<h4>Australian Journal of Jewish Studies</h4>



<p>Deadline: June 29, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12775273/australian-journal-jewish-studies-volume-xxxvi-2023">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12775273/australian-journal-jewish-studies-volume-xxxvi-2023</a></p>



<h4>Postclassical Philosophy in the Muslim World: A Symposium on Fakhr al-Din al-Razi</h4>



<p>Deadline: August 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12778902/cfp-symposium-fakhr-al-din-al-razi-d-6061210">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12778902/cfp-symposium-fakhr-al-din-al-razi-d-6061210</a></p>



<h4>“Europes” in Margins</h4>



<p>Deadline: June 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: philevents.org/event/show/110925</p>



<h2>Conferences:</h2>



<h4>Ecology, Extraction, and Religion</h4>



<p>UC Santa Barbara</p>



<p>Date: May 4, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://twitter.com/verstimmungen/status/1648032422221725696?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw">https://twitter.com/verstimmungen/status/1648032422221725696?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw</a></p>



<h4>Land, Law, Religion and Reconciliation: A Colloquium</h4>



<p>University of Victoria, Canada</p>



<p>Date: May 4-6, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://twitter.com/uvicreligionews/status/1648817601928384512?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw">https://twitter.com/uvicreligionews/status/1648817601928384512?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw</a></p>



<h4>2023 Annual Meeting of the Canadian Society of Christian Philosophers</h4>



<p>York University, Canada</p>



<p>Date: June 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/110689">https://philevents.org/event/show/110689</a></p>



<h4>American Academy of Religion Annual Meeting (Early Bird Rates)</h4>



<p>San Antonio, USA</p>



<p>Date: November 18-21, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/FkQeOZ1WbZ">https://t.co/FkQeOZ1WbZ</a></p>



<h4>British &amp; Irish Association for Practical Theology Annual Conference 2023</h4>



<p>United Kingdom</p>



<p>Date: June 11-13, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12769143/british-irish-association-practical-theology-annual-conference">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12769143/british-irish-association-practical-theology-annual-conference</a></p>



<h4>Jessica Zu, “Karma and Structural (In)justice: Buddhist Social Philosophy in Modern Asia”</h4>



<p>Online</p>



<p>Date: May 9-10, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12773779/jessica-zu-%E2%80%9Ckarma-and-structural-injustice-buddhist-social">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12773779/jessica-zu-%E2%80%9Ckarma-and-structural-injustice-buddhist-social</a></p>



<h4>Between Healthcare Practitioners and Clergy: Evangelicals and COVID-19 Vaccine Hesitancy</h4>



<p>Online</p>



<p>Date: May 19, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://twitter.com/religresearch/status/1653021456798711809?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw">https://twitter.com/religresearch/status/1653021456798711809?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1683178627986770</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ January 16, 2024 -  January 18, 2024] Conference or similar: Imam Reza (PBUH) and Interreligious Dialogue</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/110949</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p>Astan Quds Razavi’s Foundation of Islamic Researches in collaboration with Imam Sadiq University and various Iranian and international academic and religious centers will hold the international conference on “Imam Reza (PBUH) and Interreligious Dialogue” in January 2024. This conference aims to create an atmosphere for dialogue and peaceful coexistence between the followers of different religions and denominations, to strengthen scientific interaction between the scholars of different religions and denominations, to strengthen the scientific interaction between Iranian and International religious institutions, to laying a groundwork for Intellectual cooperation between different religions and denominations on contemporary social challenges, and to emphasize the role of the family as a sacred institution from the perspective of religions and denominations. Laying the groundwork for the conference, the scientific secretariat has planned to hold numerous virtual/in-person pre-con meetings in Persian, Arabic, and English at the different Iranian and international academic/religious centers.</p>
<p>Chairman: Mohammad Hadi Abdkhodaei (Professor, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Iran)</p>
<p>Scientific Secretary: Ahad Faramarz Qaramaleki (Professor, University of Tehran, Iran)</p>
<p>Executive Secretary: Mohsen Sharfaei (Ph. D Graduate, Astan Quds Razavi’s Foundation of Islamic Researches, Iran)</p>
<p>Executive Manager: Roohollah Fadaei (Ph. D Graduate, Tarbiat Modares University, Iran)</p>
 
<p>Venue: Mashhad, Iran</p>
<p>Conference issues:</p>
<p>1. Theory and Method in Interreligious Dialogue:</p>
<p>- Philosophical Approaches: Phenomenology, Epistemology, Narrative, Intercultural Philosophy, etc.</p>
<p>- Sociological Approaches</p>
<p>- Empirical Approaches</p>
<p>- Psychological Approaches</p>
<p>…</p>
<p>2. Family and Interreligious Dialogue</p>
<p>- Theological Attitudes Towards Family Relationships</p>
<p>- Religions and the Threats to Family Life</p>
<p>- Religions and the Mental Images of Family</p>
<p>- Theology of Gender</p>
<p>- Religions and the Rival Institutions to the Family</p>
<p>- Religions and the Family Roles</p>
<p>We are honored to host some of the well-known scholars in interfaith studies in the scientific board:</p>
<p>·       Rahim Acar: Marmara University, Turkey</p>
<p>·       Ahad Faramarz Qaramaleki: University of Tehran, Iran</p>
<p>·       Lucinda Allen Mosher: Hartford International University for Religion and Peace, USA</p>
<p>·       Seyyed Hossein Nasr: The George Washington University, USA</p>
<p>·       Rasoul Rasoulipour: Kharazmi University, Iran</p>
<p>·       Mohammad Saeedi Mehr: Tarbiat Modares University, Iran</p>
<p>·       Mun'im Sirry: Notre Dame University, USA</p>
<p>·       Amy Yu Fu: Hangzhou City University, China</p>
<p>….</p>
<p>Important Dates</p>
<p>·       Abstract submission deadline: August 23, 2023</p>
<p>·       Notification of acceptance: September 6, 2023</p>
<p>·       Paper submission deadline: November 22, 2023</p>
<p>·       Paper acceptance notification: December 6, 2023</p>
<p>·       Announcement of the selected papers and presentations’ schedule: December 21, 2023</p>
<p>·       Conference date: January 16-18, 2024</p>
<p>Only Ph. D holders and postgraduate students may submit abstracts and papers independently. Undergraduates' submissions should be coauthored by a professor.</p>
<p>Abstract Features:</p>
<p>·       Abstracts should be no less than 250 words in length and no more than 300.</p>
<p>·        Abstracts should be followed by 3 to 5 keywords.</p>
<p>Paper Features:</p>
<p>·       Papers should be no less than 1500 words in length and no more than 2000 (the abstract and bibliography are not counted).</p>
<p>·       Whole text should be typed in Times New Roman font (font-size: 11 for body and 9 for endnotes and bibliography).</p>
<p>·       All titles and subtitles in the paper should be arranged numerically (English numbers not Roman).</p>
<p>·       All marginal but useful and important notes should be mentioned as endnotes not footnotes.</p>
<p>·       All references (in-text and reference list) should follow the 16th edition of Chicago citation style.</p>
<p>The conference registration and participation are free of charge. Nevertheless, Participants are responsible for organizing and paying their own travel costs to the venue of the conference as well as for their accommodation. For any further information about the conference and traveling to Iran, contact us: irirdialogue@gmail.com</p>
<p>Conference website, submissions and registration:  <a href="https://irirdialogue.ir/">https://irirdialogue.ir/</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 05:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1683092231243217</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ August 23, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Imam Reza (PBUH) and Interreligious Dialogue</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/110953</link>
						<description><p>Astan Quds Razavi’s Foundation of Islamic Researches in collaboration with Imam Sadiq University and various Iranian and international academic and religious centers will hold the international conference on “Imam Reza (PBUH) and Interreligious Dialogue” in January 2024. This conference aims to create an atmosphere for dialogue and peaceful coexistence between the followers of different religions and denominations, to strengthen scientific interaction between the scholars of different religions and denominations, to strengthen the scientific interaction between Iranian and International religious institutions, to laying a groundwork for Intellectual cooperation between different religions and denominations on contemporary social challenges, and to emphasize the role of the family as a sacred institution from the perspective of religions and denominations. Laying the groundwork for the conference, the scientific secretariat has planned to hold numerous virtual/in-person pre-con meetings in Persian, Arabic, and English at the different Iranian and international academic/religious centers.</p>
<p>Chairman: Mohammad Hadi Abdkhodaei (Professor, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Iran)</p>
<p>Scientific Secretary: Ahad Faramarz Qaramaleki (Professor, University of Tehran, Iran)</p>
<p>Executive Secretary: Mohsen Sharfaei (Ph. D Graduate, Astan Quds Razavi’s Foundation of Islamic Researches, Iran)</p>
<p>Executive Manager: Roohollah Fadaei (Ph. D Graduate, Tarbiat Modares University, Iran)</p>
 
<p>Venue: Mashhad, Iran</p>
<p>Conference issues:</p>
<p>1. Theory and Method in Interreligious Dialogue:</p>
<p>- Philosophical Approaches: Phenomenology, Epistemology, Narrative, Intercultural Philosophy, etc.</p>
<p>- Sociological Approaches</p>
<p>- Empirical Approaches</p>
<p>- Psychological Approaches</p>
<p>…</p>
<p>2. Family and Interreligious Dialogue</p>
<p>- Theological Attitudes Towards Family Relationships</p>
<p>- Religions and the Threats to Family Life</p>
<p>- Religions and the Mental Images of Family</p>
<p>- Theology of Gender</p>
<p>- Religions and the Rival Institutions to the Family</p>
<p>- Religions and the Family Roles</p>
<p>We are honored to host some of the well-known scholars in interfaith studies in the scientific board:</p>
<p>·       Rahim Acar: Marmara University, Turkey</p>
<p>·       Ahad Faramarz Qaramaleki: University of Tehran, Iran</p>
<p>·       Lucinda Allen Mosher: Hartford International University for Religion and Peace, USA</p>
<p>·       Seyyed Hossein Nasr: The George Washington University, USA</p>
<p>·       Rasoul Rasoulipour: Kharazmi University, Iran</p>
<p>·       Mohammad Saeedi Mehr: Tarbiat Modares University, Iran</p>
<p>·       Mun'im Sirry: Notre Dame University, USA</p>
<p>·       Amy Yu Fu: Hangzhou City University, China</p>
<p>….</p>
<p>Important Dates</p>
<p>·       Abstract submission deadline: August 23, 2023</p>
<p>·       Notification of acceptance: September 6, 2023</p>
<p>·       Paper submission deadline: November 22, 2023</p>
<p>·       Paper acceptance notification: December 6, 2023</p>
<p>·       Announcement of the selected papers and presentations’ schedule: December 21, 2023</p>
<p>·       Conference date: January 16-18, 2024</p>
<p>Only Ph. D holders and postgraduate students may submit abstracts and papers independently. Undergraduates' submissions should be coauthored by a professor.</p>
<p>Abstract Features:</p>
<p>·       Abstracts should be no less than 250 words in length and no more than 300.</p>
<p>·        Abstracts should be followed by 3 to 5 keywords.</p>
<p>Paper Features:</p>
<p>·       Papers should be no less than 1500 words in length and no more than 2000 (the abstract and bibliography are not counted).</p>
<p>·       Whole text should be typed in Times New Roman font (font-size: 11 for body and 9 for endnotes and bibliography).</p>
<p>·       All titles and subtitles in the paper should be arranged numerically (English numbers not Roman).</p>
<p>·       All marginal but useful and important notes should be mentioned as endnotes not footnotes.</p>
<p>·       All references (in-text and reference list) should follow the 16th edition of Chicago citation style.</p>
<p>The conference registration and participation are free of charge. Nevertheless, Participants are responsible for organizing and paying their own travel costs to the venue of the conference as well as for their accommodation. For any further information about the conference and traveling to Iran, contact us: irirdialogue@gmail.com</p>
<p>Conference website, submissions and registration:  <a href="https://irirdialogue.ir/">https://irirdialogue.ir/</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 05:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1683092231243216</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Muslim Intellectual History in Mughal South Asia [Conference and Publication]</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12791252/muslim-intellectual-history-mughal-south-asia-conference-and</link>
						<dc:creator>S. Shiraz Ali</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-10-06T00:00:00-04:00">October 6, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>California</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Intellectual History, Islamic History / Studies, South Asian History / Studies, Middle East History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><h5><b>Call for Abstracts:</b><b> </b>Conference and Publication</h5><hr/><h2>Muslim Intellectual History in Mughal South Asia</h2><h4><span>Asad Q. Ahmed, S. Shiraz Ali, and Daniyal Channa</span></h4><h6><span><strong>Department of Middle Eastern Languages and Cultures, University of California, Berkeley</strong></span></h6><p> </p><h5>Fresh waves of research on the postclassical Islamic East are reshaping the shores of South Asian and Islamic studies. Recovering from the long shadow of decline theories and narratives, the ongoing study of Muslim intellectual pursuits in the subcontinent is bringing to light a world far more dynamic than previously believed. The region appears better situated within transregional contexts, while offering unique intellectual trajectories with reverberations across a broader range of fields. This conference invites specialists to present research on Muslim intellectual history in Mughal South Asia within the following areas:</h5><ol><li><h5>Philosophy, Theology, and Science</h5></li><li><h5>Rhetoric, Law, and Scripturalist Disciplines</h5></li><li><h5>Islamo-Sanskrit Engagements</h5></li><li><h5>Socio-Intellectual History</h5></li></ol><h5>Despite great strides in the study of the social, political, and cultural institutions of early modern South Asia, these efforts are yet to be reconciled with parallel developments in the study of knowledge production across Persianate frontiers.  Meanwhile within history of ideas, we are only gradually overcoming the trappings of conventional accounts of intellectual life in the region, specifically the sweeping theses of intellectual marginality and decline grounded in dichotomies like canon vs. commentary, rationalism vs. mysticism/scripturalism, Arabic orthodoxy vs. Persian/Indian cosmopolitanism, and their projection onto the source material at face value, i.e., as exhaustive binaries that tend to obfuscate actual disciplinary frameworks, literary practice, and transmission of knowledge.  While there is growing consensus that the postclassical intellectual currents were longer lasting and more intricate than previously believed, the variegated details of this past pose new methodological challenges.</h5><h5>The conference invites current research on Muslim intellectual history in Mughal South Asia across areas like philosophy, theology, astronomy, rhetoric, jurisprudence, hadīth, tafsīr, Perso-Sanskrit interactions, infrastructures of knowledge production. The event will be hosted at U.C. Berkeley on October 6-7, 2023, with travel and accommodation covered for visiting participants.  Abstracts must be received by June 23.  Selected applicants will be notified by July 7.  Each participant will have 45 minutes to present (including Q&amp;A).  The final articles will be published as a special issue or volume edited by the organizers.  The submission deadline for articles is March 15, 2024.</h5><ul><li><h5>The conference will be held on <b>October 6-7, 2023 </b>at the University of California, Berkeley.</h5></li><li><h5>Abstracts of 300-400 words must be sent to <b><a href="mailto:ali_syed@berkeley.edu">ali_syed@berkeley.edu</a></b> no later than <b>June 23, 2023</b>.</h5></li><li><h5>The deadline for complete articles is <b>March 15, 2024</b>.</h5></li><li><h5>Expenses for travel and accommodation will be covered for visiting participants.</h5></li></ul><h5>The event is sponsored by Berkeley's Center for Middle Eastern Languages and Cultures (CMES) and the Institute of South Asia Studies (ISAS)</h5><address> </address><address> </address></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Asad Q. Ahmed: <a href="mailto:asad.ahmed@berkeley.edu">asad.ahmed@berkeley.edu</a></p><p>S. Shiraz Ali: <a href="mailto:ali_syed@berkeley.edu">ali_syed@berkeley.edu</a></p><p>Daniyal Channa: <a href="mailto:dchanna@berkeley.edu">dchanna@berkeley.edu</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ali_syed@berkeley.edu">ali_syed@berkeley.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 18:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1683092231243215</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ June 15, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: 'Europes' in Margins</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/110925</link>
						<description><p>Who gets to think about, write and shape ideas of Europe? How are bodies, stories, and perspectives made invisible or visible? What political horizons open up when we think across marginalisations of bodies, ecologies and societies that have been produced in the making of ‘European’ institutions? </p>
<p>We are looking forward to receiving your individual paper proposals! We welcome abstracts until <strong>15th of June</strong> 2023. Please submit your abstract (max. 300 words) via the electronic from link below. In the abstract <strong>include your name, affiliation</strong> and <strong>contact details</strong>. For questions, please contact: <strong><a href="mailto:europesinmarginsconference@helsinki.fi">europesinmarginsconference@helsinki.fi</a></strong></p>
<p>Invited guests <strong>Denise Ferreira da Silva</strong> and <strong>Fatima El-Tayeb </strong>(remote).</p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 05:37:10 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1683005831493777</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ November 15, 2023 -  November 17, 2023] Conference or similar: 'Europes' in Margins</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/110921</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p>Who gets to think about, write and shape ideas of Europe? How are bodies, stories, and perspectives made invisible or visible? What political horizons open up when we think across marginalisations of bodies, ecologies and societies that have been produced in the making of ‘European’ institutions?</p>
<p>We are looking forward to receiving your individual paper proposals! We welcome abstracts until <strong>15th of June</strong> 2023. Please submit your abstract (max. 300 words) via the electronic from link below. In the abstract <strong>include your name, affiliation</strong> and <strong>contact details</strong>. For questions, please contact: <strong><a href="mailto:europesinmarginsconference@helsinki.fi">europesinmarginsconference@helsinki.fi</a></strong></p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 05:37:10 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1683005831493776</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CfP: A Symposium on Fakhr al-Din al-Razi (d. 606/1210)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12778902/cfp-symposium-fakhr-al-din-al-razi-d-6061210</link>
						<dc:creator>Michael Rapoport</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-08-01T00:00:00-04:00">August 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Florida</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Intellectual History, Islamic History / Studies, Middle East History / Studies, Philosophy, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><b><span>Postclassical Philosophy in the Muslim World:</span></b></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><b><span>A Symposium on Fakhr al-Dīn al-Rāzī (d. 606/1210)</span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><i>Friday to Sunday, 26-28 April 2024 at </i></b><a href="https://www.fau.edu/" rel="nofollow"><b><i>Florida Atlantic University</i></b></a><b><i> in Boca Raton, Florida</i></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><u>Symposium Focus</u>: Fakhr al-Dīn al-Rāzī’s (d. 606/1210) position as a preeminent figure of Postclassical Islam (ca. 1200-1900 CE) is becoming increasingly well known among scholars of Islam. As Rāzī was influential in nearly all areas of knowledge, this symposium welcomes proposals for presentations on any of the fields to which Rāzī dedicated himself, e.g., philosophy, logic, the sciences, magic and sorcery, theology, Qurʾānic exegesis, and jurisprudence. Presentations may also focus on Rāzī’s life and legacy. Proposals for presentations with a strong philological focus are encouraged. </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><u>Details of the Symposium</u>:</span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span>Up to twelve presentations of 30-45 minutes each, plus Q&amp;A. Scholars in all career stages are welcome to apply.</span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><a href="https://religiousstudies.yale.edu/people/frank-griffel" rel="nofollow">Frank Griffel</a> (Yale University) will present the symposium’s keynote lecture. </span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span>Attendees’ meals (dinner on Friday; breakfast, lunch, and dinner on Saturday; and breakfast and lunch on Sunday) will be provided. Attendees will be responsible for all other costs. </span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><u>How to Apply</u>: </span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span>Email your CV and an abstract, both in English, of no more than 500 words to <a href="https://www.fau.edu/artsandletters/llcl/faculty/faculty-profiles/michaelrapoport/" rel="nofollow">Michael Rapoport</a> at <a href="mailto:mrapoport@fau.edu?subject=Razi%20Symposium">mrapoport@fau.edu</a> by <b>1 August 2023</b>. </span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span>Please include “<b>Razi Symposium</b>” in the email’s subject field. </span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span>Decision emails are expected to be sent in September 2023. </span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span>Please address all questions to <a href="mailto:mrapoport@fau.edu?subject=Razi%20Symposium">mrapoport@fau.edu</a> </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>The symposium is supported by Florida Atlantic University’s Chastain-Johnston Middle Eastern Studies Distinguished Professorship in Peace Studies</span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Michael Rapoport, Assistant Professor of Arabic and Islamic Studies, Florida Atlantic University</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:mrapoport@fau.edu">mrapoport@fau.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.fau.edu/artsandletters/llcl/faculty/faculty-profiles/michaelrapoport/" target="_blank">https://www.fau.edu/artsandletters/llcl/faculty/faculty-profiles/michaelrapoport/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 17:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1683005831493775</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
