<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 12:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 12:20:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – December 27th, 2022</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-december-27th-2022/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find 2 jobs, and a Call For Papers.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 34!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Robert H. N. Ho Family Foundation Program in Buddhist Studies – Public Scholars program</h4>



<p>Deadline: January 11, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.acls.org/competitions/the-robert-h-n-ho-family-foundation-buddhism-public-scholars/">The Robert H. N. Ho Family Foundation Buddhism Public Scholars – ACLS</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor: Department of Religious Studies – Focus on Buddhism and expertise in South and Southeast Asia (3-year teaching appointment, non-Tenure track, possibility of renewal)</h4>



<p>University of Virginia, US</p>



<p>Deadline: January 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.insidehighered.com/job/2642959/assistant-professor-general-faculty-department-of-religious-studies/">Assistant Professor, General Faculty – Department of Religious Studies job with University of Virginia | 2642959 (insidehighered.com)</a></p>



<h4>AAR/SBL Job Forum</h4>



<p><a href="https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search">https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search</a></p>



<h2>Call For Papers:</h2>



<h4><em>CrossCurrents </em>journal – “Queer Muslim Media”</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.aprilonline.org/cfps/">CFPs – April Online</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1672295825776266</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ July 3, 2023 -  July 21, 2023] Conference or similar: God and Fine-Tuning Summer School</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/106338</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 06:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1672209425618583</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ January 20, 2023 -  January 21, 2023] Conference or similar: Jean Cavaillès and his intellectual milieu</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/106254</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p>The last decade has witnessed a renewed interest in the work of Jean Cavaillès (1903-1944). Cavaillès specialized in philosophy of mathematics and philosophy of science, though his oeuvre was cut short due to his death in the French Resistance. Nonetheless, his work proved to be very influential in France, impacting the work of, among others, Gaston Bachelard, Georges Canguilhem, Jean-Toussaint Desanti, Michel Foucault, Louis Althusser, Jules Vuillemin, Gilles-Gaston Granger and Jacques Bouveressse.  Hence, this interest goes hand in hand with a revival of studies on ‘French epistemology’ or historical epistemology. In the case of Cavaillès, the new focus is not only on his philosophy of mathematics but also on his broader program for a theory of science based on a conceptual dynamics. In this process of rediscovery the intellectual milieu of French philosophy and history of science between 1920 and 1950 plays its role and gets its share. The exchanges between Cavaillès and Albert Lautman, the connection with Gaston and Suzanne Bachelard, the Dialectica movement around Ferdinand Gonseth, the relations with the founders of Bourbaki, the formation of the new generation of students (Granger, Vuillemin, Desanti), the friendship with Georges Canguilhem, etc. all deserve to be highlighted.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 06:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1671777429671956</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP: Writing Religious Conflict and Community in the Southwest, 1500–1800 (21st April 2023, Exeter, UK)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12021756/cfp-writing-religious-conflict-and-community-southwest-1500</link>
						<dc:creator>David Parry</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-01-13T00:00:00-05:00">January 13, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Literature, British History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Early Modern History and Period Studies, Local History</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><b>Writing Religious Conflict and Community in the Southwest, 1500–1800</b></p><p><b>Friday 21<sup>st</sup> April 2023</b></p><p>Proposals are invited for a day conference at the University of Exeter on religious identity, community and conflict in the southwest of England from 1500-1800, and their representation in written and printed texts. Proposals are welcome focusing on any religious group in the period (including conformists, Puritans, Protestant Nonconformists/Dissenters, Catholics, freethinkers, Jews and Muslims) and the relationships between them, and on any kind or genre of writing, but papers should have a clear link to the southwest region.</p><p>Possible topics may include (but are not limited to):</p><ul><li>Devotional, polemical, didactic and narrative modes of religious writing, and their dissemination via manuscript circulation and the printed book trade.</li><li>The role of religion in political upheavals in the southwest, such as the Prayer Book Rebellion/Western Rising of 1549, the Civil Wars, and the Glorious Revolution.</li><li>The shaping and practice of conformist/‘Anglican’ religion by writers including theologians such as Richard Hooker and poets such as Robert Herrick.</li><li>Texts emerging from or responding to Dissenters in the southwest including Presbyterians, Independents/Congregationalists, Baptists, Quakers, Unitarians and Methodists.</li><li>The Exeter Arian controversy and the split between ‘orthodox’ and ‘rational’ Dissent.</li><li>Jewish communities in the southwest, including the Ottolenghi Affair of the 1730s.</li><li>Encounters with the Islamic world (e.g. via travel writing and captivity narratives).</li></ul><p>Within this religiously plural and contested region, individuals and religious groups expressed their convictions and communal identities as well as their relationships and conflicts with others through a wide variety of written genres. These texts include poems, sermons, prophecies, pamphlets, letters, travel writing, captivity narratives, diaries, memoirs, and spiritual autobiographies. We welcome exploration of such texts from a variety of methodological approaches, including approaches derived from history, literary studies, bibliography, theology, network analysis and more. We anticipate these discussions providing unique insights into the construction of shared identities and collective memories, and the ways in which these play out in local histories of community and conflict. An edited collection of selected papers from the conference is also envisaged for publication.</p><p>Please send a biography (100 words), along with a CV, title and brief abstract (250 words) of a 20 minute paper, or for panels (3 x 20 minute papers) to <a href="mailto:d.parry@exeter.ac.uk">d.parry@exeter.ac.uk</a> by 13th January 2023.  Early expressions of interest welcome. Remote participation may be possible for participants unable to travel to Exeter – please get in touch if this would be of interest. Modest travel bursaries (on request via e-mail) are available for postgraduate students whose papers are accepted.</p><p>Organised by Leverhulme Trust-funded project ‘Writing Religious Conflict and Community in Exeter’ (ReConEx) in association with the International John Bunyan Society with the endorsement of the Ecclesiastical History Society.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr David Parry, Department of English and Creative Writing, University of Exeter</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:d.parry@exeter.ac.uk">d.parry@exeter.ac.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://reconex.exeter.ac.uk/events/" target="_blank">https://reconex.exeter.ac.uk/events/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 18:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1671777429671955</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
