<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 12:27:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 12:27:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>The Book of Qohelet in its Hellenistic Jewish context</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11768049/book-qohelet-its-hellenistic-jewish-context</link>
						<dc:creator>Sara Ben-Isaac</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-22T00:00:00-05:00">November 22, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Humanities, Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span>Online lecture (Zoom) by Professor Lili Samet.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>The research of the book of Qohelet in the light of extra-biblical materials has traditionally been focused on three main arenas, all representing the book’s indirect context: Mesopotamia, Egypt and Greece. Qohelet’s immediate environment, that is, the book’s relationship to the Jewish discourse of its time, has scarcely been studied.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>This lecture attempts to explore some of the unexhausted potential of studying Qohelet within its Hellenistic Jewish context. Two test cases, one belonging to the legal realm and the other involving theological and philosophical concerns, will be used to exemplify the ways in which innovative interpretations of Qohelet’s words and ideas can be proposed in light of the intellectual history of its time and place.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Nili</span></span><span><span> Samet is a professor of Bible and Assyriology at Bar-Ilan University, and currently a visiting professor at UCL and at Oxford University. She is the author of a book and several dozens of articles in the fields of wisdom literature in Israel and Mesopotamia, with a focus on the Book of Qohelet; Biblical Hebrew, with a focus on linguistic dating; and comparative study of the Bible and the Ancient Near East, with a focus on Sumerian literature. One of her main current projects is a commentary on Qohelet in the series <i>Miqra Le-Yisrael</i></span></span><span><span>.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>The research of the book of Qohelet in the light of extra-biblical materials has traditionally been focused on three main arenas, all representing the book’s indirect context: Mesopotamia, Egypt and Greece. Qohelet’s immediate environment, that is, the book’s relationship to the Jewish discourse of its time, has scarcely been studied.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Institute of Jewish Studies, UCL</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ijs@ucl.ac.uk">ijs@ucl.ac.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/424489017077" target="_blank">https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/424489017077</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 18:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1668839832550742</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Editorial Members</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11760553/call-editorial-members</link>
						<dc:creator>Dina Ripsman Eylon</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Journal</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-12-31T00:00:00-05:00">December 31, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Canada</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Ontario</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Cultural History / Studies, Humanities, Jewish History / Studies, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><i>Women in Judaism: A Multidisciplinary e-Journal</i> is seeking new members to join our editorial board. Scholars in any field in the Humanities and/or Social Sciences are invited to apply.</span></span></p><p><span><span>This refereed, biannual, open access, e-journal is published solely on the Internet and is devoted to an exploration of gender issues in Jewish religion, culture, society and history. Now in its 26th year of publication, the journal features articles, essays, book and film reviews, bibliographies, conference proceedings and more.</span></span></p><p><span><span><i>Women in Judaism: A Multidisciplinary e-Journal</i> is indexed by Érudit, Ulrich's International Periodicals Directory, RAMBI- The Index of Articles on Jewish Studies by the Jewish National and University Library, Index of Jewish Periodicals, and Contemporary Women’s Issues by the Gale Group. In addition, the journal is indexed and linked to by dozens of electronic directories and web sites. [For more details, check our About section.]</span></span></p><p><span><span>New editorial members will be asked to review 1-3 submitted articles a year. The materials fall within the members’ areas of expertise. Members will be asked to promote the journal within their respective academic communities. As members of the editorial board, they could also</span></span><span><span> </span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span>Refer to the journal in their course outlines, bibliographies and even mundane chats in their departments. </span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span>Assign readings from the journal to students. </span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span>Suggest to colleagues and graduate students to write book (and other media) reviews for the journal. </span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span>Solicit colleagues, graduate students to submit articles and other materials. </span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span>Current and previous issues are freely available at <a href="http://www.womeninjudaism.org/" rel="nofollow">www.womeninjudaism.org</a></span></span></p><p><span><span>Please include your CV with your electronic application. We would greatly appreciate your participation in our journal, and thank you for your consideration.</span></span></p><p><span><span>For more info and details, email Dr. Dina Ripsman Eylon, Editor-in-Chief at</span></span></p><p><span><span><a href="https://networks.h-net.org/subject-fields/dina.eylon@alum.utoronto.ca">dina.eylon@alum.utoronto.</a></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr. Dina Ripsman Eylon, Eedtor-in-Chief</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:dina.eylon@alum.utoronto.ca">dina.eylon@alum.utoronto.ca</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://wjudaism.library.utoronto.ca/index.php/wjudaism/index" target="_blank">https://wjudaism.library.utoronto.ca/index.php/wjudaism/index</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 18:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1668839832550741</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Contributions for Journal special issue &quot;Accounting Practices and Religious Orders in Missionary Territories&quot;</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11755628/call-contributions-journal-special-issue-accounting-practices</link>
						<dc:creator>Rebecca Carnevali</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Publications</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-12-15T00:00:00-05:00">December 15, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Early Modern History and Period Studies, Economic History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><strong>Call for contributions</strong></p><p><strong>Journal special issue</strong></p><p><strong>Accounting Practices and Religious Orders in Missionary Territories</strong></p><p> </p><p>While economic questions have long been almost entirely absent from research on Catholic missions, a growing body of scholarship has begun to point to the importance of an economic approach for an adequate understanding of the organization and the local practices of early modern missions. Following the ground-breaking work of Dauril Alden (1996), more recent studies have mostly focused on the economy of the Jesuits’ missions (Crocitti: 2002; Tutino: 2021; Vu Thanh: 2016; Županov: 2012), with fewer studies also looking at other orders (Ye Junyang, Manel Ollé: 2021; Vu Thanh, Županov: 2021; Windler: 2018). This growing body of scholarship makes a fundamental contribution to our knowledge of important aspects of the history of missionary economies: e.g. their internal organization; the missionaries’ participation in local economies; or the role played by the global circulation of objects and commodities in ensuring the economic viability of the mission. However, a key element of the economic organization of the missions remains largely absent from these studies: the accounting practices, that may be traced in surviving account books and missionary correspondences. Indeed, to date few scholars have worked on the account books kept by missionaries (Windler, 2018; Borges, 1994; Golvers, 1999; Vermote, 2018).</p><p>Departing from these considerations and inspired by works on religious orders’ accounting practices in Europe (Lenoble, 2013; Bertrand, 2004; Cevins, 2018; Bériou, Chiffoleau, 2009, Röhrkasten, 2004; Quattrone, 2004), we are editing a journal special issue on accounting in early modern missions. Among the topic that the journal special issue will address are the following:</p><p>- Normative frameworks: what are the rules that regulated missionaries’ production of account books? What might explain the absence of account books beyond the hazards of conservation?</p><p>- Recording practices: what kind of resources and expenses were recorded? How were they recorded?</p><p>- Account books as a source: how (and to what extent) can the study of account books contribute to our understanding of missionaries’ economic activities and social integration, of the funding system they relied upon and of the organization of missions more generally?</p><p>- Functions: what role does accounting play in the economic organization of the mission and, more broadly, what were the functions of account books?</p><p>We welcome <strong>abstracts</strong> (of c. 300 words) for <strong>original research articles</strong> that intersects with these themes and a short professional bio (of c. 100 words) by the deadline of the <strong>15th December 2022</strong>. The deadline for the submission of a first draft of the articles will be the 30th November 2023. The authors will be invited to discuss their contributions at a conference in Rome to be held at the beginning of 2024.</p><p>The co-editors are Prof. Felicita Tramontana, Department of Political Science, Università degli Studi Roma Tre (<a href="mailto:felicita.tramontana@uniroma3.it">felicita.tramontana@uniroma3.it</a>), Prof. Hélène Vu Thanh, Department of History, Université Bretagne Sud/Institut universitaire de France (<a href="mailto:helene.vu-thanh@univ-ubs.fr">helene.vu-thanh@univ-ubs.fr</a>) and Prof. Christian Windler, Historisches Institut, Universität Bern (<a href="https://networks.h-net.org/subject-fields/'+atob('Y2hyaXN0aWFuLndpbmRsZXJAdW5pYmUuY2g=')">christian.windler@unibe.ch</a>), who will be pleased to provide further details and information.</p><p>The journal issue will be one of the outputs of the project “HOLYLAB.  A global economic organization in the early modern period: The Custody of the Holy Land through its account books (1600-1800)”, funded by the European Research Council (ERC) under the European Union’s Horizon 2020 research and innovation program (Grant Agreement ID 101001857), P.I. Prof. Felicita Tramontana.</p></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 18:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1668753429152939</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Worldly Weil -- EXTENDED CALL: Simone Weil and Political Theology</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11754507/worldly-weil-extended-call-simone-weil-and-political-theology</link>
						<dc:creator>Benjamin Davis</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-05-30T00:00:00-04:00">May 30, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Philosophy, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>A workshop on religion, politics, and Simone Weil at The John C. Danforth Center, Washington University in St. Louis</p><p>Dates: 30 May-1 June, 2023</p><p>What is the relationship between politics and religion, political commitment and religious commitment in the work of Simone Weil? To what extent does Weil’s theology influence her politics, and her politics influence her theology—and how might attention to this question change how we read Weil today? How does Weil separate questions of Church from questions of religion, and what can our answers to these questions tell us about connections between Church and State in the U.S.? This workshop will consider these and other questions about Simone Weil’s political theology and inquiries emerging from it.</p><p>This workshop will be held at the John C. Danforth Center on Religion and Politics at Washington University in St. Louis. In keeping with the Center’s focus on scholarly and public engagement with issues at the intersection of politics and religion in the United States, we invite reflection on Weil that considers her thought in dialogue with religious life in the U.S. While Weil kept her eyes largely on her native France, she spent the summer and early fall of 1942 in New York, where she conducted research at public libraries in order to “dig into the hidden recesses of theology.” Weil’s thought has been influential for leading U.S. public intellectuals, from Susan Sontag and Mary McCarthy to Christian Wiman, Christy Wampole, and others today.</p><p>The conference will convene at the John C. Danforth Center on the campus of Washington University in St. Louis, where lodging will be available for participants. Additional travel grants will also be available.</p><p>We call for proposals of works in progress, more polished moments of ongoing inquiries, experimental projects, and other approaches to thinking together about the above questions and contexts.</p><p>Please send your 500-word abstracts on Weil and political theology to Fannie Bialek and Ben Davis by December 15, 2022. Emails: abialek[at]wustl.edu and benjamin.davis.1[at]slu.edu.</p></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 18:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1668753429152938</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>AAR Buddhist Pedagogy Seminar</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11752351/aar-buddhist-pedagogy-seminar</link>
						<dc:creator>Gloria Chien</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Colorado</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Area Studies, Asian History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span>Dear all,</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Below is information on the Buddhist Pedagogy Seminar panels on Sunday, Nov. 20 at the American Academy of Religion Annual Meeting in Denver. The business meeting will be held at the end of A20-335 session. We are looking forward to seeing you. </span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span>A20-335</span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Sunday, Nov. 20, 3:00­–4:30 PM. Hyatt Regency-Granite B (Third Level)</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Theme: Teaching Buddhism: Environment, Violence, and Role Play</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>This panel examines the teaching of undergraduates about Buddhism regarding the environment, violence, and using role play to enact Buddhist history. Ellen Posman proposes that teaching about Buddhism and environmental concerns can allow for more critical discussions of the relationship between Buddhism and indigenous religions. Julie Regan discusses the “forest experiments” assignment that includes readings and activities to address topics on personal healing, racial injustice, and environmental problems. Geoffrey Barstow challenges students’ assumptions about Buddhism as a peaceful religion by showing samurai glorified as enlightened warriors and asks students to investigate how the ideas of emptiness can be justified for interpersonal violence. Noel Hubler and Joel Dubois adopt “Reacting The Past Simulations” to have students role-play events in Buddhist history, which deepens their understanding of practices chosen by different traditions. In sum, this panel reflects on specific methods of teaching past and contemporary issues of Buddhism. </span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span>Ellen Posman, Baldwin Wallace University</span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span><span>         </span><a href="https://papers.aarweb.org/paper/blurring-buddhist-indigenous-lines-environmental-work" rel="nofollow"><span>Blurring the Buddhist-Indigenous Lines in Environmental Work</span></a></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span>Julie Regan, La Salle University</span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span><span>         </span></span><a href="https://papers.aarweb.org/paper/touching-earth-making-connections-woods" rel="nofollow"><span><span>Touching the Earth &amp; Making Connections in the Woods</span></span></a></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span>Geoffrey Barstow, Oregon State University</span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span><span>          </span></span><a href="https://papers.aarweb.org/paper/teaching-buddhist-violence-samurai" rel="nofollow"><span><span>Teaching Buddhist Violence via the Samurai</span></span></a></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span>J. Noel Hubler, Lebanon Valley College; Joel Dubois, California State University, Sacramento</span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span><span>         </span></span><a href="https://papers.aarweb.org/paper/king-ashoka-emperor-wuzong-and-dalai-lama-walk-classroom-using-historical-simulations-teach" rel="nofollow"><span><span>King Ashoka, Emperor Wuzong, and the Dalai Lama Walk into a Classroom: Using historical simulations to teach Buddhism</span></span></a></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span>A20-436</span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Theme: Teaching Buddhism Outside the Classroom</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Sunday, Nov. 20, 5:00­–6:30 PM. Hyatt Regency-Granite C (Third Level)</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>This panel examines teaching Buddhism in the Tibetan monastery, chaplaincy, and to second-generation Asian American children in American Buddhist temples. Sherab Chomphel’s presentation analyzes the conflict of modernity in Tibetan monastic educational regulations in exile during the 1970s. Chomphel highlights the changes of former ritual performances and the proposed reasons for and against the planned innovations. Xiandong Shi’s research investigates how the monastery can help the second-generation Chinese American children cope with ethnical identity issues and tools that the monastery can use to promote their identity as young Asian American Buddhists. Outside the monastery, Leigh Miller draws on ethnographic researchwith Buddhist chaplains who received contemplation training in Buddhist graduate programs to elucidate the relationship between contemplative education and contemplative experience in professional or community service-learning contexts. In sum, this panel offers insights into the challenges and adaptations need to teach Buddhism in diverse settings. </span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span>Sherab Chomphel, Banaras Hindu University</span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><a href="https://papers.aarweb.org/paper/conflict-modernity-among-tibetan-buddhist-religious-institutions" rel="nofollow"><span><span>Conflict of Modernity among Tibetan Buddhist Religious Institutions</span></span></a></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span>Xiandong Shi, University of the West</span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><a href="https://papers.aarweb.org/paper/buddhist-ministry-2nd-generation-chinese-american-buddhist-children-addressing-development" rel="nofollow"><span><span>Buddhist Ministry to 2nd - Generation Chinese American Buddhist Children: Addressing the Development of Ethnic Identity</span></span></a></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span>Leigh Miller, Maitripa College</span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span>      <a href="https://papers.aarweb.org/paper/fruits-practice-contemplative-experience-after-contempaltive-educational-training" rel="nofollow"><span>Fruits of the Practice: Contemplative Experience after Contempaltive Educational Training</span></a></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span>Panel Respondent</span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span>: Todd Lewis, College of the Holy Cross</span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><br/><span><span><span><span>Chairs: Gloria Chien; Trung Huynh<br/>Steering Committee: Todd Lewis; Beverley McGuire; Jonathan Young; Ben Van Overmeire</span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Gloria Chien, Religous Studies, Gonzaga Univerisy</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:chien@gonzaga.edu">chien@gonzaga.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 18:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1668753429152937</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ December 15, 2022] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/105117</link>
						<description>Publication Name: Call for Papers for Special Issue of CPR: 'Objectivity and Truth in Cassirer's Philosophy of Culture and Philosophy of Science'<br/><br/><p>REMINDER:</p>
<p>Call for Papers for Special Issue: </p>
<p>'Objectivity and Truth in Cassirer's Philosophy of Culture and Philosophy of Science'</p>
<p>Journal: <em>Continental Philosophy Review</em></p>
<p>Guest Editors: Tobias Endres (TU Braunschweig) and Simon Truwant (KU Leuven) </p>
<p>DESCRIPTION:</p>
<p>"Is there really something like an objective theoretical truth [...]? In a time in which such questions can be raised, philosophy cannot stand aside, mute and idle." (Cassirer, Symbol, Myth, and Culture, 61) There is no doubt that this question, which Cassirer found indicative of the European Zeitgeist of the first decades of the twentieth century, also pervades Western culture today. In times of fake news, conspiracy theories, alternative facts, and science denial, as well as the rise of political myth and the erosion of expertise and democratic institutions, doubt about the possibility of objectivity and truth is a defining characteristic of contemporary culture. Hence, if we follow Cassirer, philosophy has once again a crucial societal duty to fulfill: the duty to safeguard some notion of objectivity and of truth against epistemic and cultural relativism, skepticism, and indifference.</p>
<p>This collection of essays reconsiders the enduring relevance of Cassirer's own philosophy in view of this challenge. The <em>Philosophy of Symbolic Forms</em> was after all an ambitious attempt to radically widen and diversify the meaning of objectivity without forfeiting its claims to universality or its firm footing in human reason. By ascribing to mythical, religious, and linguistic perceptions and expressions an objective status that modern Western philosophy had preserved for scientific thought, Cassirer's philosophy can however be taken as either enriching or weakening the ideas of objectivity, truth, and rationality. In view of the current crisis of truth, we thus ask what Cassirer's theory of culture and of science can teach us about the plurality, relativity, or universality of human understanding.</p>
<p>We invite papers that reflect, from a contemporary viewpoint, on Cassirer’s view on objectivity and truth in relation to the plurality of the symbolic forms, their inherent tendencies towards dogmatism, the relativity of their cultural viewpoints, and their unity in the whole of human culture. Within this broad theme, we specifically welcome paper proposals that reflect on the transcendental status of science, its relation to other symbolic forms (incl. language, politics, technology, and art), and its significance for understanding (the present state or the progress of) human culture as a whole. We also welcome papers that initiate a dialogue between Cassirer and other contemporary thinkers on the issues of truth or objectivity. </p>
<p>The special issue will contain a first-time English translation of Cassirer's 1929 inaugural address as rector of Hamburg University: 'Formen und Formwandlungen des philosophischen Wahrheitsbegriffs' (ECW 17). We will give preference to paper submissions that in some way connect to the concept of functional truth that Cassirer suggests in this address (we can send you a pdf copy of the German text upon request).</p>
<p>HOW TO SUBMIT:</p>
<p>Submissions should be no longer than 7000 words and must be written in English. Non-native English speakers may be asked to have their paper proofread by a native English speaker before it goes through the peer review process. Please follow the <em>Instructions for Authors</em> from <em>CPR</em> under </p>
<p>https://www.springer.com/journal/11007/submission-guidelines for citations and formatting.</p>
<p>All papers must be submitted via Editorial Manager under</p>
<p>https://www.editorialmanager.com/mawo/default1.aspx with a note that it is for the special issue on Cassirer <u>and</u> to the Guest Editors' E-Mail-Addresses.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact the guest editors at t.endres@tu-braunschweig.de or simon.truwant@kuleuven.be.</p>
<p>The deadline for submissions is December 15, 2022.</p>
<p>Tobias Endres (TU Braunschweig) </p>
<p>Simon Truwant (KU Leuven)</p></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 06:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1668667028397637</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Research Fellowships at the Massachusetts Historical Society, 2023-2024</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11728239/research-fellowships-massachusetts-historical-society-2023</link>
						<dc:creator>Cassie Cloutier</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Fellowship</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-01T00:00:00-05:00">March 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>African American History / Studies, Environmental History / Studies, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Military History</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><a href="https://www.masshist.org/" rel="nofollow"><span>The Massachusetts Historical Society</span></a> will offer dozens of research fellowships for the 2023-2024 academic year, ranging from short-term support to long-term residency. The <a href="https://www.masshist.org/collections" rel="nofollow"><span>MHS collections</span></a> primarily consist of manuscripts, as well as books, pamphlets, maps, newspapers, graphics, photographs, works of art, and historical artifacts.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>In addition to receiving funding, MHS Research Fellows become part of a scholarly community that includes other current fellows, MHS staff, Boston-area scholars, and former fellows. They may participate in our Brown Bag Lunch Series, present their own research, attend seminars, and join MHS staff and other fellows for weekly coffees.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>For the latest information regarding fellowship offerings during and in the wake of Covid restrictions, <a href="https://www.masshist.org/research/fellowships" rel="nofollow"><span>please see our website</span></a>. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Mark your calendar with the deadlines below! </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Questions? See our <a href="https://www.masshist.org/research/fellowships/faq" rel="nofollow"><span>FAQ</span></a> or e-mail <a href="mailto:fellowships@masshist.org"><span>fellowships@masshist.org</span></a>.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><a href="https://masshistfellowships.slideroom.com/" rel="nofollow"><span>Start your application today!</span></a><br/> </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>New England Regional Fellowship Consortium<br/>Deadline: February 1, 2023</span></span></span></b></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The Society also participates in the New England Regional Fellowship Consortium. These grants provide a stipend of $5,000 for a minimum of eight weeks of research conducted at three or more participating institutions. Thirty-one cultural institutions hope to offer a minimum of twenty fellowships in 2023-2024. <a href="https://www.masshist.org/fellowships/nerfc" rel="nofollow"><span>Learn more.</span></a><br/> </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>Suzanne and Caleb Loring Fellowship<br/>Deadline: February 15, 2023</span></span></span></b></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>For those studying the U.S. Civil War, the Boston Athenaeum and the MHS will offer one Suzanne and Caleb Loring Fellowship on the Civil War, Its Origins, and Consequences. Fellows spend at least four weeks at each institution. This fellowship carries a stipend of $4,000. <a href="https://www.masshist.org/research/fellowships/suzanne-and-caleb-loring-research-fellowship" rel="nofollow"><span>Learn more.</span></a><br/> </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>MHS Short-Term Fellowships<br/>Deadline March 1, 2023</span></span></span></b></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Most MHS Short-term Fellowships carry a stipend of $3,000 to support a minimum of four weeks of research in the Society’s collections. One application automatically puts you into consideration for any applicable short-term fellowships. Graduate students, faculty, and independent researchers are welcome to apply. We will offer more than fifteen short-term fellowships in the coming year! <a href="https://www.masshist.org/research/fellowships/short-term-research-fellowships" rel="nofollow"><span>Learn more.</span></a></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ccloutier@masshist.org">ccloutier@masshist.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.masshist.org/research/fellowships" target="_blank">https://www.masshist.org/research/fellowships</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 19:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1668667028397636</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FEATURED JOB: Edgar Bronfman Chair in Modern and Contemporary Judaic Studies - University of Virginia</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11741953/featured-job-edgar-bronfman-chair-modern-and-contemporary</link>
						<dc:creator>Erika Suchecki， H-Net Staff</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Home Office Notices (Jobs, Reviews)</div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Virginia</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The Department of Religious Studies at the University of Virginia invites applications for the Edgar Bronfman Chair in Modern and Contemporary Judaic Studies, to start in Fall 2023.</p><p>We invite applications from accomplished scholars of modern and contemporary Jewish culture, thought, and religion whose work demonstrates broad interdisciplinary grounding in Jewish Studies.  We are especially interested in those scholars who engage with the fields of Jewish religious thought, Jewish politics and ethics, including bioethics and environmental ethics, ritual and material culture, Judaism and gender/sexuality, Sephardi/Mizrahi studies, the American Jewish experience, and/or Judaism, race &amp; ethnicity.</p><p>Ideal applicants should be a full professor in rank by the time of appointment. Advanced associate professors are encouraged to apply, as well as those already in the rank of full or endowed professor. The appointment will be made at the rank of endowed professor. Candidates will be assessed in terms of their demonstrated record and potential for excellence in research, teaching, and service.  Screening of applications will begin on December 12, 2022 and will continue until the position is filled. Salary is commensurate with education and experience.</p><p>The successful candidate will be expected to teach two courses a semester at the undergraduate and graduate levels, maintain an active research program, and contribute to and develop initiatives in areas of research that complement and expand departmental strengths in Jewish Studies. The successful candidate will also demonstrate a record of institutional/administrative leadership, mentorship, and professional collegiality. They will be able to take advantage of collaborative relationships with students and faculty in other departments, units, and research initiatives, including the Democracy Institute and the Institute for the Humanities and Global Cultures.</p><p>The holder of the Bronfman Chair will join the core faculty of the Jewish Studies Program, an interdepartmental unit that features a vibrant, interdisciplinary roster of outstanding faculty engaged in undergraduate and graduate training, and a university-wide fellowship program for graduate students from across the Graduate School of Arts and Sciences.</p><p>The University will perform background checks on all new hires prior to employment. </p><p><strong>To Apply:</strong></p><p>Please apply through <a href="http://uva.wd1.myworkdayjobs.com/UVAJobs" rel="nofollow">Workday</a>, and search for R0042082.  Complete an application online with the following documents:</p><ul><li>Cover letter (2 pages) addressing areas of research, teaching experience, and potential projects or collaborations at the University of Virginia</li><li>CV addressing research, teaching, and service record</li><li>Inclusive excellence statement (1 page) that addresses the applicant’s demonstrated experience working on issues of diversity, equity and inclusion and/or working with diverse populations and/or cultivating a diverse, equitable, and inclusive culture in your work.</li><li>The names and contact information for three references</li></ul><p>Upload all materials into the resume submission field, multiple documents can be submitted into this one field. Alternatively, merge all documents into one PDF for submission.  Applications that do not contain all required documents will not receive full consideration. Internal applicants must apply through their UVA Workday profile by searching 'Find Jobs'. </p><p>For additional information about the position, please contact Asher Biemann at <a href="mailto:ab5j@virginia.edu">ab5j@virginia.edu</a>.</p><p>For questions about the application process, please contact Melanie Sponaugle, Academic Recruiter, at <a href="mailto:unw5dq@virginia.edu">unw5dq@virginia.edu</a>.</p><p>UVA is located in beautiful Charlottesville with easy access to the Blue Ridge Mountains, the eastern shore and the nation's Capital. Charlottesville is one of the best places to live; outdoors, vibrant town with culture, music, restaurants, excellent schools, etc. Opportunities for excellent clinical, and laboratory-based research and teaching pursuits working within the collegial work environment are available.</p><p>UVA assists faculty spouses and partners seeking employment in the Charlottesville area.  To learn more please visit <a href="https://dualcareer.virginia.edu/" rel="nofollow">https://dualcareer.virginia.edu/</a>  For more information about UVA and the Charlottesville community please see <a href="http://www.virginia.edu/life/charlottesville" rel="nofollow">http://www.virginia.edu/life/charlottesville</a> and <a href="https://dualcareer.virginia.edu/" rel="nofollow">https://embarkcva.com/</a>.</p><p>For more information on the benefits available to faculty at UVA, visit <a href="https://provost.virginia.edu/subsite/faculty-development" rel="nofollow">https://provost.virginia.edu/subsite/faculty-development</a> and <a href="https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=http-3A__hr.virginia.edu_benefits&amp;d=DwMGaQ&amp;c=Cu5g146wZdoqVuKpTNsYHeFX_rg6kWhlkLF8Eft-wwo&amp;r=vc6Qja9eoPBnlgIE5EUK0g&amp;m=OO516Gnq_-L1tY4J4dV3ApY5ij9aOqYrapE9z6RNG_g&amp;s=hyZUs1gwzbnuh0FphzYoHvEH57oDfrHshRePFRvE1oc&amp;e=" rel="nofollow">hr.virginia.edu/benefits</a>.</p><p>MINIMUM REQUIREMENTS<br/><br/>Education: Ph.D. or terminal degree.<br/>Experience: Three years<br/>Licensure: None<br/><br/>PHYSICAL DEMANDS<br/><br/>This is primarily a sedentary job involving extensive use of desktop computers. The job does occasionally require traveling some distance to attend meetings, and programs.<br/><strong>COVID Vaccination Requirement and Guidelines</strong></p><p>Please visit the <a href="https://hr.virginia.edu/uva-covid-19-job-requirements-and-guidelines" rel="nofollow">UVA COVID-19 Job Requirements and Guidelines</a> webpage prior to applying for current information regarding vaccination requirements and guidelines for employment at UVA.</p><p><em>The University of Virginia, i</em><em>ncluding the UVA Health System which represents the UVA Medical Center, Schools of Medicine and Nursing, UVA Physician’s Group and the Claude Moore Health Sciences Library,</em> <em>are fundamentally committed to the diversity of our faculty and staff.  We believe diversity is excellence expressing itself through every person's perspectives and lived experiences.  We are equal opportunity and affirmative action employers. All qualified applicants will receive consideration for employment without regard to age, color, disability, gender identity or expression, marital status, national or ethnic origin, political affiliation, race, religion, sex (including pregnancy), sexual orientation, veteran status, and family medical or genetic information.</em></p><hr/><p>To submit YOUR job posting, please visit the H-Net Job Guide:<a href="https://www.h-net.org/jobs" rel="nofollow"> https://www.h-net.org/jobs</a></p><p>Featured jobs receive an added boost on H-Announce and H-Net’s social media channels.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Professor Asher Biemann, <a href="mailto:ab5j@virginia.edu">ab5j@virginia.edu</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ab5j@virginia.edu">ab5j@virginia.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php" target="_blank">https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php?id=64649</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 19:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1668667028397635</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – November 16, 2022</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-november-16-2022/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find multiple full-time job listings, a Call for Papers, and upcoming conferences.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 36!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs</h2>



<h4>Assistant Professor in Medieval/Early Modern Jewish History</h4>



<p>UNC Chapel Hill, US</p>



<p>Deadline: December 9, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://jewishstudies.unc.edu/2022/11/recruiting-faculty-position-in-history/">Recruiting: Faculty Position in Medieval/Early Modern Jewish History | Jewish Studies (unc.edu)</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor, General Faculty – Department of Religious Studies, Emphasis in Buddhism (Full time, 3 years, Possibility of renewal, non-Tenure track)</h4>



<p>University of Virginia, US</p>



<p>Deadline: January 15<sup>th</sup>, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://uva.wd1.myworkdayjobs.com/en-US/UVAJobs/job/Charlottesville-VA/Assistant-Professor--General-Faculty---Department-of-Religious-Studies_R0042078?q=R0042078">https://uva.wd1.myworkdayjobs.com/en-US/UVAJobs/job/Charlottesville-VA/Assistant-Professor–General-Faculty—Department-of-Religious-Studies_R0042078?q=R0042078</a></p>



<h3>Smithsonian National Museum of African American History and Culture: Supervisory Museum Curator (Religion)</h3>



<p>Washington DC, US</p>



<p>Deadline: December 10, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php?id=64610">https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php?id=64610</a></p>



<h4>Lecturer in Islamic Studies</h4>



<p>University of Melbourne, Australia</p>



<p>Deadline: November 20<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://eur01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Faasr.us20.list-manage.com%2Ftrack%2Fclick%3Fu%3D66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c%26id%3Dc87a97620e%26e%3D0f674ac9ff&amp;data=05%7C01%7Cdavid.robertson%40open.ac.uk%7C45e7f69edb704b5ad0c008dac2a83312%7C0e2ed45596af4100bed3a8e5fd981685%7C0%7C0%7C638036324930409850%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=3dovpFJ5AyPOCqXRzPC3JF4ufkr%2BxC8wj5F%2Fh3sDMi8%3D&amp;reserved=0">https://eur01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Faasr.us20.list-manage.com%2Ftrack%2Fclick%3Fu%3D66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c%26id%3Dc87a97620e%26e%3D0f674ac9ff&amp;data=05%7C01%7Cdavid.robertson%40open.ac.uk%7C45e7f69edb704b5ad0c008dac2a83312%7C0e2ed45596af4100bed3a8e5fd981685%7C0%7C0%7C638036324930409850%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=3dovpFJ5AyPOCqXRzPC3JF4ufkr%2BxC8wj5F%2Fh3sDMi8%3D&amp;reserved=0</a></p>



<h2>Conferences</h2>



<h4>INFORM: New Religious Responses to the Climate Crisis – Radical Environmentalism and Protest</h4>



<p>Online</p>



<p>Date: December 7<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://inform.ac/upcoming-events/">https://inform.ac/upcoming-events/</a></p>



<h4>Australian Association for the Study of Religion</h4>



<p>Melbourne Australia</p>



<p>Date: December 1<sup>, </sup>2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://eur01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Faasr.us20.list-manage.com%2Ftrack%2Fclick%3Fu%3D66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c%26id%3Dc1738b2455%26e%3D0f674ac9ff&amp;data=05%7C01%7Cdavid.robertson%40open.ac.uk%7C45e7f69edb704b5ad0c008dac2a83312%7C0e2ed45596af4100bed3a8e5fd981685%7C0%7C0%7C638036324930253633%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=lniYBeyfv4pZ3%2ByHwbJRnW1h6nSfydNJvYiwuM5Oyn4%3D&amp;reserved=0">https://eur01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Faasr.us20.list-manage.com%2Ftrack%2Fclick%3Fu%3D66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c%26id%3Dc1738b2455%26e%3D0f674ac9ff&amp;data=05%7C01%7Cdavid.robertson%40open.ac.uk%7C45e7f69edb704b5ad0c008dac2a83312%7C0e2ed45596af4100bed3a8e5fd981685%7C0%7C0%7C638036324930253633%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=lniYBeyfv4pZ3%2ByHwbJRnW1h6nSfydNJvYiwuM5Oyn4%3D&amp;reserved=0</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers</h2>



<h4>Australian National University Religion Conference: <em>Religion in Modern Education – Politics, Policy, and Practice</em></h4>



<p>Date: April 13-15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://eur01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Faasr.us20.list-manage.com%2Ftrack%2Fclick%3Fu%3D66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c%26id%3D5c1074c5d6%26e%3D0f674ac9ff&amp;data=05%7C01%7Cdavid.robertson%40open.ac.uk%7C45e7f69edb704b5ad0c008dac2a83312%7C0e2ed45596af4100bed3a8e5fd981685%7C0%7C0%7C638036324930409850%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=oEDCbfkYHYOdW1vmuA7SPiyJk1Cv1%2BXGqCGtX6e%2BTMI%3D&amp;reserved=0">https://eur01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Faasr.us20.list-manage.com%2Ftrack%2Fclick%3Fu%3D66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c%26id%3D5c1074c5d6%26e%3D0f674ac9ff&amp;data=05%7C01%7Cdavid.robertson%40open.ac.uk%7C45e7f69edb704b5ad0c008dac2a83312%7C0e2ed45596af4100bed3a8e5fd981685%7C0%7C0%7C638036324930409850%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=oEDCbfkYHYOdW1vmuA7SPiyJk1Cv1%2BXGqCGtX6e%2BTMI%3D&amp;reserved=0</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1668667028397634</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Papers: Apocalyptic Nostalgia? Cold War Imagery in Popular Culture (Manchester, 13th July 2023)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11725157/call-papers-apocalyptic-nostalgia-cold-war-imagery-popular</link>
						<dc:creator>Andrew Crome</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-28T00:00:00-05:00">February 28, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>American History / Studies, Cultural History / Studies, Popular Culture Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Social History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><strong>Apocalyptic Nostalgia? Cold War Imagery in Popular Culture</strong></p><p>Manchester Metropolitan University and the Centre for the Critical Study of Apocalyptic and Millenarian Movements.</p><p>Thursday 13<sup>th</sup> July 2023 at Imperial War Museum North, Manchester, UK.</p><p><strong>Deadline for submissions: Tuesday 28<sup>th</sup> February 2023.</strong></p><p>Since the end of the Cold War, its imagery, atmosphere, and music have been repeatedly appropriated and reappropriated within contemporary popular culture. More than thirty years after the Berlin Wall fell, these images continue to appeal to generations with no memory of the original tensions of the time. From the early Cold War imagery of games such as the <em>Fallout</em> series, or the mid-1980s backdrop of Soviet infiltration in <em>Stranger Things</em>, visual culture, music, and ideas from the period are constantly recycled in popular culture. These images are often linked to fears of nuclear destruction or disturbing post-apocalyptic settings, while also recalling nostalgic and often patriotic images of a lost world of the West. With the recent Russian invasion of Ukraine and heightened fear of nuclear war, these images are being appropriated and applied in new ways online and in popular entertainment.</p><p>This conference invites participants to examine this theme and to explore the complexities of encountering Cold War imagery within popular film, television, video and tabletop games, music, graphic novels and social media content. In particular, it aims to examine the way in which this imagery impacts understandings of the apocalyptic and post-apocalyptic within popular culture. Potential topics might include, but are not limited to:</p><ul><li>The role of nostalgia and nuclear destruction on screen.</li><li>The influence of popular culture on historical memory.</li><li>“Alternative histories” of the Cold War in popular culture.</li><li>Live action roleplay.</li><li>“Apocalyptic fandom”.</li><li>Use of Cold War-era music in film, television and gaming.</li><li>The role of Cold War narratives and imagery in Marvel/DC franchises media.</li><li>The use of apocalypticism in historical and popular documentaries.</li><li>Cold War imagery on social media related to the Ukraine War.</li><li>Cold War kitsch and ironic nostalgia.</li><li>Player agency in apocalyptic video games.</li></ul><p>The conference will take place on Thursday 13<sup>th</sup> July 2023 at Imperial War Museum North, Manchester, UK. There is no charge for registration/attendance for those presenting papers.</p><p>For submissions, email 250-word abstracts with a short biography to Dr. Andrew Crome <a href="mailto:a.crome@mmu.ac.uk">a.crome@mmu.ac.uk</a> by Tuesday 28<sup>th</sup> February 2023.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Andrew Crome, Senior Lecturer in Early Modern History, Manchester Metropolitan University</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:a.crome@mmu.ac.uk">a.crome@mmu.ac.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://censamm.org/conferences/cold-war-nostalgia" target="_blank">https://censamm.org/conferences/cold-war-nostalgia</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 18:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1668580629478140</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Submissions to Open Access Forum in Theological Librarianship</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11694666/call-submissions-open-access-forum-theological-librarianship</link>
						<dc:creator>Garrett Trott</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-12T00:00:00-05:00">November 12, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-01T00:00:00-04:00">June 1, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Library and Information Science, Religious Studies and Theology, Philosophy</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The <a href="https://nam04.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.atla.com%2Fabout%2Fscholarly-communication-committee%2F&amp;data=05%7C01%7Cgtrott%40corban.edu%7C3e484efc49574c5177b308dac28fc753%7C8ca445b8b5ec48d19ceea57565b0f7af%7C0%7C0%7C638036220923913480%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C2000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=mSrhBhjDIRWqn9CvcVvYWrksWfPzq9PLF6OBVnyXqRc%3D&amp;reserved=0" rel="nofollow"><span>Atla Scholarly Communication &amp; Digital Initiatives Committee</span></a> in collaboration with the <a href="https://nam04.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fserials.atla.com%2Ftheolib&amp;data=05%7C01%7Cgtrott%40corban.edu%7C3e484efc49574c5177b308dac28fc753%7C8ca445b8b5ec48d19ceea57565b0f7af%7C0%7C0%7C638036220923913480%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C2000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=D0Ook7nPjTdrgVzAMuPkDgpL8jxxSagO3XT%2BrEeqZUo%3D&amp;reserved=0" rel="nofollow"><em><span>Theological Librarianship</span></em></a> editorial board seeks submissions for a special forum on the “ethical imperative of Open” to be published in October 2023 to commemorate Open Access Week 2023.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The opening sentence of the <a href="https://nam04.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.budapestopenaccessinitiative.org%2Fread%2F&amp;data=05%7C01%7Cgtrott%40corban.edu%7C3e484efc49574c5177b308dac28fc753%7C8ca445b8b5ec48d19ceea57565b0f7af%7C0%7C0%7C638036220923913480%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C2000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=JILIWN9KZ7jSumTpEwh1xEsaw16AAEhqHH9nb5FSxdo%3D&amp;reserved=0" rel="nofollow"><span>Budapest Open Access Initiative in 2002</span></a> is very clear in stating that the nascent movement was seeking to “make possible an unprecedented good.” The question that arises out of that statement is if there is anything that turns the Open movement into something that <em><span>should</span></em> happen rather than merely something that <em><span>can</span></em> happen. In other words, is there an ethical imperative that should compellingly drive librarians to promote the production and dissemination of Open resources? And if so, what is it? </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Theological librarians are in a unique position to reflect on ethical issues from the perspective of spirituality. In order to explore this underdeveloped area of the Open environment, the fall 2023 issue of <em><span>Theological Librarianship</span></em> will host a forum that invites librarians and other information professionals to share their experiences with, or reflections on, the development or use of an ethical imperative to promote the production and/or dissemination of Open resources.   </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Submissions (750-1500 words) are due by June 1, 2023 and should be submitted at <a href="https://nam04.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fserials.atla.com%2Ftheolib%2Fabout%2Fsubmissions&amp;data=05%7C01%7Cgtrott%40corban.edu%7C3e484efc49574c5177b308dac28fc753%7C8ca445b8b5ec48d19ceea57565b0f7af%7C0%7C0%7C638036220923913480%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C2000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=VrZLzHVosrX5qEUgAqptmo1Cp93ej8uI73%2Fb7cA4YnY%3D&amp;reserved=0" rel="nofollow"><span>https://serials.atla.com/theolib/about/submissions</span></a>. Any questions about the forum or submitting to it should be directed to the <a href="mailto:editors-tl@atla.com"><span>editorial board of <em><span>Theological Librarianship</span></em></span></a>.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Garrett Trott</p><p>Editor-in-Chief of <em>Theological Librarianship</em></p><p><a href="mailto:gtrott@corban.edu">gtrott@corban.edu</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:gtrott@corban.edu">gtrott@corban.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1668580629478139</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
