<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 12:24:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 12:24:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>Interfaith Dialogue 2023 : Interfaith Dialogue What is a perfect human being?</title>
			<link>http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=171786&amp;copyownerid=179615</link>
						<description>Interfaith Dialogue What is a perfect human being? [Berlin, Online] [Mar 17, 2023 - Mar 17, 2023]</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 06:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676356629355917</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Interfaith Dialogue  2023 : Interfaith Dialogue What is a perfect human being?</title>
			<link>http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=171787&amp;copyownerid=179616</link>
						<description>Interfaith Dialogue What is a perfect human being? [Berlin, Online] [Mar 17, 2023 - Mar 17, 2023]</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 06:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676356629355916</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Political Theology and the State of Exce 2023 : NEW DEADLINE FOR SUBMISSIONS: CALL FOR PAPERS - Political Theology and the State of Exception: Critical readings on the centenary of Political Theology &amp; Roman Catholicism and Poli</title>
			<link>http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=171861&amp;copyownerid=173363</link>
						<description>NEW DEADLINE FOR SUBMISSIONS: CALL FOR PAPERS - Political Theology and the State of Exception: Critical readings on the centenary of Political Theology &amp; Roman Catholicism and Poli</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 06:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676356629355915</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ March 2, 2023] Conference or similar: Self-Narratives and Irony</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/107997</link>
						<description>Venue: Deakin Downtown, Level 12, 727 Collins Street<br/><br/><p>Over the last fourty years, the philosophical question surrounding the problem of personal identity has undergone two important and concomitant transformations. These transformations have durably affected theories of personal identity. Departing from the metaphysical ground of analysis of the modalities of identification and temporal synthesis of the Ego, a significant number of historical or systematic works devoted to the question of the Self have first sought to re-inscribe the problem a practical perspective. This allows the question of personal identity to be approached in narrower frameworks: those of moral philosophy or philosophy of action (Williams B. 1982, Frankfurt 1988, Ricœur 1990, Taylor 1992, Korsgaard 1996, Moran 2001, Larmore 2004, Descombes 2014). A second important displacement in the question of personal identity occurred in parallel to this first transformation with the rise of the narrative approaches of the self (MacIntyre 1981, Ricœur 1984, Bruner 1987 and 1991, Schechtman 1996, 73, Hutto 2007, Goldie 2012), engaging an in-depth reinterpretation of the question of individual identity and initiating the "narrative turn" of identity theories (Stokes 2015, 166).</p>

<p>These two lines of transformation have converged and come together over the last fifteen years through various works seeking to take advantage of the resources offered by narrative identity theories in order to propose a new model of "practical identity” (Williams S. 2004, Atkins 2008, Atkins and Mackenzie 2008, Korsgaard 2009, Mackenzie and Poltera 2010, Davenport 2012). However, this philosophical attempt to renew our understanding of personal identity highlight the practical dimension of the self and paid little attention to the various forms of self-detachment that narratives allow. The use of irony in the construction of narratives is paradigmatic of such forms of self-detachment, which enable the narrator to take a critical distance towards the characters of the story told.</p>

<p>The purpose of this workshop is to analyze the forms of self-detachment that ironical self-narratives involve, so as to highlight the role and philosophical significance of irony with regard to the constitution of one’s identity. </p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 06:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676356629355914</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Funding opportunities from the Friends Historical Association</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12364483/funding-opportunities-friends-historical-association</link>
						<dc:creator>Jordan Landes</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Grant</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-04-15T00:00:00-04:00">April 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The Friends Historical Association is pleased to offer funding to support contributions to the field of Quaker history. There are three grant opportunities: project support, publication subventions, and research funds. All opportunities run on the same cycle, and applications are due April 15, 2023. Details about each opportunity and application instruction are provided at <a href="https://www.quakerhistory.org/grants" rel="nofollow">https://www.quakerhistory.org/grants</a>.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Friends Historical Association<br/>c/o Haverford College Library<br/>370 Lancaster Ave. <br/>Haverford, PA 19041-1392</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:president@quakerhistory.org">president@quakerhistory.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.quakerhistory.org/grants" target="_blank">https://www.quakerhistory.org/grants</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 19:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676356629355913</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Symposium Understanding Judaism: New Approaches to Rabbinic Literature</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12346767/symposium-understanding-judaism-new-approaches-rabbinic</link>
						<dc:creator>Albertina Oegema</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Symposium</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-20T00:00:00-04:00">March 20, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-21T00:00:00-04:00">March 21, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Netherlands</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Ancient History, Classical Studies, Humanities, Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span>The board of the </span>Compendia Rerum Iudaicarum ad Novum Testamentum<span> is<span> thrilled to extend our invitation to you to join the two-day symposium ‘Understanding Judaism: New Approaches to Rabbinic Literature’, featuring honored Yale Professor Christine Hayes and other notable speakers such as Professors Peter Tomson, Martin Goodman, Lutz Doering, and Annette Merz. </span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>The symposium addresses the ways recent developments in the study of rabbinic literature affect long-standing modes of approaching culture, religion, and society in Late Antiquity. The seminar will take place at Utrecht University (Utrecht, the Netherlands) on March 20th and 21st, 2023, and celebrates the publication of Christine Hayes’ groundbreaking volume of </span></span><a href="https://brill.com/display/title/62292" rel="nofollow"><i><span><span><span><span>The Literature of the Sages: A Re-Visioning</span></span></span></span></i></a><a href="https://brill.com/display/title/62292" rel="nofollow"><span><span><span><span> (CRINT 16; Leiden: Brill, 2022)</span></span></span></span></a><span><span>. The symposium will include a masterclass featuring up-and-coming students and their work. For internationally based scholars, there are possibilities to attend the symposium virtually.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span>Symposium Programme</span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><u><span>Day 1</span></u></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span>09:30 Entrance</span></i></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>10:00 Eric Ottenheijm, Opening</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>10:10 Introduction by Peter J. Tomson </span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>10:45</span><i><span> Coffee/Tea Break</span></i></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>11:00 Christine Hayes, Introductory Lecture</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>11:45 Questions from the audience</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span>12:15 Lunch</span></i></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>13.30 Responses by three external specialists: Lutz Doering; Martin Goodman; Annette Merz.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span>15.00 Tea Break </span></i></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>15.30 Response of prof. Hayes</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Followed by a general discussion on the volume’s merits and final words by Eric Ottenheijm</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span>16.00 Reception</span></i></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span>18:00 Dinner (invited guests only)</span></i></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><u><span><span>Day 2</span></span></u></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span>09:30 Entrance</span></i></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>10:00 Eric Ottenheijm, Opening</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>10:15 Masterclass (part I)</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span>11:30 Coffee/Tea break</span></i></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>11:45 Masterclass (part II)</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span>13:00 Lunch</span></i></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span>You can sign up with this sign-up link to register for the symposium or receive more information:</span><a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeqcJ4MQm2xbnH5mrHEvGW7YLW0JFPmS5kRr6yHe7nYshg-Kw/viewform?usp=sf_link" rel="nofollow"><span><span><span> <span><span><span>https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeqcJ4MQm2xbnH5mrHEvGW7YLW0JFPmS5kRr6yHe7nYshg-Kw/viewform?usp=sf_link</span></span></span></span></span></span></a> </span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Moreover, it would be most beneficial if you could spread the word about this exciting event. Please send this e-mail to anyone interested in the event in your network. Attached are both the poster and the social media post of the event. If you have channels to post about the event, please feel free to do so. Additionally, printing the poster and hanging it up in relevant areas near you would be beneficial to us. We have provided a caption for you to copy and paste into social media posts. </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>“On the 20th and 21st of March, 2023, CRINT presents the unique opportunity to learn from Yale Professor Christine Hayes through attending the Symposium on ‘Understanding Judaism’ in Utrecht. Sign up with this link to register for the symposium, receive more information, or view the program:</span><a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeqcJ4MQm2xbnH5mrHEvGW7YLW0JFPmS5kRr6yHe7nYshg-Kw/viewform?usp=sf_link" rel="nofollow"><span><span><span> <span><span><span>https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeqcJ4MQm2xbnH5mrHEvGW7YLW0JFPmS5kRr6yHe7nYshg-Kw/viewform?usp=sf_link</span></span></span></span></span></span></a><span><span>"</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Thank you for all your support. We hope to see you at the symposium soon and welcome all questions you may have. </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Kind regards, </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>On behalf of Dr. Eric Ottenheijm, Utrecht University, Chair of the CRINT Foundation.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Dr. Albertina Oegema, Radboud University Nijmegen / J. Gutenberg University Mainz, Secretary of the CRINT Foundation. </span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span>Perlei Toor (Student Assistant)</span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr. Albertina Oegema <br/><span><span><span><span><span><span>Radboud University Nijmegen / J. Gutenberg University Mainz, Secretary of the CRINT Foundation</span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:albertina.oegema@uni-mainz.de">albertina.oegema@uni-mainz.de</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 18:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676356629355912</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ July 1, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Philosophy and the Age of the Anthropocene</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/107937</link>
						<description><p>The term “Anthropocene” was coined by geologists in the latter half of the 20th century and popularized in the early 2000s to propose a new definition of the current geological era as one in which human activity has become the most dominant factor in the earth’s processes. The claim, proponents argue, is evidenced by phenomena such as anthropogenic climate change, loss of biodiversity, ocean acidification, and more. At the same time, philosophers have increasingly utilized the term to pursue related questions. What is the human? What is nature? Where does responsibility lie for the current ecological crisis? Would a category other than the human—such as capitalism, industrial technology, colonialism, or anthropocentric thinking itself—be more fruitful for these analyses? This work also dovetails with questions about the current relationship between philosophy and science more generally, such as questions about the legitimacy of using and expanding the meanings of scientific terms in extra-scientific contexts. Moreover, if we accept the term’s use, we are faced with practical and ethical questions: Can living in the Anthropocene be sustainable in the long term, or would moving beyond the Anthropocene even be possible? This conference aims to develop these and related questions.</p>
<p>We welcome abstract submissions from all academic disciplines, approaches, and traditions. Presentations will be 20 minutes long with a 15-20 minute Q&amp;A to follow each presentation. Potential paper topics include, but are not limited to, the following:</p>
<p>• The history of the term Anthropocene</p>
<p>• The dating of the Anthropocene</p>
<p>• Weighing the risks and urgency of various potential existential threats, including nuclear technology, superintelligence, artificial intelligence, climate change, nanotechnology, and gene editing technology</p>
<p>• Proposed definitions of the Anthropocene from different disciplinary perspectives</p>
<p>• Critical perspectives (including feminism, philosophy of race, decolonial thought, Marxism, deconstruction, and critical theory) on the Anthropocene</p>
<p>• Alternative proposed names for the Anthropocene, such as the Capitalocene (Moore), Chthulucene, Plantationocene (Haraway), Eurocene, and/or Entropocene (Stiegler)</p>
<p>• Philosophical approaches to humans, nature, and technology from figures in the history of philosophy</p>
<p>• Topics in philosophical anthropology related to the meaning of the human and the relation of the human to nature, non-human animals, and technology</p>
<p>• Topics in environmental philosophy related to the meaning of terms such as nature, ecosystem, environment, biodiversity, and sustainability</p>
<p>• Topics in the philosophy of science related to the use and expansion of meanings of scientific terms in extra-scientific contexts</p>
<p>• Practical, ethical, and political questions concerned with the possibility of living in or exiting the Anthropocene (such as Stiegler’s notion of the Neganthropocene)</p>
<p><strong>Please send 300-500 word abstracts prepared for anonymous review in PDF format to: depaulconference2023@gmail.com.</strong></p>
<p><strong>In the body of your email, please include 1) Name, 2) Institutional Affiliation, 3) Title of Paper, and 4) Contact Information (Email and phone number).</strong></p>
<p>While we are unable to provide any assistance with travel costs, the conference organizers will do our very best to find free accommodation for conference presenters who do not receive institutional funding for travel to conferences.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 06:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676270235358730</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ September 29, 2023 -  September 30, 2023] Conference or similar: Philosophy and the Age of the Anthropocene</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/107933</link>
						<description>Venue: 2350 N Kenmore Ave<br/><br/><p>The term “Anthropocene” was coined by geologists in the latter half of the 20th century and popularized in the early 2000s to propose a new definition of the current geological era as one in which human activity has become the most dominant factor in the earth’s processes. The claim, proponents argue, is evidenced by phenomena such as anthropogenic climate change, loss of biodiversity, ocean acidification, and more. At the same time, philosophers have increasingly utilized the term to pursue related questions. What is the human? What is nature? Where does responsibility lie for the current ecological crisis? Would a category other than the human—such as capitalism, industrial technology, colonialism, or anthropocentric thinking itself—be more fruitful for these analyses? This work also dovetails with questions about the current relationship between philosophy and science more generally, such as questions about the legitimacy of using and expanding the meanings of scientific terms in extra-scientific contexts. Moreover, if we accept the term’s use, we are faced with practical and ethical questions: Can living in the Anthropocene be sustainable in the long term, or would moving beyond the Anthropocene even be possible? This conference aims to develop these and related questions.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 06:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676270235358729</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[Today] Talk or similar: For a New Perspectivism: Defending Alternatives in the Age of Post-Truth</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/107869</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/>Speakers at this event: <br/>Emmanuel Alloa (Université de Fribourg)<br/>Emmanuel Alloa (Universität Basel)<br/><br/></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 06:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676097427341493</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ June 1, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Seventh Theistic Ethics Workshop</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/107901</link>
						<description><p>Applying: Those interested in participating should submit an abstract of up to 750 words and a current C.V. to Christian Miller at millerc@wfu.edu by June 1, 2023. Word or PDF file formats only. Please prepare abstracts for anonymous review.  For although the organizers seek to have a balanced program both in terms of topics and presenters, the initial stage of review will be done anonymously. Submitters to a previous year’s workshop, whether successful or unsuccessful, are welcome to apply to this year’s workshop. Questions about the workshop should be sent to millerc@wfu.edu. Notification will be made by June 17, 2023. If your abstract is selected, we will cover all of your expenses for the workshop, including travel (this includes international travel). Co-authors are welcome, but only one author’s expenses can be covered. You do not have to send your paper in advance of the workshop, and it certainly can be a work in progress.</p>
<p>Goal: Contemporary philosophy of religion has been richly informed by important work in metaphysics and epistemology. At the same time, there has not been nearly as much work done at the intersection of philosophy of religion and meta-ethics or normative theory. To help inspire more good work in this area, Christian Miller (Wake Forest), Mark Murphy (Georgetown), and Chris Tucker (William &amp; Mary) have been organizing a series of annual workshops on theistic ethics for a number of years.</p>
<p>Logistics: The seventh workshop will be held at the Graylyn Conference Center at Wake Forest University (www.graylyn.com), one of the nicest conference facilities in the country. We will begin with dinner and the first paper on Thursday, September 7 and conclude at the end of the day on Saturday, September 9, 2023. There will be five invited papers and four spots for submitted papers. All papers have 40 minutes for presentation and at least 40 minutes for discussion.</p>
<p>Themes: “Theistic ethics” is to be understood broadly to include such topics as divine command and divine will theories, God and natural law, ethics and the problem of evil, moral arguments for a theistic being, infused and acquired virtues, the harms and benefits of theistic religions, specific ethical issues in Judaism, Christianity, or Islam, and many other topics as well.</p>
<p>Applying: Those interested in participating should submit an abstract of up to 750 words and a current C.V. to Christian Miller at millerc@wfu.edu by June 1, 2023. Word or PDF file formats only. Please prepare abstracts for anonymous review.  For although the organizers seek to have a balanced program both in terms of topics and presenters, the initial stage of review will be done anonymously. Submitters to a previous year’s workshop, whether successful or unsuccessful, are welcome to apply to this year’s workshop. Questions about the workshop should be sent to millerc@wfu.edu. Notification will be made by June 17, 2023. If your abstract is selected, we will cover all of your expenses for the workshop, including travel (this includes international travel). Co-authors are welcome, but only one author’s expenses can be covered. You do not have to send your paper in advance of the workshop, and it certainly can be a work in progress.</p>
<p>Supported by generous funding from the Carswell Fund of the Wake Forest University Philosophy Department</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 06:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676097427341492</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ September 7, 2023 -  September 9, 2023] Conference or similar: Seventh Theistic Ethics Workshop</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/107897</link>
						<description>Venue: 1900 REYNOLDA ROAD<br/><br/><p>Goal: Contemporary philosophy of religion has been richly informed by important work in metaphysics and epistemology. At the same time, there has not been nearly as much work done at the intersection of philosophy of religion and meta-ethics or normative theory. To help inspire more good work in this area, Christian Miller (Wake Forest), Mark Murphy (Georgetown), and Chris Tucker (William &amp; Mary) have been organizing a series of annual workshops on theistic ethics for a number of years.</p>
<p>Logistics: The seventh workshop will be held at the Graylyn Conference Center at Wake Forest University (www.graylyn.com), one of the nicest conference facilities in the country. We will begin with dinner and the first paper on Thursday, September 7 and conclude at the end of the day on Saturday, September 9, 2023. There will be five invited papers and four spots for submitted papers. All papers have 40 minutes for presentation and at least 40 minutes for discussion.</p>
<p>Themes: “Theistic ethics” is to be understood broadly to include such topics as divine command and divine will theories, God and natural law, ethics and the problem of evil, moral arguments for a theistic being, infused and acquired virtues, the harms and benefits of theistic religions, specific ethical issues in Judaism, Christianity, or Islam, and many other topics as well.</p>
<p>Supported by generous funding from the Carswell Fund of the Wake Forest University Philosophy Department</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 06:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676097427341491</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>MLA 24: Milton's Networks, Transhistorical and Global</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/02/08/mla-24-miltons-networks-transhistorical-and-global</link>
						<dc:creator>esong1@swarthmore.edu</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Friday, February 10, 2023 - 12:24pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Milton Society of America</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:esong1@swarthmore.edu">esong1@swarthmore.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/fan-studies-and-fandom">fan studies and fandom</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/poetry">poetry</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/renaissance">renaissance</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/translation-studies">translation studies</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>March 3, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p> The Milton Society of America invites papers that locate Milton’s writings in different networks across periods and boundaries. Potential topics include adaptation, influence, and translation. Please send a brief abstract (approximately 200 words) and an abbreviated cv to Eric Song (<a href="mailto:esong1@swarthmore.edu">esong1@swarthmore.edu</a>) no later than March 3, 2023.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 19:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676097427341490</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>MLA 24: Milton and Bodily Freedom</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/02/08/mla-24-milton-and-bodily-freedom</link>
						<dc:creator>esong1@swarthmore.edu</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Friday, February 10, 2023 - 12:24pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Milton Society of America</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:esong1@swarthmore.edu">esong1@swarthmore.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/gender-studies-and-sexuality">gender studies and sexuality</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/renaissance">renaissance</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>March 3, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>The Milton Society of America invites papers considering the freedom or unfreedom of the body as a political, religious, philosophical, and artistic concept. Potential topics include reproduction, restrictions on movement, and enslavement. Please send a brief abstract (approximately 200 words) and an abbreviated cv to Eric Song (<a href="mailto:esong1@swarthmore.edu">esong1@swarthmore.edu</a>) no later than March 3, 2023.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 19:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676097427341489</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Legacy and Limits of Vatican II in an Age of Crisis: Gender, Race, Abuse, and the Living Catholic Tradition</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12333457/legacy-and-limits-vatican-ii-age-crisis-gender-race-abuse-and</link>
						<dc:creator>Massimo Faggioli</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-04-30T00:00:00-04:00">April 30, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Pennsylvania</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies, Jewish History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><u><span><strong>Villanova University</strong></span></u></p><p><span><strong>The Department of Theology and Religious Studies at Villanova University announces an upcoming conference and call for papers</strong></span></p><p><span><u><strong>The Legacy and Limits of Vatican II in an Age of Crisis: </strong></u></span></p><p><span><u><strong>Gender, Race, Abuse, and the Living Catholic Tradition</strong></u></span></p><p><span><strong>November 30 – December 2, 2023, Villanova University</strong></span></p><p><u><strong>Keynote Speakers</strong></u></p><p><strong>Edward Hahnenberg </strong>(John Carroll University – Cleveland)<br/><strong>Mary Kate Holman</strong> (Benedictine University - Chicago)<br/><strong>Jaisy Joseph </strong>(Villanova University - Pennsylvania)<br/><strong>Carlos Schickendantz </strong>(Universidad Alberto Hurtado - Santiago de Chile)</p><p><span><u><strong>Call for papers</strong></u></span></p><p>Villanova University announces a call for papers for a conference on the Second Vatican Council (November 30 – December 2, 2023, Villanova University). In light of the serious challenges facing the Church today—many of which were not anticipated by the council—the conference will explore how the event of Vatican II, its agenda for renewal, and its reception (or lack thereof) can inform a faith-filled response to the new “signs of the times.” The legacy of the council’s teaching on topics ranging from the laity, ecclesiology, and ecumenism to the Church’s understanding of the modern state, culture, and the very nature of the human person risk becoming irrelevant if they cannot be retrieved and reimagined within the atmospheres of a polarized Church and world. This conference seeks to begin just such a conversation about Vatican II in the context of the current ecclesial crisis.</p><p>Paper proposals, related to the theology and reception of Vatican II, are encouraged on the following topics: theology of the laity and clericalism; gender and the role of women in the Church; racism; the abuse crisis in the Church; post- colonial and de-colonial critique; the resurgence of anti-Semitism; the new “political ecumenism”; the Church and the internet/social media; evangelization</p><p>and the youth; the rise of anti-Vatican II traditionalism/conservatism; the Church and the “culture wars”; Vatican II and the identity of Catholic institutions today (education, health care, charities, etc.).</p><p>The steering committee is composed of Catherine Clifford (Saint Paul University, Ottawa), Kristin Colberg (St. John’s University, Collegeville MN), Massimo Faggioli (Villanova University), and Edward Hahnenberg (John Carroll University, Cleveland).</p><p>Proposals of no more than 300 words should be submitted by <span><strong>April 30, 2023</strong></span>, to <u><strong>Massimo Faggioli (<a href="mailto:mfaggiol@villanova.edu">mfaggiol@villanova.edu</a>) </strong></u>and to the secretary of the steering committee, <strong><u>Theresa Gardner (<a href="mailto:tgardn02@villanova.edu">tgardn02@villanova.edu</a>).</u></strong> Further details about the conference will be provided at villanova.edu/vatican2conference.</p><p>Liturgical Press is committed to publish an edited volume of the proceedings of the conference.</p><p>The conference is sponsored by the Department of Theology and Religious Studies, the College of Liberal Arts and Sciences, the Office of Diversity, Equity and Inclusion, and the Office for Mission and Ministry at Villanova University.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><u><strong>Massimo Faggioli (<a href="mailto:mfaggiol@villanova.edu">mfaggiol@villanova.edu</a>)</strong></u> </p><p>Secretary of the steering committee, <u><strong>Theresa Gardner (<a href="mailto:tgardn02@villanova.edu">tgardn02@villanova.edu</a>).</strong></u> </p><p>Website: <strong>villanova.edu/vatican2conference.</strong></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:mfaggiol@villanova.edu">mfaggiol@villanova.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="http://villanova.edu/vatican2conference." target="_blank">http://villanova.edu/vatican2conference.</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 18:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676011027205281</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call For Papers (CFP) for National Seminar on 'Religion &amp; Society in India: Contemporary Multi-Disciplinary Explorations'</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12329115/call-papers-cfp-national-seminar-religion-society-india</link>
						<dc:creator>Anjali  Joseph</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-31T00:00:00-04:00">March 31, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>India</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology, Philosophy, Sociology, Psychology, Social Sciences</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>National Biblical Catechetical and Liturgical Centre (NBCLC), networking with esteemed institutions of higher education in Bengaluru, plans to organise a research seminar on <strong>07-08 August 2023</strong>. The theme of the seminar is <strong>'Religion &amp; Society in India: Contemporary Multi-Disciplinary Explorations'</strong>. NBCLC invites<strong> Call for Papers </strong>from students, research scholars and faculty for this seminar.</p><p>The possible sub-themes for submission under CFP include, but are not limited to, the following:</p><ul><li>Social Identities and Indian Religions</li><li>Personality Developments and Indian Religions</li><li>Spiritualities and Philosophies</li><li>Indian Personality Traits and Religio-Philosophical Traditions</li><li>Spirituality and Counselling</li><li>Spirituality and Youth</li><li>Cultural Creativity and Indian Religious Traditions Today</li><li>Indian Religions in their Contemporary Phase of Transformations</li><li>Indian Religions and Social Transformations Today</li><li>Indian Religions and Spiritualities</li><li>Indian Philosophical Traditions</li><li>Indian Religio-Philosophical Traditions and Civil Society Today</li><li>Global Civil Society and Indian Religious Diaspora</li><li>Religions, Philosophies, and Spiritualities and the Public Sphere in India</li><li>Indian Religio-Philosophical Traditions and Higher Education in India</li><li>Gender and Religion in India</li><li>Subaltern communities and Religio-Cultural Traditions in India</li><li>Dietary Management and Religious Beliefs and Practices in India</li><li>Physical well-being and Religious and Spiritual Practices in India</li><li>Religion, Art and Culture in India</li><li>Freedom of Religion and Indian Politics</li><li>Religious Centres and Civil Society in India</li></ul><p><strong>Dates to remember</strong></p><ul><li>Last Date to receive paper proposals: <strong>31 March 2023</strong></li><li>Announcement of Selection of Papers: <strong>15 April 2023</strong></li><li>Full-paper submissions: <strong>25 July 2023 </strong>(6000 – 7000 words, including notes and bibliography)</li><li>Seminar Dates: <strong>07-08, August 2023</strong></li></ul><p><strong>Venue</strong>: NBCLC, Hutchins Road, 2nd Cross, Bengaluru</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>+91 080-25472369, +91 9482402369</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:nbclcresearch@gmail.com">nbclcresearch@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.nbclcindia.org/pdf/ProposedseminaronReligion-Society-IndiaConceptNote.pdf" target="_blank">https://www.nbclcindia.org/pdf/ProposedseminaronReligion-Society-IndiaConceptNote.pdf</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 18:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676011027205280</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Symposium: Gender and Voice in Japanese Art</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12327512/symposium-gender-and-voice-japanese-art</link>
						<dc:creator>Einor Cervone</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Symposium</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-25T00:00:00-05:00">February 25, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Colorado</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Art, Art History &amp; Visual Studies, Early Modern History and Period Studies, Japanese History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The Denver Art Museum is pleased to host a one-day international symposium in conjunction with the exhibition, <a href="https://www.denverartmuseum.org/en/exhibitions/her-brush" rel="nofollow"><em><strong>Her Brush: Japanese Women Artists from the Fong-Johnstone Collection</strong></em></a>. Scholars and specialists from various disciplines will add to the discourse on approaches and methodologies in the study, connoisseurship, and exhibition of Japanese art through the lens of gender, agency, and artistic voice.</p><p><a href="https://www.denverartmuseum.org/en/calendar/symposium-gender-and-voice-japanese-art" rel="nofollow"><strong>Free with Registration</strong></a></p><p><strong>Onsite &amp; Online</strong></p><p>Sturm Grand Pavilion</p><p>At the Denver Art Museum</p><hr/><p>SPEAKERS</p><p><strong>Paul Berry</strong> Independent scholar and former professor at Kansai Gaidai University and University of Washington (Kyoto, Japan)</p><p><strong>Patricia Fister</strong> Professor Emeritus, International Research Center for Japanese Studies Director of Research, Medieval Japanese Studies Institute/Center for the Study of Women, Buddhism, and Cultural History (Tokyo, Japan)</p><p><strong>Melissa McCormick</strong> Andrew W. Mellon Professor of Japanese Art and Culture, Harvard University (Cambridge, MA)</p><p><strong>Alison J. Miller</strong> Associate Professor of Art History and Director of Asian Studies, The University of the South (Sewanee, TN)</p><p><strong>Amy Beth Stanley</strong> Wayne V. Jones II Research Professor in History at Northwestern University (Evanston, IL)</p><p><strong>Marcia A. Yonemoto </strong>Professor of History, University of Colorado, Boulder (Boulder, CO)</p><hr/><p>SCHEDULE</p><p>9am Coffee and Welcome</p><p>9:20am Introductions</p><p>9:30-10am Patricia Fister/ <strong>Shining Light on Art by Japanese Buddhist Nuns</strong></p><p>10-10:30am Melissa McCormick/ <strong>Ōtagaki Rengetsu’s Buddhist Poetics: Gender and Materiality </strong></p><p>10:30–10:40am Coffee break</p><p>10:45–11:15am Paul Berry/ <strong>Narratives of Japanese Art History: Where are the Women?</strong></p><p>11:15-11:45am Q&amp;A</p><p>11:45-1:30pm Lunch Break </p><p>1:30-2pm Marcia A. Yonemoto/ <strong>Her Brush, Her Needle: Rethinking theRelationship Between Art and ArtisanalWork by Women in Early Modern Japan</strong></p><p>2–2:30pm Amy Beth Stanley/ <strong>Reading an Archive of Everyday Life</strong></p><p>2:30–2:40pm Coffee break</p><p>2:45–3:15pm Alison J. Miller/ <strong>Finding Gender in Japanese Literati Painting</strong></p><p>3:15-3:45pm Q&amp;A</p><p>3:45-3:50pm Concluding remarks</p><p>4–5pm Exhibition walkthrough/ <strong>Her Brush: Japanese Women Artistsfrom the Fong-Johnstone Collection</strong></p><hr/><p><em>This event is fully supported by the generous gift of The William Sharpless Jackson, Jr. Endowment for the Advancement of Asian Art and Culture.</em></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><table><tr><td><p> </p><p><span><span><span>Einor Cervone, PhD</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Associate Curator of Arts of Asia</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>(she/her/hers)</span></span></span></p><p> </p><table><tr><td><p><span><span><span><span><span>100 W 14th Avenue Pkwy<br/>Denver, CO 80204</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>(720) 865-5141<br/><a href="https://nam10.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fdenverartmuseum.org%2F&amp;data=04%7C01%7CECervone%40denverartmuseum.org%7Ca8ebf891d3734fda4fce08d97e0e1ce7%7Cce07caf59ef14a37b466a44073737e5f%7C0%7C0%7C637679421335212598%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&amp;sdata=SunN7WF4r9F53P79xd%2B1QnGJz0qe47dvjfHqyBs6qpg%3D&amp;reserved=0" rel="nofollow"><span><span>denverartmuseum.org</span></span></a></span></span></span></span></span></p></td></tr></table></td><td> </td></tr><tr><td> </td></tr><tr><td> </td></tr><tr><td> </td></tr></table></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ecervone@denverartmuseum.org">ecervone@denverartmuseum.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.denverartmuseum.org/en/calendar/symposium-gender-and-voice-japanese-art" target="_blank">https://www.denverartmuseum.org/en/calendar/symposium-gender-and-voice-japanese-art</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 18:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676011027205279</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>White House History Quarterly Call for Abstracts</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12302068/white-house-history-quarterly-call-abstracts</link>
						<dc:creator>Margaret Strolle</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2024-12-31T00:00:00-05:00">December 31, 2024</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>American History / Studies, Literature, Military History, Popular Culture Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The <em>White House History Quarterly </em>has an ongoing call for abstracts for articles relating to White House history. Current topics of interest include: the White House in literature and poetry, inaugural traditions, the White House and World War II, and first ladies. Please contact Margaret Strolle, Editorial and Production Manager with any questions at <a href="mailto:mstrolle@whha.org">mstrolle@whha.org</a>. Abstracts will receive a response 6 to 8 weeks after submission. Find out more information about the White House Historical Association at whhitehousehistory.org. </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:mstrolle@whha.org">mstrolle@whha.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.whitehousehistory.org/publishing/white-house-history-quarterly/for-current-and-potential-authors" target="_blank">https://www.whitehousehistory.org/publishing/white-house-history-quarterly/for-current-and-potential-authors</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 18:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676011027205278</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Updated - University of Manchester-Manchester Wesley Research Centre Joint Visiting Research Fellowship</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12301683/updated-university-manchester-manchester-wesley-research</link>
						<dc:creator>Geordan Hammond</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Fellowship</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-15T00:00:00-05:00">February 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>We're accepting applications for the University of Manchester-Manchester Wesley Research Centre Joint Visiting Research Fellowship. The aim of the fellowship is to promote research in the Methodist and Wesleyan traditions by facilitating scholarly access to the internationally renowned Methodist Archives held at the John Rylands Research Institute and Library in Manchester and the MWRC and Nazarene Theological College library. The extended deadline for applications is 15 February 2023. Information about other MWRC Fellowships can be found here: <a href="https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/visiting-fellows" rel="nofollow">https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/visiting-fellows. </a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ghammond@nazarene.ac.uk">ghammond@nazarene.ac.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/visiting-fellows" target="_blank">https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/visiting-fellows</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 18:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675924629710735</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Episcopal Historical Society Seeks Grant Requests</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12321147/episcopal-historical-society-seeks-grant-requests</link>
						<dc:creator>Matthew Payne</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Grant</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-05-01T00:00:00-04:00">May 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span>The Historical Society of the Episcopal Church invites applications for grants to be awarded July 2023. Grants are awarded for pursuing the Historical Society’s objectives, especially promotion of the preservation of the particular heritage of the Episcopal Church and its antecedents. This includes any part of the worldwide Anglican Communion. Applications must be submitted by May 1st to be considered with awards announced in July.</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Applications for a regular grant may be from individuals as well as academic and ecclesiastical groups. Requests may support significant research, conferences, and publication relating to the history of the Episcopal Church as well as the worldwide Anglican Communion. A typical request may include funding for travel to visit an archives or other resource, dissertation research, seed money or support for a larger project. Examples of past awards include dissertation research, publication of books and articles, support of documentary films, and history conference support. Awards generally are $500-$2,000, depending on the number of awards approved and funds available.</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>For details including application instruction and information, visit </span><a href="http://hsec.us/grants" rel="nofollow"><span>hsec.us/grants</span></a><span>.</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Applications for the triennial Robert W. Prichard Prize for the best dissertation which considers the history of the Episcopal Church or Anglican Communion will be next requested in 2025.</span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><span><span><span><span><span>Mr. Matthew P. Payne, Historical Society of the Episcopal Church  </span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span>Director of Operations</span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span>PO Box 1301| Appleton, WI 54912 | </span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span>(920) 383-1910 | </span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><a href="mailto:administration@hsec.us"><span><span>administration@hsec.us</span></span></a> |<a href="http://www.hsec.us/" rel="nofollow"><span><span>hsec.us</span></span></a></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:administration@hsec.us">administration@hsec.us</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://hsec.us/grants" target="_blank">https://hsec.us/grants</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 18:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675924629710734</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Translations, Transgressions, and Transformations: The Global Movement of Objects in Catholic Cultures</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12321019/translations-transgressions-and-transformations-global</link>
						<dc:creator>Mary Dunn</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-10-20T00:00:00-04:00">October 20, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Missouri</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Art, Art History &amp; Visual Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, World History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The Center for Research on Global Catholicism is delighted to announce plans for a major conference, entitled <b>"Translations, Transgressions, and Transformations: the Global Movement of Objects in Catholic Cultures,"</b> to be held at Saint Louis University <b>October 20-21, 2023</b>. </p><p>This interdisciplinary conference examines the cultural mobility of Catholicism through the physical movement of Catholic objects from the European Middle Ages into the twenty-first century. Building on recent scholarship that integrates analysis of objects into religious studies, attends to the agency of things, and engages movement as a heuristic for making sense of dynamics of historical change, the conference interrogates the place of material items as Catholicism has moved into new spaces and returned into familiar ones, attending to the role played by objects in mediating meanings at the nexus of Catholicism and cultures. </p><p>Calls for papers have been posted on the conference website here [<a href="https://nam02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Furldefense.com%2Fv3%2F__https%3A%2F%2Fwww.crgcbiennielconference.com%2F__%3B!!K543PA!LGHDMzP-yhRbw8xUXPM9oFev6z_j3zvjBltD_Dat6Vna74m210uMIT1tHZBYNH4FPTFd3wgQmrVCFXb75Gw5VGc81aY%24&amp;data=05%7C01%7Cmary.dunn%40slu.edu%7C4ae75984c7bb46c411be08db04af5fea%7C6711039ec265432cb680a3af66790e06%7C1%7C0%7C638108923500237075%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=pEzpb9eW0x0K370VCgxTEHIHRU%2BR1zJbchtjmbUAjKk%3D&amp;reserved=0" rel="nofollow">link</a>]. Please circulate and consider submitting a proposal! Proposals due <b>March 15, 2023</b>. </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:crgc@slu.edu">crgc@slu.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.crgcbiennielconference.com/" target="_blank">https://www.crgcbiennielconference.com/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 18:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675924629710733</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Generative Contemplation Symposium: The Art and Science of Effortless and Self-Emergence Contemplative Practices in Indian and Tibetan Buddhism</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12320126/generative-contemplation-symposium-art-and-science-effortless</link>
						<dc:creator>Michael Sheehy</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Symposium</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-04-20T00:00:00-04:00">April 20, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-04-21T00:00:00-04:00">April 21, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Virginia</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Philosophy, Psychology, Humanities, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span>On Thursday April 20th and Friday April 21st, 2023, the Contemplative Sciences Center at the University of Virginia is hosting the Generative Contemplation Symposium, an interdisciplinary dialogue on the art and science of effortless and self-emergence contemplative practices in Indian and Tibetan Buddhism.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Registration is now open for the two-day symposium, including a private screening of the documentary film, <em>Tukdam: Between Worlds</em>. See the registration page: </span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/generative-contemplation-symposium-tickets-525849188077" rel="nofollow">https://www.eventbrite.com/e/generative-contemplation-symposium-tickets-...</a></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Across the multi-millennial discourse on contemplative practices within Indian and Tibetan Buddhism, there is a pervasive tension that persists between practices that apply effort and those that are effortless. Recently this has emerged as an important framework for interdisciplinary engagement about enhanced cognitive performance. While presented as a binary in classical accounts—as if effort is a fixed and static quantity that is present or absent—it is better understood as a descriptive framework for a spectrum of contemplative dynamics that unfold during meditative experiences, and which can be intentionally enacted, or fostered, by different contemplative techniques. These practices are performed in ongoing and dynamic shifts across a spectrum of intensities of effort.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>The symposium promises to catalyze transdisciplinary research collaborations to advance a collective understanding of the underlying dynamics of contemplative practices. We are bringing together leading specialists for an exploration of these practices in light of contemporary philosophical inquiry and psychological research on effort and effortless, self-emergent experiences. Themes of effortlessness and self-emergence in Indian and Tibetan Buddhist contemplative practices will be addressed in four overlapping domains: (I) Cognitive Effort and Control Practices, (II) Nondual Awareness Practices, (III) Dream and Illusion Practices. (IV) Self-Emergent Visionary Practices. </span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span>Each domain will involve a creative mix of Buddhist Studies scholars, scientists, philosophers, teacher-practitioners, and experts in the arts and technology with distinct bodies of expertise – textual, experiential, and empirical.</span></span></span></span></p><p><strong><span><span><span><span>Participants</span></span></span></span></strong></p><p><strong><span><span><span><span>Session I: Cognitive Effort and Control Practices</span></span></span></span></strong></p><ol><li><span><span><span><span><span>Zac Irving (Philosophy), University of Virginia </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Sonam Kachru (Buddhist Studies), Yale University </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Chandra Sripada (Psychiatry), University of Michigan </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Karin Meyers (Practitioner), Mangalam Research Center </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Georges Dreyfus (Buddhist Studies), Williams College</span></span></span></span></span></li></ol><p><strong><span><span><span><span>Session II: Nondual Awareness Practices</span></span></span></span></strong><strong><span><span><span><span><span> </span></span></span></span></span></strong></p><ol><li><span><span><span><span><span>John Dunne (Buddhist Studies), University of Wisconsin-Madison </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Cat Prueitt (Buddhist Studies), University of British Columbia </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Antoine Lutz (Neuroscience), University of Lyon, France </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Willa Miller (Practitioner), Natural Dharma Fellowship </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Bryce Huebner (Philosophy) Georgetown University</span></span></span></span></span></li></ol><p><strong><span><span><span><span>Session III: Dream and Illusion Practices</span></span></span></span></strong></p><ol><li><span><span><span><span><span>Michael Sheehy (Buddhist Studies), University of Virginia </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Jake Dalton (Buddhist Studies), University of California-Berkeley </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Andrew Holocek (Practitioner), Edge of Mind </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Ken Paller (Neuroscience), Northwestern University </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Melanie Boly (Neuroscience), University of Wisconsin-Madison </span></span></span></span></span></li></ol><p><strong><span><span><span><span>Session IV: Self-Emergent Visionary Practices</span></span></span></span></strong><strong><span><span><span><span><span> </span></span></span></span></span></strong></p><ol><li><span><span><span><span><span>David Germano (Buddhist Studies), University of Virginia  </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Per Sederberg (Neuroscience), University of Virginia </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>James Gentry (Buddhist Studies), Stanford University </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Anne Klein (Practitioner), Rice University </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Dave Glowacki (Technology), CiTIUS Intelligent Technologies Research Centre, Spain </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Susan Magsamen (Neuroaesthetics), Johns Hopkins University </span></span></span></span></span></li></ol><p><span><span><span>This is an in-person public event designed to foster dialogue with an international community of specialists. The symposium will not be on Zoom or otherwise broadcasted. Sessions will be recorded and disseminated at a later date.</span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Michael Sheehy and David Germano</p><p>University of Virginia</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:sheehy@virginia.edu">sheehy@virginia.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/generative-contemplation-symposium-tickets-525849188077" target="_blank">https://www.eventbrite.com/e/generative-contemplation-symposium-tickets-525849188077</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 18:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675924629710732</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP: Jerusalem - From the Umbilicus Mundi to the Four Corners of the Earth and Back (Deadline 28 Feb)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12319365/cfp-jerusalem-umbilicus-mundi-four-corners-earth-and-back</link>
						<dc:creator>Sharon Gordon</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-28T00:00:00-05:00">February 28, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Israel</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Islamic History / Studies, Jewish History / Studies, World History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Cultural History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Dear Colleagues, </p><p>Attached you will find a<a href="https://www.ybz.org.il/_Uploads/dbsAttachedFiles/Call_for_Papers_International_Conference_on_the_Study_of_Jerusalem_Eng.pdf" rel="nofollow"> </a><u><a href="https://www.ybz.org.il/_Uploads/dbsAttachedFiles/Call_for_Papers_International_Conference_on_the_Study_of_Jerusalem_Eng.pdf" rel="nofollow">Call for Papers</a> </u>for an international conference on Jerusalem. The conference will be held in Yad Ben Zvi Institute, Jerusalem in July 2023. </p><p>We will be grateful if you would suggest a paper (or a session) for this conference. We will highly appreciate if you will forward this call for papers among your colleagues and advanced students who might be interested in the topics suggested there. </p><p>With best wishes </p><p>Prof. Rehav (Buni) Rubin, Head                   </p><p>Dr. Amnon Ramon, Deputy                                    </p><p>Dr. Nicolay Tabah, Project Officer</p><p>Institute for the Study of the Land of Israel </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Nicolay Tabah</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:niko@ybz.org.il">niko@ybz.org.il</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.ybz.org.il/_Uploads/dbsAttachedFiles/Call_for_Papers_International_Conference_on_the_Study_of_Jerusalem_Eng.pdf" target="_blank">https://www.ybz.org.il/_Uploads/dbsAttachedFiles/Call_for_Papers_International_Conference_on_the_Study_of_Jerusalem_Eng.…</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 18:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675924629710731</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – February 8, 2023</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/__trashed/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find a new job opportunity, 1 grant, and 2 Call for Papers.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 32!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>The University of Chicago Press Editorial Assistant (Full Time)</h4>



<p>California, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: February 15, 2023 (but the application will remain open until the position is filled)</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careerspub.universityofcalifornia.edu/psp/ucop/EMPLOYEE/HRMS/c/HRS_HRAM.HRS_APP_SCHJOB.GBL?Page=HRS_APP_JBPST&amp;Action=U&amp;FOCUS=Applicant&amp;SiteId=19&amp;JobOpeningId=48502&amp;PostingSeq=1">https://careerspub.universityofcalifornia.edu/psp/ucop/EMPLOYEE/HRMS/c/HRS_HRAM.HRS_APP_SCHJOB.GBL?Page=HRS_APP_JBPST&amp;Action=U&amp;FOCUS=Applicant&amp;SiteId=19&amp;JobOpeningId=48502&amp;PostingSeq=1</a></p>



<h4>AAR/SBL Job Forum</h4>



<p><a href="https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search">https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search</a></p>



<h2>Grants:</h2>



<h4>UK/Europe Research Funding</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.researchprofessional.com/funding-opportunities/fop/a40c3257-8c95-4ad0-9719-f2f1552f7976">https://www.researchprofessional.com/funding-opportunities/fop/a40c3257-8c95-4ad0-9719-f2f1552f7976</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>National Study of Catholic Priests</h4>



<p>Deadline: February 19, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="http://www.rraweb.org/call-for-proposals-national-study-of-catholic-priests/">http://www.rraweb.org/call-for-proposals-national-study-of-catholic-priests/</a></p>



<h4>Vice, Virtue, &amp; Conflict</h4>



<p>Deadline: February 26, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/107574">https://philevents.org/event/show/107574</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675924629710730</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
