<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 12:18:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 12:18:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>Τ Ε Κ Μ Η Ρ Ι Α, 1  Greeks in the Archaic Age: Institutions, Interactions, Traditions</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/03/17/%CF%84-%CE%B5-%CE%BA-%CE%BC-%CE%B7-%CF%81-%CE%B9-%CE%B1-1-greeks-in-the-archaic-age-institutions-interactions-traditions</link>
						<dc:creator>Carmine Nastri</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Friday, March 24, 2023 - 9:15am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Chair of Greek History of the Department of Humanistic Studies of the University of Salerno (DipSum – Unisa)</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:tekmeria@unisa.it">tekmeria@unisa.it</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/classical-studies">classical studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/international-conferences">international conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>May 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p align="center"><strong><em>Τ</em></strong><strong><em>Ε</em></strong><strong><em>Κ</em></strong><strong><em>Μ</em></strong><strong><em>Η</em></strong><strong><em>Ρ</em></strong><strong><em>Ι</em></strong><strong><em>Α</em></strong><strong>,</strong><strong> 1</strong><strong> </strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>Greeks in the Archaic Age: Institutions, Interactions, Traditions</strong></p>
<p>Τ Ε Κ Μ Η Ρ Ι Α, 1 is a Study Meeting born from the desire of young researchers, associated to the Chair of Greek History of the Department of Humanistic Studies of the University of Salerno (DipSum – Unisa) and coming from <em>Curriculum</em> 1 of the RAMUS Doctoral Program, to create a space for exchange, dialogue, and discussion in the wake of interdisciplinarity. Before included for three years in the Series hitherto called <em>Seminari dei Giovanissimi </em>– as part of the <em>Seminari Salernitani di Storia e Storiografia Greca </em>-, the initiative now takes on an autonomous name and dedicates its first new meeting to the memory of Clara Talamo, who recently passed away. For this reason, the Call proposes the development of themes to which the Scholar was particularly sensitive, and which have connoted the research directions of the Chair. The subject of Τ Ε Κ Μ Η Ρ Ι Α, 1 will therefore be <em>Greeks in the Archaic Age: Institutions, Interactions, Traditions.</em></p>
<p>The topics of the proposals may include:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Archaic institutions of the </em>poleis<em> in the Greek Mediterranean</em></li>
<li><em>Archaic aristocracies and their traditions</em></li>
<li><em>Religiosity and cultic practices in the archaic Greek world</em></li>
<li><em>History and monumentalization in the archaic age</em></li>
<li><em>Relationships among the components of the </em>polis <em>and elaborations on them</em></li>
<li><em>Evolutions in forms of government and their historiographical reception</em></li>
<li><em>Archaic institutions in political and philosophical reflection </em></li>
<li><em>Greeks and forms of interaction in the Mediterranean: traditions and material culture</em></li>
<li><em>Aspects and phenomena of colonial societies in the Archaic age: history, archaeology, historiography from East to West</em></li>
<li><em>Greeks and non-Greeks in land of migration and colony</em></li>
<li><em>Archaic Greekness in the history of European studies</em></li>
<li><em>Compared methodologies and research approaches on the subject</em></li>
</ul>
<p>The Conference will be held, on <strong>October 10, 11, 12, 2023</strong>, in hybrid mode: in presence in the ‘Sala Conferenze del Dipartimento di Studi Umanistici’(building D3, third floor) of the University of Salerno (via Giovanni Paolo II,132, 84084 Fisciano), remotely on the Microsoft Teams platform at the link <a href="https://teams.microsoft.com/l/channel/19%3Aq_ci3pflhBSpQJJKB31-G6qjrJltgWof3eArxZFH5Uk1%40thread.tacv2/Generale?groupId=c121b357-4af3-42c1-af87-170e825bc953&amp;tenantId=c30767db-3dda-4dd4-8a4d-097d22cb99d3">https://teams.microsoft.com/l/channel/19%3aq_ci3pflhBSpQJJKB31-G6qjrJltgWof3eArxZFH5Uk1%40thread.tacv2/Generale?groupId=c121b357-4af3-42c1-af87-170e825bc953&amp;tenantId=c30767db-3dda-4dd4-8a4d-097d22cb99d3</a>.</p>
<p>Those who hold a master's degree in Classics or History or are about to obtain it, PhD students and PhDs are invited to participate.</p>
<p>To participate with a paper, it’s required to send an abstract of up to 500 words, equipped with a title, five keywords, and accompanied by a concise <em>curriculum</em> <em>vitae</em> <em>et</em> <em>studiorum</em>, <strong>by 15 May </strong>to this e-mail address: <a href="mailto:tekmeria@unisa.it">tekmeria@unisa<em>.</em>it</a> . <strong>Abstracts can be sent in Italian, English, French, German, or Spanish</strong>. Attendance in person is free: only for organizational reasons, we invite you to send us an e-mail in which you express your wish to attend; in order to attend remotely, the booking via e-mail is required by the previous day (any request to attend remotely sent during the conference will be equally admitted but may require unforeseeable technical waiting time). No registration fee is required. The Organization Committee will offer participants a courteous sign of welcome, but travel, food, and lodging expenses will be their responsibility.</p>
<p>The Study Meeting will be structured in thematic sessions. Each talk will last 30 minutes; a discussion moderated by the Session Chair will follow at the end of each session to encourage participation and collaboration on all topics. The Conference will start with an opening paper by a keynote speaker and end with a final discussion moderated by a Chair who will draw Conclusions.</p>
<p>Scientific Committee: Elisabetta Bianco (Unito), Maria Paola Castiglioni (Univ. de Grenoble), Elena Franchi (Unitn), Marina Polito (Unisa, Scientific Coordinator of the Meeting), Luigi Vecchio (Unisa).</p>
<p>Organization Committee: Carmine Nastri (Organization Coordinator), Alfredo Novello, Marianna Rago, Annalisa Savino.</p>
<p>If you require any clarification or information, you can contact the Organization Committee ( <a href="mailto:tekmeria@unisa.it">tekmeria@unisa.it</a> ).</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 11:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679722623507719</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ October 26, 2023 -  October 28, 2023] Conference or similar: Between Substance and Subject. The Presence of Spinoza in Hegel</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/109577</link>
						<description>Venue: Aškerčeva cesta 2<br/><br/><p>In the Lectures on the History of Philosophy Hegel notes that Spinoza confronts us with the fundamental alternative: Either Spinozism or no philosophy. In the Science of Logic, he affirms that the only possible refutation of Spinozism consists in first acknowledging its standpoint as essential and necessary and then raising it to a higher level out of its own resources. In philosophy one is accordingly bound to begin as a Spinozist, but it is of equal importance not to remain one. Even Hegel’s programmatic declaration in the Preface to the Phenomenology of Spirit that in his view the true must be comprehended not merely as substance but also as subject, may be read in a double reference to Spinoza: on the one hand, Hegel seems to put the task of philosophy in accepting Spinozist metaphysics and nonetheless in preserving the dimensions of freedom, beauty and life that is usually associated with subjectivity, which Spinozism is supposed to lack; according to the methodological reading, on the other hand, Hegel may be said to call for developing a new conceptual regime that would supersede the mechanistic logic of understanding, exemplified by Spinoza’s mos geometricus, into a truly Hegelian logic of reason. Hegel’s entire philosophical system can thus be understood as a prolonged argument with Spinoza that raised to prominence with the Pantheism Controversy. What is more, not only there was a time when Hegel himself defended metaphysics of one substance, it may be argued that he eventually distanced himself from Spinozist metaphysics under the influence of Spinoza’s own political philosophy. The question is, of course, to what extent Hegel’s understanding of Spinoza was correct (for instance, omnis determinatio negatio, the concept of infinity) and to what extent he read it through Jacobi or Schelling. But it is obvious that, in most various forms, Spinoza is present throughout his philosophy, be it as the ideal to match or the adversary to beat. The aim of the conference is to explore this multifaceted presence of Spinoza in Hegel. We welcome papers on any aspect of the topic and stimulate fruitful exchange between established scholars, junior researchers, and PhD students</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 05:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679636227331736</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ June 15, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Between Substance and Subject. The Presence of Spinoza in Hegel</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/109581</link>
						<description><p>In the Lectures on the History of Philosophy Hegel notes that Spinoza confronts us with the fundamental alternative: Either Spinozism or no philosophy. In the Science of Logic, he affirms that the only possible refutation of Spinozism consists in first acknowledging its standpoint as essential and necessary and then raising it to a higher level out of its own resources. In philosophy one is accordingly bound to begin as a Spinozist, but it is of equal importance not to remain one. Even Hegel’s programmatic declaration in the Preface to the Phenomenology of Spirit that in his view the true must be comprehended not merely as substance but also as subject, may be read in a double reference to Spinoza: on the one hand, Hegel seems to put the task of philosophy in accepting Spinozist metaphysics and nonetheless in preserving the dimensions of freedom, beauty and life that is usually associated with subjectivity, which Spinozism is supposed to lack; according to the methodological reading, on the other hand, Hegel may be said to call for developing a new conceptual regime that would supersede the mechanistic logic of understanding, exemplified by Spinoza’s mos geometricus, into a truly Hegelian logic of reason. Hegel’s entire philosophical system can thus be understood as a prolonged argument with Spinoza that raised to prominence with the Pantheism Controversy. What is more, not only there was a time when Hegel himself defended metaphysics of one substance, it may be argued that he eventually distanced himself from Spinozist metaphysics under the influence of Spinoza’s own political philosophy. The question is, of course, to what extent Hegel’s understanding of Spinoza was correct (for instance, omnis determinatio negatio, the concept of infinity) and to what extent he read it through Jacobi or Schelling. But it is obvious that, in most various forms, Spinoza is present throughout his philosophy, be it as the ideal to match or the adversary to beat. The aim of the conference is to explore this multifaceted presence of Spinoza in Hegel. We welcome papers on any aspect of the topic and stimulate fruitful exchange between established scholars, junior researchers, and PhD students.</p>
<p><strong>Abstracts </strong>(no more than 500 words!) should be sent as attachment to <a href="mailto:luca.illetterati@unipd.it">luca.illetterati@unipd.it</a> and <a href="mailto:zdravko.kobe@ff.uni-lj.si">zdravko.kobe@ff.uni-lj.si</a></p>
<p><strong>Abstracts </strong>should be prepared for double-blind review by removing any identification details. The author’s name, paper title, institutional position and affiliation, as well as contact information and a short CV, should be included in the body of the e-mail, with ‘Submission Hegel Network 2023’ in the subject line.</p>
<p>Information about the conference and the network will be available on <a href="https://www.speculativethought.com/">https://www.speculativethought.com</a> &amp; <a href="https://vu.nl/en/about-vu/more-about/international-network-hegel-s-relevance-in-german">https://vu.nl/en/about-vu/more-about/international-network-hegel-s-relevance-in-german</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 05:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679636227331735</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ May 21, 2023 -  May 22, 2023] Conference or similar: The Conference “In Search of a Hidden Phenomenology”</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/109541</link>
						<description>Venue: Kanonicza 9<br/><br/><p>The Department of the History of Philosophy of the Pontifical University in Kraków is pleased to invite you to The Second Conference “In Search of a Hidden Phenomenology”. The conference will focus on the variety of phenomenological methods and their application in various fields of research. The conference will be held on May 22-23, 2023 in the Senate Room (no. 200) at 9 Kanonicza Street.</p>
<p>“I” and the Other, the world of nature and the world of values, the sacred and God represent only some of the phenomena that the method initiated by Husserl and developed and modified by numerous phenomenologists sought to describe. It strove at its origins to grasp the essence of what transpires, while rejecting earlier presuppositions, theories, and speculations. But is the application of the presuppositionless method still possible in today's world dominated by scientism, and does the obvious ensure the true? Isn't the phenomenology today a method that is receding into the background of other philosophical trends, or is it itself concealed under the veil of scientificness derived from empiricism and positivism? The answers to these questions will be explored in the fields of philosophy, psychology, sociology, medicine, art and literature, and theology. Students, doctoral students, and academics are invited to contribute to this search. We will discuss not only the original understanding of phenomenology as a method and its subsequent development, but also the possibilities of its application today.</p>
<p>Should you be interested in taking part in the conference, please fill in the application form and send your paper outline in Polish or English (between 400 and 600 words) by April 30, 2023. In case of a larger number of submissions, the organizers reserve the right to select the papers. You will receive confirmation of acceptance of your paper within a few days after the submission deadline. Speeches at the conference should not exceed 20 minutes. The application form can be found at: <u>https://forms.gle/BwqV5fZzbPZVNcrf7</u></p>
<p>The conference fee is PLN 100 (lunch on one day) or PLN 200 (lunch on each day of the conference) and will also cover the cost of publication. Deadline and payment information will be provided upon acceptance of the paper to the conference. We also encourage the publication of papers in the form of scientific articles in the university's philosophical journal Logos and Ethos.</p>
<p>The organizers reserve the right to alter the formula of the event and introduce other changes dictated by current sanitary regulations. Any questions about the conference should be emailed to: konferencja.fenomenologiczna@gmail.com</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 05:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679636227331734</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ May 25, 2023 -  May 26, 2023] Conference or similar: Postsecular Studies, Literature, and Care</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/109513</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p>The role of religion in culture and society has become an urgent question in today’s society. In a context of global escalation of politico-religious conflicts and revision of concepts which shed new light onto the allegedly secular modern thought, the tension between religion and (post)secular society must be framed within a multidisciplinary perspective.</p>
<p>Coined in 2001 by Jürgen Habermas to refer to the reconsideration of the role of religion in modern industrial societies, the term “postsecular” reflects the rebirth of debates on the religious phenomenon in different areas of the humanities. Far from being dismissed as a relic of a distant past, religion has become a key concept since the late twentieth century, triggering a veritable “religious turn” in philosophy (in Charles Taylor, Jacques Derrida, Jean Luc Marion, Julia Kristeva or Jean-Luc Nancy), a renewed interest in the history of secularization (in Foucaultian anthropologists such as Talal Asad, Saba Mahmood or Tomoko Masuzawa), the reemergence of critical political theology (in Alain Badiou, Carl Schmitt, Claude Lefort and Giorgio Agamben), the fusion of feminist, ecocritical and postsecular perspectives (in Rossi Braidotti and Michael Hardt), as well as the appearance of numerous studies on the relationship of religion and literature (in Mark Knight and Lori Branch).</p>
<p>The conference “Postsecular Studies, Literature, and Care” pays attention to these current phenomena from two emerging lines or research or turns which have had a deep impact on literary studies in recent years: the “postsecular turn” and the “political turn”. These turns are on the one hand a response to several historical developments—from 9/11 to the coexistence of different though migration—which have caused Western, allegedly secular societies to rethink the role of religion in today’s world. On the other hand, the genealogical analyses of Michel Foucault have uncovered, from the perspective of the history of Western thought, the religious origins of secular modernity’s conceptual framework, and have brought attention to the exhaustion of modernity in the face of the challenges posed by capitalism as the “crisis of great narratives”.</p>
<p>This diverse and multidisciplinary approach to postsecularism entails—as was the case with other concepts such as “postcolonialism” or “postmodernism”—a certain ambivalence and polysemy. In recent years, the postsecular has tended to be considered not as a chronological category following a period of secularization in modernity but rather as a critical stance and as category of analysis capable of gauging the tensions between the religious and the secular. In short, the postsecular has been defined as an epistemic perspective which observes that the religious and the secular have been inextricably connected since modernity. The present conference shall endeavor to develop a notion of the postsecular as a way of paying attention to the relationship between religious and political power, new political theologies, the historical construction of religion and the secular, as well as the emergence of new spiritualities in (post)industrial societies.</p>
<p>From this vantage point, the present conference acknowledges the inherent pluralism of the postsecular and sets out to study its ambivalence and polysemy from a plural perspective which pays attention to its several dimensions, from philology and history, to philosophy and the critical analysis of the present era. In addition, the politics of literature as proposed by Jacques Rancière and Michel Foucault, is one of the main avenues of analysis of the postsecular.</p>
<p>Please submit a short 150-word of your proposed paper topic (in Spanish, English, German or French) including five keywords to <a href="mailto:aalias@ugr.es">antonioalias@ugr.es</a>; <a href="mailto:tespino@ugr.es">tespino@ugr.es</a> by April 15th, 2023.</p>
<p>Registration fee: 35 €</p></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679549831798054</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ April 15, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Postsecular Studies, Literature, and Care</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/109517</link>
						<description><p>The role of religion in culture and society has become an urgent question in today’s society. In a context of global escalation of politico-religious conflicts and revision of concepts which shed new light onto the allegedly secular modern thought, the tension between religion and (post)secular society must be framed within a multidisciplinary perspective.</p>
<p>Coined in 2001 by Jürgen Habermas to refer to the reconsideration of the role of religion in modern industrial societies, the term “postsecular” reflects the rebirth of debates on the religious phenomenon in different areas of the humanities. Far from being dismissed as a relic of a distant past, religion has become a key concept since the late twentieth century, triggering a veritable “religious turn” in philosophy (in Charles Taylor, Jacques Derrida, Jean Luc Marion, Julia Kristeva or Jean-Luc Nancy), a renewed interest in the history of secularization (in Foucaultian anthropologists such as Talal Asad, Saba Mahmood or Tomoko Masuzawa), the reemergence of critical political theology (in Alain Badiou, Carl Schmitt, Claude Lefort and Giorgio Agamben), the fusion of feminist, ecocritical and postsecular perspectives (in Rossi Braidotti and Michael Hardt), as well as the appearance of numerous studies on the relationship of religion and literature (in Mark Knight and Lori Branch).</p>
<p>The conference “Postsecular Studies, Literature, and Care” pays attention to these current phenomena from two emerging lines or research or turns which have had a deep impact on literary studies in recent years: the “postsecular turn” and the “political turn”. These turns are on the one hand a response to several historical developments—from 9/11 to the coexistence of different though migration—which have caused Western, allegedly secular societies to rethink the role of religion in today’s world. On the other hand, the genealogical analyses of Michel Foucault have uncovered, from the perspective of the history of Western thought, the religious origins of secular modernity’s conceptual framework, and have brought attention to the exhaustion of modernity in the face of the challenges posed by capitalism as the “crisis of great narratives”.</p>
<p>This diverse and multidisciplinary approach to postsecularism entails—as was the case with other concepts such as “postcolonialism” or “postmodernism”—a certain ambivalence and polysemy. In recent years, the postsecular has tended to be considered not as a chronological category following a period of secularization in modernity but rather as a critical stance and as category of analysis capable of gauging the tensions between the religious and the secular. In short, the postsecular has been defined as an epistemic perspective which observes that the religious and the secular have been inextricably connected since modernity. The present conference shall endeavor to develop a notion of the postsecular as a way of paying attention to the relationship between religious and political power, new political theologies, the historical construction of religion and the secular, as well as the emergence of new spiritualities in (post)industrial societies.</p>
<p>From this vantage point, the present conference acknowledges the inherent pluralism of the postsecular and sets out to study its ambivalence and polysemy from a plural perspective which pays attention to its several dimensions, from philology and history, to philosophy and the critical analysis of the present era. In addition, the politics of literature as proposed by Jacques Rancière and Michel Foucault, is one of the main avenues of analysis of the postsecular.</p>
<p>Please submit a short 150-word of your proposed paper topic (in Spanish, English, German or French) including five keywords to <a href="mailto:aalias@ugr.es">antonioalias@ugr.es</a>; <a href="mailto:tespino@ugr.es">tespino@ugr.es</a> by April 15th, 2023.</p>
<p>Registration fee: 35 €</p></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679549831798053</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Society for Reformation Research: &quot;Intercultural Reformations&quot; / Sixteenth Century Society &amp; Conference, 26-29 October 2023</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12604235/society-reformation-research-intercultural-reformations</link>
						<dc:creator>David Luebke</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-10-26T00:00:00-04:00">October 26, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-10-29T00:00:00-04:00">October 29, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Oregon</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Cultural History / Studies, Early Modern History and Period Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Social History / Studies, World History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span>The<span> </span><b>Society for Reformation Research<span> </span></b>(SRR) is now accepting proposals for SRR-sponsored sessions at the 2023 annual meeting of the Sixteenth Century Society and Conference (SCSC),<span> </span><b>26-29 October 2023</b>at the<span> </span><b>Renaissance Baltimore Harborplace Hotel</b>.</span></p><p><span>The SRR invites individual papers and complete sessions (panels, roundtables, or workshops) on any theme related to the Protestant and Catholic Reformations and all other aspects of religious life and theology in the early modern era. In line with our mission to support instruction of Reformation themes in other courses, we also solicit papers with a primary focus on teaching.</span><br/><br/><span>For the 2023 meeting, the SRR is sponsoring a series of panels with the theme of “<b>Intercultural Reformations</b>.” Specifically, the SRR seeks papers and panels that compare experiences and perceptions of reform and its effects across the boundaries of religious, cultural, and ethnic division. Topics may include, but are not limited to</span></p><ul><li><span>Muslim / Jewish / Orthodox Christian perceptions of Reformation and/or Catholic Reform</span></li><li><span>Catholics and Protestants abroad in Asia, Africa, and the Americas</span></li><li><span>African / Asian / indigenous American experiences in Europe of religion and reform</span></li><li><span>Sixteenth-century conceptualizations of cultural difference and similarity</span></li><li><span>Intercultural comparisons – persecution, conversion, exile, refuge</span></li><li><span>Engagement between Christian and non-Christian scholars and intellectuals</span></li><li><span>Non-Christian influences on Protestant and Catholic Reforms</span></li></ul><p><br/><span>Papers should not have been previously published or presented at a different scholarly meeting. All presenters must register for the conference if accepted. Papers should not exceed twenty minutes.</span></p><p><span><b>To submit a paper or panel, go to the SCSC website (<a href="https://urldefense.com/v3/__https://l.facebook.com/l.php?u=https*3A*2F*2Fsixteenthcentury.org*2Flogin*3Ffbclid*3DIwAR2jJZi-md9TrLr5nXQJv4MXswO8rea41YQgxj5zybnBjQ2CJbv5kOgs41I&amp;h=AT0oEDcjFBKAavhP49E9xPJMbPnUyHm_6JDSsGmbUNNUXjmzD7xAVu7dYW7b893JJco3eYXHfmff4WxPygM7Fy9Ol517S_yvHuB96FTztDSWV5Zh3oUZltrbRrKsPcBhUBUyrui-S9tdssHhCwnIWDM&amp;__tn__=-U-UK-R&amp;c*5b0*5d=AT3JEHYMmBWR6tPqNsYrGjTjLjmgWtIzeB7Vvk9MKuwCB56LdfqPUI4SViJj6KAV016zqdti3IAte9koK5RmuNcb2AiIOViMftkzpUHT_T17g89Ac2DENRhY6DIsVAgKumKxTqKVCKYCs6EwQxVroKfRJCUU7vCQzxkNqquGmC0EKQfX1Zx7yyJq2QiZvIZTPkxO3kt1Jb_H9EMaf4NWKhM__;JSUlJSUlJSU!!C5qS4YX3!EPdykFvNJ1xUFLwFx7RtzQIlL5Jzc_D-SkbEHPgRtvhCeqW6CM2uGr91b-t-D-o2xGzxEzBhiYqYxsI6lS-8Ebx028sxl-Y%24" rel="nofollow">https://sixteenthcentury.org/login</a>) and log into your SCSC account</b>. You do not need to joint the SCSC to create an account. One you have logged in, you will be automatically transferred to a page with a link to the Submission Page. Click on that link and you see the SCSC Call for Papers and a menu of options on the right-hand side of the page. Click on the option that best suits your proposal (“Roundtable,” “Workshop,” “Individual Paper,” “Panel”). On the first submission page, you’ll see a list of “Sponsor Organizations”:<span> </span><b>be sure to click the box for “Society for Reformation Research.”<span> </span></b>On the second page, you’ll be asked to “<b>Choose Discipline</b>”; there,<span> </span><b>make sure that you click on “Reformation Studies.”</b></span><br/><br/><span>If you would like help with submitting a paper, panel, workshop, roundtable for sponsorship or need additional information about SRR sponsorship, please contact the SRR program chair: David M. Luebke (<a href="mailto:dluebke@uoregon.edu">dluebke@uoregon.edu</a>). The deadline for submission of paper and panel proposals is Monday, 17 April 2023.</span></p><p><span>Paper proposals should include:</span></p><ul><li><span>Paper Title</span></li><li><span>Abstract (250 words maximum)</span></li><li><span>The presenter’s name, affiliation, and email address</span></li><li><span>The presenter’s biography or brief CV (3-4 sentences, maximum 150 words, including rank and most important publications or evidence of scholarship)</span></li></ul><p><br/><span>Paper proposals should also indicate:</span></p><ul><li><span>Whether audiovisual equipment is needed and what kind</span></li><li><span>Whether you have submitted a paper to the SCSC previously</span></li><li><span>Whether you need official confirmation of paper acceptance</span></li><li><span>Whether you wish to have your paper considered for the Mayer prize</span></li></ul><p><br/><span>Panels, roundtables, and workshops should include:</span></p><ul><li><span>Panel, roundtable, or workshop title</span></li><li><span>Abstract of the panel, roundtable, or workshop (300 words maximum)</span></li><li><span>Any additional affiliate society / sponsor beyond the SRR</span></li><li><span>Organizer’s name, affiliation, and email address</span></li><li><span>Chair / commentator’s name, affiliation, and email address</span></li><li><span>List of papers / presenters with relevant paper proposals, including all of the above information</span><br/> </li></ul><p><span><a href="https://urldefense.com/v3/__https://l.facebook.com/l.php?u=https*3A*2F*2Fwww.reformationresearch.org*2Findex.html*3Ffbclid*3DIwAR2kfY1xIo5DzwmL1CyQFo6htwe-Q83q3Sc-ObSA2-u2SmzOnHBV7HXOKkg&amp;h=AT2XJ14fCE3GoVnZE0t31fzb6KSKY3AblZJTcqhbjdofNzlsBLutMXkjw1xJI-yXvlulRWZmmjRXVYH6sijWZHPnOU34r9eaU1X4diEaRZlQu8J30UEbHw1avWZWJ3QiJ2vNsq8G5Lxnda24SwpHm14&amp;__tn__=-UK-R&amp;c*5b0*5d=AT3JEHYMmBWR6tPqNsYrGjTjLjmgWtIzeB7Vvk9MKuwCB56LdfqPUI4SViJj6KAV016zqdti3IAte9koK5RmuNcb2AiIOViMftkzpUHT_T17g89Ac2DENRhY6DIsVAgKumKxTqKVCKYCs6EwQxVroKfRJCUU7vCQzxkNqquGmC0EKQfX1Zx7yyJq2QiZvIZTPkxO3kt1Jb_H9EMaf4NWKhM__;JSUlJSUlJSU!!C5qS4YX3!EPdykFvNJ1xUFLwFx7RtzQIlL5Jzc_D-SkbEHPgRtvhCeqW6CM2uGr91b-t-D-o2xGzxEzBhiYqYxsI6lS-8Ebx0bp2Lxxw%24" rel="nofollow">https://www.reformationresearch.org/index.html</a></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>David M. Luebke<br/>1288 Department of History<br/>University of Oregon<br/>Eugene OR 97403-1288<br/>tel: (541) 346-2394</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:dluebke@uoregon.edu">dluebke@uoregon.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://sixteenthcentury.org/" target="_blank">https://sixteenthcentury.org/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 19:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679549831798052</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Colloquium on “Interreligious Interactions in South Asia,” April 3–12, 2023</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12593006/colloquium-%E2%80%9Cinterreligious-interactions-south-asia%E2%80%9D-april-3%E2%80%9312</link>
						<dc:creator>Pranav Prakash</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Symposium</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-04-03T00:00:00-04:00">April 3, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-04-12T00:00:00-04:00">April 12, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Area Studies, Cultural History / Studies, Middle East History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, South Asian History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Dear Colleagues and Friends, </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>We are delighted to announce a virtual colloquium on “<b>Interreligious Interactions in South Asia</b>” that will take place over Zoom from <b>April 3 to April 12, 2023</b> (15:00–16:30 GMT / 10:00–11:30 EST / 20:30–22:00 IST). </span></span></span> </span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Zoom link: </span></span></span><a href="https://zoom.us/j/94189387595?pwd=Q0hvNDZvYjhDUVZOTHkxSWxNVGIyQT09" rel="nofollow"><span><span><span><span><span>https://zoom.us/j/94189387595?pwd=Q0hvNDZvYjhDUVZOTHkxSWxNVGIyQT09</span></span></span></span></span></a>   </span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Meeting ID: 941 8938 7595</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Passcode: 181402 </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>We envision our colloquium to be brainstorming sessions for examining how interreligious interactions are analysed and theorised in diverse disciplines today, and in what ways historical sources and ethnographic data from South Asia elaborate such interactions. Our presenters have pre-circulated reading materials that would be helpful in understanding their arguments. If you would like to consult these reading materials and/or if you would like to a copy of the full program, along with abstracts of each presentation, please email: </span></span></span><a href="mailto:trinbarua@gmail.com"><b><span><span><span><span><span>trinbarua@gmail.com</span></span></span></span></span></b></a><span><span><span>. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Please find the abstracts of our colloquium and the flyer as attachments to this email.</span></span></span><br/><br/><span><span><span>April 3, 2023 </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Speaker: Samia Khatun (SOAS, University of London)</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Title: Nur, Darshan &amp; Enlightenment: Three Approaches to Connecting Texts and Textiles in 18th century Bengal</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>April 4, 2023</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Speaker: Sohini Sarah Pillai (Kalamazoo College)</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Title: A Bhakti Mahabharata for Aurangzeb? Sabalsingh Chauhan’s Bhasha Retelling of the Epic </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>April 5, 2023</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Speaker: Kashshaf Ghani (Nalanda University)</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Title: Seeking Allah and Krishna: Sufism and Religious Interactions from South Asia</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>April 6, 2023</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Speaker: SherAli Tareen</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Title: Contests over the Boundaries of Hindu-Muslim Friendship</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>April 7, 2023</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Speaker: Jyoti Gulati Balachandran (Penn State University)</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Title: Socio-Political Dimensions of Spiritual Practice in Gujarat: Notes from Two 15th century Sufi silsilahs</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>April 12, 2023</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Speaker: Shankar Ayillath Nair </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Title: Rāma and Sītā as Adam and Eve: The Rāmāyaṇa through the Prism of the Persian Romance</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>We eagerly look forward to your participation in our colloquium. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Sincerely, </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Ankur Barua (University of Cambridge)</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Hina Khalid (University of Cambridge)</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Pranav Prakash (University of Oxford)</span></span></span> </span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Ankur Barua (University of Cambridge) </span></span></span><br/><span><span><span>Hina Khalid (University of Cambridge) </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Pranav Prakash (University of Oxford)</span></span></span> </span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:trinbarua@gmail.com">trinbarua@gmail.com</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 17:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679463431489316</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Fresh News from China: Introducing Chinese Documents in the Propaganda Fide</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12592525/fresh-news-china-introducing-chinese-documents-propaganda-fide</link>
						<dc:creator>Daryl Ireland</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Event</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-28T00:00:00-04:00">March 28, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Massachusetts</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Chinese History / Studies, Early Modern History and Period Studies, East Asian History / Studies, Maritime History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The Center for Global Christianity and Mission at Boston University will offer a Zoom presentation on Tuesday, March 28th at 9 am Eastern Time that will introduce the recently published <a href="https://www.urbaniana.press/catalogo/catalogue-of-chinese-documents-in-the-%E2%80%9Cpropaganda-fide%E2%80%9D-historical-archives-(1622-1830)-by-ad-dudink/9834?path=catalogo" rel="nofollow"><em>Catalogue of Chinese Documents in the 'Propaganda Fide" Historical Archives (1622-1830)</em></a>. This volume offers not only an annotated list of its invaluable resources, but also reproduces the full text of a few rare or unique Chinese Christian texts. The Catalogue, compiled by Dr. Ad Dudink (Katholieke Universiteit Leuven, ret.) and edited by Drs. Giuseppe Zhao Hongtao (Centre for Chinese Studies, Pontifical Urbanian University, Rome) and Emanuele Raini (University "L'Orientale", Naples) is preceded by an essay by Dr. Eugenio Menegon (Boston University) that gives a full explanation of the entire structure and contents of the Archives pertaining to the China missions and sketches the activity of Propaganda Fide missionaries in China up to the early 19th century. The Chinese documents catalogued here open a window on the daily life of the Chinese Christian communities and their pastors, and the reaction of Chinese society to Catholic activities. Read together with the letters and reports sent from Asia in European languages to accompany them, they offer a corrective to a Rome-centered vision of the missions.</p><p>You are welcome to participate through this link: <span> </span><a href="https://bostonu.zoom.us/j/7085784737" rel="nofollow">https://bostonu.zoom.us/j/7085784737</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Daryl Ireland</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:dri@bu.edu">dri@bu.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://bostonu.zoom.us/j/7085784737" target="_blank">https://bostonu.zoom.us/j/7085784737</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 18:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679377031889366</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Annual conference of the INTERNATIONAL COUNCIL OF CHRISTIANS AND JEWS (ICCJ)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12586174/annual-conference-international-council-christians-and-jews</link>
						<dc:creator>Ophir Yarden</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-18T00:00:00-04:00">June 18, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-21T00:00:00-04:00">June 21, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Massachusetts</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, American History / Studies, Black History / Studies, Colonial and Post-Colonial History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Registration is open for the annual conference of the<br/><strong>INTERNATIONAL COUNCIL OF CHRISTIANS AND JEWS (ICCJ)</strong>.</p><p>The conference's theme is <em>Negotiating Multiple Identities </em>and it has purposefully been scheduled to take place over Juneteeth Day.</p><p>ICCJ is proud to be conducting the conference with our local partners:</p><ul><li>Betty Ann Greenbaum Miller Center for Interreligious Learning and Leadership, Hebrew College,</li><li>The Center for Christian-Jewish Learning, Boston College,</li><li>The Council of Centers on Jewish Christian Relations (CCJR).</li></ul><p> </p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:office@iccj.org">office@iccj.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.iccj.org/activities/conferences/iccj-conference-2023.html" target="_blank">https://www.iccj.org/activities/conferences/iccj-conference-2023.html</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 18:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679377031889365</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Don Yoder Prize for the Best Graduate Student Paper in Folk Belief or Religious Folklife</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12576902/don-yoder-prize-best-graduate-student-paper-folk-belief-or</link>
						<dc:creator>Joseph Sciorra</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Prize</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-01T00:00:00-04:00">June 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology, Cultural History / Studies, Humanities</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The <a href="https://americanfolkloresociety.org/folk-belief-and-religious-folklife/" rel="nofollow"><strong>Folk Belief and Religious Folklife Section</strong></a> of the American Folklore Society invites submissions for The Don Yoder Prize for the Best Graduate Student Paper in Folk Belief or Religious Folklife, with an honorarium of $500. The award is given to recognize an excellent graduate student paper on a topic in folk belief and religious folklife. The prize is named in honor of folklorist and religious studies scholar, Don Yoder (1921-2015), professor of Folklore and Folklife and Religious Studies at the University of Pennsylvania, an expert on American sectarian religions, who mentored many scholars in the academic study of religion and folklife in the United States.</p><p>Submissions: All research papers, in English, by graduate students written after January 1 of the previous year (i.e., during the previous 17 months), published or unpublished at the time of submission, and written on a folk belief or religious folklife topic, broadly construed, are eligible.</p><p>Interested applicants must submit the following materials for consideration: (1) A cover letter specifying the date when the paper was written; the conference, colloquium, or course where the paper has been or will be submitted; or the publication in which it will be published. (2) The paper should be a minimum of 8 pages, and a maximum of 36 pages, double-spaced, 12 pt. font, with one-inch margins. PLEASE NOTE: To ensure blind judgment of papers, please remove the author’s name and identifying metadata from the paper. Entries must be fully footnoted for a reading audience, using <em>Journal of American Folklore</em> citation style. (3) A short (100-word) biographical statement about the author, including the author’s current graduate student status, with description of the research. Prize winners may also be asked later to send a photo for publicity. (4) An email letter from a faculty sponsor endorsing submission of the paper, sent to the prize committee chair, Margaret Kruesi, <a href="mailto:maggiekruesi@verizon.net">maggiekruesi@verizon.net</a>.</p><p><strong>Change of Deadline! </strong>The 2023 deadline for submissions is <strong>midnight June 1</strong>. Any materials received after this deadline will not be considered. Electronic submissions are required.</p><p>The (1) cover letter; the (2) paper with its title only; the (3) biographical statement about the author; and the (4) faculty sponsor’s letter should be submitted as Microsoft Word documents or pdf to the AFS prize application <a href="https://americanfolkloresociety.org/prize-application-form/" rel="nofollow"><strong>submission form linked here</strong></a>. For any technical questions related to the submission, please send an email to AFS Executive Director <a href="mailto:jturner@afsnet.org"><strong>Jessica Turner</strong></a> at <a href="mailto:jturner@afsnet.org"><strong>jturner@afsnet.org</strong></a>.</p><p>One submission per person, please. Previous winners of the Folk Belief and Religious Folklife Student Prizes are not eligible; except for winners of the William A. Wilson Prize for the Best Undergraduate Student Paper, who may later submit a new research paper for the Don Yoder Prize for the Best Graduate Student Paper. The papers will be evaluated by three judges who are members of both the American Folklore Society and the Folk Belief and Religious Folklife Section. The winner will be announced at the Section’s business meeting at the Society’s annual meeting and the winner will be featured in the AFS newsletter.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>For any technical questions related to the submission, please send an email to AFS Executive Director <a href="mailto:jturner@afsnet.org"><strong>Jessica Turner</strong></a> at <a href="mailto:jturner@afsnet.org"><strong>jturner@afsnet.org</strong></a>.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:jturner@afsnet.org">jturner@afsnet.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://americanfolkloresociety.org/our-work/prizes/don-yoder-prize/" target="_blank">https://americanfolkloresociety.org/our-work/prizes/don-yoder-prize/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 17:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679377031889364</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>William A. Wilson Prize for the Best Undergraduate Student Paper in Folk Belief or Religious Folklife</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12576903/william-wilson-prize-best-undergraduate-student-paper-folk</link>
						<dc:creator>Joseph Sciorra</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Prize</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-01T00:00:00-04:00">June 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Cultural History / Studies, Humanities, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The <a href="https://americanfolkloresociety.org/folk-belief-and-religious-folklife/" rel="nofollow"><strong>Folk Belief and Religious Folklife Section</strong></a> of the American Folklore Society invites submissions for the William A. Wilson Prize for the Best Undergraduate Student Paper in Folk Belief or Religious Folklife, with an honorarium of $250. The award is given to recognize an excellent undergraduate paper on a topic in folk belief and religious folklife in honor of professor emeritus of Brigham Young University, William Albert “Bert” Wilson (1933-2016) for his work as folklorist, editor, archivist, teacher, and scholar of the Finnish Kalevala and of Mormon folklore.</p><p>Submissions: All research papers, in English, by undergraduate students written after January 1 of the previous year (i.e., during the previous 17 months), published or unpublished at the time of submission, and written on a folk belief or religious folklife topic, broadly construed, are eligible.</p><p>Interested applicants must submit the following materials for consideration: (1) A cover letter specifying the date when the paper was written; the conference, colloquium, or course where the paper has been or will be submitted; or the publication in which it will be published. (2) The paper should be a minimum of 8 pages, and a maximum of 36 pages, double-spaced, 12 pt. font, with one-inch margins. PLEASE NOTE: To ensure blind judgment of papers, please remove the author’s name and identifying metadata from the paper. Entries must be fully footnoted for a reading audience, using <em>Journal of American Folklore</em> citation style. (3) A short (100-word) biographical statement about the author, including the author’s current student status, with description of the research. Prize winners may also be asked later to send a photo for publicity. (4) An email letter from a faculty sponsor endorsing submission of the paper, sent to the prize committee chair, Margaret Kruesi, <a href="mailto:maggiekruesi@verizon.net">maggiekruesi@verizon.net</a>.</p><p><strong>Change of Deadline!</strong> The deadline for submissions is <strong>midnight June 1</strong>. Any materials received after this deadline will not be considered. Electronic submissions are required.</p><p>The (1) cover letter; the (2) paper with its title; the (3) biographical statement about the author; and the (4) faculty sponsor’s letter should be submitted as Microsoft Word documents or pdf to the AFS prize application <a href="https://americanfolkloresociety.org/prize-application-form/" rel="nofollow"><strong>submission form linked here</strong></a>. For any technical questions related to the submission, please send an email to AFS Executive Director <a href="mailto:jturner@afsnet.org"><strong>Jessica Turner</strong></a> at <a href="mailto:jturner@afsnet.org"><strong>jturner@afsnet.org</strong></a></p><p>One submission per person, please. Previous winners of the William A. Wilson Undergraduate Student Paper Prize are not eligible. The papers will be evaluated by three judges who are members of both the American Folklore Society and the Folk Belief and Religious Folklife Section. The winner will be announced at the Section’s business meeting at the Society’s annual meeting and the winner will be featured in the AFS newsletter.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>For any technical questions related to the submission, please send an email to AFS Executive Director <a href="mailto:jturner@afsnet.org"><strong>Jessica Turner</strong></a> at <a href="mailto:jturner@afsnet.org"><strong>jturner@afsnet.org</strong></a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:jturner@afsnet.org">jturner@afsnet.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://americanfolkloresociety.org/our-work/prizes/william-a-wilson-prize/" target="_blank">https://americanfolkloresociety.org/our-work/prizes/william-a-wilson-prize/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 17:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679377031889363</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Leonard Norman Primiano Book Prize on Vernacular Catholicism</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12576901/leonard-norman-primiano-book-prize-vernacular-catholicism</link>
						<dc:creator>Joseph Sciorra</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Prize</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-05-01T00:00:00-04:00">May 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology, Cultural History / Studies, Humanities</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The <a href="https://americanfolkloresociety.org/folk-belief-and-religious-folklife/" rel="nofollow"><strong>Folk Belief and Religious Folklife</strong></a> Section of the American Folklore Society invites submissions for the annual Leonard Norman Primiano Book Prize on Vernacular Catholicism. The purpose of the Prize is to recognize and stimulate new work in vernacular Catholicism and to commemorate the life and work of distinguished scholar Leonard Norman Primiano (1957-2021).</p><p>Primiano was a folklorist, religious studies scholar, and educator who published widely on the religious traditions of American Catholics and others from the methodological perspective of what he termed “vernacular religion.” He defined vernacular religion as, “religion as it is lived: as human beings encounter, understand, interpret, and practice it.” The definition was a departure from the terms “lay,” “folk,” or “unofficial” religion which were often contrasted with “institutional” or “official” religion. Primiano sought to unify these disparate discourses into one framework that invited scholars to engage deeply in the lives of their fieldwork collaborators. He challenged scholars to take seriously the minutiae of how people live their religion in particular contexts, their interaction with material culture, their often-flexible attitude to and use of tradition, their frequently complex relationships and negotiations with institutional forms of religiosity, and above all their agency. In the spirit of this method, the work should be interdisciplinary with attention to the religious life of the individual as well verbal, customary, and/or material expressions of religious believers.</p><h3>Submission guidelines</h3><ul><li>All submissions must be focused on vernacular Catholicism, broadly construed.</li><li>Works submitted must be book-length monographs in English published in the 16 months prior to the annual submission deadline of <strong>May 1.</strong> </li><li>Articles, dissertations, reissues of older works (unless they have been substantially revised and rewritten), editions of works by others, or works-in-progress will not be considered for the prize.</li><li>A cash award is made to the winner or winners of the prize. </li><li>If no entry is deemed worthy, no prize will be awarded. </li><li>AFS requires that publishers submit hard copies of all books, with the exception of books that are only available in electronic formats.</li><li>The winner/s will be announced at the American Folklore Society’s annual meeting in October or November each year. </li><li>Publishers should mail four copies (clothbound or paperback) to American Folklore Society, “attention: Leonard Norman Primiano Book Prize,” 800 East Third Street, Bloomington, IN 47405 USA. Email questions to <a href="mailto:info@afsnet.org">info@afsnet.org</a>.</li><li>Publishers of books available in electronic formats only should email a PDF of the book, or download instructions, to <a href="mailto:americanfolkloresociety@afsnet.org"><strong>americanfolkloresociety@gmail.com</strong></a>.</li></ul></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>American Folklore Society</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:info@afsnet.org">info@afsnet.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://americanfolkloresociety.org/our-work/prizes/leonard-norman-primiano-book-prize-on-vernacular-catholicism/" target="_blank">https://americanfolkloresociety.org/our-work/prizes/leonard-norman-primiano-book-prize-on-vernacular-catholicism/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 17:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679377031889362</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ March 30, 2023] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/109329</link>
						<description>Publication Name: New Moderate Narratives in Times of Extremism - Call for abstracts<br/><br/><p><strong>13th BRAGA MEETINGS ON ETHICS AND POLITICAL PHILOSOPHY</strong>  </p>
<p>June 15 and 16, 2023 | Braga, Portugal   <strong></strong></p>
<p><strong>Website</strong>: <a target="_blank" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://13bragameetings.weebly.com/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1679262520074000&amp;usg=AOvVaw3p2xWKyZYwF9bLXEDBDB2H">https://13bragameetings.weebly.com/</a>     <strong></strong></p>
<p><strong>Invited speakers</strong>:   </p>
<p><strong>DANIELE ARCHIBUGI  </strong><em>/// CNRS and Birkbeck College</em><strong><br/>HELEN FROWE  </strong><em>/// Stockholm University</em><br/><strong>MATHIAS THALER</strong> <em>///</em> <em>University of Edinburgh<br/></em><strong>MIHAELA MIHAI </strong><em>/// University of Edinburgh</em><br/><strong>NADIA URBINATI </strong> <em>/// </em> <em>Columbia University</em><br/><strong>RICHARD BELLAMY </strong> <em>/// </em> <em>University College London</em><br/><strong>SILJE LANGVATN</strong> <em>///</em> <em>University of Bergen</em><br/><strong>STUART WHITE</strong> <em>/// </em> <em>University of Oxford</em>  </p>
<p>Call for abstracts to constitute a panel on "New Moderate Narratives in Times of Extremism" at the <a target="_blank" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://13bragameetings.weebly.com/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1679262520075000&amp;usg=AOvVaw2x7tAluDhF9L9475G7pbk9">Braga Meetings on Ethics and Political Philosophy</a></p>
<p>Convenor: Pedro Góis Moreira (<a target="_blank" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://tcu.academia.edu/PedroMoreira&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1679262520075000&amp;usg=AOvVaw2Y_ghwAm-t9afa-vAZMqIt">https://tcu.academia.edu/PedroMoreira</a>) <a target="_blank">pedrogoismoreira@gmail.com</a>  </p>
<p>The 90s opened a time of optimism for proponents of constitutional democracy who were vividly discussing the possibilities of public deliberation and rational dialogue. However, these last few years have seen the re-emergence of radical and antagonistic forms of politics - populism, nativism, and left activism. We currently find ourselves in "an <em>interregnum</em>: a period of crisis during which several tenets of the [political] consensus (...) are challenged" and where "a solution to the crisis is not yet in sight" (Mouffe, 2018).  </p>
<p>This "crisis of liberalism" sets the tone of the discussions on the left and on the right. On the left, debates have centered around radical democracy, left populism, and on the means to further radicalize democracy (Mouffe 2018, de la Torre and Srisa-nga 2021). Radical democrats claim that they seek to reform liberalism rather than reject it, yet they are often more explicit about what they reject in liberalism than about what they wish to retain. On the right, many have been more candid, calling themselves "postliberals" (Deneen 2018) and embracing populist (Benoist 2017) or nationalist (Hazony 2022) alternatives.  </p>
<p>Liberal and moderate responses to these developments have been markedly defensive. On the one hand, several works have taken a critical approach to populism (Müller 2016, Urbinati 2019) and identity politics (Fukuyama 2018). On the other hand, there have been talks of how a militant democracy (Malkopoulou and Kirshner 2019) could be deployed to contain the extremes. But here, too, the discussion is more about the defensive response that liberals should adopt against the extremes.  </p>
<p>The questions that seem to be missing are the sort of new narratives and new self-understanding that moderates should develop in response to the extremes. In the 1930s, several liberal landmarks emerged, not just as critiques, but as insightful and original reaffirmations of the open society (Lippmann 1937, Popper 1944). What, then, is extremism and what unites it? What is moderation (Craiutu 2023)? What conceptions of democracy and politics should moderates develop in response to the extremes (Muller 2021)? The panel welcomes contributions related (but not limited) to the following questions:</p>
<ul>
<li>What is extremism? What is moderation? How should we understand and frame this binary historically and philosophically?</li>
<li>What new conceptions of democracy and politics should moderates develop in response to the extremes?</li>
<li>What are the potential benefits and shortcomings of extremism/moderation? For instance, can extremism act as a "corrective"? Does moderation have depoliticizing tendencies?</li>
<li>What are some of the rhetorical tactics of extremism (e.g., demonization) and how can moderates counter them? Should moderates adopt militant democracy?</li>
</ul>
<p>  <strong>Submission Guidelines:</strong> </p>
<p>To apply, please send an email to <a target="_blank">Pedrogoismoreira@gmail.com</a> with the following items by <strong>Thursday, 30 March</strong>: name, affiliation, email, short bio (max 300 words), abstract title, abstracts (max 500 words), and five keywords.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 05:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679204240483989</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
