<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 12:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 12:04:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ October 14, 2024 -  June 21, 2025] Conference or similar: NGRE 24/25</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/124058</link>
						<description>Venue: Krakowskie Przedmieście 3<br/><br/><p>New Generation Research Exchange</p>
<p> Call for Applications </p>
<p>Summary </p>
<p>The Ian Ramsey Centre for Science and Religion, University of Oxford, the Faculty of Philosophy, Universities of Warsaw, and the Humane Philosophy Society, in collaboration the Faculty of Philosophy, Zagreb University invite applications for the New Generation Research Exchange programme. The Exchange programme will give young scholars in Central and Eastern Europe (CEE) working on Big Questions at the intersection of science, theology and philosophy the opportunity to participate in three fully funded workshops taking place at the Universities of Warsaw, Zagreb and Oxford. Participants will have the further opportunity to apply to continue the research they undertake for the Fellowship during a term of funded supervised research at the University of Oxford. Participants’ research projects will be assessed by an external committee after the final workshop takes place to determine possible supervisors for research visits to Oxford. The Fellowship will conclude with an alumni workshop in the summer of 2025 to take place in Trogir, Croatia. </p>
<p>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vfaPrP2W2Hs&amp;ab_channel=IanRamseyCentre</p>
<p>Eligibility</p>
<p>Applicants will normally be MA or early PhD students at Central and Eastern European research institutions, including universities, research academies and seminaries, or young scholars from CEE on equivalent degree programmes outside the region. The programme is intended to support research projects of successful candidates during the final year of their MA course, or developing their MA research topics for publication, or with a PhD application in mind, as well as those beginning to work on a PhD. Proposed projects should broadly fall under the project themes, which are outlined below.  It is expected that most applications will be submitted by natural scientists, theologians and philosophers, but there are no disciplinary restrictions and applicants with academic backgrounds in other areas are also welcome. Applications are welcome from researchers working in any religious tradition, and from researchers working in no religious tradition.</p>
<p>For the purposes of the project, Central and Eastern Europe (CEE) is defined as: Albania, Armenia, Azerbaijan, Belarus, Bosnia and Herzegovina, Bulgaria, Croatia, Czechia, the former East Germany, Estonia, Georgia, Hungary, Kosovo, Latvia, Lithuania, Moldova, Montenegro, North Macedonia, Poland, Romania, Serbia, Slovakia, Slovenia and Ukraine.</p>
<p>Activities</p>
<p>Successful candidates will participate in a series of three masterclasses during the course of the programme. The meetings will take place over three days each at the Universities of Zagreb, Warsaw, and Oxford. Participants will have the opportunity to discuss their work as a group and with IRC-appointed tutors, as well as participate in seminars led by prominent visiting speakers. The Fellowship will cover all the costs of participating in each masterclass including travel and accommodation. The fellowship will conclude with an alumni workshop in the summer of 2025 which will cover all participant costs except travel. The total value of the Fellowship is 3000 USD. </p>
<p>Selected participants will have a further opportunity to receive the Marek Matraszek Oxford Fellowship to complete their work during a term at Oxford University, where they will be able to work closely with a secondary supervisor to advance their research. The funding for research visits at Oxford University will cover accommodation, living costs, college fees, and supervision and have a total value of 5000 USD. </p>
<p>Supported Research Themes</p>
<p>The programme will support research which engages with Big Questions at the intersection of science theology and philosophy. Applicants will be expected to engage with recent developments in their disciplines, and demonstrate a high standard of academic rigor. The Project encourages applications that fall within three broad themes: science and religion in the CEE context; reason and faith; and persons, mind and cosmos. Suitable topics include:</p>
<p>▪        The significance of theological traditions for scientific practice today;</p>
<p>▪        The relations of brains, minds and human persons;</p>
<p>▪        Whether physical cosmology can explain the origin of the cosmos;</p>
<p>▪        The role of religion in the historical development of science;</p>
<p>▪        The place of values in the natural world;</p>
<p>▪        How the history of CEE has influenced views on science and religion;</p>
<p>▪        Free will and scientific determinism and/or divine foreknowledge;</p>
<p>▪        Empirical psychology and the second person perspective;</p>
<p>▪        Phenomenological approaches to religion;</p>
<p>▪        Understanding notions of God, good and evil in a scientific age. </p>
<p>For further example areas, applicants are strongly encouraged to visit the Ian Ramsey Centre’s website where example areas of interest for the New Horizons for Science and Religion in Central and Eastern Europe project as a whole are listed.</p>
<p>For more information on the NGRE fellowship programme as well as on NGRE alumni visit: https://cee.ianramseycentre.ox.ac.uk/applications</p>
<p>Application process</p>
<p>Applications for Exchange Fellowships must be submitted no later than 2 August 2024 for the cycle of the programme starting October 2024. Applications must include the following documents.  </p>
<p>▪A proposal describing the research the candidate is carrying out, how far the research is advanced, and an outline of the work the candidate expects to complete during the course of their final year. </p>
<p>▪A full curriculum vitae, and a statement saying how the candidate expects to benefit from participating in the programme</p>
<p>▪Two academic references including a reference from the candidate’s supervisor if the research project is part of an MA degree. </p>
<p>▪A confirmation from the candidate’s institution stating that they are allowed to participate in the programme during the academic year 2024–5. </p>
<p>All application materials should be submitted via email to cee.irc@theology.ox.ac.uk stating in the subject line: “NGRE application”. The results of the competition will be announced in September 2024.</p>
<p>By submitting an application for the New Generation Research Exchange candidates accept and acknowledge the terms of processing their personal data for the purpose of the application process. For further information concerning the processing of personal data by the University of Warsaw see the personal data information sheet. If you have any questions please contact Dr Mikołaj Sławkowski-Rode: m.slawkowski-rode@uw.edu.pl </p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1717825024020089</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FreshRSS 1.24.1</title>
			<link>https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/releases/tag/1.24.1</link>
						<dc:creator>Alkarex</dc:creator>
			<description><ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/milestones/1.24.1">Milestone</a></li>
</ul>
<p>This is a bug-fix release for the <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/releases/tag/1.24.0">1.24.0 release</a>, addressing several regressions.</p>
<p>A few highlights ✨:</p>
<ul>
<li>New button to export OMPL of a category</li>
<li>Many bug fixes</li>
</ul>
<p>This release has been made by <a data-hovercard-type="user" data-hovercard-url="/users/Alkarex/hovercard" data-octo-click="hovercard-link-click" data-octo-dimensions="link_type:self" href="https://github.com/Alkarex">@Alkarex</a>, <a data-hovercard-type="user" data-hovercard-url="/users/math-GH/hovercard" data-octo-click="hovercard-link-click" data-octo-dimensions="link_type:self" href="https://github.com/math-GH">@math-GH</a>, and newcomers <a data-hovercard-type="user" data-hovercard-url="/users/ramazansancar/hovercard" data-octo-click="hovercard-link-click" data-octo-dimensions="link_type:self" href="https://github.com/ramazansancar">@ramazansancar</a>, <a data-hovercard-type="user" data-hovercard-url="/users/robinmetral/hovercard" data-octo-click="hovercard-link-click" data-octo-dimensions="link_type:self" href="https://github.com/robinmetral">@robinmetral</a></p>
<p>Full <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/blob/1.24.1/CHANGELOG.md">changelog</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Features
<ul>
<li>New button to export OMPL of a category <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6519" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6519/hovercard">#6519</a></li>
<li>Better git error messages in built-in Web update <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6496" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6496/hovercard">#6496</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Bug fixing
<ul>
<li>Fix regression HTTP GET curl options <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6492" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6492/hovercard">#6492</a></li>
<li>Fix regression of <em>mark as read if an identical title already exists</em> <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6536" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6536/hovercard">#6536</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6543" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6543/hovercard">#6543</a></li>
<li>Fix connection to PostgreSQL databases with uppercase letters <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6482" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6482/hovercard">#6482</a></li>
<li>Fix UI regression hover over title while having the navigation buttons in mobile view <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6486" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6486/hovercard">#6486</a></li>
<li>Fix UI for some drag &amp; drops <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6505" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6505/hovercard">#6505</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6508" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6508/hovercard">#6508</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>i18n
<ul>
<li>Improve Czech <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6504" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6504/hovercard">#6504</a></li>
<li>Improve Turkish <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6506" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6506/hovercard">#6506</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Misc.
<ul>
<li>Update dev dependencies <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6525" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6525/hovercard">#6525</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6526" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6526/hovercard">#6526</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6528" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6528/hovercard">#6528</a>,<br/>
<a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6529" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6529/hovercard">#6529</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6530" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/6530/hovercard">#6530</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 15:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1717652223252064</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Volume - 5, Issue - 1, 2024</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2024/06/03/volume-5-issue-1-2024</link>
						<dc:creator>literarydruid@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, June 4, 2024 - 11:28am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Maheswari Publishers (The publishing unit of PANDIAN EDUCATIONAL TRUST- TN32D0026797)</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:nt.jou.oftemplestudies@gmail.com">nt.jou.oftemplestudies@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>June 30, 2024</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Aims and Scope</p>
<p>Tamil culture is very ancient. This is evidenced by the fact that over the years its impact has spread around the world. Temples play an important role in Tamil culture. Its antiquity, statues, architectural techniques, yoga and spiritual philosophies are not only surprising but also portraying the intelligence of the ancients and supernatural powers. The Tamil Siddhars have created, evinced and clarified the doctrine of temples. The temples are built as the signifier, the signified, and the outward appearance of body, mind and soul. The Cheras, Cholas and Pandyas (triumvirs), the Tamil kings, built thousands of temples and made great penances to the Gods for goodwill. There are millions of Shaiva and Vaishnava temples in Tamil Nadu and uncountable temples all over India. Hinduism is one of the oldest religions in the world. There are countless subsections in it. All the temples, from the great temples to the small temples, have a different central theme of spiritual doctrine and philosophy that is merged with life. Temples are considered as energy centers, chakras, and the replica of the human body itself. The purpose of this peer-reviewed journal is to explore the origins, design, worship, spiritual philosophy, doctrines of the temples, architecture, temple work of the Tamils, charity, music and musical instruments, folk music, temple folk, the spiritual hymns of the sect, Tamil Bhakthi literature, Bhakthi literature in general to Hindu religion from any language of India and Abroad and universal temple art. It gives more chances and acts as a pioneer to the academicians, research scholars and freelancers who focus on the Bhakthi heritage, tradition and literature from Literatures of various Indian languages.</p>
<p>Call for</p>
<p>The Pandian Tamil Journal of Temple Studies (PTJTS) E-ISSN 2583-0880 publishes articles twice a year in the months of Karthikai and Vaikasi (November, May). Submit articles in the months of Purattasi (September) and Panguni (March). Research articles should be sent to <a href="mailto:editorptjts@pandianeducationaltrust.com">editorptjts@pandianeducationaltrust.com</a>, <a href="mailto:int.jou.oftemplestudies@gmail.com">int.jou.oftemplestudies@gmail.com</a>.  Research articles are published online twice a year for the benefit of the green environment. Special issues will be also called to study on new research areas related to the goals of the journal. Researchers, professors, and freelance writers are welcome to submit their elegant articles.</p>
<p>Manuscript Guidelines and Policies</p>
<p>Size of the research article:</p>
<p>The research paper should be typed in Arial Unicode (Tamil), Times New Roman (English) font on A4 paper 12 size, 1.5 spacing, not receding or exceeding to 8-15 pages. Article title, Abstract, Keywords and References ought to be in Tamil and English for Tamil written articles. English written articles should be fully in English. Other language articles should have English Title, Abstract, Keywords and References. They have to give details of four subject experts (reviewers) designation and acceptation certificate in their language for peer review. (for more details see Publication ethics and malpractice statement below)</p>
<p>Title page</p>
<p>The title page should contain the Title of the article, Name, Designation, ORCiD id and email address.</p>
<p>Abstract</p>
<p>Provide an English Abstract of 150 - 200 words. Keywords: 5 - 6.</p>
<p>Article Structure</p>
<p>Research articles should be of novelty, originality and quality. “Research Methods” ஆராய்ச்சி நெறிமுறைகள், உலக தமிழாராய்ச்சி நிறுவனம் (தமிழ்) and the current MLA 8th Edition (English)</p>
<p>Quotations</p>
<p>Be sure to quotations are included in the reference list with proper ethical methods.</p>
<p>Reference List</p>
<p>Authors should follow alphabetical order of their used books, journals, research articles, dissertations and web data in concordance to the research ethics.</p>
<p>Publication</p>
<p>The Pandian Tamil Journal of Temple Studies (PTJTS) E-ISSN 2583-0880 publishes articles twice a year in the months of Karthikai and Vaikasi (November, May). Submit articles in the months of Purattasi (September) and Panguni (March). Research articles should be sent to <a href="mailto:editorptjts@pandianeducationaltrust.com">editorptjts@pandianeducationaltrust.com</a>, <a href="mailto:int.jou.oftemplestudies@gmail.com">int.jou.oftemplestudies@gmail.com</a>. Research articles are published online twice a year for the benefit of the green environment. Only full issue pdf, individual pdf and e-certificate will be provided to the author by mail.</p>
<p>Release / Peer-review Policy</p>
<p>Research articles will be published online only. Research articles are subjected to double blind peer-review method. PDF documents will be published on the Internet only after the reviewed articles have been evaluated for originality, novelty and other ethical principles in research and publishing methods.</p>
<p>Anti-plagiarism</p>
<p>The journal views plagiarism as an injustice to a scholar's intellectual knowledge. Proper attribution is expected. If there is plagiarism in the work of the researchers, the editorial board will reject the article. If any found after publication, it will be retracted.</p>
<p>Open access Policy</p>
<p>Our Open access Policy allows our journal readers to honestly search, read, download, copy, and link articles.</p>
<p>Archival Policy</p>
<p>Our journal adopts a constant policy to deposit the full issues in Internet Archive for the Long-term preservation service.</p>
<p>License</p>
<p>Our journal adopts CC BY Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License  <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</a> benefit. It allows real works to be used, distributed and redesigned with appropriate attribution methods. Every work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.</p>
<p>Copyright</p>
<p>If the article is accepted for publication, authors will continue to retain their copyright of the published article.</p>
<p>Article processing charges</p>
<p>The fee for reviewing and publishing articles (APC) is fixed as 1000 INR. Pay after the consent letter from the journal for publishing the articles along with the copyright form.</p>
<p>See here for Special Issue Details - <a href="https://pandianeducationaltrust.com/pandian-tamil-journal-of-temple-studies-special-issue-details.html">https://pandianeducationaltrust.com/pandian-tamil-journal-of-temple-studies-special-issue-details.html</a></p>
<p>Publication Ethics and Malpractice Statement</p>
<p>Pandian Tamil Journal of Temple Studies (E-ISSN 2583-0880) is a biannual open-access and peer-reviewed journal published for educators, researchers and freelancers in the field of Temple Studies and related domain areas. The journal is committed to support ethical research practices. The editors, authors, reviewers, publication staff, and the publisher abide to the guidelines as evinced by the Code of Conduct <a href="https://publicationethics.org/resources/flowcharts/general-approach-publication-ethics-editorial-office">https://publicationethics.org/resources/flowcharts/general-approach-publication-ethics-editorial-office</a> (COPE) and aims to disseminate ethical Guidelines in research.</p>
<p>Publication Process</p>
<p>All submissions are viable for double-blind peer-review to two academicians’ relevant expertise. Peer reviewers will advise the editors whether the article be published or if any constructive suggestions to modify the article. In case a third reviewer may be also employed and his/her decision is final. The editor connects the author with their decision and proper modifications needed in the article for publication. Manuscripts should follow ஆராய்ச்சி நெறிமுறைகள், உலக தமிழாராய்ச்சி நிறுவனம் (தமிழ்) and MLA style for English or else it will be declined. Misleading and inaccurate data, opinions, statements and plagiarism issues are the sole responsibility of the author concerned. The editorial team take no responsibility or liability under such consequences. PDF of the Issue and Publication E-Certificate will be provided.</p>
<p>Archival Policy:<br/>Our journal adopts a constant policy to deposit the full issues in Internet Archive for the Long-term preservation service.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 18:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1717565823637657</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ October 16, 2024] Talk or similar: Sharif International School on Theism: East and West</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/123910</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/>Speakers at this event: <br/>Elliott Sober (University of Wisconsin, Madison)<br/>Denis Alexander<br/>Erkki V. R. Kojonen<br/>Herman Johan Selderhuis<br/>Michael J. Behe<br/>Sara Walker<br/>Zachary Ardern<br/>Shoaib Ahmed Malik<br/>Nidhal Guessoum<br/>Mohammadsaleh Zarepour<br/>Naeime Pourmohammadi<br/>Seyed Hassan Hosseini<br/>Reza Naderloo<br/><br/><p><strong>“Sharif International School on Theism: East and West”</strong> is a theological-philosophical event having a 10-year vision. Its first three years were planned for 2021, 2022 and 2023. For three years in a row, these schools have focused on three categories:<strong> “God,” “Man” and “Nature”.</strong> The first school, centering on “God”, took place in 2021, and featured distinguished international professors. This event was around the main themes of God, including concepts, proofs, attributes, and actions. The second school was conducted online in 2022, focusing on “Man” and delved into topics such as the mind-body problem, the problem of evil, and the problem of free will. The third one named “Nature”, was held in 2023, featuring top international professors. This school had organized its curriculum into three categories: natural kinds, laws of nature, and teleology. Now, for the second three years of the school, we intend to focus our attention on Theism and its relations with natural and social sciences. <strong>The fourth school will be on Theism and Natural Sciences: with special scrutiny of Foundations, Theoretical Contemplations, and Evolutionary Explanations, and it is scheduled to be held online on October 16-19, 2024.</strong> Our aim is to host distinguished and renowned Iranian and international professors specializing in theism and science.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1717393024754986</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ June 12, 2024] Conference or similar: Heidegger's &quot;The Question concerning Technology&quot; - New Readings</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/123906</link>
						<description>Venue: 115 Victoria Parade, Fitzroy<br/><br/><p>Session 1  (9.00-11.00)</p>
<p>Dermot Moran: AI and the Resistance of the Life-World: Phenomenological Reflections</p>
<p>Richard Colledge: Enframing and Interrogating Nature: Heidegger’s Technology Essay in Light of Bacon and Kant</p>
<p>Jess Martin/Christopher O’Neill: Gestell as ‘Correction’: Derrida’s Reading of ‘The Question’ and the Philosophy of Error.</p>
<p>James Philips: A Dog-Leg Reading of Heidegger and Plato on Poetry as technē</p>

<p>Morning Tea 11.00-11.15</p>

<p>Session 2  (11.15-12.45)</p>
<p>Andrew Inkpin:Can the 'Saving Power' Save Us?</p>
<p>Robert Sinnerbrink: ‘Saving Power’: Heidegger on the Ethical Ambiguity of Technics</p>
<p>Lucy Benjamin: The Question Concerning the Prelude to Breakdown</p>

<p>Lunch 12.45-1.30</p>

<p>Session 3 (1.30-3.00)</p>
<p>Marilyn Stendera: Concerning Time</p>
<p>Jeff Malpas: Technology and Spatialization</p>
<p>Claude Romano: Heidegger and Carlyle on Technology</p>

<p>Afternoon Tea 3.00-3.15</p>

<p>Session 4  (3.15-4.45)</p>
<p>Justin Clemens:Intricacies of the Eventing-Structuring of the Becoming-Enframing of Technology’</p>
<p>Lucy Myers: Understanding the Role of Labour in 'The Question Concerning of Technology'.</p>
<p>Joe Hughes: Technologies of the Event: Toward a Theory of Presentational Forms.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1717393024754985</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ambedkar and Community: Minor Figurations and Comparative Mediations</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2024/05/30/ambedkar-and-community-minor-figurations-and-comparative-mediations</link>
						<dc:creator>Ambedkar community conference</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Sunday, June 2, 2024 - 7:14pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Centre for Comparative Literature, University of Hyderabad</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ambedkar.community2024@gmail.com">ambedkar.community2024@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/general-announcements">general announcements</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/international-conferences">international conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/postcolonial">postcolonial</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>June 22, 2024</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Singularly remembered for his influential role in authoring the Constitution of India, Ambedkar’s<br/>thinking continues to provoke new thoughts on the normative orders of the social and the state.<br/>However, foregrounding the centrality of “community” in understanding the social and the state,<br/>this conference invites scholars to rethink Ambedkar as a paradigmatic figure—a writer and a<br/>thinker—on community, understood as critical, even conflictual, constellations of affinities and<br/>associations.<br/>The idea of such a conference itself was an offshoot of conversations and contestations among a<br/>few scholars of Humanities and Social Sciences in Hyderabad, working and worrying<br/>“community,” from diverse linguistic and gender/caste/religious/tribal (re)locations as well as<br/>from within and across various political and aesthetic performativities. A pithy, and probably<br/>belated, realization that though a lot of academic work seems to be blithely happening on<br/>“community,” not much still seems to be happening in/to the communities, was the trigger to<br/>reach out to other scholars in similar predicaments and whose research also intersects with<br/>various community form(ul)ations.<br/>But, indeed, a lot seem to be still happening in/to various caste-tribal-communities, then as well<br/>as now, regardless of “our” understanding, or lack thereof. Hence, the central question, in a way,<br/>would be whether we can ever again re-think the question of community in the wake of, and re-<br/>awaken, Ambedkar? For, thinking community is rethinking Ambedkar, in almost every way. And<br/>probably vice versa as well. Therefore, this conference invites scholars and researchers to<br/>“closely” re-read Ambedkar as well as juxtapose his thoughts with other figures and figurations<br/>from the subcontinent, if only to re-conceive a critical framing of what, how, where, why and<br/>when is Ambedkar’s community, and, significantly, also the other way round, today?<br/>As such, even today, this would be to start afresh, to adopt a comparative approach that invites,<br/>even enjoins, all of us to co(a)gitate and contribute to, at least, the emerging scholarship on both<br/>“Ambedkar” and “community,” if only within the Humanities and the Social Sciences, for now.<br/>Hence, as an overture, we invite papers/presentations that explore the questions of community<br/>vis-a-viz Ambedkar, and vice versa, especially in relation to the many anti-casteist and religious<br/>traditions, movements and writings from across the country that have been generally overlooked<br/>by Ambedkar studies.<br/>Firstly, we would like to foreground Ambedkar’s readings of various caste-community<br/>subjectivities and sovereignties. If Ambedkar is a spatial scholar and temporal actor who<br/>interconnects communities, did he foreground a community of critique, over the long 20 th<br/>century, through Buddhism? The conference hopes to generate a differential reading of<br/>Ambedkar, as a critical thinker and writer on community of his times, but who is still a<br/>monumental, if not a spectral, force for our times.<br/>Secondly, the conference looks forward to engagements of a nuanced and more rigorous<br/>comparison of Ambedkar with other resistant or recalcitrant figures of his/our times in order to</p>
<p>configure possibilities of mediation from different, although connected, intellectual traditions<br/>and histories—not only from the anti-casteist movements in the country, but also through the<br/>centrifugal ruptures from northern-southern-western-and-eastern regions of the nationalized-<br/>subcontinent. Through the very many figures, who embodied such digressive imaginaires and<br/>discourses, such as Periyar E.V. Ramasamy (1879-1973), Naoria Phulo (1888-1941), Abul Kalam<br/>Azad (1888-1958), Sahodaran Ayyapan (1889-1968), and many such others. Ambedkar may also<br/>be brought into an unconventional conversation with his contemporaries, such as Marx,<br/>Gramsci, Benjamin, Fanon and Du Bois, and with Jinnah, Gandhi, Tagore, Nehru, Patel and<br/>many others.<br/>And lastly, we also would like to focus on the re-presentations of Ambedkar, mediated through<br/>journals, cinema, cartoons and movements across time. We invite scholarly evaluations as well as<br/>accounts on the critical figuration of Ambedkar as a communicator and a communicated<br/>phenomenon.<br/>Altogether, this conference would primarily revolve around Ambedkar’s many lives in the<br/>imaginations and reconfigurations of communities. And, of course, vice versa. Hence, the<br/>conference, at once, attempts to be a timely document and a momentary reflection on the<br/>constituted world of/on Ambedkar in the context of an unprecedented amendment to the ideas<br/>of imagined political communities.<br/>Dates to Remember:<br/>Those interested should upload the Abstracts of about 600 words to:<br/><a href="https://forms.gle/CERZhVZhccrSCdm27">https://forms.gle/CERZhVZhccrSCdm27</a> by 22 June 2024.<br/>If accepted, drafts of full papers should be emailed by 31 August 2024.<br/>Paper presenters will be provided local hospitality (including accommodation) &amp;amp; TA as per UoH norms.<br/>For others, a token registration fee of Rs. 500/- for faculty and Rs. 300/- for students will ensure<br/>limited hospitality, excluding accommodation.<br/>Link for online registration: <a href="https://forms.gle/3pSpjRuRWD6K3jAN9">https://forms.gle/3pSpjRuRWD6K3jAN9</a></p>
<p>Contact:<br/>Jomina George (Scholar, CCL): <a href="mailto:jomina.c.george@gmail.com">jomina.c.george@gmail.com</a> / 9495295157<br/>Jayshreeram Dash (Scholar, CCL): <a href="mailto:shreeramdash53@gmail.com">shreeramdash53@gmail.com</a> / 8249201184<br/>Thahir Jamal (Guest Faculty, CCL): <a href="mailto:tkmjamal@gmail.com">tkmjamal@gmail.com</a> / 9400605696<br/>Bivitha Easo (Guest Faculty, CCL): <a href="mailto:bivi.easo@gmail.com">bivi.easo@gmail.com</a> / 9441175737<br/>Prof. M.T. Ansari<br/>Centre for Comparative Literature<br/>School of Humanities, University of Hyderabad<br/>Central University P.O., Gachibowli<br/>Hyderabad 500046, Telangana</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 10:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1717393024754984</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CfP: FOOD FEST, FEASTS &amp; GATHERINGS</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2024/05/29/cfp-food-fest-feasts-gatherings</link>
						<dc:creator>festival.culture.edu@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, June 6, 2024 - 1:25pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Journal of Festival Culture Inquiry and Analysis</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:festival.culture.edu@gmail.com">festival.culture.edu@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/general-announcements">general announcements</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/popular-culture">popular culture</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>October 1, 2024</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Food fests, feasts, and gatherings address the role of food in events, gatherings, celebrations, and ceremonies. Exploring how people incorporate ideas about food into festival culture, including history, heritage, tradition, creativity, and social and political factors. </p>
<p>In addition, it examines festivals in which food is not the main focus, yet contributes significantly to the atmosphere, memory, and tradition. It also looks at people's fascination with taste. In addition to examining these notions, we will also examine trends in the consumption and production of food.</p>
<p>We welcome submissions for next year's symposium (ISFC 2025) and journal (JFCIA 2026) examining food experiences through travel and the relationship between street food and food at festivals. We also encourage submissions that focus on policies, preparation, and organising festival food and food festivals. Practitioners are welcome to submit articles on their specific areas of interest in festival culture.</p>
<p>We welcome theoretically informed and empirically grounded narratives about festivals, feasts, rituals, gatherings, and celebration food, including but not limited to:</p>
<p> </p>
<p>• History, heritage, and traditions</p>
<p>• Harvest</p>
<p>• Tourism</p>
<p>• Recipes and festivals</p>
<p>• Cultural identity and festivals</p>
<p>• Temporality</p>
<p>• Religion</p>
<p>• Religious celebrations</p>
<p>• Rituals and Ceremonies</p>
<p>• Food experiences</p>
<p>• Food: medicinal and ritual use</p>
<p>• Festival food and the senses</p>
<p>• Agriculture</p>
<p>• Food processing</p>
<p>• Taste and pleasure</p>
<p>• Food festivals</p>
<p>• Food festival competitions</p>
<p>• Festive cooking and eating versus everyday</p>
<p>• Organising and preparation of food </p>
<p> </p>
<p>Symposium submissions: </p>
<p>Abstracts of up to 500-word (only abstracts/papers that have not been previously presented and published will be considered) and biographies of no more than 100 words (in Word .doc format). Send Abstracts for consideration for next year's symposium here: <a href="https://tinyurl.com/5bebffv7">https://tinyurl.com/5bebffv7</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>If you would like your work to be considered for volume 5 (2026) send an early submission of an abstract proposal please click the link .</p>
<p>Journal submissions for 2026: All submissions considered for inclusion will be peer-review. Please send your 500-word abstract (only abstracts/papers which have not been previously presented and published will be considered), and a bio of no longer than 100 words should be included (Microsoft Word Document). Full articles no more than a 5,000 words.</p>
<p>Abstracts/papers previously published or under consideration for publication while being evaluated for this Journal will not be accepted.</p>
<p>Submit Journal Abstract Proposal here:<a href="https://tinyurl.com/bdzejudr">https://tinyurl.com/bdzejudr</a>.</p>
<p>Submit full Paper: <a href="https://form.jotform.com/241575009751356">https://form.jotform.com/241575009751356</a></p>
<p>Visit our journal <a href="https://www.festivalculture.co.uk/jfcia-2022" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.festivalculture.co.uk/jfcia-2022">https://www.festivalculture.co.uk/jfcia</a>.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 10:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1717393024754983</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
