<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 12:17:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 12:17:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ May 1, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Religious Symbolism and Symbolic Logic</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/110137</link>
						<description><p>On the one hand symbolism is important in most religions, on the other hand modern logic is often  characterized as symbolic.  This workshop, part of the 4th World Congress on Logic and Religion, explores the relation bewteen these two symbolic approaches. Suggested topics include - but are not limited to - the following:</p>
<p>- Boole's symbolic mathematical notation in logic and abstract religious notions  </p>
<p>- Zoroastrianism's dualism, Pythagoras's table of oppositions, Trinity Christian triangle, Islamic geometrical objects and the theory of oppositions</p>
<p>- Yin/Yang and the notion of complementary contradiction</p>
<p>- the symbolism of the cross, crucification, negation and abnegation </p>
<p>- Venn symbolic logic, Venn diagrams and their application to understanding of religious phenomena</p>
<p>- the universal quantifier and <em>catho</em>licism as a religion for all </p>
<p>-  is the existential quantifier really symbolizing existence? </p>
<p>- Cabala symbolism and logic in <em>Alice's Adventures in Wonderland</em> by Charles Dodgson, aka Lewis Carroll, deacon in the Church of England and symbolic logician</p>
<p>- logical "interpretation" of Gödel's proof of the existence of God in symbolic logic</p>
<p>Submit a one page abstract by May 1st to jyb.logos@gmail.com</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 05:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680932232851034</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ September 3, 2023 -  September 8, 2023] Conference or similar: Religious Symbolism and Symbolic Logic</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/110133</link>
						<description>Venue: Octavian Goga Street, 4<br/><br/><p>On the one hand symbolism is important in most religions, on the other hand modern logic is often  characterized as symbolic.  This workshop, part of the 4th World Congress on Logic and Religion, explores the relation bewteen these two symbolic approaches. Suggested topics include - but are not limited to - the following:</p>
<p>- Boole's symbolic mathematical notation in logic and abstract religious notions  </p>
<p>- Zoroastrianism's dualism, Pythagoras's table of oppositions, Trinity Christian triangle, Islamic geometrical objects and the theory of oppositions</p>
<p>- Yin/Yang and the notion of complementary contradiction</p>
<p>- the symbolism of the cross, crucification, negation and abnegation </p>
<p>- Venn symbolic logic, Venn diagrams and their application to understanding of religious phenomena</p>
<p>- the universal quantifier and <em>catho</em>licism as a religion for all </p>
<p>-  is the existential quantifier really symbolizing existence? </p>
<p>- Cabala symbolism and logic in <em>Alice's Adventures in Wonderland</em> by Charles Dodgson, aka Lewis Carroll, deacon in the Church of England and symbolic logician</p>
<p>- logical "interpretation" of Gödel's proof of the existence of God in symbolic logic</p>
<p>Submit a one page abstract by May 1st to jyb.logos@gmail.com</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 05:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680932232851033</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Graduate Student Institute - Islam in the Contemporary World</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12686832/graduate-student-institute-islam-contemporary-world</link>
						<dc:creator>Ermin  Sinanovic</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Summer Program</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-05-30T00:00:00-04:00">May 30, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-13T00:00:00-04:00">June 13, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Virginia</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Islamic History / Studies, Middle East History / Studies, Political Science, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><div> </div><div>Center for Islam in the Contemporary World</div><div>at Shenandoah University (CICW)</div><div> </div><div><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Graduate Student Institute</span><br/><span>“Islam in the Contemporary World”</span><br/><span>May 30 – June 13, 2023</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></div><div> </div><div>Venue: George Mason University</div><div>Fairfax, VA</div><div> </div><div><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The CICW’s summer student program, “Islam in the Contemporary World,” is a graduate students’ institute whose objective is twofold: (1) to provide graduate students with foundational instructions in Islamic studies with a focus on contemporary issues and (2) to have discussions about the lived experiences of Muslim graduate students, especially as they pertain to issues of wellness, equity, and belonging. By combining academic and mentoring sessions, we aim to provide a rounded approach to Islam in the contemporary world.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></div><div> </div><div><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>More info at this link<span><span><span>: </span></span></span><a href="https://www.contemporaryislam.org/graduate-student-institute-2023.html" rel="nofollow">https://www.contemporaryislam.org/graduate-student-institute-2023.html</a></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></div><div> </div><div><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Please address any questions to Marjan Popal, Program Manager, at <a href="mailto:mpopal@contemporaryislam.org">mpopal@contemporaryislam.org</a></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></div></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Marjan Popal, <a href="mailto:mpopal@contemporaryislam.org">mpopal@contemporaryislam.org</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:mpopal@contemporaryislam.org">mpopal@contemporaryislam.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.contemporaryislam.org/graduate-student-institute-2023.html" target="_blank">https://www.contemporaryislam.org/graduate-student-institute-2023.html</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 17:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680932232851032</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Global China in a Religious World</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12680637/global-china-religious-world</link>
						<dc:creator>Valerie  Yeo</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-08-17T00:00:00-04:00">August 17, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-08-23T00:00:00-04:00">August 23, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Singapore</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><div> </div><div> </div><div><span><strong>Global China in a Religious World<br/>17-18 Aug | University of Hong Kong (in-person) &amp;<br/>22-23 Aug | via Zoom (Online)</strong></span></div><p><strong>CALL FOR PAPERS DEADLINE | 20 April 2023</strong></p><p>Discussions on the rise of Global China, through the Belt and Road Initiative (BRI) and beyond, have focused on physical infrastructures, financial investments, commerce, and geopolitics. What about the religious dimension of China’s deepening entanglements with the world? Religion is central to the culture and national identity of most BRI and adjacent countries, and, often, their political system and ideology as well. These religions include Islam, Buddhism, Hinduism, and Protestant, Catholic and Orthodox Christianity, among others. What are the religious implications and consequences of these circulations and frictions? The growing presence of China in countries of the Global South may increase the importance of China in the imagination, strategies, or missionizing goals of religious organizations, movements, political parties and ideologies in those countries. These imaginations, strategies and identity formations may be inflected by a resurfacing of historical imaginations and networks. At the same time, growing links offer opportunities for the international expansion of Chinese religious and spiritual networks and organizations. This increased circulation may impact on China’s religious ecology and complicate China’s internal religious policy as well as its management of religious exchanges in the service of diplomacy and soft power.</p><p>This international conference will bring together scholars working on different regions and disciplines, to map out the contours of the religious dimensions and implications of Global China, through discussion of empirical studies and testing of different analytical frameworks.</p><p>Scholars are invited to submit paper proposals on empirical studies touching on one or more of the following topics:</p><ul><li>The circulation and penetration of religious networks, personnel and practices between China and other countries, including countries of the BRI and beyond, including through migration, trade or missionary movements;</li><li>Religious entanglements and responses to Chinese-invested infrastructure projects;</li><li>Evolving religious and civilizational discourses, identities and imaginaries as a consequence of intensified relationships between China and other nations;</li><li>State management and control, whether by China or other countries, of increased religious flows in a context of securitization and geopolitical tensions;</li><li>Religious factors in national politics or geopolitics involving China.</li></ul><p>The conference will be held both in-person, at the University of Hong Kong on 17-18 August, and online, hosted by the Asia Research Institute on 22-23 August.</p><p><strong>The conference is generously supported by the project <a href="https://asiar.hku.hk/brinfaith/home/" rel="nofollow"><em>Infrastructures of Faith: Religious Mobilities on the Belt and Road</em> (BRINFAITH)</a> at the Asian Religious Connections research cluster of the Hong Kong Institute for the Humanities and Social Sciences (HKIHSS), University of Hong Kong, and jointly organized by HKIHSS; Asia Research Institute, National University of Singapore; and Center for Global Asia, New York University Shanghai.</strong></p><p><br/><strong>SUBMISSION OF PROPOSALS</strong></p><p>Paper proposals should include a title, an abstract (250 words maximum) and a brief personal biography of 100 words for submission. Please use the <a href="https://ari.nus.edu.sg/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/CFP-Proposal-Form_Global-China-Religious-World.docx" rel="nofollow">paper proposal form</a> and send it as a word document file to <a href="mailto:asiar@hku.hk">asiar@hku.hk</a> by <strong>20 April 2023</strong>. Successful applicants will be notified by <strong>early May</strong>.</p><p>Applicants may indicate a preference for in-person and/or online participation. Conference participants selected for in-person participation will be provided with return economy airfare to Hong Kong and three nights of accommodation at the conference hotel (one author per paper), and will also be provided with an honorarium of 5000 HKD. Online participants will be provided with a modest honorarium.</p><p>Please also include a statement confirming that your paper has not been published previously. Conference papers may potentially be invited for inclusion in an edited volume or special issue, in collaboration with the conference organizers and/or other participants. Paper presenters will be required to submit paper drafts by <strong>12 Aug. 2023</strong>. These drafts will be circulated to fellow panelists and discussants in advance. Drafts need not be fully polished as we expect that presenters will wish to incorporate feedback from fellow participants.</p><p><br/><strong>CONFERENCE CONVENOR</strong></p><p><strong>Prof David A. Palmer</strong><br/>Hong Kong Institute for the Humanities and Social Sciences, The University of Hong Kong</p><p><br/><strong>CONFERENCE CO-CONVENORS</strong></p><p><strong>Prof Tansen Sen</strong><br/>Center on Global Asia, New York University Shanghai</p><p><strong>Dr Michel Chambon</strong><br/>Initiative for the Study of Asian Catholics, Asia Research Institute, National University of Singapore</p><p><strong>Dr Emily Hertzman</strong><br/>Asia Research Institute, National University of Singapore</p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Valerie Yeo<br/>Asia Research Institute,<br/>National University of Singapore</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:valerie.yeo@nus.edu.sg">valerie.yeo@nus.edu.sg</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://ari.nus.edu.sg/events/global-china-religious-world/" target="_blank">https://ari.nus.edu.sg/events/global-china-religious-world/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 17:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680845830571879</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Journal of Social Encounters  special issue on Extractive Politics, Conflict and Peacebuilding</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12643265/journal-social-encounters-special-issue-extractive-politics</link>
						<dc:creator>Ron Pagnucco</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Journal</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-30T00:00:00-04:00">March 30, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-08-16T00:00:00-04:00">August 16, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Minnesota</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Area Studies, Colonial and Post-Colonial History / Studies, Environmental History / Studies, Peace History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The March 2023 issue of the Journal of Social Encounters (JSE), a special issue on Extractive Politics, Conflict and Peacebuilding, includes case studies from Mozambique, Myanmar, Democratic Republic of Congo, Serbia, Mexico, the United States. Colombia and Kenya. The issue also includes a section of essays on religious leaders and peacebuilding. The JSE is an online, peer-reviewed, open access journal; the March special issue can be found at this link:<br/>Journal of Social Encounters   Volume 7, Issue 1 (March 2023) Extractive Politics, Conflict and Peacebuilding<br/><a href="https://digitalcommons.csbsju.edu/social_encounters/" rel="nofollow">https://digitalcommons.csbsju.edu/social_encounters/</a><br/><br/>For more information, please contact:<br/>Dr. Ron Pagnucco<br/>Coordinating Editor<br/>Journal of Social Encounters<br/><a href="mailto:rpagnucco@csbsju.edu">rpagnucco@csbsju.edu</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr. Ron Pagnucco<br/>Coordinating Editor<br/>Journal of Social Encounters</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:rpagnucco@csbsju.edu">rpagnucco@csbsju.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 17:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680845830571878</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>2nd Online Conference Cycle: Gender and Sexuality in Greek Mythology</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12676109/2nd-online-conference-cycle-gender-and-sexuality-greek</link>
						<dc:creator>Filipe Fernandes</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-05-02T00:00:00-04:00">May 2, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-05-16T00:00:00-04:00">May 16, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Portugal</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Ancient History, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies, Sexuality Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Anthropology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The Centre for History of the University of Lisbon (Uses of the Past Research Group) promotes the 2nd Online Conference Cycle: Gender and Sexuality in Greek Mythology (May 2-16, 2023, 5pm GMT). This second edition is coordinated by Nuno Simões Rodrigues and Joana Pinto Salvador Costa. The working languages will be Portuguese and Spanhish. Admission is free, but subject to prior registration: <a href="mailto:gender.sexuality.ch@gmail.com">gender.sexuality.ch@gmail.com</a>. </p><p><strong>Programme</strong></p><p>May 2, 2023: "De mãe primordial a um corpo sacro-erótico: algumas reflexões sobre a representação de Reia Silvia na literatura latina", Katia Teonia (Universidade Federal do Rio de Janeiro)<br/>                        <br/>May 9, 2023: "Desfazendo o tecido de Penélope: cultura material, pesos de tear e a questão de género", Airton Pollini (Université de Haute-Alsace)</p><p>May 16, 2023: "El Peligro de lo Femenino en la Creación y Consolidación de la Comunidad de Dioses y Hombres", Carmen Morenilla (Universitat de València)</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Joana Pinto Salvador Costa</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:gender.sexuality.ch@gmail.com">gender.sexuality.ch@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="http://www.centrodehistoria-flul.com/" target="_blank">http://www.centrodehistoria-flul.com/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 17:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680759431272784</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>“Life is War”: Social Militarization and the Culture of Prayers in Africa</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12675996/%E2%80%9Clife-war%E2%80%9D-social-militarization-and-culture-prayers-africa</link>
						<dc:creator>Abimbola Adelakun</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-30T00:00:00-04:00">June 30, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-07-27T00:00:00-04:00">July 27, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>African History / Studies, Contemporary History, Cultural History / Studies, Humanities, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>NAGEL INSTITUTE, CALVIN UNIVERSITY (USA) </span></span></span></b><span><span><span>&amp; <b>ADEKUNLE AJASIN UNIVERSITY (NIGERIA)</b> Announce International Conference</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Prayers are a ritual common to all religions, but the intensity of their performance and social application differ from one religion to another. One resonant factor in the rituals of prayer offered in contemporary Africa is how the context of physical insecurity, social instability, and economic precarity have penetrated through and shaped its content and rites. Our responses to the challenges of underdevelopment and weakness of state political apparatuses through the instrumentality of prayer have configured daily life around militarization. Despite the pervasiveness of prayer as a form of warfare against extant reality, this spectacular practice that reverberates through the cultural landscape in Africa and beyond has not received enough scholarly attention. Militarized prayers, aimed at cosmic forces perceived to be militating against social progress, are initiatives toward addressing existential realities. They demonstrate African cosmological insights into the mechanisms of world-ordering and agency of those who want to re-order it. Warfare prayers are thus worth understanding on these terms. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>This conference calls for papers that engage the sort of world Africans build when they employ prayers as a form of warfare. How do these forms of prayers re-order personal, social, and political life? What cultural understanding of the nature of reality drives these prayers? How do these prayers integrate the physical and psychic with the political? What is the nexus between prayer performance, pleasures, and political practices?  This interdisciplinary conference welcomes presentations that engage these questions and many more from scholars, theologians, postgraduate students, and members of faith communities. This study is not limited to any religious traditions. We welcome presentations from across a broad spectrum of faith practices. Please send in abstracts/proposals of not more than 250 words and proposals by June 24, 2023 to: </span></span></span><a href="mailto:violentprayersconference@gmail.com"><span><span><span>violentprayersconference@gmail.com</span></span></span></a><u><span><span><span>.</span></span></span></u></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Papers are expected from these subthemes but are not limited to:</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Typologies of prayer practices within and across religious spectrum</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Theoretical conceptions of prayers and social militarization</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Comparative religious perspectives on prayer and social militarization</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Historical study of prayer and social militarization</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Methodological approaches to prayer and social militarization</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Ethical issues in warfare prayer </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Popular culture, prayer, and prayer warfare</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Spaces, places, and prayer as warfare</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Politics, democracy, and notions of power in prayer </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Urban culture and prayer warfare </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Language and poetics of prayer warfare</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Language, literature and creativity in prayer warfare</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Gender issues in prayer warfare</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Technology, medium, and warfare prayers</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Warfare prayers and shaping of social imaginary</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Performance, sacred objects, and rituals of warfare prayers </span></span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Conference Date: 24</span><span>th </span><span>– 27</span><span>th </span><span>July, 2023. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Venue: The Redeemed Christian Bible College, Redemption Camp, Mowe, Ogun State. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Note: This conference has a virtual component for international participants</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span> </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><a href="mailto:violentprayersconference@gmail.com">violentprayersconference@gmail.com</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:adelakun@austin.utexas.edu">adelakun@austin.utexas.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 17:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680759431272783</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Opportunities Digest – April 5, 2023</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-opportunities-digest-april-5-2023/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find 2 new job opportunities,  2 Calls for Papers, and 1 upcoming conference/speaker.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 33!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Lecturer of Philosophy (full-time, renewable, non-tenure track)</h4>



<p>Old Dominion University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: 4/28/2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://jobs.odu.edu/postings/18304">https://jobs.odu.edu/postings/18304</a></p>



<h4>Freelance Subject Matter Expert: Crash Course World Religions</h4>



<p>Complexly</p>



<p>Deadline: 4/16/2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://complexly.com/jobs/">https://complexly.com/jobs/</a></p>



<h4>AAR/SBL Job Forum</h4>



<p><a href="https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search">https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>Review of Religious Research Journal</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://rraweb.us10.list-manage.com/track/click?u=55bb1644f88e9457d182915ac&amp;id=3c3199d513&amp;e=c7b3861607">https://rraweb.us10.list-manage.com/track/click?u=55bb1644f88e9457d182915ac&amp;id=3c3199d513&amp;e=c7b3861607</a></p>



<h4>The Religious Origins of White Supremacy: <em>Johnson v. M’Intosh </em>and the Doctrine of Christian Discovery</h4>



<p>Deadline: August 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://doctrineofdiscovery.org/blog/religious-origins-white-supremacy/">https://doctrineofdiscovery.org/blog/religious-origins-white-supremacy/</a></p>



<h2>Conferences:</h2>



<h4>Public Health after Covid: Beliefs, Religion, and Competing Epistemologies</h4>



<p>Kings College London, UK</p>



<p>Date: May 26-27, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/public-health-after-covid-beliefs-religion-and-competing-epistemologies-tickets-529497359857">https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/public-health-after-covid-beliefs-religion-and-competing-epistemologies-tickets-529497359857</a>?</p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680759431272782</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ May 15, 2023] Conference talk or similar: CFP: Rethinking Racism Through Embodiment and Place (A thematic stream for the 47th  Annual Meeting of the International Merleau-Ponty Circle)</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/109945</link>
						<description>Venue: Deakin Downtown<br/><br/><p>CFP: Rethinking Racism Through Embodiment and Place </p>
<p>A thematic stream for the 47th Annual Meeting of the International Merleau-Ponty Circle </p>
<p>4-6 December 2023 </p>
<p>In-person and virtual (hybrid) </p>
<p>Deakin University, Melbourne / Narrm, Australia </p>
<p>To many critical phenomenologists working on race, racism, and decoloniality, Maurice Merleau-Ponty’s philosophical account of the body as central to all lived experience has been a productive touchstone. Building on the classic phenomenological tradition while advancing critiques of its assumptions, these accounts have drawn attention to the ways in which racism impacts the bodily experience, self-perceptions, lived temporalities, habits, and social worlds of marginalised groups. Critical phenomenologists of race – among whom we might name Frantz Fanon, Sara Ahmed, Alia Al-Saji, Linda Martín Alcoff, George Yancy, Mariana Ortega, and others – have variously examinedthe existential, everyday, and deeply embodied impacts of racist oppression, and how these can affect our experience of place and placemaking. </p>
<p>As part of the 47th annual International Merleau-Ponty Circle (IMPC), we warmly invite submissions for a thematic stream exploring questions of racism, place, and embodiment. Interdisciplinary approaches that engage with these themes through phenomenology – critically or otherwise – are most welcome. We also encourage intersectional analyses that consider multiple systems of oppression (e.g., based on gender, class, disability, sexual orientation) and the differential impacts these may have.</p>
<p>Potential paper topics may include, but are not limited to: </p>
<ul>
<li>interpersonal and structural forms of oppression </li>
<li>settler colonialism and dispossession </li>
<li>home, placemaking, and belonging </li>
<li>social justice, protest, and resistance </li>
<li>migration, mobility, and diaspora </li>
<li>language, gesture, and embodiment </li>
</ul>
<p>We especially encourage submissions from First Nations people, people of colour, and other underrepresented groups in Philosophy and the academy more generally.  </p>
<p>This stream will be curated by Helen Ngo for a research project funded by the Australian Research Council (DE220100329). Anumber of travel bursaries will be available for students and unsalaried/low-waged early career researchers (ECRs) presenting in-person in this stream. (An ECR is defined as being fewer than 5 years out of their PhD, excluding career interruptions.) Participants wishing to be considered for a bursary should indicate on their cover letter: (1) your usual place of residence, and (2) whether you are a student or a low-waged ECR. Please note that submissions which engage directly with Merleau-Ponty’s work are also eligible to be considered for the two student prizes outlined in the conference’s general call for papers.  </p>
<p>Full paper submissions of no more than 3,500 words should be prepared for anonymous review and sent to Helen Ngo (helen.ngo@deakin.edu.au) and Ryan Gustafsson (r.gustafsson@deakin.edu.au) with the subject heading "IMPCRethinking Racism submission." The deadline for submissions is May 15, 2023.   </p>
<p>As this conference will be held as a hybrid event, please indicate whether, upon acceptance, you plan to attend in-person or virtually. In order to host the conference at a physical location, a certain percentage of talks will need to be presented in person, and this will be factored in during the review process. Please also include any anticipated accessibility needs, which will greatly assist in planning.  </p>
<p>Helen Ngo and Jack Reynolds/ IMPC 2023 conference co-convenors </p>
<p>Ryan Gustafsson / Research Assistant  </p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 05:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680673038711653</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Theme: “Life is War”: Social Militarization and the Culture of Prayers in Africa</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12671589/theme-%E2%80%9Clife-war%E2%80%9D-social-militarization-and-culture-prayers</link>
						<dc:creator>Abimbola Adelakun</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-07-24T00:00:00-04:00">July 24, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>African History / Studies, Cultural History / Studies, Humanities, Religious Studies and Theology, Theatre &amp; Performance History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Theme: “Life is War”: Social Militarization and the Culture of Prayers in Africa</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Prayers are a ritual common to all religions, but the intensity of their performance and social application differ from one religion to another. One resonant factor in the rituals of prayer offered in contemporary Africa is how the context of physical insecurity, social instability, and economic precarity have penetrated through and shaped its content and rites. Our responses to the challenges of underdevelopment and weakness of state political apparatuses through the instrumentality of prayer have configured daily life around militarization. Despite the pervasiveness of prayer as a form of warfare against extant reality, this spectacular practice that reverberates through the cultural landscape in Africa and beyond has not received enough scholarly attention. Militarized prayers, aimed at cosmic forces perceived to be militating against social progress, are initiatives toward addressing existential realities. They demonstrate African cosmological insights into the mechanisms of world-ordering and agency of those who want to re-order it. Warfare prayers are thus worth understanding on these terms. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>This conference calls for papers that engage the sort of world Africans build when they employ prayers as a form of warfare. How do these forms of prayers re-order personal, social, and political life? What cultural understanding of the nature of reality drives these prayers? How do these prayers integrate the physical and psychic with the political? What is the nexus between prayer performance, pleasures, and political practices?  This interdisciplinary conference welcomes presentations that engage these questions and many more from scholars, theologians, postgraduate students, and members of faith communities. This study is not limited to any religious traditions. We welcome presentations from across a broad spectrum of faith practices. Please send in abstracts/proposals of not more than 250 words and proposals via email: </span></span></span><a href="mailto:violentprayersconference@gmail.com"><span><span><span>violentprayersconference@gmail.com</span></span></span></a><u><span><span><span>.</span></span></span></u></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Papers are expected from these subthemes but are not limited to:</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ol><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Typologies of prayer practices within and across religious spectrum</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Theoretical conceptions of prayers and social militarization</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Comparative religious perspectives on prayer and social militarization</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Historical study of prayer and social militarization</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Methodological approaches to prayer and social militarization</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Ethical issues in warfare prayer </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Popular culture, prayer, and prayer warfare</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Spaces, places, and prayer as warfare</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Politics, democracy, and notions of power in prayer </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Urban culture and prayer warfare </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Language and poetics of prayer warfare</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Language, literature and creativity in prayer warfare</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Gender issues in prayer warfare</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Technology, medium, and warfare prayers</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Warfare prayers and shaping of social imaginary</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Performance, sacred objects, and rituals of warfare prayers </span></span></span></span></span></span></li></ol><p> </p><p> </p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Date: 24</span><span>th </span><span>– 27</span><span>th </span><span>July, 2023 (Arrival: 24</span><span>th </span><span>July and Opening Ceremony: 25</span><span>th </span><span>July, 2023). </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Venue: The Redeemed Christian Bible College, Redemption Camp, Mowe, Ogun State. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Conference fee: N15,000 (scholars), N5,000 (PG students) and $60 (non-Nigerians) </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Note: This conference has a virtual component for international participants</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span> </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p> </p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:benson.igboin@aaua.edu.ng">benson.igboin@aaua.edu.ng</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 19:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680673038711652</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Esoteric Theology of Philip K. Dick</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/04/03/the-esoteric-theology-of-philip-k-dick</link>
						<dc:creator>mbarros</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, April 4, 2023 - 11:49am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>George Sieg &amp; Michael Barros</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:pkdandtheology@gmail.com">pkdandtheology@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/fan-studies-and-fandom">fan studies and fandom</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/general-announcements">general announcements</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>May 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>Call for Abstracts:</strong> <em>The Esoteric Theology of Philip K. Dick</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Editors:</strong> Dr. George Sieg &amp; Michael Barros</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Philip K. Dick was one of the most influential science fiction authors of the 20th century, and he remains the most adapted.His work has exemplified qualities and features that have become increasingly significant within the science fiction genre, anticipating its exploration of artificial intelligence, alternate and parallel realities, and the problems of identity.  Dick’s work is most popularly known through its adaptation to films such as <em>Blade Runner, Total Recall, A Scanner Darkly, The Adjustment Bureau, </em>and <em>Paycheck</em>, as well as Amazon’s streaming adaptation of <em>The Man in the High Castle</em>, followed by its recent anthology homage to Dick, <em>Philip K. Dick’s Electric Dreams</em>.   His work is pervaded by the uncanny intersection of derealization with the hyper-real, with protagonists and readers embarking on a journey of uncertainty together.</p>
<p>Later in his life, Dick retrospectively viewed his work as expressing spiritual truths. He believed in unconventional concepts like “retrograde time,” he communed with and channeled a deceased Episcopalian Bishop, and he was immensely interested in both the Essenes and the Gnostics. In February and March of 1974, he had his most important spiritual experiences, launched by his encounter with a a delivery girl with an ichthysnecklace. </p>
<p>With a goal of publication on the 50th anniversary of those formative experiences, the editors invite submissions exploring theological, religious, and esoteric themes within the work and life of Philip K. Dick. Some possible topics are (and are certainly not limited to):</p>
<ul>
<li>The relationship between Dick's gnostic vision and his portrayal of religion and spirituality in his works.</li>
<li>The postmodern themes and motifs in Dick's writing and how they relate to his theological perspective.</li>
<li>The ways in which Dick's works engage with questions of epistemology and uncertainty and how this relates to larger theological and philosophical themes.</li>
<li>Dick's use of dystopian and apocalyptic imagery and how this relates to his understanding of human nature and the divine.</li>
<li>The relationship between science fiction and theology in Dick's writing and how he uses the genre to explore religious and spiritual themes.</li>
<li>The role of technology in Dick's works and how it relates to his larger theological and philosophical vision.</li>
<li>The relationship between ethics and theology in Dick's writing and how he uses his works to explore questions of morality and the divine.</li>
<li>The reception of Dick's works within the context of contemporary theology and religious studies and the ways in which his works continue to shape theological and philosophical discourse today.</li>
<li>The impact of Dick’s theology on the sci-fi genre.</li>
<li>Dick’s engagement with the Dead Sea Scrolls.</li>
<li>Dick’s eschatology.</li>
<li>Dick’s Apocalyptic Dualism.</li>
<li>The role of conspiracism in Dick’s work: secularized theology &amp; demonology</li>
<li>Mysticism in Dick’s work.</li>
<li>Augustine &amp; Dick on the concept of time.</li>
</ul>
<p>Interested authors should send chapter abstracts of 300-700 words and a CV to <a href="mailto:pkdandtheology@gmail.com">pkdandtheology@gmail.com</a>.</p>
<p>The call for chapters ends May 15, 2023. Authors will be notified of accepted proposals after June 1st, 2023, with the first drafts of chapters (6,000-8,000 words) being due by November 1st, 2023. Final manuscript is to be delivered to the publisher in January 2024.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 04:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680673038711651</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Saints and Mystics in Legend and Tradition</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/03/26/saints-and-mystics-in-legend-and-tradition</link>
						<dc:creator>Jeremy Harte</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, April 4, 2023 - 10:25am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Folklore Society</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:jrmharte@gmail.com">jrmharte@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/medieval">medieval</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/popular-culture">popular culture</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>August 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Where is the spring that rose where St. Alban’s blood fell? Who cares for Cuddy Ducks? Can we see Enoch and Elijah? When the Virgin fell in labour, was Romani St. Sarah at her side? How did St. Sebastian become a gay icon? Who were the Twin Saints, the Three Pure Ones, the Four Friends and the Five Major Prophets? What goes into a Dumb Cake for St. Agnes’ Eve? Does a wet St. Swithun’s day really foretell forty days of rain? Do girls still appeal to St. Andrew of the fishermen for a good catch in marriage? Can we still hear Old Clem at the hammer and the thunders of St. Barbara? Whether you weave a cross of reeds for Lá Féile Bríde, wear a daff for Dewi Sant, or bear a rose for St. George, come and join our day or we may have to call on St. Jude, patron saint of lost causes.</p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p>A two-day conference on Saints and Mystics in Legend and Tradition will be held on Saturday 2nd (St. Justus of Lyons) and Sunday 3rd (St. Gregory the Great) September 2023 at the Chapter House, St. Albans Cathedral. Anyone can join us – scholars, storytellers, hermits and hagiographers. We invite proposals about any saint, mystic, martyr or prophet. Presentations, which should be 20 minutes long, can take the form of talks, performances, or film. For more information, see <a href="https://folklore-society.com/events">https://folklore-society.com/events</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The conference fee is £35 for speakers, £70 for others attending. If you would like to attend or to present a paper or performance, please contact, by 1st July: Jeremy Harte, Bourne Hall, Spring Street, Ewell, Surrey KT17 1UF. Telephone: 020 8394 1734. Email: <a href="mailto:jrmharte@gmail.com">jrmharte@gmail.com</a></p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 17:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680673038711650</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Australia-India Encounters: Past, Present, Future</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/03/25/australia-india-encounters-past-present-future</link>
						<dc:creator>tanmoy.kundu@midnaporecollege.ac.in</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, April 4, 2023 - 10:26am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>The Centre for Australian Studies, Department of English and Culture Studies,  The University of Burdwan in collaboration with Australian Studies Institute, Australian National University, Canberra</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:cas.buruniv@gmail.com">cas.buruniv@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/ecocriticism-and-environmental-studies">ecocriticism and environmental studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/ethnicity-and-national-identity">ethnicity and national identity</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/international-conferences">international conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/world-literatures-and-indigenous-studies">world literatures and indigenous studies</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>April 20, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p align="center"><strong>Australia-India Encounters: Past, Present, Future</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>3-4 May, 2023</strong></p>
<p align="center"> </p>
<p align="center">Organised by</p>
<p align="center">The Centre for Australian Studies, Department of English and Culture Studies,</p>
<p align="center">The University of Burdwan</p>
<p align="center">in collaboration with</p>
<p align="center">Australian Studies Institute, Australian National University, Canberra</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The history of Australia-India encounters dates back to the first half of the nineteenth century. Even before the 1840s, the presence of the Indians (mainly servants to British families who were given land grants in colonies) in Australia has been traced. Many Indians, later, went to Australia as indentured labourers to work in sugar plantations and on farms. Some of them were ‘hawkers,’ small traders who travelled through different towns of Australia. The nineteenth century also saw a gradual increase in the number of Indian travellers to Australia (such as, Fazulbhoy Vikram, N.L. Doss and T. N. Mukharji), many of whom even documented their encounters with Australian polity, society and culture by writing journals and travelogues.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Australia-India encounters started taking new forms in the 1970s as Australia adopted multicultural policies rejecting ‘The White Australia Policy.’ This resulted in a steady flow of the Indian migrants to Australia fostering new cross-cultural exchanges between the two countries. In Australia, the Government organized events like Utsav Australia or Indian Art Exhibitions (Museum Victoria), while in Kolkata Book Fair, Australia has been projected several times either as “Guest of Honour Country” or the “Focus Country” (2007).</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Australian Government’s intention to establish international links has also contributed significantly to develop and re-shape its politico-economic-cultural relationships with India. India’s shift from its ‘Look East’ policy to ‘Act East’ policy has similarly strengthened India’s relationship with Australia in matters relating to international strategic planning, security, commerce and culture. In fact, India’s ‘Act East Policy’ is in tune with its growing interest in the Asia Pacific region and its ideological position of considering Australia as a part of larger Asia. In the post-pandemic era, both the countries are working towards transforming the Asia Pacific as a politically important region of independent and sovereign states.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>This international conference welcomes scholars from across disciplines to consider upon the past, present and the future of Australia-India encounters to identify new discursive strategies to facilitate a better understanding of each other in terms of history, politics and culture.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The conference will address, but not strictly limit itself to, the following issues:</p>
<p> </p>
<ul>
<li>Re-writing History</li>
<li>Race and Identity</li>
<li>Federalism</li>
<li>Terrorism and Conflict Resolution</li>
<li>International Relations</li>
<li>Economic Paradigms in Bilateral Relations</li>
<li>Linkages of Sports and Culture</li>
<li>Tourism and Cultural Exchange</li>
<li>Colonial/Postcolonial/ Contemporary Writings</li>
<li>Literature and Socio-cultural Activism</li>
<li>Indigenous Australian Literature</li>
<li>Literature and Films</li>
<li>Climate Change and Climate Fiction</li>
<li>Indian Diasporic Literature of Australia</li>
<li>Environment and Security</li>
<li>Judicial Activism </li>
<li>Australian Studies: Research and Methodology</li>
<li>Teaching Australia in India</li>
<li>Teaching India in Australia</li>
</ul>
<p> Abstracts (not exceeding 300 words) may be emailed to <a href="mailto:cas.buruniv@gmail.com">cas.buruniv@gmail.com</a></p>
<p> Registration Fees:    2000 INR (National)</p>
<p>                               150 AUD (International)</p>
<p>Online presentation facility will be available only for the international participants. Though it may not be possible to arrange accommodation, the conference team may provide assistance to the national participants, if contacted beforehand.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 16:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680673038711649</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ May 15, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Merleau-Ponty and Embodiment: Between the Cognitive, Aesthetic, and Socio-Political</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/109901</link>
						<description><p><strong>Merleau-Ponty and Embodiment: Between the Cognitive, Aesthetic, and Socio-Political</strong></p>
<p>47th Annual Meeting of the International Merleau-Ponty Circle</p>
<p>In-person and virtual (hybrid)</p>
<p>4-6 December 2023</p>
<p>Deakin University, Melbourne (Narrm), Australia </p>
<p><em>“Le corps est notre moyen général d’avoir un monde</em>. / <em>The body is our general means of having a world.”</em></p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p>Merleau-Ponty's seminal work on embodiment has been of enduring interest and influence in a wide range of fields. It has, for example, played a significant role in research on embodied cognition and enactivism, subjectivity and intersubjectivity, affectivity, movement, art, place, and more. Although sometimes criticised for providing an account of embodiment that is too general, Merleau-Ponty’s philosophical foregrounding of embodiment has also facilitated critical phenomenological studies attending to the specificities of how particular bodies inhabit social and political environments, through considerations of race, gender, disability, ageing, and illness. This year’s meeting of the IMPC seeks to bring together these rich and varied strands of enquiry, in order to think with, against, and beyond Merleau-Ponty’s own contributions on the lived body. </p>
<p>Only its third time outside North America, this year’s meeting will take place in Melbourne (Narrm), Australia, on the traditional and unceded lands of the Kulin Nation. The conference is being directed by Helen Ngo and Jack Reynolds, with support from Andrew Inkpin and others. Keynote and plenary speakers will be announced shortly. The conference will be held at the centrally located and accessible Deakin Downtown campus, and recommended accommodation options will be provided nearer the date. </p>
<p><strong>Full paper submissions</strong> of no more than 3,500 words should be prepared for anonymous review and sent to <em>both</em> the directors at helen.ngo@deakin.edu.au and jack.reynolds@deakin.edu.au with the subject heading "IMPC submission" <strong>by May 15, 2023</strong>. As is custom, submissions on any aspect of Merleau-Ponty’s work, in addition to the conference theme, are also welcome.</p>
<p>This year’s event will include a thematic stream on <em>Race, place, and bodies</em> curated by Helen Ngo for a research project funded by the Australian Research Council (DE220100329). A small number of bursaries will be available for students and unwaged early career researchers presenting in-person in this stream. Participants wishing to be considered for this are asked to indicate so on the cover letter of your submission. </p>
<p>The conference features the M. C. Dillon prize and lecture for the best graduate student paper submission (https://www.merleauponty.org/m-c-dillon-memorial/). To be considered for this prize, please indicate so on the cover letter of your submission. This year’s conference will also inaugurate a second graduate student prize, the Morstyn prize, which recognises our late colleague, from Sydney, Australia, Ron Morstyn, who contributed to and attended the IMPC over many years, with special interests in psychology and psychiatry. Details for consideration for this prize will be announced between now and the submission deadline.  </p>
<p>Finally, as this conference will be held as a hybrid event, please indicate whether, upon acceptance, you plan to attend in-person or virtually. In order to host the conference at a physical location, a certain percentage of talks will need to be presented in person, and this will be factored in during the anonymous review process. If you plan to attend virtually because doing so physically presents insurmountable accessibility issues (of whatever sort, including economic ones), you are welcome (but not required) to include that information. You are also welcome to include any anticipated accessibility needs, which will greatly assist in planning.</p>
<p>Helen Ngo and Jack Reynolds, on behalf of International Merleau-Ponty Circle.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 05:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680586628555805</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ December 4, 2023 -  December 6, 2023] Conference or similar: Merleau-Ponty and Embodiment: Between the Cognitive, Aesthetic, and Socio-Political</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/109897</link>
						<description>Venue: Deakin Downtown<br/><br/><p>47TH ANNUAL CONFERENCE OF THE INTERNATIONAL MERLEAU-PONTY CIRCLE</p>
<p>Dec 4th – Dec 6th 2023 | Deakin University, Melbourne (Narrm), Australia | In-person and virtual (hybrid)</p>
<p><em>“Le corps est notre moyen général d’avoir un monde</em>. / <em>The body is our general means of having a world.”</em></p>
<p>Merleau-Ponty’s seminal work on embodiment has been of enduring interest and influence in a wide range of fields. It has, for example, played a significant role in research on embodied cognition and enactivism, subjectivity and intersubjectivity, affectivity, movement, art, place, and more. Although sometimes criticized for providing an account of embodiment that is too general, Merleau-Ponty’s philosophical foregrounding of embodiment has also facilitated critical phenomenological studies attending to the specificities of how particular bodies inhabit social and political environments, through considerations of race, gender, disability, ageing, and illness. This year’s meeting of the IMPC seeks to bring together these rich and varied strands of enquiry, in order to think with, against, and beyond Merleau-Ponty’s own contributions on the lived body.</p>
<p>Only its third time outside North America, this year’s meeting of IMPC will take place in Melbourne (Narrm), Australia, on the traditional and unceded lands of the Kulin Nation.</p>
<p>The conference is being directed by Helen Ngo and Jack Reynolds.</p>
<p>Keynote and plenary speakers will be announced shortly. The conference will be held at the centrally located and accessible Deakin Downtown campus, and recommended accommodation options will be provided nearer the date. Registration will be required; this page will be updated when registration deadlines have been set.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 05:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680586628555804</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
