<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 21:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 21:35:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Opportunities Digest – 24 August 2022</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-opportunities-digest-24-august-2022/</link>
						<dc:creator>Ella Bock</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! You will find one post-doctoral research position and three jobs.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 37!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Post-Doctoral Research Positions</h2>



<h4>Digital British Islam</h4>



<p>The University of Wales Trinity Saint David</p>



<p>Deadline: 1 September 2022</p>



<p>More information: <a href="https://jobs.uwtsd.ac.uk/JobDescription/ON287itY--o?&amp;mId=txVlKFaFAVc">https://jobs.uwtsd.ac.uk/JobDescription/ON287itY–o?&amp;mId=txVlKFaFAVc</a></p>



<h2>Jobs</h2>



<h4>Assistant Professor – Ancient Mediterranean Languages and Cultures</h4>



<p>Princeton University, US</p>



<p>Deadline: 14 October 2022</p>



<p>More information: <a href="https://classicalstudies.org/placement-service/2021%E2%80%932022/36766/assistant-professor">https://classicalstudies.org/placement-service/2021%E2%80%932022/36766/assistant-professor</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor, Arabic and Islamic Studies</h4>



<p>Cornell University, US</p>



<p>Deadline: 15 October 2022</p>



<p>More information: <a href="https://academicjobsonline.org/ajo/jobs/22309?fbclid=IwAR2jPaRGOmSGdxWtkU89iZmaQb81GgVWmhOTkht9joBD4SxU87oubPFP8ho">https://academicjobsonline.org/ajo/jobs/22309?fbclid=IwAR2jPaRGOmSGdxWtkU89iZmaQb81GgVWmhOTkht9joBD4SxU87oubPFP8ho</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Religion in the United States</h4>



<p>Boston University, US</p>



<p>Deadline: 14 October 2022</p>



<p>More information: <a href="https://academicjobsonline.org/ajo/jobs/22376">https://academicjobsonline.org/ajo/jobs/22376</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1661405826352332</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>James Baldwin: then and now</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/08/18/james-baldwin-then-and-now</link>
						<dc:creator>ppowers@messiah.edu</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, August 23, 2022 - 2:43pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Peter Kerry Powers/ Christianity &amp; Literature</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ppowers@messiah.edu">ppowers@messiah.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/african-american">african-american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/ethnicity-and-national-identity">ethnicity and national identity</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/gender-studies-and-sexuality">gender studies and sexuality</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>April 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p> James Baldwin’s presence in American culture and political history follows a trajectory that is perhaps unique in American letters, being the signature literary voice for two very different cultural moments: the Civil Rights movement of the 1950s and 60s and then—after a period of relative quiet—being taken up again six decades later as a prophetic precursor and guiding spirit for the larger Black Lives Matter movement.  Baldwin’s continuing relevance for our discourse and disputation about race, nationhood, masculinity and sexuality is now all but taken for granted.  His voice helps us navigate the thicket of cultural politics as we seek a world that is more just and more free than the one in which we live. </p>
<p>Baldwin’s work was never far from the language, thought, and practices of Black Christianity.  If, as some have said, Baldwin left the church, it is also true that the church never left Baldwin: its conceptions of love, truth-telling, confession, and mercy are never far from his epistemologies. Even Baldwin’s argument with Christianity is carried out through the identifiable rhythms, cadences, and rhetoric of what Josef Sorett calls “Afro-Protestantism.” Ultimately, Baldwin’s insistence on social justice and liberation is informed by a radical critique of structures of oppression and the workings of power, coupled with images of redemption such as “the welcome table.” As a religiously informed thinker and writer, Baldwin decries the violence of humanity while celebrating the sacredness of our human agency, bodies, and desires.</p>
<p>This special issue of <em>Christianity &amp; Literature</em> calls for submissions that examine Baldwin’s life and work in light of his lifelong engagement (and argument) with the principles and practices of the Christianity he inherited. Essays that take up any of the following issues are encouraged:  </p>
<p> </p>
<ul>
<li>Baldwin and Christianity now—esp. changes in Baldwin’s reputation over the past few decades</li>
<li>Baldwin as cultural icon: figure and symbol </li>
<li>Baldwin as public intellectual, activist, social historian, and cultural theorist</li>
<li>Genre criticism—Baldwin as essayist, novelist, playwright, etc.</li>
<li>Baldwin and antecedents—inquiry and imagination re: Black literary and theological traditions</li>
<li>Baldwin, sexuality (desires, acts, practices; histories, activism), constructions of gender, and religious experience or sacred traditions</li>
<li>Baldwin, Christian faith, and political action or accommodation </li>
<li>Baldwin, Christianity, and African American secularism or atheism</li>
<li>Baldwin, Critical Race Theory and the social construction of race</li>
<li>Baldwin and past and present political conflicts over teaching American history (e.g., The 1619 Project, chattel slavery, national identity)</li>
<li><em>I Am Not Your Negro</em> (2016 film, dir. Raoul Peck) </li>
<li>Any other issue re: Baldwin and Christianity</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Deadline: </strong> Abstract (300-500 words) due to Peter Powers (<a href="mailto:ppowers@messiah.edu">ppowers@messiah.edu</a>) by April 1, 2023.  Drafts of accepted essays (6000-9000 words) will be due August 1, 2023. All essays should be formatted according to the Chicago Manual of Style, 17th edition. </p>
<p> <strong>Inquiries: </strong> Direct inquiries about the issue to either Peter Powers (<a href="mailto:ppowers@messiah.edu">ppowers@messiah.edu</a>) or Jennifer McFarlane-Harris (<a href="mailto:mcfarlanehaj@spu.edu">mcfarlanehaj@spu.edu</a>).</p>
<p> <strong>Journal Editorial Statement</strong>: <em>Christianity &amp; Literature</em> is a scholarly journal devoted to the exploration of how literature engages Christian thought, experience, and practice. The journal presupposes no particular theological orientation but respects an orthodox understanding of Christianity as a historically defined religious faith. Contributions appropriate for submission should demonstrate a keen awareness of the author's own critical assumptions in addressing significant issues of literary history, interpretation, and theory. <em>Christianity &amp; Literature</em> is the official publication of the Conference on Christianity &amp; Literature (CCL).</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 17:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1661405826352331</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ September 22, 2022] CFP for conference or similar: South African Society for Critical Theory 4th Annual Conference</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/102418</link>
						<description><p><strong>South African Society for Critical Theory 4th Annual Conference</strong></p>
<p>17 – 19 November 2022</p>
<p>North-West University South Africa</p>
<p>https://www.facebook.com/groups/2185466648172350/</p>

<p><u><strong>Culture Industry 2.0: </strong><strong>Africa, Global South, World</strong></u><strong><br/><br/></strong></p>
<p> &gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;</p>

<p><em>The South African Society for Critical Theory is pleased to announce the keynote speakers for its forthcoming conference...</em><em></em></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;</p>

<p><strong>Keynote Speaker: Prof Samir Gandesha (Simon Fraser University)</strong><strong></strong></p>

<p>Associate Professor in the Department of the Humanities and the Director of the Institute for the Humanities at Simon Fraser University, specializing in modern European thought and culture with a particular emphasis on the 19th and 20th centuries. He is co-editor with Lars Rensmann of <em>Arendt and Adorno: Political and Philosophical Investigations</em> (Stanford, 2012), and with Johan Hartle of <em>Spell of Capital: Reification and Spectacle</em> (University of Amsterdam Press, 2017) and <em>Aesthetic Marx</em> (Bloomsbury Press, 2017). In the Spring of 2017, he was the Liu Boming Visiting Scholar in Philosophy at the University of Nanjing and Visiting Lecturer at Suzhou University of Science and Technology in China. He also taught a course on the “Neo-Liberal Personality” in the Summer Semester at the University of Sao Paulo in Brazil in February, 2019 and is a regular contributor to <em>openDemocrac</em>y.</p>

<p> &gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;</p>

<p><strong>Next Gen Keynote Speaker: Kiasha Naidoo (University of the Western Cape)</strong><strong></strong></p>

<p><em>The Next Generation Keynote is intended as a means of supporting and developing future SA thought-leaders by offering early career academics the opportunity to deliver a keynote address.</em></p>

<p>Kiasha’s research concerns thinking neoliberalism as a governing rationality in the domain of means and ends. Moreover, to consider the way that such a rationality might bear on the human subject in terms of its ontology as fundamentally futural. She draws on the work of Michel Foucault and Wendy Brown in order to consider the functioning, limits, and high points of the exercise of power on subjects and collectivities with regard to life and death. Her research interest includes the effects of a neoliberal governmentality on our democratic ideals, notions of political collectivity, as well as on virtues and ends such as freedom, equality, and justice.</p>

<p>&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;</p>

<p>The South African Society for Critical Theory (SASCT) invites abstract submissions of up to 500 words for its 4th Annual Conference which will take place at the Potchefstroom Campus of the North-West University, from the 17th to the 19th of November 2022. This will be a hybrid conference, with in-person attendance recommended but with accommodation made for online participation and presentations.</p>

<p>SASCT invites papers which address the concept of the culture industry, as described by Adorno and Horkheimer in <em>Dialectic of Enlightenment. </em>The culture industry sees forms of culture become part of the capitalist system of production which in the contemporary age has seen commodification spread from "culture" to all non-work activities of humanity - hobbies, sports, self-improvement, mental health, tourism, and so on. Of particular interest in this regard is the examination of the perils and potentialities of the imminent total colonisation of the life world, strategies of resistance, points of breakdown, as well as cultural and natural heritage as a public good or commodity – all questions that Critical Theory is geared to address.</p>

<p>As part of such considerations, this conference welcomes papers that consider the question of the culture industry in relation to Critical Theory, including but not limited to:</p>

<p>·         What might a critical analysis of the contemporary culture industry reveal?</p>
<p>·         What stance should Critical Theory adopt towards the culture industry in both its modern figurations, but also historically?</p>
<p>·         How does the culture industry figure into contemporary education?</p>
<p>·         Has the coronavirus outbreak affected the contemporary culture industry, and in what ways does nature’s otherness influence the culture industry?</p>
<p>·         How does migration factor into the culture industry of the world today?</p>
<p>·         Is ‘cancel culture’ a reaction to, or expression of, the Culture Industry?</p>
<p>·         How is the culture industry functioning in relation to postcoloniality, and what does an "African Culture Industry" entail?</p>

<p>The conference welcomes approaches from all aspects of Critical Theory, broadly construed. In particular, the conference welcomes papers that address issues relating to: African Critical Theory, Digital Culture, the intersections between Critical Theory of European origin (Frankfurt School, Foucault, etc.), Black Existentialism, and Africana Critical Theory as well as contributions <strong>on any and all</strong> aspects of Critical Theory, e.g. the 3 generations of Frankfurt School Critical Theory, Postcolonial Theory, De-colonial Theory, Critical Feminism, Critical Film Studies, Critical Race Theory, Critical Theory of Technology, Critical Legal Studies, Post-structuralism, Psychoanalysis, Critical Hermeneutics, Liberation Theory, Critical Pedagogy, Critical Theology, Critical Anthropology, etc. </p>

<p>The Conference organisers would also appreciate papers that address thinkers whose work lies outside the “canon” of Critical Theory, but whose work can extend current research in Critical Theory or whose work in itself embodies alternative forms of Critical Theory. Whilst the organisers encourage contributions that address the conference theme, the theme itself should be viewed as merely suggestive.</p>

<p><strong><u> </u></strong></p>
<p><strong><u>Submission</u></strong></p>

<p>Please submit a 300-word abstract to sascrit@gmail.com by the 23rd of September 2022. Acceptance letters will be sent by the 30th of September at the latest. The full paper should be no more than 3500-4000 words for a 30 min. presentation. Proposals for panel discussion are also welcome.</p>


<p><strong><u>Accommodation</u></strong></p>

<p>In-person attendance at Sports Village in Potchefstroom, South Africa. Accommodation is available at the conference venue (Sports Village) – submit queries to sportsvillage@nwu.ac.za.</p>
<p>A list of alternative places to stay will also be provided.  </p>
<p>Arrangement will be made for online attendance by international participants.</p>


<p><strong><u>Conference fees</u></strong></p>

<p>The fee for the three-day conference (including teas and lunches) is R800 (including VAT).</p>
<p>The fee for participating graduate and PhD students is R150.</p>
<p>International speakers who are participating online must pay an online fee of R150.</p>
<p><strong><u> </u></strong></p>

<p><strong><u>Special issue</u></strong></p>

<p>Note also that a special issue on the theme of the conference will be published in<em> Acta Academica: critical views on society, culture and politics</em>, a DHET-accredited journal.</p>


<p><strong><u>Contact us</u></strong></p>

<p>Should you have queries regarding any aspect of the conference then please do not hesitate to contact the conference organising committee:</p>

<p>Jean du Toit: jean.dutoit@nwu.ac.za (host)</p>

<p>Gregory Swer: gregswer@gmail.com</p>


<p>Ewa Latecka: LateckaE@unizulu.ac.za</p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 05:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1661319429692198</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ November 17, 2022 -  November 19, 2022] Conference or similar: South African Society for Critical Theory 4th Annual Conference</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/102414</link>
						<description>Venue: NWU SPORTS VILLAGE, 36 Loop St, Noordbrug<br/><br/><p>The South African Society for Critical Theory (SASCT) 4th Annual Conference will take place at the Potchefstroom Campus of the North-West University, from the 17th to the 19th of November 2022. This will be a hybrid conference, with in-person attendance recommended but with accommodation made for online participation and presentations. This year's conference theme is: Culture Industry 2.0: Africa, Global South, World.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 05:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1661319429692197</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ January 27, 2023 -  January 28, 2023] Conference or similar: 1st Hegelian Society of Spirit Conference</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/102394</link>
						<description>Venue: Ltd 38/39 Fitzwilliam Square<br/><br/><p><strong>HEGEL AND HEGELIANISM TODAY</strong></p>
<p>In light of the resurgence of interest in the philosophy of G.W.F. Hegel, the question of what remains at the core of Hegel’s philosophy has become increasingly pertinent. Taking this into consideration, we are also wondering how we are supposed to evaluate the Hegelian philosophy that has succeeded the initial impact of Hegel’s philosophy. This is a timely and unavoidable concern that Hegel scholars must face, one which reassembles the philosophical scene after Hegel’s death with the split between left-Hegelians, right-Hegelian, and young Hegelians all of whom misconstrued Hegel in some element or another. And since the history of Hegel scholarship until today has amounted to a bad game of telephone, we are wondering what makes contemporary Hegel scholarship and Hegelian philosophy different from this trend, if at all?</p>
<p>This conference seeks to explore two major concerns then: (1) when we look at Hegel’s work, what are we drawing from it as the core to his systematization of philosophy and how does it concern us today? And (2) in light of the proliferation of works on Hegel, how are we evaluating the value of these works as well as their relevance to Hegel’s philosophy? Therefore, this conference welcomes papers that focus on Hegel’s main texts the Phenomenology of Spirit and the Science of Logic, as well as other works by Hegel such as his early theological writings, The Philosophy of Right, the Encyclopedia of Philosophy, and others. We also welcome texts that enter into conversations with the interactions of Marxism and psychoanalysis with Hegel’s philosophy, as well as papers that address the work of authors such as Slavoj Zizek, Alenka Zupancic, Mladen Dolar, Alain Badiou, Adrian Johnston, Todd McGowan, Rebecca Comay, Frank Ruda, Susan Buck-Morss, Robert Brandom, Robert Pippin, Rocio Zambrano, and other contemporary Hegel scholars and commentators.</p>
<p><strong>Topics Suggested</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Is it possible to be a Hegelian today?</li>
<li>Is Hegel dead? Or are we dead in the eyes of Hegel?</li>
<li>What is the relationship between the Phenomenology of Spirit and the Science of Logic?</li>
<li>What is a beginning in Hegel’s philosophy?</li>
<li>What is the end of Hegel’s philosophy?</li>
<li>What has changed in contemporary Hegelian scholarship from 20th century Hegelianism?</li>
<li>What is a Hegelian politics? And does Hegel genuinely offer an emancipatory project?</li>
<li>What is a Hegelian ethics? And how does it differ from other ethical orientations?</li>
<li>What is the role of religion in Hegel’s work from his early work to his more mature work starting with the Phenomenology of Spirit?</li>
<li>What is the Absolute for Hegel? And what is so radical about the Hegelian Absolute?</li>
<li>What kind of Hegelian responses can be given to contemporary neo-Kantianisms?</li>
<li>What kinds of correctives are needed in understanding the relationship between Hegel and Marx?</li>
<li>What is the relationship between Hegelianism and Marxism?</li>
<li>What is Hegel’s relationship to psychoanalysis?</li>
<li>What is the relationship between Hegel and Freud?</li>
<li>What is the relationship between Hegel and Lacan?</li>
<li>What kind of Hegelian responses can be given to contemporary accelerationisms?</li>
<li>What kind of Hegelian responses can be given to speculative realism?</li>
<li>Did the Zizekian rereading of Hegel through Lacan truly reclaim Hegel after his disavowal throughout the 19th, 20th, and 21st centuries?</li>
<li>What is the impact of Reza Negarestani’s Intelligence and Spirit to Hegelian philosophy? Do its Pittsburgh Hegelian roots aid its project or ultimately hinder it?</li>
<li>With the development of new North American Hegelianisms in the work of Adrian Johnston, Rebecca Comay, and Todd McGowan, what do they captivate or fail to understand about Hegelian philosophy?</li>
<li>What is the impact of Pittsburgh Analytic Hegelianism (Sellars, McDowell, Pippin, Brandom)? And does it captivate or miss the heart of Hegel’s philosophy?</li>
<li>What is the impact of Slovene Lacanian Hegelianism (Zizek, Zupancic, Dolar)? And does it captivate or miss the heart of Hegel’s philosophy?</li>
<li>What are we to make out of the major differences between contemporary Hegelian schools? (For example, the Pittsburgh School and the Slovene School)</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Conference Dates:</strong> January 27 and 28 2023</p>
<p><strong>Keynote Speaker:</strong> Todd McGowan </p>
<p><strong>Conference Guidelines</strong></p>
<p>Please email an abstract in pdf or word format of between 500-800 words and it should include a bibliography simone.polo@gcas.ie</p>
<p>If the author is interested in the publication of their paper, we will ask for a final copy of the paper sent to simone.polo@gcas.is by January 1, 2023 in accordance with the Chicago Manual of Style. </p>
<p>Papers should be suitable for a 20-30 minute presentation. In the body of the email include: 1) Your name, 2) Title of the paper, 3) Institutional affiliation, role (if applicable) and 4) Contact information (email, phone number, mailing address). The organisers are eager to assemble a demographically diverse programme. To aid in this endeavour, if you are a member of an underrepresented group and wish to identify yourself as such, please include this information in your email. Please send documents in word format or pdf with no identifying information for blind review. </p>
<p><strong>SUBMISSION DEADLINE:</strong> November 1, 2022</p>
<p>This is an online conference that will be taking place on Zoom. There will be recordings of the conference sessions that will be shared via the Society’s YouTube channel for public viewing and sharing.</p>
<p><strong>Publication</strong></p>
<p>Select papers for the conference will be included in an online publication. This selection will be made by the organising body of the conference who will edit the compiled publication. The organising body will invite authors for the publication and proceed with the author’s approval. This is a non-exclusive publication as we encourage authors’ philosophical development in whatever form that may take. Papers for publication should be 5000-7000 words, however, this is not a strict guideline as papers will be taken up by their merits.</p>
<p><strong>Organising Body:</strong></p>
<p>Simone A. Medina Polo</p>
<p>(Global Center for Advanced Studies)</p>
<p>simone.polo@gcas.ie</p>
<p>Lucas Potts</p>
<p>(University of Alberta)</p>
<p>ldpotts@ualberta.ca</p>
<p>Julian Rodka</p>
<p>(Independent Scholar)</p>
<p>jcrodtka@gmail.com</p>

<p>We extend our gratitude to the Global Center for Advanced Studies for their sponsorship support of this event by providing us with licensed Zoom accounts to run the conference. The GCAS college is a significant part of para-academic and academic studies furthering the interests of philosophy and psychoanalysis globally while offering degrees and certificates on some of the most cutting-edge contemporary work. We are simply excited to partner with them. We want to express a deep thank you to Creston Davis, Francisco Gonzales, and Alberto Pacheco Benites for their support of the conference.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 05:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1661233026041911</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ September 6, 2022] Conference or similar: Heidegger and the Greeks</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/102354</link>
						<description>Venue: 17-27 Young Street <br/><br/><p><strong>Workshop: “Heidegger and the Greeks” </strong></p>
<p>6 September, 9:30 am – 3:30 pm AEST</p>
<p>Hybrid format:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>In-person location: </strong>Australian Catholic University, Melbourne campus, Daniel Mannix Building, Level 7 (403.7.02), 17-29 Young Street Fitzroy.</li>
</ul>
<p>Light catering provided.</p>
<p>Please register by replying to: <a href="mailto:richard.colledge@acu.edu.au">richard.colledge@acu.edu.au</a></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Participation via Videolink:</strong> Those unable to attend in person are invited to join remotely.</li>
</ul>
<p>Register by replying to: <a href="mailto:richard.colledge@acu.edu.au">richard.colledge@acu.edu.au</a>.</p>
<p>The link will be sent prior to the day.     </p>
<p><strong>SCHEDULE:</strong></p>
<p>9.00-9.30 am     Coffee </p>
<p>9.30-10.30 (AEST) - Richard Capobianco (Stonehill College, MA).  “Heidegger on Heraclitus and the Later Thinking of Being”</p>
<p>10.45-11.45 (AEST) - Marilyn Stendera (Deakin).  “Order, Motion, Eternity: Heidegger on Ancient Greek Models of Time”</p>
<p>11.45-12.45 pm (AEST) - Andrew Benjamin (Monash).  “What and Where is Human Dasein: Heidegger and Heraclitus DK119”</p>
<p>1.30-2.30  (AEST) - Jeff Malpas (UTas).  “Heidegger and Char: Parmenides, Place and the Other Beginning”</p>
<p>2.30-3.30 (AEST) - Richard Colledge (ACU).  “Being as <em>archē</em> and <em>apeiron</em>: Heidegger’s Anaximander Retrieval”</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 05:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1661060229209212</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Romancing the Gothic Online Talk Series</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/08/15/romancing-the-gothic-online-talk-series</link>
						<dc:creator>hollyhirst84@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, August 18, 2022 - 2:04pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Romancing the Gothic</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:sam@romancingthegothic.com">sam@romancingthegothic.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/film-and-television">film and television</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/popular-culture">popular culture</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/world-literatures-and-indigenous-studies">world literatures and indigenous studies</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>October 31, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Romancing the Gothic offers free classes every week. The programme is online, open to all, and pays an honorarium to all our speakers. Talks are delivered twice (usually at 10am and 7pm British time those these times can change depending upon the time zone of the speaker) to include people from different time zones and recorded (with permission) to be placed on our YouTube channel. The talks (with Q and A session) should last between 1 and 1.5 hours.</p>
<p>Previous classes have gained hundreds (and some even thousands) of views and been used at universities around the world to supplement couses. Our classes are accessed by people from all over the world and are designed to make education accessible to all.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>We are looking for speakers for the year 2023. Recruitment is on a rolling basis. The end of the first recruitment period is 31/10/2022 but spaces are given on a 'first come, first served' basis. As months are filled, I will update the call for papers. </p>
<p> </p>
<p>To find out more about the project, including a list of previous talks, go to <a href="http://www.romancingthegothic.com/">www.romancingthegothic.com</a>. You can find lists of previous talks on the 'Online Classes' and 'Sunday Gothics' pages.</p>
<p>Each month has a different theme and you should indicate the month/s that you believe your talk to be relevant to. </p>
<p>January: Science fiction and horror/the Gothic</p>
<p>February: Witches (we particularly welcome papers on ‘witchcraft’ and magic traditions in non-European cultures)</p>
<p>March: Religion and the Gothic/horror. This month, each week will look at a different religion. Please note that we have already booked papers on Judaism and Christianity.</p>
<p>April: The supernatural and Horror in African fiction. We welcome papers from all different countries and traditions on literature, film and also folklore. (Please note: we welcome papers from all countries, cultures and continents all year round, not just in the month’s dedicated to them)</p>
<p>May: Eco horror, nature and the Gothic/horror. We welcome papers on all aspects of the natural world and horror/the Gothic. Themes could include ecohorror, cli-fi, caves, geology and the Gothic, Gothic landscapes, the sea…</p>
<p>June: Latin America and horror/the Gothic/the supernatural/magical realism</p>
<p>July: Horror film. This month we’re asking for each talk to be an overview of a genre or movement. Examples include, creature features, Giallo, J-horror, folk horror…</p>
<p>August: Northern Gothic. We welcome talks on all areas of Gothic literature, film, tv, music and tourism which fit with the definition of Northern Gothic.</p>
<p>September: Gothic, horror, the supernatural and dark speculative fiction from Oceania.</p>
<p>October: Crime. Any intersection of the Gothic or horror and crime you can think of! We also welcome history papers.</p>
<p>November: Gothic, horror and the supernatural in Asian literature, film and folklore.</p>
<p>Decemeber: Ghosts</p>
<p> </p>
<p>To do a talk with us, please submit an abstract or blurb for the talk of up to 250 words to <a href="mailto:sam@romancingthegothic.com">sam@romancingthegothic.com</a>. No biography or bibliography is required. We accept papers based on their strengths. If you haven’t written an abstract before, I run occasional abstract writing workshops. Please get in touch to ask about them. We welcome talks from people at all levels of academia and experts in the field. </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 19:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1660973823937125</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[Today - Tomorrow] Conference or similar: Rethinking Institutions: Heterodox and Critical Perspectives</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/102306</link>
						<description>Venue: Novi trg 2<br/><br/><p>WIth the workshop we aim to address the following questions:</p>
<p>Can <em>critical theory</em>, by utilizing its vast underlying philosophical currents of German Idealism, Marx and materialist thought, Freud and contemporary psychoanalysis, provide a meta-theoretical discourse in determining the conceptual maturation of the notion Institution? How do institutions conceptually emerge, what are their historical and material conditions, what are their modes of presentation and representation, what are they in essence and what forms do they acquire, how are they reflected in subject’ consciousnesses, what is the relation between human agency and institutional frameworks etc.? Can we transcend the analytical framework of rules, behaviour and coordination, by historically and ideologically deconstructing institutional structures and frameworks of contemporary societies?</p>
<p>Programme:</p>
<p><strong>Thursday 25th August</strong> – Mala dvorana</p>
<p><em><u>Introduction</u></em><u> (9.30)</u></p>
<p><em><u>Session 1 </u></em><u>(10.00 – 11.30)<em> – Philosophy and Institutions</em></u></p>
<p><em>Oliver Feltham</em> (American University of Paris)</p>
<p>Institution or Organization? A Humean reply to Nunes</p>
<p><em>Uroš Kranjc </em>(University of York)</p>
<p>Can Institutions be Thought as Multiplicities – Marx, Veblen, Badiou</p>
<p><strong>Coffee Break</strong></p>
<p><em><u>Session 2 </u></em><u>(12.00 – 14.00)<em> – Sociological and Political Roots of Contemporary Institutions  </em></u></p>
<p><em>Rudi Rizman </em>(University of Ljubljana &amp; University of Bologna) (via ZOOM)</p>
<p>What is Left of Institutional Regulation and Democracy in the Time of Neoliberal Hegemony?</p>
<p><em>Tomaž Mastnak</em> (ZRC SAZU)</p>
<p>Is Economic Power an Institution? The Limits of August Ludwig von Rochau's Redefinition of Liberal Politics</p>
<p><em>Peter J. Verovšek</em> (University of Sheffield)</p>
<p>A Critical Theory of Political Institutions: Charting the Frankfurt School's Shift from Social to Political Categories</p>

<p><strong>Friday 26th August</strong> – Mala dvorana</p>
<p><em><u>Session 3 </u></em><u>(9.00 – 12.00)<em> – Psychoanalysis and Institutions</em></u></p>
<p><em>Cindy Zeiher </em>(University of Canterbury) (via ZOOM)</p>
<p>Psychoanalysis’ Slip of the Discourse</p>
<p><em>Mike Grimshaw </em>(University of Canterbury) (via ZOOM)</p>
<p>Radical Theology and the ‘Weakening’ of Bourgeois Institutions</p>
<p><em>Jelica Šumič Riha</em> (ZRC SAZU)</p>
<p>Sade or the Institution of the Right to Enjoyment</p>
<p><em>Lorenzo Chiesa </em>(Newcastle University)</p>
<p>On Some Questions Prior to any Possible Treatment of Lacan’s Theory of Discourses as Political</p>
<p><strong>Coffee Break</strong></p>
<p><em><u>Session 4 </u></em><u>(13.00 – 15.00)<em> – Marx and the Institutional Dispositive</em></u></p>
<p><em>Carolina Alves</em> (University of Cambridge) (via ZOOM)</p>
<p>Provisional: Marx's Influence on Keynes Circle, Joan Robinson and Economic Institutions</p>
<p><em>Werner Bonefeld</em> (University of York)</p>
<p>On Real Abstraction: Wealth, Suffering and Negation</p>
<p><strong>Closing Remarks</strong></p>
<p><strong><br/></strong></p>
<p><strong>More on:<br/></strong></p></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 05:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1660887426850707</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Fantasy Goes to Hell: Depictions of Hell in Modern Fantasy Texts</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/08/17/fantasy-goes-to-hell-depictions-of-hell-in-modern-fantasy-texts</link>
						<dc:creator>mythlore@mythsoc.org</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, August 18, 2022 - 12:53pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>The Mythopoeic Society</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:mythlore@mythsoc.org">mythlore@mythsoc.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/fan-studies-and-fandom">fan studies and fandom</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/film-and-television">film and television</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/twentieth-century-and-beyond">twentieth century and beyond</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>November 15, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p align="center"> </p>
<p align="center"><strong>Call for Papers</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>Fantasy Goes to Hell: Depictions of Hell in </strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>Modern Fantasy Texts</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p align="center"><strong>A Mythcon Online Winter Seminar</strong> (28 January 2023)</p>
<p align="center">and <strong>Special Issue of <em>Mythlore</em></strong> (Fall/Winter 2023)</p>
<p align="center"><strong>Chairs/Editors:</strong> Janet Brennan Croft and Erin Giannini</p>
<p align="center"> </p>
<p align="center"><strong>Deadlines:</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>Proposals for the seminar:</strong> November 15, 2022</p>
<p align="center"><strong>Submissions for the special issue:</strong> May 15, 2023</p>
<p> </p>
<p align="center"><strong>Submit proposals to</strong></p>
<p align="center"><a href="mailto:janet.croft@uni.edu"><strong>janet.croft@uni.edu</strong></a><strong> AND </strong><a href="mailto:egiannini37@gmail.com"><strong>egiannini37@gmail.com</strong></a></p>
<p align="center"> </p>
<p align="center">Seminar registration is <strong>$20.00 USD</strong>. Register for the seminar at</p>
<p align="center"><a href="https://www.mythsoc.org/oms/oms-2023.htm#registration">https://www.mythsoc.org/oms/oms-2023.htm#registration</a></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Hell in modern fantasy</strong> is usually a far cry from traditional depictions in major world religions—the dry and dusty hells of ancient Mesopotamia and the Classical world, the ambiguous Hel of the Norse, the fiery pit and everlasting torment of medieval Christianity and Islam, the purgatorial hells of reincarnative religions like Buddhism and Hinduism.</p>
<p>How do creators of fantasy imagine Hell differently? And more importantly, why? What do these depictions have to tell us about what is hellish in our modern world?</p>
<p> </p>
<ul>
<li>The mystical spiritual descent: what can be gained from a descent to hell</li>
<li>The escape from hell: What is saved, and what is left behind</li>
<li>The harrowing of hell: the rescue of others from hell</li>
<li>The pact with hell: self-damnation or turning the tables</li>
<li>The intersection of race, racism, and hell</li>
<li>Hellish places: Mordor, Charn, the Upside Down, the post-apocalyptic world</li>
<li>The influence of fantastic ur-texts about Hell: Aeneas’s visit in <em>The Aeneid</em>; Dante’s <em>Inferno </em>(and Dorothy L. Sayers’s translation); Marlowe’s <em>Doctor Faustus</em>; Milton’s <em>Paradise Lost</em>; Jean-Paul Sartre’s <em>No Exit;</em> the art of Hieronymus Bosch; Mozart’s <em>Don Giovanni</em></li>
<li>“This IS the Bad Place!”: The primary world as Hell</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p>We’re interested in ANY form of media—text, graphic novels, television, movies, music and music videos, games—as long as it can be described as fantasy and includes a hell or its denizens.</p>
<p>Some texts to consider:</p>
<p> </p>
<ul>
<li>C.S. Lewis’s <em>The Screwtape Letters </em>and <em>The Great Divorce</em></li>
<li>Charles Williams’s <em>All Hallows’ Eve</em></li>
<li>Terry Pratchett and Neil Gaiman’s <em>Good Omens</em> (book and television series)</li>
<li>Lois McMaster Bujold’s Five Gods series</li>
<li>Music videos: Lil Nas X’s “Montero” and “Industry Baby”</li>
<li>Television series: <em>Buffy the Vampire Slayer,</em> <em>Angel, </em><em>Lovecraft Country</em>, <em>Supernatural, The Good Place, Stranger Things</em></li>
<li><em>Lucifer </em>(graphic novels and television series)</li>
<li>Movies: <em>Get Out, Dogma </em></li>
<li>Tanith Lee’s <em>Tales From the Flat Earth</em> series (<em>Death’s Master</em> et seq.)</li>
<li>Works by Vaclev Havel, Franz Kafka, Nikolai Gogol, George Orwell</li>
<li>Neil Gaiman’s <em>Sandman</em> (graphic novels and television series)</li>
<li>Walter Wangerin, Jr.’s <em>Dun Cow</em> trilogy</li>
<li>Evan Dahm’s <em>Harrowing of Hell </em>(graphic novel)</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p align="center">Proposals should be approximately 200 words in length and should be sent to both co-chairs.</p>
<p align="center">See you in January! –Erin and Janet</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 15:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1660887426850706</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
