<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 12:20:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 12:20:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>İSAR Symposium on Ethics in the Ottoman Period</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12872600/i%CC%87sar-symposium-ethics-ottoman-period</link>
						<dc:creator>Yasin  Seven</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-12-15T00:00:00-05:00">December 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Turkey</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Islamic History / Studies, Social Sciences, Religious Studies and Theology, Philosophy</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><strong>İSAR Ottoman Sciences Symposium Series IX</strong></p><p><strong>Ethics in the Ottoman Empire: Scholars, Works, and Problems</strong></p><p>In recent years, the Istanbul Center for Research and Education (ISAR) has organized a series of symposiums that deal with different branches of the Ottoman scientific tradition. The purpose of these symposiums is to redefine the place of the Ottoman tradition in both the overall scheme of the Islamic sciences and the history of thought in general, in order to contribute to the growing literature on these sciences within Ottoman society. In this context, eight symposiums have been organized so far, focusing on the disciplines of philosophical theology (<em>kalām</em>), jurisprudence (<em>fiqḥ</em>), sufism (<em>taṣawwuf</em>), quranic exegesis (<em>tafsīr</em>), prophetic traditions (<em>ḥadīth</em>), Arabic linguistic sciences (<em>al-ʿulūm al-ʿarabiyya</em>), logic and argumentation theory (<em>man</em><em>ṭ</em><em>iq</em> and <em>munāẓara</em>), and historiography. The output of each symposium has been published as an edited book. The ninth of these symposiums will be about ethics (<em>ʿilm al-akhlāq</em>) in the Ottoman period.</p><p>Ethics as a discipline in the history of Islamic thought, as in other civilizations, relates to the examination of the origin of our behavior which is subject to the predicates of good and bad, the criteria for good and bad, the faculties that occur in the human soul or mind and are accepted as virtue or vice, and virtues and vices that different classes of people need to obtain or refrain from. From the 13th century onward, the field of ethics transformed into a corpus which covers economics and politics, and has dealt with political, economic, and cultural relations beyond individual life. It has also been effective in the development of different perspectives and various understandings of the human being. Considering the long history of the basin of civilization established by Islam, it is clear that contemplation on ethics, which has various stages and forms of expression, is a suitable research area.</p><p>The Ottoman period is privy to a long and rich heritage in which the conceptual repertoire and discussions of the old heritage are kept alive thanks to copied works. On the other hand, intellectual production continued and solutions were offered to social and political problems through original texts, commentaries, and translations. Ottoman writings on ethics , which became evident in the 15th century, acquired its own original qualities in addition to encompassing the heritage of its predecessors. Led by such names as Cemaleddin Aksarayī, Ahmed al-Amāsī, Sinan Pasha, and Kāsım Karahisari,  the venture of Ottoman writings on ethics continued with such scholars as: Idris-i Bitlis, Taşköprülüzāde, Kınalızāde, Pir Muhammed, Celālzāde Mustafa Çelebi, Gelibolulu Āli, Muhyi-i Gülşenī, and Müneccimbaşı Ahmed Dede. It has reached modern times with the works of intellectual and artistic connoisseurs like Yağıkçızâde Mehmet Arif, Ali Seydi, and Ömer Ferit Kam.</p><p>Despite being a vast research area, the Ottoman period, which reflects the contemplation on ethics in Islam with all its richness and originality, has still not been the subject of sufficient examination. In this context, the symposium <em>Ethics in the Ottoman Period</em> will focus on the scholars who dealt with ethics, works on the subject, and problems of the period. The symposium aims to illuminate the works, sources, methods, tendencies, aims, and theories of individual scholars who dealt with ethics on one hand, and to illuminate the principles, various aspects, and stages of the contemplation on ethics in the Ottoman Empire on the other. A holistic evaluation of all these, together with both their theoretical extensions and their application areas throughout history, can only be possible with an interdisciplinary effort that encompasses such sciences as history, jurisprudence, literature, Sufism, theology, philosophy, and medicine.</p><p> </p><p><strong>While not limiting, the titles of the symposium include the following sample themes:</strong></p><p>The scope and main milestones of ethical thought in the Ottoman period</p><p>Possible classifications (chronological, regional, religious, ethnolinguistic, vocational, subject-based, etc.) for ethical texts and authors in the Ottoman period</p><p>Ottoman thinkers' expectancy from ethics and the way they posited this science</p><p>The place of ethics in the classification of sciences</p><p>The relationship of ethics with the other disciplines, such as history, jurisprudence, politics, economics, literature, and Sufism</p><p>Sources used in Ottoman ethical works</p><p>Authoring motivations of Ottoman ethical thinkers and their intellectual traditions</p><p>Types of authoring of ethical works of the Ottoman period</p><p>Translation activities in the context of Ottoman ethical though</p><p> </p><p><strong>Notes</strong></p><p>After the program, the authors will be given time for the selected papers to be arranged as book chapters and the texts will be published as part of a separate edited book.</p><p>The languages of the symposium to be held in Istanbul are Turkish, Arabic, and English.</p><p>Travel and accommodation expenses of accepted notifiers will be covered.</p><p>Abstracts should be arranged no more than 250 words.</p><p>Abstracts should be sent to <a href="mailto:symposium@isar.org.tr">symposium@isar.org.tr</a> along with the applicants' contact information and academic CVs.</p></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.isar.org.tr/en/symposiums-workshops/ethics-in-the-ottoman-period/call-for-papers-13" target="_blank">https://www.isar.org.tr/en/symposiums-workshops/ethics-in-the-ottoman-period/call-for-papers-13</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 19:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1686029837181657</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Manchester Wesley Research Centre Annual Lecture</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12872799/manchester-wesley-research-centre-annual-lecture</link>
						<dc:creator>Geordan Hammond</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-20T00:00:00-04:00">June 20, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>African American History / Studies, American History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The 2023 lecture will be given by Cheryl J. Sanders, Professor of Christian Ethics at Howard University School of Divinity, and is titled ‘Holiness and Black Consciousness: The Social Witness of Black Saints, Shepherds, and Sages’. The lecture will be on Tuesday 20 June 2023 at 5pm. This event will be both in person and online. If you plan to attend online, registration is <a href="https://form.jotform.com/230374400923044" rel="nofollow">required here</a>. A video preview of the lecture is <a href="https://youtu.be/mxMx6b000Ps" rel="nofollow">available here</a>. Further details can be found at: <a href="https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/mwrc-annual-lecture" rel="nofollow">https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/mwrc-annual-lecture</a>. </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Nazarene Theological College </p><p>Dene Road, Didsbury </p><p>Manchester M20 2GU</p><p>UK</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ghammond@nazarene.ac.uk">ghammond@nazarene.ac.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/mwrc-annual-lecture" target="_blank">https://www.mwrc.ac.uk/mwrc-annual-lecture</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 19:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1686029837181656</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ June 22, 2023] Talk or similar: Kant on the Dilemma of Rational Religion</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/112050</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/>Speakers at this event: <br/>Richard Velkley (Tulane University)<br/><br/><p><strong>Abstract<br/><br/></strong>Kant’s critical philosophy offers a limited defense of religion in the form of pure rational religion based on rational autonomy. Such religion contains an internal difficulty in that morality as autonomy inevitably leads to religion as hope for the achievement of a moral world that finite humans strive to realize but know they cannot bring about wholly through human powers. Humans are, therefore, inevitably drawn to forms of deliverance from evil granted through higher powers as taught by historical religions. But such deliverance weakens or even opposes autonomous human efforts at improvement. In Religion within the Bounds of Mere Reason, Kant argues that pure rational religion needs to draw support from historical religion, specifically Christianity, but must oppose the salvific claims of such religion. These requirements lead to Kant’s remarkable doctrine about radical evil, the propensity of human reason to place self-love above the demands of the moral law. According to this doctrine, the believer must regard the evil inherent in the human disposition as inextirpable and must also commit to unending progress in opposing evil. One could call this the dilemma of teleology in rational religion.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1685943424624668</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ June 27, 2023] Conference or similar: Home and Exile in Levinas and Beyond</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/111938</link>
						<description>Venue: Putvinskio g. 23<br/><br/><p><strong>Colloque international organisé par Viktoras</strong> <strong>Bachmetjevas (Vytautas Magnus University, head of French Philosophy Cluster) et Danielle Cohen-Levinas (Sorbonne Université, responsable du Collège des études juives et de philosophie contemporaine – Centre Emmanuel Levinas)</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>

<p>Mardi 27 juin 2023</p>
<p>Vytautas Magnus University, Kaunas, Lithuania</p>
<p>Putvinskio st. 23, Room 312</p>
<p> <strong> </strong></p>
<p>The topics of home and exile are extremely important if not immediately connected in Emmanuel Levinas‘s oeuvre. On the one hand, some of the most original and insightful pages of <em>Totality and Infinity</em> are devoted to the notion of home and habitation. Levinas discusses the question of what it means to feel at home in the world, the related concepts of familiality, possession, work, and body. Sometimes in explicit and always implicit discussion with Heidegger, Levinas develops an original account of habitation. On the other hand, exile, if not as explicitly, is ever present in Levinas’s discussions in the concepts of uprootedness, losing one’s country [<em>dépaysement</em>] and, of course, the encounter with the stranger.</p>

<p>The goal of this study day is to revisit, juxtapose, and critically engage these two dimensions of Levinas’s thought. This event marks the beginning of the collaboration between Collège des études juives et de philosophie contemporaine at the University of Sorbonne and French Philosophy Cluster at Vytautas Magnus University.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Working languages: English &amp; French.</p>

<p>10 :00 Ouverture par Viktoras Bachmetjevas et Danielle Cohen-Levinas</p>
<p><em>Words of Welcome</em> Michael Levinas</p>


<p><em>Présidence</em> : Viktoras Bachmetjevas</p>
<p><strong>10:15 – 11:15 Keynote</strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Inaugural Lecture</em></strong></p>
<p><strong>Jean-Luc Marion (Académie Française)</strong></p>

<p>- 15 minute break</p>

<p>11:30 – 12:30</p>
<p><em>Le temps de l’exil</em></p>
<p>Danielle Cohen-Levinas (Sorbonne Université, « Collège des études juives et de philosophie contemporaine -Centre Emmanuel Levinas ; Archives Husserl de l’ENS-CNRS)</p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p>12:30 – 13:30</p>
<p><em>La demeure et l’exode</em></p>
<p>Philippe Capelle-Dumont (Université de Strasbourg)</p>

<p>Lunch Break</p>

<p><em>Présidence </em>: Danielle Cohen-Levinas</p>
<p>15:00 – 16:00</p>
<p><em>On the Temporal Horizons of Nostalgic Experience: Nostalgia for the Past, Present, and Future</em></p>
<p>Saulius Geniušas (Chinese University of Hong Kong)</p>

<p>16:00 – 17:00</p>
<p><em>Tentative Ethics of Home</em></p>
<p>Viktoras Bachmetjevas (Vytautas Magnus University)</p>

<p>- 15 minute break</p>

<p>17:15 – 18:15</p>
<p><em>Emmanuel Levinas and His Family in Kaunas</em></p>
<p>Arvydas Pakštalis (Vytautas Magnus University)</p>

<p>If you have any questions, please feel free to reach out at viktoras.bachmetjevas@vdu.lt</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 05:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1685684235093921</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CfP: Zero Hour: Rethinking 1945 from a Jewish Transnational Perspectives (University of Virginia, April 8-10, 2024)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12871347/cfp-zero-hour-rethinking-1945-jewish-transnational</link>
						<dc:creator>Yaniv Feller</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Workshop</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-07-15T00:00:00-04:00">July 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Virginia</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>European History / Studies, Holocaust, Genocide, and Memory Studies, Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Philosophy</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><b><span>Zero Hour: Rethinking 1945 From Jewish Transnational Perspectives</span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span>An Interdisciplinary Workshop</span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>University of Virginia, April 8-10, 2024 </span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><b><span>Concept:</span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>The end of the Second World War in Europe on May 8<sup>th</sup> 1945 is sometimes referred to in German as <i>Stunde null</i>, the zero hour, a term that allows a sense of radical rupture and crisis, while also implying a clean slate and a new beginning. The immediate aftermath of the war and the Holocaust across the Atlantic gave rise to tectonic global changes. Some intellectuals questioned the future of humanity. Others called for a new humanism, for a “common cause” and the constitution of “one world” greater and more inclusive than the failed European tradition of nationalism. The publicly emerging details of the Holocaust added to the sense of profound rupture later expressed in Theodor Adorno’s famous epithet about the end of poetry after Auschwitz or Jean-Francois Lyotard’s declaration that Auschwitz is like an earthquake that destroyed the measuring instruments. Indeed, scholars often speak of <i>post</i>-Holocaust philosophy and theology, marking it as an event from which there is a clear separation of before and after. The goal of our workshop, however, is not to revisit the long trajectory of post-Holocaust thought, but to reconstruct overlooked continuities and sense of rupture in the Jewish (and general) intellectual atmosphere during the immediate aftermath—that is about the first decade—following 1945.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>The profound changes were not limited to the European scene. The atomic bombings of Hiroshima and Nagasaki ended the war also in the Pacific, while raising urgent questions about the meaning of technology and the possibility of the human to initiate global destruction. The Cold War brought with it a world under the sway of two superpowers. At the same time, the emergence of the United Nations as a world-organization allowed thinkers to imagine new world-constellations and helped give rise to the discourse of human rights. In the Jewish context, the founding of the State of Israel in 1948 brought with it a promise and many challenges.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>What kind of philosophies, or theologies, informed the immediate postwar constellation? How were past and present interpreted by historians or political thinkers? What futures were envisioned and a time of radical change? How was the turning point of 1945 theorized through the perspectives of flight and refuge?</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Our workshop will bring together scholars to think about 1945 and its immediate aftermath through a transnational lens of the Jewish experience. Its focus will be on voices—philosophical, theological, theoretical, or personal—reflecting on the Jewish condition at the end of the war and the beginning of a new era. This approach allows us to explore the interchange of ideas across multiple spaces and travel itineraries. We contend that such a perspective, which in this form has rarely been emphasized in the study of modern Jewish thought, can offer more complexity and nuance to the idea of a <i>Stunde null</i> in Jewish philosophy and theology by showing the extent to which thinkers navigated multiple international contexts before, during, and after the Holocaust and World War II. The focus on an epochal “watershed” also allows us to reflect more broadly on how intellectuals have grappled with historical discontinuities, turning points, and ideas of return and restoration.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span>Some of the questions this workshop will ask: </span></b></span></span></span></p><ol><li><span><span><span><span>What kind of intellectual networks—Jewish and non-Jewish—developed in the immediate postwar era?</span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span>What continuities exist between pre- and post-Holocaust thought?</span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span>How was the atomic bomb theorized by Jewish and non-Jewish thinkers across continents?</span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span>How did the emergent Cold War context shape Jewish thought? </span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span>Are there new historiographies that emerge in this period as a result of the World War and the Holocaust?</span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span>In what way do itineraries of Jewish thinkers change the way we think about Jewish thought as often focused on the nation-state or linguistic commonality (such as German-Jewish thought)?</span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span>What accounts for the emerging interest in the post-1945 era today?</span></span></span></span></li></ol><p><span><span><span><b><span>Some of the figures of Jewish background we might discuss: </span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Hannah Arendt, Raymond Aron, Leo Baeck, Eliezer Berkovitz, Ernst Bloch, Martin Buber, Ernst Cassirer, Arthur Cohen, Lucy Dawidowicz, Isaac Deutscher, Emil Fackenheim, Erich Fromm, Nahum Glatzer, Abraham J. Heschel, Hans Jonas, Jacquline Kahanoff, Alfred Kantorowicz, Ernst Kantorowicz, Hans Kohn, Hersch Zvi Lauterpacht, Primo Levi, Karl Löwith, Ignaz Maybaum, Albert Memmi, Esther Azhari Moyal, Zalman Schachter Shalomi, Judith Shklar, Menachem Mendel Schneerson, Leo Strauss, Margarete Susman, Jacob and Susan Taubes, Joel Teitelbaum, Simone Weil, Trude Weiss-Rosmarin, Arnold Zweig.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>In addition, we hope to touch upon the works of other intellectuals reflecting on the Jewish and human conditions during the post-war years, including James Baldwin, G. A. Borgese, Albert Camus, W. E. B. Du Bois, Karl Jaspers, Jacques Maritain, Reinhold Niebuhr, Max Picard, Herman Rauschning, Jean Paul Sartre, Albert Schweitzer, Paul Tillich, Peter Viereck, and others.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span>About the Workshop Organizers:</span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Prof. Asher Biemann teaches modern Jewish thought and intellectual history at the University of Virginia. He is the author of</span><span> <i>Inventing New Beginnings: On the Idea of Renaissance in Modern Judaism</i> (2009) and <i>Dreaming of</i> <i>Michelangelo: Jewish Variations on a Modern Theme</i> (2012), which appeared in German as <i>Michelangelo und die jüdische Moderne</i> (2016). Together with Richard I. Cohen and Sarah E. Wobick-Segev he edited <i>Spiritual Homelands: The Cultural Experience of Exile, Place and Displacement Among Jews and Others</i> (2020). He is currently completing a book entitled <i>Enduring Modernity: Judaism Eternal &amp; Ephemeral</i>.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Prof. Yaniv Feller is a scholar of modern Jewish thought and museum studies at the University of Florida. His first book, <i>The Jewish Imperial Imagination: Leo Baeck and German-Jewish Thought</i> will appear with Cambridge University Press in Fall 2023. He is also the co-editor of <i>Covenantal Thinking: Essays on the Philosophy and Theology of David Novak</i>, scheduled to appear with the University of Torontio Press in Spring 2024.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span>We invite proposals for short (20 minute) presentations to be sent directly to the workshop organizers by <b>July 15, 2023</b>. Please include a tentative title, abstract (150-250 words), and a brief bio. Graduate students and independent scholars are encouraged to apply. We seek original papers that can be published in an intended conference volume. The University of Virginia will cover up to 4 nights of accommodation. Travel stipends may be available pending on final budget approval. For inquiries please contact </span><span>Asher Biemann (</span><a href="mailto:ab5j@virginia.edu"><span>ab5j@virginia.edu</span></a><span>) and Yaniv Feller (</span><a href="mailto:yfeller@ufl.edu"><span>yfeller@ufl.edu</span></a><span>).</span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><span><span><span><span>Asher Biemann, University of Virginia (</span></span><a href="mailto:ab5j@virginia.edu"><span><span>ab5j@virginia.edu</span></span></a><span><span>) </span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Yaniv Feller, University of Florida (</span></span><a href="mailto:yfeller@ufl.edu"><span><span>yfeller@ufl.edu</span></span></a><span><span>) </span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:yfeller@ufl.edu">yfeller@ufl.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 17:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1685684235093920</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>THE 4TH INTERNATIONAL SYMPOSIUM ON RELIGIOUS LITERATURE AND HERITAGE (ISLAGE-4) 2023</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12871345/4th-international-symposium-religious-literature-and-heritage</link>
						<dc:creator>Islage Kemenag</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Symposium</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-10T00:00:00-04:00">June 10, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Indonesia</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Asian History / Studies, Cultural History / Studies, Islamic History / Studies, Literature, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>REGISTER NOW! AND SUBMIT YOUR ABSTRACT HERE "<a href="https://forms.gle/Ymu9seZEyH8pCK2N9%22" rel="nofollow">https://forms.gle/Ymu9seZEyH8pCK2N9"</a></p><p>Theme: “Religious Heritage on Tolerance, Non-Violence, and Accommodated Traditions”</p><p>SUB-THEME:</p><ul><li>1. Religious Moderation and Local Wisdom</li><li>2. Interreligious Interaction in Literature &amp; Heritage</li><li>3. The Making of Religious Identity as Reflected in the Literature and Heritage</li><li>4. Indonesian New Capital City and New Challenges in Religious Life</li><li>5. The Dynamic of Democracy in Cultural and Religious Diversities</li><li>6. Conflict and Diplomacy Historical and Contextual Frameworks</li><li>7. Democracy and Religious Moderation Within Digital Society</li></ul><h3>IMPORTANT DATES:</h3><ul><li><strong>Deadline of Abstracts (max. 250 words):</strong> 10 June 2023</li><li><strong>Announcement of Accepted Abstracts:</strong> 15 June 2023</li><li><strong>Deadline of Extended Abstracts (1000-2000 words):</strong> 15 July 2023</li><li><strong>The Symposium uses both English and Indonesian. Paper will be reviewed by collaborated journals</strong></li></ul><p>Organized by Puslitbang Lektur, Khazanah Keagamaan, dan Manajemen Organisasi (LKKMO)</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Telp: (021) 3920718</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:islage-4@kemenag.go.id">islage-4@kemenag.go.id</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://balitbangdiklat.kemenag.go.id/islage-4/" target="_blank">https://balitbangdiklat.kemenag.go.id/islage-4/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1685684235093919</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – May 31, 2023</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-may-31-2023/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find 15 new job opportunities, 1 Fellowship, 8 Call for Papers, 5 upcoming conferences/speakers, and 1 other event/submission.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 33!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Academia:</h4>



<h4>Research Officer of Fellow, Australian Research Center for Sex, Health, and Society (Full-time, 6-month position)</h4>



<p>La Trobe University, Australia</p>



<p>Deadline: June 12, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=a31d369706&amp;e=ea2dc4a949">https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=a31d369706&amp;e=ea2dc4a949</a></p>



<h4>Coordinator of Studies in History of Christian Practice and Belief (Full-time)</h4>



<p>Pilgrim Theological College Melbourne, Australia</p>



<p>Deadline: June 12, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=cb060bddd4&amp;e=ea2dc4a949">https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=cb060bddd4&amp;e=ea2dc4a949</a></p>



<h4>Postdoctoral Researcher: Facing Gender-Based Violence</h4>



<p>Stellenbosch University, South Africa</p>



<p>Deadline: June 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=8bcc1a9044&amp;e=ea2dc4a949">https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=8bcc1a9044&amp;e=ea2dc4a949</a></p>



<h4>Postdoctoral Fellow (1-year appointment, possibility of renewal)</h4>



<p>Boniuk Institute, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: June 7, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/Yvv4PFa4EV">https://t.co/Yvv4PFa4EV</a></p>



<h4>Minerva Recruitment Job Listings Cite (with areas specifically tailored for Ph.D.)</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://minerva-recruitment.com/">Minerva Recruitment – Higher Education Graduate Jobs, UK &amp; Worldwide (minerva-recruitment.com)</a></p>



<h4>AAR/SBL Job Forum</h4>



<p><a href="https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search">https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search</a></p>



<h4>Non-Academia:</h4>



<h4>Educational Content Writer</h4>



<p>Orange Logic, USA (Remote)</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/jobs/view/3601454336/">https://www.linkedin.com/jobs/view/3601454336/</a></p>



<h4>Senior Policy Writer</h4>



<p>New Globe, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://boards.greenhouse.io/newglobesandbox/jobs/4766993004?gh_src=85ba59164us">https://boards.greenhouse.io/newglobesandbox/jobs/4766993004?gh_src=85ba59164us</a></p>



<h4>Upper School History Teacher (Graduate Degree preferred)</h4>



<p>Dwight School, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://dwightschool.applytojob.com/apply/sIL1EjxfNI/Upper-School-History-Teacher?igbTracker=684619859">https://dwightschool.applytojob.com/apply/sIL1EjxfNI/Upper-School-History-Teacher?igbTracker=684619859</a></p>



<h4>Social Science Analyst</h4>



<p>Department of Housing and Urban Development, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: June 6, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.usajobs.gov/job/727056300">https://www.usajobs.gov/job/727056300</a></p>



<h4>Director of Academic Programs (Ph.D. desired)</h4>



<p>Historic Deerfield, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: July 5, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.historic-deerfield.org/employment">https://www.historic-deerfield.org/employment</a></p>



<h4>Social Science Program Coordinator</h4>



<p>Department of Veterans Affairs, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: June 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.usajobs.gov/job/727948000">https://www.usajobs.gov/job/727948000</a></p>



<h4>Senior Researcher</h4>



<p>Impact Justice, USA (Hybrid)</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://impactjustice.org/job/senior-researcher/">Senior Researcher – Impact Justice</a></p>



<h4>Program Specialist</h4>



<p>Department of Education, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: June 8, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.usajobs.gov/job/727868600">https://www.usajobs.gov/job/727868600</a></p>



<h4>Training &amp; Development Coordinator</h4>



<p>Superior Industries, Inc., USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://superior-ind.com/about/careers/all-jobs/?jobId=a0K4Q00000s04lj&amp;sourceId=a0e1U000000c0xLQAQ">https://superior-ind.com/about/careers/all-jobs/?jobId=a0K4Q00000s04lj&amp;sourceId=a0e1U000000c0xLQAQ</a></p>



<h4>Research Communications Manager</h4>



<p>Digital Promise, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://digitalpromise.hrmdirect.com/employment/job-opening.php?req=2462338&amp;">Research Communications Manager – Careers At Digital Promise (hrmdirect.com)</a></p>



<h4>Digital Archivist</h4>



<p>Compass Connections, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://bcfs.wd5.myworkdayjobs.com/CC_Careers/job/San-Antonio-TX/Digital-Archivist_REQ-016159">https://bcfs.wd5.myworkdayjobs.com/CC_Careers/job/San-Antonio-TX/Digital-Archivist_REQ-016159</a></p>



<h2>Fellowships:</h2>



<h4>MECAM-Long-Term Fellowships 2023-2026</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://mecam.tn/call-for-applications-mecam-long-term-fellowships-2023-2026/?lang=en#:~:text=2023-2026%20%E2%80%93%20MECAM-,CALL%20FOR%20APPLICATIONS%3A%20MECAM-Long-Term%20Fellowships%202023-,September%202023%20to%20August%202026">https://mecam.tn/call-for-applications-mecam-long-term-fellowships-2023-2026/?lang=en – :~:text=2023-2026%20%E2%80%93%20MECAM-,CALL%20FOR%20APPLICATIONS%3A%20MECAM-Long-Term%20Fellowships%202023-,September%202023%20to%20August%202026</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>Oxford Public Philosophy Open Call</h4>



<p>Deadline: October 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.oxfordpublicphilosophy.com/submissions-turn4-1">https://www.oxfordpublicphilosophy.com/submissions-turn4-1</a></p>



<h4><em>Anātman</em> and Philosophy</h4>



<p>Deadline: July 7, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://anatmanconference.wordpress.com/">Anātman Conference (wordpress.com)</a></p>



<h4>Inaugural Alana Bowden Memorial Seminar: On Rituals, Rites, and Ceremonies: Powers of Performance</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="mailto:zoe.alderton@sydney.edu.au">mailto:zoe.alderton@sydney.edu.au</a></p>



<h4>Journal of the Contemporary Study of Islam: Islam and the Discourse of the Enlightenment</h4>



<p>Deadline: June 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://contemporarystudyofislam.org/index.php/jcsi/announcement/view/3">Special Issue: Islam and the Discourse of Enlightenment | Journal of the Contemporary Study of Islam</a></p>



<h4>Bloomsbury Handbook on Religion, Space and Place</h4>



<p>Deadline: June 26, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=ccb2462c9f&amp;e=ea2dc4a949">https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=ccb2462c9f&amp;e=ea2dc4a949</a></p>



<h4>Australian Journal of Law and Religion</h4>



<p>Deadline: August 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=4084feebf5&amp;e=ea2dc4a949">https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=4084feebf5&amp;e=ea2dc4a949</a></p>



<h4>“History: Questions and Debates:” Religious Diversity Between Expressions and Asymmetries</h4>



<p>Deadline: September 5, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://revistas.ufpr.br/historia/about/submissions#onlineSubmissions">Submissions (ufpr.br)</a></p>



<h4>Religious Discourse and Argumentation</h4>



<p>Deadline: June 10, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/111786">https://philevents.org/event/show/111786</a></p>



<h2>Conferences:</h2>



<h4>Masterclass with Professor Paul Bramadat: Research on Religious and Spiritual Communities: Insiders, Outsiders, and Other Useful Fictions</h4>



<p>University of Notre Dame, Australia</p>



<p>Date: June 16, 2023</p>



<h4>Encounter World Religions Center Discovery Week</h4>



<p>Toronto, Canada</p>



<p>Date: July 9-15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/wggs4v7XFK">https://t.co/wggs4v7XFK</a></p>



<h4>Concepts of God: Consistency, Inconsistency, and Paraconsistency Issues</h4>



<p>Sinaia, Romania</p>



<p>Date: September 3-8, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/111666">https://philevents.org/event/show/111666</a></p>



<h4>4<sup>th</sup> World Congress on Logic and Religion</h4>



<p>Sinaia, Romania</p>



<p>Date: September 3-8, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/111694">CFP: 4th World Congress on Logic and Religion – PhilEvents</a></p>



<h4>Religion, Logic, and AI</h4>



<p>Sinaia, Romania</p>



<p>Date: September 3-8, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/111790">Religion, Logic and AI – PhilEvents</a></p>



<h2>Miscellaneous:</h2>



<h4>Young Scholars in American Religion 2023-2025</h4>



<p>Deadline: June 20, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.rraweb.org/young-scholars-in-american-religion-2023-2025call-for-applications/">https://www.rraweb.org/young-scholars-in-american-religion-2023-2025call-for-applications/</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1685597831929044</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>350 Years of Paradise Lost, A Poem in Twelve Books (1674-2024)</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/05/30/350-years-of-paradise-lost-a-poem-in-twelve-books-1674-2024</link>
						<dc:creator>esong1@swarthmore.edu</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, May 30, 2023 - 12:02pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Milton Society of America</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:MiltonSocietySec@gmail.com">MiltonSocietySec@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/poetry">poetry</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/renaissance">renaissance</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>June 30, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>The Milton Society of America will propose a panel at the RSA 2024 that commemorates the 350th anniversary of the second edition of <em>Paradise Lost</em>—the twelve-book version that would become familiar to us and regarded as the great epic poem in the English language. We invite papers on any aspect of the twelve-book <em>Paradise Lost</em> or on the ways its significance has been reshaped between 1674 and now. Topics may include (but are not limited to) the revision of the original ten-book poem, book history, reception history, and adaptation. For consideration, please submit an abbreviated CV and a 200-word abstract to Eric Song at <a href="mailto:MiltonSocietySec@gmail.com">MiltonSocietySec@gmail.com</a>, no later than June 30, 2023.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 13:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1685511423813463</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
