<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 12:25:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 12:25:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>Call for Papers: Apocalyptic Nostalgia? Cold War Imagery in Popular Culture (Manchester, 13th July 2023)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11725157/call-papers-apocalyptic-nostalgia-cold-war-imagery-popular</link>
						<dc:creator>Andrew Crome</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-28T00:00:00-05:00">February 28, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>American History / Studies, Cultural History / Studies, Popular Culture Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Social History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><strong>Apocalyptic Nostalgia? Cold War Imagery in Popular Culture</strong></p><p>Manchester Metropolitan University and the Centre for the Critical Study of Apocalyptic and Millenarian Movements.</p><p>Thursday 13<sup>th</sup> July 2023 at Imperial War Museum North, Manchester, UK.</p><p><strong>Deadline for submissions: Tuesday 28<sup>th</sup> February 2023.</strong></p><p>Since the end of the Cold War, its imagery, atmosphere, and music have been repeatedly appropriated and reappropriated within contemporary popular culture. More than thirty years after the Berlin Wall fell, these images continue to appeal to generations with no memory of the original tensions of the time. From the early Cold War imagery of games such as the <em>Fallout</em> series, or the mid-1980s backdrop of Soviet infiltration in <em>Stranger Things</em>, visual culture, music, and ideas from the period are constantly recycled in popular culture. These images are often linked to fears of nuclear destruction or disturbing post-apocalyptic settings, while also recalling nostalgic and often patriotic images of a lost world of the West. With the recent Russian invasion of Ukraine and heightened fear of nuclear war, these images are being appropriated and applied in new ways online and in popular entertainment.</p><p>This conference invites participants to examine this theme and to explore the complexities of encountering Cold War imagery within popular film, television, video and tabletop games, music, graphic novels and social media content. In particular, it aims to examine the way in which this imagery impacts understandings of the apocalyptic and post-apocalyptic within popular culture. Potential topics might include, but are not limited to:</p><ul><li>The role of nostalgia and nuclear destruction on screen.</li><li>The influence of popular culture on historical memory.</li><li>“Alternative histories” of the Cold War in popular culture.</li><li>Live action roleplay.</li><li>“Apocalyptic fandom”.</li><li>Use of Cold War-era music in film, television and gaming.</li><li>The role of Cold War narratives and imagery in Marvel/DC franchises media.</li><li>The use of apocalypticism in historical and popular documentaries.</li><li>Cold War imagery on social media related to the Ukraine War.</li><li>Cold War kitsch and ironic nostalgia.</li><li>Player agency in apocalyptic video games.</li></ul><p>The conference will take place on Thursday 13<sup>th</sup> July 2023 at Imperial War Museum North, Manchester, UK. There is no charge for registration/attendance for those presenting papers.</p><p>For submissions, email 250-word abstracts with a short biography to Dr. Andrew Crome <a href="mailto:a.crome@mmu.ac.uk">a.crome@mmu.ac.uk</a> by Tuesday 28<sup>th</sup> February 2023.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Andrew Crome, Senior Lecturer in Early Modern History, Manchester Metropolitan University</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:a.crome@mmu.ac.uk">a.crome@mmu.ac.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://censamm.org/conferences/cold-war-nostalgia" target="_blank">https://censamm.org/conferences/cold-war-nostalgia</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 18:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1668580629478140</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Submissions to Open Access Forum in Theological Librarianship</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11694666/call-submissions-open-access-forum-theological-librarianship</link>
						<dc:creator>Garrett Trott</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-12T00:00:00-05:00">November 12, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-01T00:00:00-04:00">June 1, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Library and Information Science, Religious Studies and Theology, Philosophy</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The <a href="https://nam04.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.atla.com%2Fabout%2Fscholarly-communication-committee%2F&amp;data=05%7C01%7Cgtrott%40corban.edu%7C3e484efc49574c5177b308dac28fc753%7C8ca445b8b5ec48d19ceea57565b0f7af%7C0%7C0%7C638036220923913480%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C2000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=mSrhBhjDIRWqn9CvcVvYWrksWfPzq9PLF6OBVnyXqRc%3D&amp;reserved=0" rel="nofollow"><span>Atla Scholarly Communication &amp; Digital Initiatives Committee</span></a> in collaboration with the <a href="https://nam04.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fserials.atla.com%2Ftheolib&amp;data=05%7C01%7Cgtrott%40corban.edu%7C3e484efc49574c5177b308dac28fc753%7C8ca445b8b5ec48d19ceea57565b0f7af%7C0%7C0%7C638036220923913480%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C2000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=D0Ook7nPjTdrgVzAMuPkDgpL8jxxSagO3XT%2BrEeqZUo%3D&amp;reserved=0" rel="nofollow"><em><span>Theological Librarianship</span></em></a> editorial board seeks submissions for a special forum on the “ethical imperative of Open” to be published in October 2023 to commemorate Open Access Week 2023.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The opening sentence of the <a href="https://nam04.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.budapestopenaccessinitiative.org%2Fread%2F&amp;data=05%7C01%7Cgtrott%40corban.edu%7C3e484efc49574c5177b308dac28fc753%7C8ca445b8b5ec48d19ceea57565b0f7af%7C0%7C0%7C638036220923913480%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C2000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=JILIWN9KZ7jSumTpEwh1xEsaw16AAEhqHH9nb5FSxdo%3D&amp;reserved=0" rel="nofollow"><span>Budapest Open Access Initiative in 2002</span></a> is very clear in stating that the nascent movement was seeking to “make possible an unprecedented good.” The question that arises out of that statement is if there is anything that turns the Open movement into something that <em><span>should</span></em> happen rather than merely something that <em><span>can</span></em> happen. In other words, is there an ethical imperative that should compellingly drive librarians to promote the production and dissemination of Open resources? And if so, what is it? </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Theological librarians are in a unique position to reflect on ethical issues from the perspective of spirituality. In order to explore this underdeveloped area of the Open environment, the fall 2023 issue of <em><span>Theological Librarianship</span></em> will host a forum that invites librarians and other information professionals to share their experiences with, or reflections on, the development or use of an ethical imperative to promote the production and/or dissemination of Open resources.   </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Submissions (750-1500 words) are due by June 1, 2023 and should be submitted at <a href="https://nam04.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fserials.atla.com%2Ftheolib%2Fabout%2Fsubmissions&amp;data=05%7C01%7Cgtrott%40corban.edu%7C3e484efc49574c5177b308dac28fc753%7C8ca445b8b5ec48d19ceea57565b0f7af%7C0%7C0%7C638036220923913480%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C2000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=VrZLzHVosrX5qEUgAqptmo1Cp93ej8uI73%2Fb7cA4YnY%3D&amp;reserved=0" rel="nofollow"><span>https://serials.atla.com/theolib/about/submissions</span></a>. Any questions about the forum or submitting to it should be directed to the <a href="mailto:editors-tl@atla.com"><span>editorial board of <em><span>Theological Librarianship</span></em></span></a>.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Garrett Trott</p><p>Editor-in-Chief of <em>Theological Librarianship</em></p><p><a href="mailto:gtrott@corban.edu">gtrott@corban.edu</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:gtrott@corban.edu">gtrott@corban.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1668580629478139</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>AGAPE Launch: Mapping Greek Patristics in the Early Modern Book World</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11716222/agape-launch-mapping-greek-patristics-early-modern-book-world</link>
						<dc:creator>Paolo Sachet</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Online Digital Resources</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Digital Humanities, Humanities, Intellectual History, Religious Studies and Theology, Classical Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>14 October 2022 marked the official launch of <b>AGAPE, a new open-access database </b>which maps <b>the reception of the Greek Church Fathers in print throughout early modern Europe</b>. AGAPE represents the main outcome of the four-year FNS Ambizione project <i>The Greek Imprint on Europe: Patristics and Publishing in the Early Swiss Reformation</i>, based at the Institut d’histoire de la Réformation, University of Geneva.</p><p><a href="http://agapepatristics.net/" rel="nofollow">agapepatristics.net</a></p><p>In contrast to the Renaissance interest in the pagan Antiquity and classical literature, <b>the highly significant rediscovery of the Greek Fathers remains untold and largely understudied</b>. The number of inaccuracies in the regional, national and collective online repertoires available at present turns bibliographical research into a time-consuming and little-rewarding exercise, severely affecting the development of the subject. </p><p>To tackle this issue, AGAPE records <b>any edition of Greek patristic works printed in Europe from 1465 to 1600</b> in the original language, as well as in Latin and vernacular translations. AGAPE refines the available data and substantially improves their level of detail: not only does it link each work to the ID of the <i>Clavis Patrum Graecorum</i> (<b>CPG</b>), the standard authority in the field, but also thoroughly describes all contents (<b>text as well as paratext</b>) and strictly relies on the analysis of at least one copy of each edition.</p><p>AGAPE currently provides access to <b>all editions printed in the fifteenth century</b> (c. 310). Data related to the sixteenth century will be disclosed decade by decade (1501-1510, 1511-1520, 1521-1530 etc.) to ensure reliability.</p><p>Users are encouraged to give their <b>feedback and suggestions </b>through the AGAPE email address available in the colophon of the website homepage.</p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><a href="http://agapepatristics.net/" rel="nofollow">agapepatristics.net</a></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:p_sachet@yahoo.it">p_sachet@yahoo.it</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="http://agapepatristics.net/" target="_blank">http://agapepatristics.net</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 18:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1668494231796893</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CALL FOR APPLICATIONS | Asian Graduate Student Fellowship 2023 &amp; 18th Singapore Graduate Forum on Southeast Asian Studies</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11710533/call-applications-asian-graduate-student-fellowship-2023-18th</link>
						<dc:creator>Minghua Tay</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-12-14T00:00:00-05:00">December 14, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Singapore</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Southeast Asian History / Studies, Immigration &amp; Migration History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Humanities, Social Sciences</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p> </p><p><span><strong>CALL FOR APPLICATIONS DEADLINE: 14 DECEMBER 2022</strong></span></p><p>The Asia Research Institute (ARI) of National University of Singapore (NUS) invites applications from <strong>currently enrolled PhD graduate students</strong> and <strong>junior scholars who have graduated with a PhD degree within the past two years (from the date of PhD conferral)</strong>, whose research is focused on Southeast Asia, for the annual fellowship and forum:</p><p>--------------------</p><p><span><strong>ASIAN GRADUATE STUDENT FELLOWSHIP</strong> | 15 May – 23 June 2023</span></p><p><strong>WEBSITE | <a href="https://ari.nus.edu.sg/opportunities/asian-graduate-student-fellowship-2023/" rel="nofollow">https://ari.nus.edu.sg/opportunities/asian-graduate-student-fellowship-2023/</a></strong></p><p>The fellowship program is open to graduate students currently enrolled in a PhD program in the humanities or social sciences, as well as junior scholars who graduated from a PhD program within two years from the date of PhD conferral, and whose research focuses on Southeast Asia, a region defined for inclusion in this program as ASEAN member countries plus East Timor. This opportunity will allow the recipients to connect with NUS in a hybrid format, including a virtual fellowship for a period of five weeks, and an in-person fellowship during the Singapore Graduate Forum for a period of five days. Selected participants in the AGSF will also undergo an intensive six-week program of independent research, training in academic writing, mentorship meetings, skills-based training sessions and an opportunity for an academic conference presentation.</p><p>Successful candidates can expect the following benefits:</p><p>1.    Access to library and computer resources in NUS<br/>You can look forward to excellent library access to e-resources at NUS’ main library (<a href="https://nus.edu.sg/nuslibraries" rel="nofollow">https://nus.edu.sg/nuslibraries</a>), that has 2 million volumes covering all topics.<br/>2.    An appointed mentor/advisor on your research topic<br/>3.    Automatic inclusion in an intensive English academic writing workshop<br/>4.    Exposure to seminars by various experts in the field<br/>5.    An opportunity to present your research paper at the Singapore Graduate Forum on Southeast Asian Studies to an audience of young international scholars and senior Southeast Asia specialists<br/>6.    Accommodation in NUS for six days for the Singapore Graduate forum (19-23 June 2023)</p><p><strong><em>English Academic Writing Workshop</em></strong><br/>Participants will take part in an intensive course on English academic writing, to be held online during the first three weeks of the fellowship. This program is specifically intended for students who want to improve their academic English because they either come from non-English speaking backgrounds or are looking for advanced strategies to make academic communication more effective.</p><p>--------------------</p><p><span><strong>SINGAPORE GRADUATE FORUM ON SOUTHEAST ASIAN STUDIES</strong> | 19-23 June 2023</span></p><p><strong>WEBSITE | <a href="https://ari.nus.edu.sg/events/18th-singapore-graduate-forum/" rel="nofollow">https://ari.nus.edu.sg/events/18th-singapore-graduate-forum/</a></strong></p><p>This five-day forum, the eighteenth of an annual series of forums for PhD graduate students and early career scholars who have graduated with a PhD degree within the past two years, and whose research focuses on Southeast Asia, will be organised thematically and held at the Asia Research Institute on 19-23 June 2023. Themes of the forum broadly reflect the core research strengths of the Asia Research Institute, including the dynamics of Asian religions, politics, economy, gender, culture, language, migration, urbanism, science and technology, identities, population and social change. In addition to these large research cluster topics, we invite applicants to submit proposals about one or more of ARI’s cross-cutting priority themes: food, heritage and infrastructures.</p><p>The first two days of the forum will be dedicated to Skills Based Sessions during which senior scholars will address various professional development topics including:</p><p>•    How to get published in peer-reviewed journals<br/>•    How to apply for international grants<br/>•    How to flourish as an early career academic<br/>•    How to effectively employ new research methodologies</p><p>During the final three days, participants will be given the opportunity to present their work in the Singapore Graduate Forum. Eligible students/scholars working on topics related to Southeast Asia are invited to submit abstracts based on research at an advanced stage (i.e. already completed data collection and analysis). If research plans were disrupted due to the COVID-19 pandemic, students are encouraged to submit proposals based on work in progress that critically reflects upon pandemic research modalities through methodological innovation. NUS students are also encouraged to take advantage of this unprecedented opportunity to interact and exchange ideas with students from other regions whose interests focus on Southeast Asia.</p><p>--------------------</p><p><br/><span><strong>REQUIREMENTS &amp; EXPECTATIONS</strong></span></p><p>Successful candidates for the fellowship are expected to submit a draft of their papers by <strong>26 April 2023</strong>. This paper will be shared with his/her local mentor in preparation for his/her interactions with her/him.</p><p>Those selected for both the fellowship and forum are required to send in a full-length paper (4,000-5,000 words) by <strong>31 May 2023</strong>, and make a presentation on their work at the Singapore Graduate Forum on Southeast Asian Studies on 19-23 June 2023.</p><p>Please note that the paper must be based on your own work, and only previously unpublished papers or those not already presented elsewhere can be accepted.</p><p><br/><span><strong>APPLICATION PROCEDURE</strong></span></p><p>Please click <a href="https://ari.nus.edu.sg/events/18th-singapore-graduate-forum/" rel="nofollow"><strong>HERE</strong></a> for the application form. Candidates are to submit their applications by <strong>14 December 2022</strong>, and successful applicants will be notified by <strong>mid January 2023</strong>.</p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><strong>Ms Minghua TAY</strong><br/>Asia Research Institute, National University of Singapore<br/>AS8 Level 7, 10 Kent Ridge Crescent, Singapore 119260<br/>Email: <a href="mailto:minghua.tay@nus.edu.sg">minghua.tay@nus.edu.sg</a><br/>Tel: (65) 6516 4224<br/>Fax: (65) 6779 1428</p><p>URL: <a href="https://ari.nus.edu.sg/upcoming-events/" rel="nofollow">https://ari.nus.edu.sg/upcoming-events/</a></p></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 18:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1668494231796892</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FreshRSS 1.20.1</title>
			<link>https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/releases/tag/1.20.1</link>
						<dc:creator>Alkarex</dc:creator>
			<description><ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/milestones/1.20.1">Milestone</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/discussions/4837" data-hovercard-type="discussion" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/discussions/4837/hovercard">Discussion</a></li>
</ul>
<p>A few highlights <g-emoji alias="sparkles" fallback-src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/2728.png">✨</g-emoji>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Focusing mostly on bug-fixes of 1.20.0</li>
<li>Several UI / themes improvements</li>
<li>Improved and new translations (Greek, Indonesian)</li>
</ul>
<p>Detailed <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/compare/1.20.0...1.20.1">tracked changes</a>.</p>
<p>Full <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/blob/1.20.1/CHANGELOG.md">changelog</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Features
<ul>
<li>Add support for custom XPath date/time format <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4703" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4703/hovercard">#4703</a></li>
<li>Add default redirect when authenticating <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4778" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4778/hovercard">#4778</a></li>
<li>Force default user before rendering login page <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4620" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4620/hovercard">#4620</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>API
<ul>
<li>Minor Google Reader API improvements <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4763" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4763/hovercard">#4763</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Bug fixing
<ul>
<li>Fix SQL transaction rollbacks during auto-update <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4622" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4622/hovercard">#4622</a></li>
<li>Fix <code>opcache</code> bug during Web update <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4629" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4629/hovercard">#4629</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/update.freshrss.org/pull/4" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/update.freshrss.org/pull/4/hovercard">update.freshrss.org#4</a></li>
<li>Fix export bug <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4822" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4822/hovercard">#4822</a></li>
<li>Fix OPML import of special feed attributes <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4708" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4708/hovercard">#4708</a></li>
<li>Fix JavaScript bug with remembering opened categories <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4827" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4827/hovercard">#4827</a></li>
<li>Fix <code>curlopt</code> options for HTML+XPath <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4759" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4759/hovercard">#4759</a></li>
<li>Fix charset bug for HTML+XPath <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4623" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4623/hovercard">#4623</a></li>
<li>Fix HTML-encoding of CSS selectors <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4707" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4707/hovercard">#4707</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4823" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4823/hovercard">#4823</a></li>
<li>Fix some broken author links <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4743" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4743/hovercard">#4743</a></li>
<li>Fix show settings page after adding new feed <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4631" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4631/hovercard">#4631</a></li>
<li>Fix login page when user does not exist <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4621" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4621/hovercard">#4621</a></li>
<li>Fix feed manage link on stats page <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4768" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4768/hovercard">#4768</a></li>
<li>Fix minor layout bugs <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4830" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4830/hovercard">#4830</a></li>
<li>Fix minor UI bugs with Safari <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4643" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4643/hovercard">#4643</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>UI
<ul>
<li>Change some default settings related to marking articles as read <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4736" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4736/hovercard">#4736</a></li>
<li>Improve scrollbar when slider is open <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4692" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4692/hovercard">#4692</a></li>
<li>Improve Subscription Management: Show the category position number <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4679" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4679/hovercard">#4679</a></li>
<li>Improve Reader view: Mark article as read while scrolling <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4652" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4652/hovercard">#4652</a></li>
<li>Improve sharing / integration page <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4774" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4774/hovercard">#4774</a></li>
<li>Improve article summary text cut <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4666" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4666/hovercard">#4666</a></li>
<li>Improve HTML semantics for some boxes <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4665" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4665/hovercard">#4665</a></li>
<li>Change dynamic OPML icon <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4673" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4673/hovercard">#4673</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4810" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4810/hovercard">#4810</a></li>
<li>Improve box layout for global view <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4791" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4791/hovercard">#4791</a></li>
<li>Improve logs layout <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4594" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4594/hovercard">#4594</a></li>
<li>Improve Feed configuration: number of articles <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4625" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4625/hovercard">#4625</a></li>
<li>Improve drop-down menus <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4597" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4597/hovercard">#4597</a></li>
<li>Show tile with explanation when hovering empty feeds <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4617" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4617/hovercard">#4617</a></li>
<li>Added bottom nav padding for iOS <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4741" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4741/hovercard">#4741</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Themes
<ul>
<li>Implement CSS variables for easy colour customisation <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4641" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4641/hovercard">#4641</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4693" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4693/hovercard">#4693</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4789" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4789/hovercard">#4789</a></li>
<li>Improve CSS line height <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4671" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4671/hovercard">#4671</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4782" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4782/hovercard">#4782</a></li>
<li>Improved reader view with framed articles <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4663" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4663/hovercard">#4663</a></li>
<li>Improve themes<br/>
Alternative Dark <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4635" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4635/hovercard">#4635</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4797" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4797/hovercard">#4797</a>;<br/>
Blue Lagon <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4786" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4786/hovercard">#4786</a>;<br/>
Dark <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4806" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4806/hovercard">#4806</a>;<br/>
Mapco <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4648" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4648/hovercard">#4648</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4709" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4709/hovercard">#4709</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4711" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4711/hovercard">#4711</a>;<br/>
Origine <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4842" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4842/hovercard">#4842</a>;<br/>
Origine Compact <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4636" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4636/hovercard">#4636</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4735" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4735/hovercard">#4735</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4787" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4787/hovercard">#4787</a>;<br/>
Pafat <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4783" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4783/hovercard">#4783</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4792" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4792/hovercard">#4792</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4793" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4793/hovercard">#4793</a>,<br/>
<a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4796" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4796/hovercard">#4796</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4811" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4811/hovercard">#4811</a>;<br/>
Swage <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4799" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4799/hovercard">#4799</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4828" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4828/hovercard">#4828</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4829" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4829/hovercard">#4829</a></li>
<li>Rename <code>template.css</code> to <code>frss.css</code> <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4644" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4644/hovercard">#4644</a></li>
<li>Misc. <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4596" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4596/hovercard">#4596</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4619" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4619/hovercard">#4619</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4696" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4696/hovercard">#4696</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>i18n
<ul>
<li>Rename <em>tag</em> to <em>label</em> in some languages <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4770" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4770/hovercard">#4770</a></li>
<li>Improve typographic quotes <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4714" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4714/hovercard">#4714</a></li>
<li>Remove invalid i18n string <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4844" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4844/hovercard">#4844</a></li>
<li>Add Greek <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4718" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4718/hovercard">#4718</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4754" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4754/hovercard">#4754</a></li>
<li>Add Indonesian <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4706" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4706/hovercard">#4706</a></li>
<li>Improve Brazilian Portuguese <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4669" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4669/hovercard">#4669</a></li>
<li>Improve Czech <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4670" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4670/hovercard">#4670</a></li>
<li>Improve Italian <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4803" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4803/hovercard">#4803</a></li>
<li>Improve Japanese <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4668" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4668/hovercard">#4668</a></li>
<li>Improve Russian <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4719" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4719/hovercard">#4719</a></li>
<li>Improve Spanish <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4676" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4676/hovercard">#4676</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4725" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4725/hovercard">#4725</a></li>
<li>Improve Turkish <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4715" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4715/hovercard">#4715</a></li>
<li>Improve i18n tools <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4742" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4742/hovercard">#4742</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4756" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4756/hovercard">#4756</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Compatibility
<ul>
<li>Compatibility PHP 8.1+ <code>strip_tags()</code> <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4688" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4688/hovercard">#4688</a></li>
<li>Fix <code>GLOB_BRACE</code> is not available on all platforms <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4628" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4628/hovercard">#4628</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Deployment
<ul>
<li>Docker default image (Debian 11 Bullseye) updated to PHP 7.4.33</li>
<li>Docker: alternative image (Alpine 3.16) updated to PHP 8.0.25</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Misc.
<ul>
<li>Added <em>Linkding</em> as a sharing method <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4721" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4721/hovercard">#4721</a></li>
<li>Exclude <code>.git/</code> from tests <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4824" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4824/hovercard">#4824</a></li>
<li>Exclude <code>extensions/</code> from eslint and stylelint tests <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4606" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4606/hovercard">#4606</a></li>
<li>Update GitHub Actions version <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4717" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4717/hovercard">#4717</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 13:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1668494231796891</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>20th Annual Conference of the European Association for the Study of Religions (EASR) “Religions and Technologies”</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11648013/deadline-call-panels-easr-2023-approaching-20th-annual</link>
						<dc:creator>Rasa Pranskevičiūtė-Amoson</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-01-31T00:00:00-05:00">January 31, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Lithuania</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology, Sociology, Humanities, Anthropology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><b><span>20</span></b><b><sup><span><span><span>th</span></span></span></sup></b><b> </b><b><span>Annual Conference of the </span></b><b><span>European Association for the Study of Religions </span></b><b><span>(EASR) </span></b><b>“<span>Religions and Technologies</span>”</b></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><br/><span><span><span><span>4-8 September 2023 in Vilnius, Lithuania</span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><a href="https://www.easr2023.org/" rel="nofollow"><span>https://www.easr2023.org/</span></a></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Throughout most of the history of the study of religion, there has been a latent tendency among scholars to see religion and technology as not just separate phenomena, but sometimes as mutually antagonistic. Nevertheless, in recent decades, scholars have advanced a more nuanced understanding of this relationship, depending on which particular aspects are being considered.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>For instance, when considering religion as a practice, one discovers that religious institutions and individuals have used a wide range of technologies since ancient times, including printing and writing to preserve teachings, time-measurement devices and astronomical knowledge to determine the correct ritual time, and, of course, complex ritual actions to attract followers and engage natural and supernatural forces.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>These precedents illustrate the complexity of the relationship between religion and technology, a relationship which encompasses not just technology in its material sense, but techniques such as knowledge organization and the specific methods needed to achieve particular ends. In addition to the way in which technology affects religious practices, their spread, and religious dialogue, new technology underlying communications and the social and digital spheres facilitates the systematization of religious data, making religions more accessible to academic study than ever before.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Thus, what we can state about the relationship of religion and technology is not their separation or antagonism but their entanglement, which calls us to take into account how technology and religion have co-evolved in the past, consider which are the critical engagements of religion with technology today, and imagine how they could develop in the future. Considering all of the above, the theme of this year’s EASR conference encourages participants to present and discuss any aspect relating to religion and technology in the broadest sense, e.g.</span></span></span></span></p><ol><li>The concepts and connotations of technology across various religions.</li><li>Discussing how religions have viewed and treated technology historically and more recently.</li><li>The relationship between religion as practice and theory, or religion and science, including their interactions, conflicts, or other types of interactions.</li><li>Investigating esoteric, magical, or other religious practices as techniques.</li><li>Reflecting the spread and practice of religion via technology. The ways in which religions invent, adopt, and adapt technological innovations, including communication technologies and new media.</li><li>Understanding religion through the lens of concepts associated with social technologies, technological knowledge, etc.</li><li>The use of technologies and techniques in religious studies. Studying religion in the digital age: advances in the digital humanities and beyond. The ways in which existing technologies and their notions influence the study of religion.</li></ol><p><br/><span><span><span><b><span>Important Dates</span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span>Call for Session Proposal</span></b><span> (open and closed panels):<br/>October 1, 2022 – November 15, 2022</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>More details about the conference and paper submission can be found here and in information below: <a href="https://www.easr2023.org/call-for-panels/" rel="nofollow"><span>https://www.easr2023.org/call-for-panels/</span></a></span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><b>Notification of Acceptance of Panels:</b><br/>until November 25, 2022<br/><b>Call for Individual Papers</b><br/>December 1, 2022 - January 31, 2023<br/><b>Notification of Acceptance of Individual Papers</b><br/>February 28, 2023<br/><b>Registration</b></span><br/><u><span><span>Early bird registration</span></span></u><span><span>: until May 31, 2023</span></span><br/><u><span>Standard registration</span></u><span>: until June 30, 2023<span> (Deadline for presenting authors)</span><br/><u>Late registration &amp; on site</u> (non presenting participants): from July 1, 2023</span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><h3>Contact Conference Secretariat</h3><div><p>Conference and Events Agency “Seven Tips”<br/>Legal name: UAB Kalanis<br/>Rūdninkų str. 18, Vilnius<br/><a href="mailto:conference@seventips.lt">conference@seventips.lt</a><br/>+370 682 28647</p></div></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:conference@seventips.lt">conference@seventips.lt</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.easr2023.org/call-for-panels/" target="_blank">https://www.easr2023.org/call-for-panels/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 18:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1668235032100512</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ July 3, 2023 -  July 12, 2023] Conference or similar: 15th International Deleuze and Guattari Studies Conference and Camp 2023</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104973</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p>The 2023 Deleuze and Guattari Studies Conference and Camp in Belgrade, Serbia will be the first time this international event takes place in the Balkans!</p>
<p>The Conference and Camp have a long and rich history. The event first took place in 2008 at Cardiff University, Wales (then known as International Deleuze Studies Conference). Since then, the Conference and Camp visited numerous places around the world, including countries in Europe, the Latin America, as well as the US and Canada. There are also editions of the Conference and Camp in Asia and India. Its strong interdisciplinary profile gathers experts, researches, artists and students to discus and exchange ideas, as well as generate new insights in the field of Deleuze and Guattari studies.</p>
<p>Since its establishment, the Conference and Camp have been associated with the Deleuze and Guattari Studies journal. There is also a strong academic community gathered around the journal and the Conference and Camp event in the Deleuze and Guattari Facebook group.</p>
<p>Like the Conference, the journal strives toward an innovative and interdisciplinary approach to the works of Deleuze and Guattari. The journal invites philosophical, literary, cultural, historical and many other approaches to diverse topics that draw their inspiration from Deleuze and Guattari’s body of work. In this way, the Conference and Camp, as well as the journal, remain true to the spirit of Deleuze and Guattari’s legacy that always resisted traditional categorization.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 06:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1668148630974090</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ January 22, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: 15th International Deleuze and Guattari Studies Conference and Camp 2023</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104977</link>
						<description><p>The 2023 Deleuze and Guattari Studies Conference and Camp in Belgrade, Serbia will be the first time this international event takes place in the Balkans.</p>
<p>The Conference and Camp have a long and rich history. The event first took place in 2008 at Cardiff University, Wales (then known as International Deleuze Studies Conference). Since then, the Conference and Camp visited numerous places around the world, including countries in Europe, the Latin America, as well as the US and Canada. There are also editions of the Conference and Camp in Asia and India. Its strong interdisciplinary profile gathers experts, researches, artists and students to discus and exchange ideas, as well as generate new insights in the field of Deleuze and Guattari studies.</p>

<p><strong>Call for Papers - Space, Control, Resistance</strong></p>
<p>‘Control’ is the name which in 1990 Deleuze gave to the ‘new monster’ that is now our present. He said then, and it resonates still, that the most important question of our time is where and how we will find ‘new forms of resistance’.</p>
<p>The old societies of discipline, which Deleuze saw as the predecessor to those of control, operated through spaces of confinement and enclosure. Their crisis gave way to a different type of spatial organization of power: instead of discreet enclosures, we find ourselves in open spaces and within a continuous network. The subject of control is not the molded body in confinement anymore, but a faceless sample, a crowd in constant modulation.</p>
<p>The enclosed and isolated body of the prison has given way to bodies in ‘open prisons’ of connected programs, binary digital systems and their many tools – resulting in a nomadic psyche that carries the panopticon with(in) itself. Like the <em>watchwords</em> of the discipline society, control operates with <em>passwords</em> that regulate space through access/rejection to various types of flows, such as money, information, knowledge, or art.</p>
<p>However, like disciplinary societies, spaces of control offer their own avenues for resistance.  Resistance is never simply a reactive force. Indeed, as Deleuze and Guattari remind us, ‘resistance comes first’. The concepts of line of flight, war machine, micropolitics, deterritorialization, rhizome, becoming-minoritian, or becoming-woman, testify to the importance of thinking resistance in terms of an active force. This thought of the outside is more pertinent now than ever, because as Deleuze once protested, ‘resistance to the present’ is what we lack the most.</p>
<p>Whether one works in architecture, music or cinema, philosophy, art or science, politics, economics or literature, ecology and geography, entertainment, medicine and sport, or issues of race, gender, and sexuality, the question is the same: what is the nature of the form of power we are exposed to today and where can we find real potential for change? How can we think and construct spaces that would act as areas of resistance against the oppressive strategies of control?</p>
<p>The conference aims to show how an engagement with the philosophy of Deleuze and Guattari contributes to the project of discovering emancipatory dimensions of space. We welcome explorations of the way philosophy, art, or science create spaces that allow escape and counterattacks? In what way can music, art, or travel act as areas that would not be re-captured by the contemporary network of control? How can internet phenomena, such as piracy or viruses, assist us in scrambling the digital flows of controlled data? Are there perhaps creative potentials even in history, where archaisms would not only feed the mechanisms of control, but also provide avenues for chaosmotic becomings? Or are there arts of control, as Deleuze once suggested, that could also function as forms of resistance?</p>
<p>By turning to these questions, we aspire to enrich the broad field of Deleuze and Guattari studies with new and original insights: across in the disciplines of political and social theory, ethics and logic, psychoanalysis, Anthropocene studies, metaphysics and the theories of new materialisms, epistemology and aesthetics following the affective turn.</p>
<p>We invite paper and panel proposals from scholars of all disciplines, as well as performance and installation proposals from artists related to the theme of the Conference. We also kindly ask students interested in the Camp to send us their applications.</p>
<p>Deadline for submissions:<strong> January 22, 2023</strong></p>
<p>Notification of results:<strong> February 28, 2023</strong></p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 06:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1668148630974089</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Practical Theology Hub - Call for Submissions</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11655240/practical-theology-hub-call-submissions</link>
						<dc:creator>James Morris</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-12-31T00:00:00-05:00">December 31, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology, Islamic History / Studies, South Asian History / Studies, Teaching and Learning, Human Rights</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><em>Practical Theology Hub</em> publishes short essays for a popular audience on inter-disciplinary theological reflection and research on religious practice, experience and learning; therapy; chaplaincy; and public life. Whilst we accept essays pertaining to all aspects of practical theology and from authors from all faith backgrounds, we are particularly interested in encouraging potential authors to submit essays that are experiential and encourage discussion both within and across different traditions.<br/><br/>We are looking to source essays between 500 and 2,000 words in length and are particularly looking to expand our content on practical theology in the world religions.</p><p>Please find submission guidelines <a href="https://practicaltheologyhub.com/?page_id=56" rel="nofollow">here</a> and contact the editor with any questions.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr. James Harry Morris</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:editor@biapt.org">editor@biapt.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://practicaltheologyhub.com/" target="_blank">https://practicaltheologyhub.com/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 18:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1668148630974088</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>American Academy of Religion - Eastern International Region Conference CFP</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11638349/american-academy-religion-eastern-international-region</link>
						<dc:creator>Chris Miller</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-01T00:00:00-04:00">November 1, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-01T00:00:00-05:00">February 1, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Canada</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Ontario</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Anthropology, Islamic History / Studies, Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Sociology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><b>2023 Eastern International Regional Meeting of the American Academy of Religion</b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b>May 6-7, 2023</b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b>Queen’s University </b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b>Kingston, Ontario K7L 3N6</b></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><b>Deadline for submissions is February 1, 2023</b></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span>The Eastern International Region of the AAR invites you to submit proposals for the 2023 Regional Meeting. The theme for the 2023 Conference</span> is <b>The Other, Persecution and Response. </b><span>We are interested in exploring how </span>logics of otherness express themselves in religious contexts and the responses that they elicit<span>, such as othering via persecution or otherness as self-identification, from theological perspectives to political ideologies and from media to text. </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Related topics could include approaches from queer studies, decolonial religions, and social movements; persecution-response intersection across Buddhism, Hinduism, Christianity, Islam, and other religions; creative re-conceptualizations of persecution and response in the study of religions, literary analysis, and popular culture; intersections between nationalism and gender, race, sexuality; the use of science in support of nationalist politics (e.g., eugenics); religion, violence, and extremism; the nature of religious change and secularization or fundamentalism across traditions. Proposals that do not relate to the 2023 conference theme are also welcome. All methodological approaches and areas of study are encouraged. We welcome papers that address these issues from a range of different academic disciplines and methods. </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Scholars from any region or association may submit a proposal. Only proposals received by the deadline will be considered for inclusion in the program. </span><span>Undergraduate-only panels are encouraged – please see instructions below. The Program Committee also welcomes proposals for non-traditional sessions such as roundtables, dialogues, book discussions, etc.</span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><b>FORMAT FOR PROPOSALS</b></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span>One-page abstract (250 words maximum) describing the nature of the paper or panel. </span></span></li><li><span><span>Cover page that includes the submitter’s full name, title, institution, status at the institution (undergraduate, graduate student, faculty, staff, etc.), phone number, and email address. </span></span></li><li><span><span>If you require technological support for your presentation/panel (such as an internet connection or audio and projection equipment), you must note this in your proposal.</span></span></li><li><span><span>For panel proposals, identify the primary contact person. </span></span></li><li><span><span>Proposals must be sent to <a href="mailto:eirexec@gmail.com">eirexec@gmail.com</a> by the February 1, 2023 deadline </span></span></li></ul><p> </p><p><span><span><b>ADDITIONAL INFORMATION</b></span></span></p><p><span><span>As a general rule, the Region discourages panels comprised of scholars from a single institution. Exceptions to this rule would include a presentation from a research team or a panel based on other types of collaborative research, or an undergraduate-only panel (see below).</span></span></p><p><span><span>Presentations are limited to 20 minutes, with 10 minutes allowed for questions. </span></span></p><p><span><span><b>EIR PARTNERS</b></span></span></p><p><span><span>The EIR will once again meet concurrently with SCRIPT (the Society for Comparative Research on Iconic and Performative Texts). Proposals for SCRIPT papers should respond to the call for papers at <a href="https:///C:/Users/jwwatts/Google%20Drive/J%20career/Conferences/EIR/www.script-site.net">www.script-site.net</a>.</span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><b>UNDERGRADUATE PANELS</b></span></span></p><p><span><span>The EIR welcomes submissions from undergraduates in the field of Religious Studies or on the theme of the conference. Presentations in undergraduate sessions must be 15 minutes long. Each proposal should contain the following in a single e-mail attachment in Word format:</span></span></p><ul><li><span><span>One-page abstract (300 words maximum) describing the nature of the paper or panel </span></span></li><li><span><span>Letter from a faculty member who has supervised the student’s work  </span></span></li><li><span><span>Cover page that includes the student’s full name, institution, phone number, e-mail, and mailing address. For panel proposals, identify the contact person </span></span></li></ul><p><span><span>Please send your proposal to <a href="mailto:eirexec@gmail.com">eirexec@gmail.com</a>. The deadline for Undergraduate Panel submissions is February 1, 2023.</span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><b>STUDENT PAPER COMPETITION</b></span></span></p><p><span><span>Graduate and undergraduate students in the Eastern International Region are invited to enter the student paper competition. Please note that to be eligible, the student must attend a college or university in the Eastern International Region (Ontario, Quebec, Western Pennsylvania and New York). The graduate student award and the undergraduate student award will be formally presented at the business meeting during the conference. </span></span></p><p><span><span>To enter the competition, please attach a short note to your proposal indicating that you wish to enter your paper into the contest. The deadline for proposals is February 1, 2023, and the final draft of the paper must then be submitted to Chris Miller, Regional Coordinator for the EIR at <a href="mailto:chris.miller@uwaterloo.ca">chris.miller@uwaterloo.ca</a> by April 1, 2023. To be eligible for this award the student must present the entire paper at the meeting, which means the paper and presentation must conform to the respective time limits.</span></span></p><p><span><span>For more information about the conference, visit our website (<a href="https://eiraar.org/" rel="nofollow">https://eiraar.org/</a>) or email us at <a href="mailto:eirexec@gmail.com">eirexec@gmail.com</a>. Any questions can also be directed to the EIR Coordinator, Chris Miller, at <a href="mailto:chris.miller@uwaterloo.ca">chris.miller@uwaterloo.ca</a>.  </span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Chris Miller</p><p>Regionally Elected Coordinator - EIR</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:eirexec@gmail.com">eirexec@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://eiraar.org/" target="_blank">https://eiraar.org/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 18:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1668062231404056</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>&quot;Confession, Loyalty, and National Indifference&quot; Forum Launch</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11646797/confession-loyalty-and-national-indifference-forum-launch</link>
						<dc:creator>Liliya Berezhnaya</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Event</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-16T00:00:00-05:00">November 16, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Borderlands, Contemporary History, European History / Studies, Eastern Europe History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>This is the online launch of the thematic forum "Confession, Loyalty, and National Indifference," (Ab Imperio, 2, 2022). The Forum includes five articles that address the problem of emerging collective identity through the entanglement of complementing and conflicting forms of groupness: religious, political, and ethnic. The introductory essay conceptually frames these studies in terms of national indifference and confessional ambiguity, underscoring the role of religious collective identities in forging other forms of groupness–ethnocultural and political.</p><p>16th November 2022, at 13:00 (GMT+1)</p><p>Participants:</p><p>Liliya Berezhnaya (University of Münster)<br/>Catherine Gibson (University of Tartu)<br/>Irina Paert (University of Tartu)<br/>Darius Staliūnas (Institute for Lithuanian History)<br/>James A. Kapaló (University College Cork)</p><p>Andrey Shishkov (University of Tartu)</p><p> </p><p>Registration link: <a href="https://fienta.com/online-discussion-confession-loyalty-and-national-indifference" rel="nofollow">https://fienta.com/online-discussion-confession-loyalty-and-national-indifference</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr. Liliya Berezhnaya, Westfälische Wilhelms-Universität Münster, Historisches Seminar - Abteilung für Osteuropäische Geschichte<br/>Telefon: 0251 / 83 24122 (Sekretariat), E-Mail: <a href="mailto:lbere_01@uni-muenster.de">lbere_01@uni-muenster.de</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:lbere_01@uni-muenster.de">lbere_01@uni-muenster.de</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://fienta.com/online-discussion-confession-loyalty-and-national-indifference" target="_blank">https://fienta.com/online-discussion-confession-loyalty-and-national-indifference</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 18:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1668062231404055</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
