<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 12:17:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 12:17:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ April 30, 2024] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/116709</link>
						<description>Publication Name: Special Issue: Critical Phenomenology of the We<br/><br/><p><strong>CALL FOR PAPERS</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://puncta.journals.villanova.edu/"><em>Puncta. </em>Journal of Critical Phenomenology</a></p>
<p><strong>Special Issue: “Critical Phenomenology of the We”</strong></p>
<p><strong>-</strong></p>
<p><strong>Theme</strong></p>
<p>Phenomenology offers not only incisive analyses of intentionality, experience, selfhood, empathy and interpersonal understanding, but also quite sophisticated investigations of collective intentionality, affective sharing, social participation, communal experience, and group-identity. Indeed, while starting out with an interest in the individual mind, phenomenologists began exploring dyadic forms of interpersonal relations shortly before the start of World War I, and were deeply engaged in extensive analyses of communal forms of intentionality during the interwar period – at a time when nationalism was on the rise. Today, the "We" has not lost its place in philosophical, political, or popular discourse. Within the last decade, phenomenologists have shown how phenomenology can contribute to the “discovery of the We” (Szanto &amp; Moran 2016). These explorations have rediscovered lesser known early phenomenological writings on sociality by Gerda Walther, Edith Stein, Max Scheler or Aaron Gurwitsch and highlighted their relevance for contemporary problems in social cognition theory and analytic social ontology. Phenomenological approaches to sociality, we-experiences, and community, however, too-often concern themselves with ideal social ontological entities rather than the non-ideal social reality we find ourselves in.</p>
<p>A critical phenomenology of the We explores new lines of questioning at the intersection of phenomenology of sociality and critical phenomenology, putting pressure on the allegedly neutral and unpolitical nature of the recent phenomenological discovery of the We. This special issue serves the purpose of demonstrating how critical perspectives both on and within phenomenological analyses can be enriching for philosophical discussions of the We and sociality more broadly. Taking critical phenomenology as the guiding methodology, we foreground the constitutive significance that lived experiences of marginalisation, exclusion, social identity, conflict, ambiguity, and asymmetry have on experiencing ourselves as part of a We. How does the recent critical turn in phenomenology support, extend, qualify, or challenge phenomenological analyses of sociality? How can phenomenological descriptions of social phenomena point out pathways for social and political transformation and change? A critical phenomenology of the We investigates the question of “who are we?” as socially situated, historically contextualised, and culturally specific subjects.</p>
<p>We encourage original submissions on the theme Critical Phenomenology of the We which critically engage with themes found within both classical and contemporary phenomenological discussions of the We. We particularly encourage submissions that speak to one (or more) of the following lines of inquiry:</p>
<p>(1) For one, we are looking for contributions that take a clear starting point in lived experiences and real-life cases. Possible themes for such inquiries are, but not limited to, the ways in which group identity informs, obscures, and motivates acts of discrimination, normalisation, and oppression; how feelings of belonging and community are manufactured for exploitative ends, the role of collective memory and collective imagination for marginalised and historically oppressed groups; how narratives are collectively constructed to both hide and bring to light past and present injustices and their complex temporality.</p>
<p>(2) We also welcome papers that critically engage with classical and contemporary debates on the 'we'. How might we challenge and contest the valuing of community over society we find in Husserl, Walther, and Stein? How has the paradigm of European culture shaped the debate and how might we look beyond it? Do phenomenological analyses of second person engagement overlook the constitutive significance of the third person?</p>
<p>(3) Finally, we are interested in contributions that show the relevance of analyses from early 20th century phenomenology for contemporary debates within the philosophy of sociality. Besides the likes of Merleau-Ponty, Fanon, Beauvoir, and Sartre, how can the likes of Edith Stein, Gerda Walther, Max Scheler, and Aron Gurwitsch enrich recent more political engagements with the phenomenological method? In what sense can the  homeworld/alienworld distinction in Husserl’s generative phenomenology help us make sense of concrete intergroup dynamics?</p>
<p>With these themes in mind, a (non-exhaustive) list of possible topics to be examined under a phenomenological lens is:</p>
<p>·        The We of political movements, protest, and resistance</p>
<p>·        Group, collective and social identities</p>
<p>·        Group antagonisms and modes of domination</p>
<p>·        Inter- and intragroup relations of solidarity and care</p>
<p>·        The role of the 'Them' or the 'Third in the constitution of the 'We'</p>
<p>·        Asymmetrical reciprocity, empathy, and language breakdowns</p>
<p>·        Critiques of the relation between familiarity and strangeness</p>
<p>·        Feelings of (non-)belonging</p>
<p>·        Collective imagination and memory</p>
<p>·        Shared narratives of political, cultural, and transgenerational communities</p>
<p>·        National and transnational identities in classical and contemporary phenomenology</p>
<p>·        Questioning the We of philosophy and academia</p>
<p>-</p>
<p><strong>Guest editors</strong></p>
<p>Tris Hedges (Center for Subjectivity Research, University of Copenhagen)</p>
<p>Julia Zaenker (Center for Subjectivity Research, University of Copenhagen)</p>
<p>-</p>
<p><strong>Submission Guidelines</strong></p>
<p>We invite any original paper which engages with the critical turn in phenomenology in relation to the We. Submissions must be prepared for double anonymous review and manuscripts should be between 6000-8000 words.</p>
<p>In addition, submissions must include an abstract of not more than 150 words along with 4-6 keywords.</p>
<p>All manuscripts must be in American English and prepared following the Chicago Manual of Style (seventeenth edition). Authors are expected to use inclusive language. For further information as to submission guidelines, see <a href="https://puncta.journals.villanova.edu/public/journals/19/Puncta_StyleGuide_UPDATED_JULY_2023.pdf">here</a>.</p>
<p>Authors should submit anonymised<em> </em>manuscripts by emailing them to <a href="mailto:we.puncta@gmail.com">we.puncta@gmail.com</a>.</p>
<p>For information about <em>Puncta. </em>and to explore previous issues, see <a href="https://puncta.journals.villanova.edu/">https://puncta.journals.villanova.edu/</a>.</p>
<p>For further information or informal enquiries about the special issue please also contact <a href="mailto:we.puncta@gmail.com">we.puncta@gmail.com</a>,</p>
<p>All inquiries about manuscript submission should be directed to <a href="mailto:punctasubmissions@gmail.com">punctasubmissions@gmail.com</a> after consulting the submission guidelines.</p>
<p>-</p>
<p><strong>Important dates:</strong></p>
<p>Deadline for submissions: <strong>30 April 2024</strong></p>
<p>Expected publication: <strong>Spring 2025</strong></p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 06:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1699771025050859</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ July 25, 2024 -  July 27, 2024] Conference or similar: 29th Conference of the Friedrich Nietzsche Society</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/116609</link>
						<description>Venue: Lungadige Porta Vittoria, 17<br/><br/><p><strong>29th Conference of the Friedrich Nietzsche Society </strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Nietzsche in the Anthropocene</em></strong><strong></strong></p>
<p><strong>University of Verona, 25–27 July 2024</strong></p>

<p><strong>Hosted by Laura Langone and Carlo Chiurco</strong></p>
<p><strong><br/></strong></p>
<p><strong>Call for abstracts:</strong></p>
<p>Western civilization has maintained an ambiguous relation with nature. The Greeks saw it as <em>physis</em>, everything that possesses in itself the principle of movement, so that nature, in turn, showed  a paradigmatic value (in ethics, for instance). Nature, according to Aristotle (<em>Eth. Nic.</em> 1153b), is the force that, by its own virtue, makes each being “something divine”. <em>Physis</em>, in Karl Jasper’s reading, was also the <em>periéchon</em> – not simply the “habitat” of living beings, but what embraces every being.</p>
<p>Especially in the past two centuries, however, the industrial revolution has degraded nature as a mere object to serve human purposes, deemed far superior to those of other living beings. Humanity’s ruthless and careless exploitation of nature has brought the entire biosphere to the brink of catastrophe. We must urgently modify our behaviour towards nature to mitigate the long-established effects of the anthropogenic changes, such as species’ mass extinction and climate change, and find our lost place in nature.</p>
<p>In this respect, Nietzsche’s philosophy appears to be particularly insightful for addressing this task. Although Nietzsche was aware of nature’s absolute cruelty and immorality (HH I 223, GS 344), he nonetheless invited us to “translate humanity back into nature” (BGE 230), thus rejecting any metaphysical world beyond the Earth among others. </p>
<p>By drawing inspiration from culturally revolutionary movements of the 19th century (e.g. Goethe and Emerson) and the challenge brought about by science (Darwin), Nietzsche stood against the blind utilitarianism of his time as well as the anthropocentrism embedded in much of Western civilisation.</p>
<p>In the light of this, how can Nietzsche’s philosophy inform the approaches we should adopt towards the Anthropocene? To what extent does Nietzsche’s revaluation of all values allow for new ethical stances towards nature and the human body?  How could and should our relations to animals and the environment possibly be reinvented?</p>
<p>Possible topics for papers can include, but are not limited to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Nietzsche and Anthropocene studies.</li>
<li>Nietzsche and animal/environmental ethics.</li>
<li>What does Nietzsche mean by “nature” (including the relation between it and individual beings), and what does it entail to “translate humanity back into nature”?</li>
<li>The will to power as a philosophy of nature.</li>
<li>The significance of our animal origins and the relationship between the animal and the overhuman.</li>
<li>Nietzsche’s relationship to his contemporary natural science including evolutionary thought.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Nietzsche and the history of the concepts of nature in Western philosophy, from ancient Greeks’ physicism to 19th-century German <em>Naturphilosophie.</em></li>
<li>Nietzsche and post/trans-nature: possibilities and dangers of the biotechnological revolution applied onto humans, animals, and plants.</li>
<li>To what extent can Nietzsche be considered a global thinker helping us imagining a different future?</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Keynote speakers:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Rebecca Bamford (<a name="_Hlk149058561">Queen’s University Belfast</a>, Northern Ireland)</li>
<li>Andreas Urs Sommer (University of Freiburg, Germany)</li>
<li>Vanessa Lemm (University of Greenwich, UK)</li>
<li>Bernhard Malkmus (University of Oxford, UK)</li>
<li>Marco Brusotti (University of Salento, Italy)</li>
<li>Martine Prange (Tilburg University, the Netherlands)</li>
<li>Martin Ruehl (University of Cambridge, UK)</li>
</ul>

<p>The conference is funded by the <strong>European Commission</strong> through its <strong>Marie Skłodowska-Curie Actions</strong>.</p>

<p><strong>Abstract Guidelines</strong></p>
<p>Submitted abstracts should be 300-500 words long. Abstracts should clearly describe proposals for a 25-minute presentation, must be written in English or Italian, and must be received by <strong>March 1st  2024</strong>. We aim to communicate decisions by <strong>April 15th 2024</strong>.</p>
<p>Abstracts must include a title and 3-5 keywords, set out a clear argument or thesis, and include references to appropriate literature.</p>
<p>Abstracts should be sent by email attachment to the FNS Conference Committee at the FNS email address: friedrich.nietzsche.society@gmail.com</p>
<p><strong>Submission Guidelines</strong></p>
<p>Please save your file using the following format: FNS2024ABSTRACT_YOURLASTNAME</p>
<p>In the body of the email, please state the following information for potential inclusion in the conference program: (1) The title of the paper; (2) Your name and institutional affiliation (if any); (3) Your preferred email contact address.</p>
<p>In the subject line of the email, please state only the following: FNS2024ABSTRACT_YOURLASTNAME_ENGLISH or FNS2024ABSTRACT_YOURLASTNAME_ITALIANO according to the language of the abstract.</p>

<p>-------------------------<em>Versione in lingua italiana</em>-----------------------------</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>29esima Conferenza della Friedrich Nietzsche Society </strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Nietzsche nell’Antropocene</em></strong><strong></strong></p>
<p><strong>Università di Verona, 25-26-27 luglio 2024</strong></p>
<p><strong>Organizzata da Laura Langone e Carlo Chiurco</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Call for abstracts:</strong></p>
<p>La civiltà occidentale ha mantenuto un rapporto ambiguo con la natura. Agli occhi degli antichi Greci essa era <em>physis</em>, ciò che ha in sé il principio del movimento, e possedeva un valore paradigmatico (ad esempio in etica), tanto che, per Aristotele (<em>Eth. Nic.</em> 1153b) «tutto per natura ha un che di divino». <em>Physis</em>, nell’interpretazione di Karl Jasper, era anche il <em>periéchon</em> – non semplicemente l'<em>habitat</em> degli esseri viventi, ma il Tutto avvolgente che circonda ogni cosa.</p>
<p>Negli ultimi due secoli la rivoluzione industriale ha degradato il mondo naturale a un mero oggetto da sfruttare a piacimento, finendo col portare l'intero ecosistema sull'orlo del baratro. È tempo di agire: dobbiamo modificare urgentemente il nostro comportamento nei confronti della natura al fine di attenuare gli effetti a lungo termine dell'Antropocene, come l'estinzione di massa delle specie e i cambiamenti climatici, e ritrovare il nostro posto perduto nella natura.</p>
<p>La filosofia di Nietzsche appare uno strumento prezioso per affrontare questo compito. Nonostante Nietzsche a volte parli della crudeltà e immoralità della natura (UTU I 223, GS 344), egli tuttavia ci ha invitato a «ritradurre l'umanità nella natura» (ABM 230), tra l’altro negando le pretese metafisiche di un mondo eterno ed immutabile al di là di quello terreno.</p>
<p>Traendo ispirazione dalle rivoluzioni culturali del XIX secolo (ad esempio Goethe ed Emerson) e le sfide introdotte dalla scienza (Darwin), Nietzsche ha sfidato la visione della natura tipica dell'utilitarismo cieco del suo tempo e l'antropocentrismo radicato in gran parte della civiltà occidentale. </p>
<p>Alla luce di ciò, cosa ha da dire Nietzsche sull'Antropocene? In che misura la sua filosofia può ispirare le risposte che dovremo mettere in campo per affrontare le sfide dell’Antropocene? In che modo la trasvalutazione di tutti i valori può condurre a nuovi approcci etici nei confronti della natura e del corpo umano? Come potremmo ripensare le nostre interazioni con gli animali e l'ambiente a partire dalla filosofia di Nietzsche? </p>
<p>Argomenti possibili:</p>
<ul>
<li>Nietzsche e gli Antropocene studies.</li>
<li>Nietzsche e l’etica animale/l’etica ambientale.</li>
<li>Cosa intende Nietzsche per «natura» (inclusa la sua relazione coi viventi), e cosa vuol dire con l’espressione <a name="_Hlk148981365">«</a>ritradurre l'umanità nella natura<a name="_Hlk148981375">»</a>? </li>
<li>La volontà di potenza come filosofia della natura.</li>
<li>Il significato delle nostre origini animali e del rapporto tra gli animali e l'oltreumano.</li>
<li>Il rapporto di Nietzsche con le scienze naturali a lui contemporanee, inclusa la teoria dell'evoluzione.</li>
<li>Nietzsche e la storia dei concetti di natura nella filosofia occidentale, dall'antica fisica greca alla <em>Naturphilosophie </em>tedesca del XIX secolo.</li>
<li>Nietzsche e la post/trans-natura: possibilità e pericoli della rivoluzione biotecnologica applicata a esseri umani, animali e piante.</li>
<li>In che misura Nietzsche può essere considerato un pensatore globale capace di farci immaginare un futuro diverso?</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Keynote speakers:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Rebecca Bamford (Queen’s Università di Belfast, Irlanda del Nord)</li>
<li>Andreas Urs Sommer (Università di Friburgo, Germania)</li>
<li>Vanessa Lemm (Università di Greenwich, Regno Unito)</li>
<li>Bernhard Malkmus (Università di Oxford, Regno Unito)</li>
<li>Marco Brusotti (Università del Salento, Italia)</li>
<li>Martine Prange (Università di Tilburg, Olanda)</li>
<li>Martin Ruehl (Università di Cambridge, Regno Unito)</li>
</ul>

<p>La conferenza è finanziata dalla <strong>Commissione Europea</strong> attraverso i fondi <strong>Marie Skłodowska-Curie Actions.</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Linee guida per gli abstract</strong></p>
<p>Gli abstract devono essere di minimo 300 e massimo 500 parole e pensati per una presentazione di 25 minuti. Devono essere redatti in inglese oppure in italiano e pervenire entro il <strong>1 marzo 2024</strong>. Le notifiche di accettazione verranno inviate entro il <strong>15 aprile 2024</strong>.</p>
<p>Gli abstract devono includere un titolo e 3-5 parole chiave, delineare una tesi precisa e includere riferimenti alla letteratura appropriata.</p>
<p>Gli abstract devono essere inviati come allegato via email al comitato scientifico della conferenza all'indirizzo email FNS: friedrich.nietzsche.society@gmail.com</p>
<p><strong>Linee guida per la candidatura</strong></p>
<p>L’abstract va salvato come segue: FNS2024ABSTRACT_ILTUOCOGNOME</p>
<p>Nell'email bisogna indicare le seguenti informazioni: (1) il titolo del contributo; (2) nome e affiliazione istituzionale (se presente); (3) un indirizzo email a cui essere contattati.</p>
<p>Nell'oggetto dell'email, bisogna specificare solo quanto segue:</p>
<p>FNS2024ABSTRACT_ILTUOCOGNOME_ENGLISH oppure FNS2024ABSTRACT_ILTUOCOGNOME_ITALIANO a seconda della lingua in cui è scritto l’abstract.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 06:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1699598224258798</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Papers: Studies of Biblical Interest</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/11/03/call-for-papers-studies-of-biblical-interest</link>
						<dc:creator>AHemmings</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, November 9, 2023 - 3:18pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Studies of Biblical Interest</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:editors@biblicaljournal.org">editors@biblicaljournal.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/classical-studies">classical studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>December 31, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Dear Colleagues,</p>
<p>We are pleased to announce that the inaugural issue of <em><a href="https://www.biblicaljournal.org/">Studies of Biblical Interest</a></em> (SBI) is now inviting submissions. SBI strives to foster an environment of open and pluralistic inquiry through articles related to comparative biblical studies, textual criticism, etymological research, archaeology, anthropology, religion and science, the study of religious and cultural texts worldwide, alternative readings, discussions, critiques, and reviews. We also reserve space in each issue for items that would not traditionally be published in an academic journal, including art, literary fiction, music, opinion pieces, photography, and poetry.</p>
<p>In biblical studies, opinions too often harden into dogmatic positions, which stifles scholarship. SBI endeavors to represent voices from across the field and beyond, regardless of whether their theories and views are in harmony with one another.</p>
<p>SBI publishes a biannual journal authored by students and scholars – academic and independent – espousing new and creative biblical ideas. We are especially interested in “back catalogues” of unpublished works. We welcome you to submit articles to <a href="mailto:editors@biblicaljournal.org">editors@biblicaljournal.org</a> per <a href="https://www.biblicaljournal.org/#submit-an-article">SBI guidelines</a> and please feel free to circulate this call to anyone you may think interested.<br/> <br/>We look forward to partnering with you in the search for greater understanding of one of the world’s foundational texts.<br/> <br/>Roger D. Isaacs (Member, Oriental Institute Advisory Council, University of Chicago)<br/>Adam R. Hemmings (Fellow, Royal Asiatic Society)<br/>Janice Williams Miller (The Publishing Institute)<br/><em>Founding Editors</em><br/><em>Studies of Biblical Interest</em><br/><a href="https://www.biblicaljournal.org/">https://www.biblicaljournal.org/</a></p>
<p>Contact Email: <a href="mailto:editors@biblicaljournal.org">editors@biblicaljournal.org</a>URL: <a href="https://www.biblicaljournal.org/">https://www.biblicaljournal.org/</a></p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 12:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1699598224258797</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>“Spiritualism Reconjured”: A special issue of Legacy: A Journal of American Women Writers</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/10/30/%E2%80%9Cspiritualism-reconjured%E2%80%9D-a-special-issue-of-legacy-a-journal-of-american-women</link>
						<dc:creator>akreed@vt.edu</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, November 9, 2023 - 1:12pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Ashley Reed</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:akreed@vt.edu">akreed@vt.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/african-american">african-american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/gender-studies-and-sexuality">gender studies and sexuality</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>August 1, 2024</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><em>Legacy: A Journal of American Women Writers</em> seeks essays devoted to the study of women's writing by, for, and about members of the nineteenth-century Spiritualist movement. Spiritualism was a wildly popular religious practice that burst onto the American scene in 1848 when two young girls in Hydesville, New York, claimed to be communicating with the dead. Within months, the movement spread from the Burned-Over District to the rest of the country, where, prompted by the cacophony of spirit voices suddenly audible to them, Spiritualist practitioners produced an enormous number and variety of publications, including transcriptions of séances and trance lectures; instruction manuals for reaching the dead; novels, short stories, and poems dictated by or devoted to the spirits; and newspapers delivering weekly and monthly news from the spirit realm. Even for those indifferent or opposed to the movement, its cultural ubiquity was impossible to ignore and its disruptive tendencies spawned debates around theology, gender, labor, domesticity, sexuality, and nearly every species of political, legal, and economic reform.  </p>
<p>In 1989, the religious historian Ann Braude persuasively (and groundbreakingly) argued that female mediums and trance lecturers contributed significantly to antebellum political debates surrounding women's rights, abolition, and temperance. In her wake, scholars of religion have continued to excavate Spiritualism's cultural importance in the nineteenth century and since, but literary critics and historians have lagged in their attention to Spiritualism's creative aspects and outputs—particularly those by women writers. Literary histories of the Spiritualist movement have often centered texts by male writers who ridiculed its association with women's rights, “free love,” and other feminist reforms. Important studies of the ghost story and the gothic novel have occluded Spiritualist writing or secularized its specifically religious elements. Studies of women's writing have overemphasized single texts (particularly Elizabeth Stuart Phelps's <em>The Gates Ajar</em>) and obscured the wider field. </p>
<p>This special issue seeks to build a more complete picture of Spiritualism as it informed or infused the lives and work of American women writers, and in particular to move beyond portraits of Spiritualism as an exclusively middle-class and white phenomenon. We invite contributions that address works by, about, or for Spiritualists, in any genre or form: novels, stories, sketches, chronicles, reports, letters, tracts, poetry, and more. We especially welcome essays or features about the Spiritualist activities of Black, indigenous, and other minoritized women (such as Rebecca Cox Jackson, Harriet Wilson, Sojourner Truth, and Elizabeth Keckley) and those that attend to the classed, gendered, and raced dynamics of Spiritualist practice and publication. And since much Spiritualist writing is not credited to a living woman at all but to a spirit speaking through her, and since women edited or co-edited at least 25% of all Spiritualist periodicals in the half-century after Hydesville, we seek essays that interrogate how Spiritualist involvement expanded notions of authorship and agency for women writers and/or how attention to women's Spiritualist writing might transform our own critical practices. </p>
<p>Possible essay topics include, but are by no means limited to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Mediumship as imaginative, authorial, rhetorical, and/or linguistic practice</li>
<li>Spiritualism and/as fiction: mediumship as fiction writing, Spiritualists as subjects for fiction, or Spiritualism's relationship to ideas of fictionality</li>
<li>Spiritualism, sexuality, and gender identity in the séance room and beyond</li>
<li>Women writers and editors in the Spiritualist press</li>
<li>Race and its implications in and for Spiritualist practice and writing </li>
<li>Spiritualism as site for women's labor and professional achievement</li>
<li>Spiritualism and disability </li>
<li>Spiritualism and indigenous (North American and African) religious practices</li>
<li>Trans- or circum-Atlantic Spiritualist networks</li>
<li>Spiritualism and/as organized religion, including its relationship to or entanglement with non-Christian religions</li>
<li>Black and Indigenous women Spiritualists, their networks and communities</li>
<li>Spiritualism and social, political, cultural, and religious reform</li>
<li>Fore- and afterlives of Spiritualism, from late-eighteenth-century mesmerism to twentieth-century New Age religion to the contemporary Spiritualist Association of Churches</li>
</ul>
<p>Deadline: Completed papers must be submitted by August 1, 2024. Length limit: 10,000 words (including endnotes and list of works cited) using MLA format. Send electronic copies of papers to the special issue's guest editor, Ashley Reed (<a href="mailto:akreed@vt.edu">akreed@vt.edu</a>). </p>
<p>In addition to articles, the guest editor also welcomes proposals for <em>Legacy</em>'s feature sections: Profiles, Reprints, From the Archives, and On Culture. (For decriptions of these sections, see <a href="https://legacywomenwriters.org/submissions/">https://legacywomenwriters.org/submissions/</a>) Proposals for these sections (500 words) should be sent to Ashley Reed (<a href="mailto:akreed@vt.edu">akreed@vt.edu</a>) by December 1, 2023; completed features must be submitted by August 1, 2024.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 15:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1699598224258796</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ January 31, 2024] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/116569</link>
						<description>Publication Name: Call for Papers: Chiasma: A Site for Thought Volume 9: Philosophy / Fascism / State<br/><br/><p><strong>Chiasma<br/> </strong><strong><em>A Site for Thought</em></strong></p>
<p>CALL FOR PAPERS<br/> Volume 9: Philosophy / Fascism / State<strong></strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Theme and Scope: </strong></p>
<p>The interconnection(s) between philosophy and Fascism is a problematic that has roots as far back as Ancient Greece. While not Fascism in the modern sense of the word, the State—and in particular the tyrants utilizing it—either usurped philosophical ideas to justify their claims to power or had philosophers in their employ. As history marched forward, philosophy followed in tow, often subordinated to the State itself. Indeed, one could plausibly read Plato’s <em>Republic</em> or Hobbes’ <em>Leviathan</em> not merely as works of political philosophy in the abstract, but playbooks for authoritarian leadership, tools taken up by the “Crown Jurist of the Third Reich” himself, Carl Schmitt. More importantly, however, it is not just political philosophy that has been captured by authoritarianism—philosophy, and in turn, philosophers <em>themselves</em> have become idealogues, intimately cozying up with far-Right political ideals. One needn’t look far to verify such a claim. From the Right-Hegelianism of Giovanni Gentile in Italy, to Oswald Spengler’s connections to the Nazi State, to the political <em>and </em>metaphysical Fascism of Martin Heidegger, to the exposure of Paul de Man’s political proclivities, to recent uptakes of Right-Nietzscheanism by former NJIT lecturer Jason Reza Jorjani and “dissident” Internet philosopher, Bronze Age Pervert, it becomes increasingly difficult to make the claim that any given thinker is a one-off crypto-Fascist—an outlier—as within every decade of the 20th century, one can find <em>mainstream</em> philosophers imbricated with, if not Fascism properly speaking, then far-Right or latent Fascistic ideals.</p>
<p>Recognizing a Philosophico-Fascistic connection, Volume 9 of <em>Chiasma</em> seeks to follow the trajectory of Gramsci’s analysis and critique of Mussolini’s Italy, examinations of Nazi Germany by Bauman and Frankfurt School theorists such as Adorno and Horkheimer, and the countless other anti-Fascist thinkers who have attacked far-Right invocations at every juncture in history.</p>
<p>It is from this perspective that we encourage theorists to engage with contemporary Fascist studies, taking seriously the rising threat of Fascism (under whatever mask it may don). Given that, potential submissions may want to take up themes such as, but not limited to:</p>
<ul>
<li><a name="_Hlk150173011"></a>the historical inter-relationship between philosophy and Fascism (or are the two <em>not</em>, in fact, imbricated?)</li>
<li>attempts to, following our theoretical forebears, <em>save</em> philosophy from Fascistic impulses which can be seen in all sub-disciplines (<em>e.g.</em>, the hierarchical world of the Platonic forms, the rigidly regulatory methodology of Kant, etc.)</li>
<li>the role Enlightenment (or anti-Enlightenment) thought as such plays in justifying far-Right ideals</li>
<li>the glorification and fetishization of violence / strength (<em>e.g.</em>, posthumous Nietzschean publications / readings, Georges Sorel, etc.)</li>
<li>the aesthetics of Fascism and/or the politicization of aesthetics <em>à la</em> the Italian Futurists, Walter Benjamin, etc.</li>
<li>pre- and post-Enlightenment figures of the human as they relate to exclusionary practices and/or contemporary uses and <em>ab</em>uses of biogenetic concepts (<em>e.g.</em>, Sylvia Wynter’s “Man1–Man2,” eugenic and/or ‘scientifically’ racist tendencies in the early biological theories of Carl Linnaeus, Georges Cuvier, Ernst Haeckel, and Julian Huxley, recapitulated by contemporary ‘race realists’ such as Jared Taylor or Steve Sailer, etc.)</li>
<li>links between Fascism and modernity (<em>e.g.</em>, Roger Griffin, Fernando Esposito, etc.)</li>
<li>contemporary instantiations of Fascism <em>à la</em> Internet “Right-Nietzscheanism,” (NRx) Neoreaction, Silicon Valleyite Monarchism, etc.</li>
<li>the connections / integrations of occultism and/or esotericism and Fascist ideologies</li>
<li>(<em>e.g.</em>, Julius Evola, Miguel Serrano, etc.)</li>
<li>links between deep ecology and “Ecofascism” (<em>e.g.</em>, Savitri Devi, Pentti Linkola, etc.)</li>
<li>psychology / psychoanalysis and Fascism (<em>e.g.</em>, Wilhelm Reich, Georges Bataille, etc.)</li>
<li><em>what</em> Fascism actually is and/or how it functions (<em>e.g.</em>, Umberto Eco’s <em>Ur-Fascism</em>, Robert Paxton’s <em>Anatomy of Fascism</em>, and/or other<em> </em>seminal definitional texts)</li>
<li>what the actual <em>philosophy of Fascism as such</em> is (<em>e.g.</em>, M.N. Roy, Mario Palmieri, Pierre Drieu la Rochelle, etc.)</li>
<li>as yet un(der)-theorized account(s) of some other aspect(s) of Fascism not mentioned above</li>
</ul>
<p>At the end of the day (reworking Jacques Derrida), Fascism can survive—and indeed, thrive—because of “the semantic vacancy or indetermination at the very center of the concept.” If we shine a light on the relationship between philosophy and Fascism—and the ways in which it appropriates philosophical ideas, be they seemingly neutral metaphysical accounts of the world or problematic philosophies of science—we may strip it of its indeterminacy and more accurately fix our sights on our target. If Fascism exists today, it is only because “[w]e do not yet know what we have inherited.”</p>
<p><strong>Submission Guidelines:</strong></p>
<p><em>Chiasma </em>accepts any and all manuscripts related to the topic at hand. That being said, submissions should be theoretically rigorous and diverse, in keeping with the trans-disciplinary nature of the journal. We ask for complete papers between 6,000–10,000 words that conform to a slightly modified version of the Chicago Manual of Style with footnotes and no bibliography (see our <a href="https://ojs.lib.uwo.ca/index.php/chiasma/styleguidelines"><em>Style Guidelines</em></a>). If there are original works of art that you think might fit within the theme, please get in contact via the email below. When submitting your manuscript, please include two documents:</p>
<ol>
<li><a name="_Hlk150173084"></a>the complete text of your manuscript with any identifying information removed (for help, see <a href="https://ucanr.edu/sites/anrpeerreview/For_Associate_Editors/Instructions_for_online_peer_system/Anonymizing_a_Word_document/"><em>here</em></a>), and</li>
<li>a title page that includes your full name, email address, institutional affiliation, short biography (no more than 100 words), and an abstract (no more than 300 words)</li>
</ol>
<p>Please submit your manuscript via our submission page <a href="https://ojs.lib.uwo.ca/index.php/chiasma/about/submissions"><em>here</em></a>. The deadline for submissions is <strong><em>January 31, 2024</em></strong>.</p>
<p>Should you have any questions, comments, or concerns, please don’t hesitate to get in touch with us at <a href="mailto:chiasma@uwo.ca"><em>chiasma@uwo.ca</em></a>.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 06:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1699511826601379</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – November 8, 2023</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-november-8-2023/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Project Opportunities Digest! This week you will find 25 new job opportunities, 1 fellowship, 3 calls for papers, 3 conferences/speakers, and 3 other events/submissions.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 42!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Academic:</h4>



<h4>Professor of Biblical Studies</h4>



<p>The Master’s University, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178599216&amp;utm_source=11_07_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178599216&amp;utm_source=11_07_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor of History (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Southern Utah University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: December 22, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178599252&amp;utm_source=11_07_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178599252&amp;utm_source=11_07_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Charles E. Scheidt Post-doctoral Fellow in Genocide and Mass Atrocity Prevention (1-year appointment)</h4>



<p>Binghamton University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: December 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178599052&amp;utm_source=11_07_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178599052&amp;utm_source=11_07_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Jews in the Muslim World (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>University of California, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: December 3, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.historians.org/jobs/19373439/assistant-professor-jews-in-the-muslim-world">https://careers.historians.org/jobs/19373439/assistant-professor-jews-in-the-muslim-world</a></p>



<h4>Postdoctoral Research Associate in Native American and Indigenous Studies</h4>



<p>Princeton University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: December 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.historians.org/jobs/19371174/postdoctoral-research-associate-announcement-native-american-and-indigenous-studies">https://careers.historians.org/jobs/19371174/postdoctoral-research-associate-announcement-native-american-and-indigenous-studies</a></p>



<h4>Postdoctoral Fellowship on Theory for Society</h4>



<p>Harvard University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: December 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://main.hercjobs.org/jobs/19368057/postdoctoral-fellowship-in-theory-for-society">https://main.hercjobs.org/jobs/19368057/postdoctoral-fellowship-in-theory-for-society</a></p>



<h4>Associate Professor of Holocaust History and Associate Directory of Holocaust Education (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Chapman University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: Until filled</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://apply.interfolio.com/134996">https://apply.interfolio.com/134996</a></p>



<h4>Lecture in Religious Studies, Islam (Full-time)</h4>



<p>Butler University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: January 5, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178594917&amp;utm_source=11_03_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178594917&amp;utm_source=11_03_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Rising Scholar Postdoctoral Research Associate (2-year appointment)</h4>



<p>University of Virginia, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: January 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178594069&amp;utm_source=11_02_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178594069&amp;utm_source=11_02_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Visiting Scholar in Jewish Studies, Mysticism and Philosophy of Religion (1-year appointment)</h4>



<p>Harvard Divinity School, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: January 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178594060&amp;utm_source=11_02_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178594060&amp;utm_source=11_02_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Religion (Tenure-track)</h4>



<p>New College, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: Until filled</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178593273&amp;utm_source=11_02_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178593273&amp;utm_source=11_02_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Non-Academic:</h4>



<h4>Research Coordinator (Graduate degree required)</h4>



<p>FedWriters, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://fedwriters.isolvedhire.com/jobs/1003467-84809">https://fedwriters.isolvedhire.com/jobs/1003467-84809</a></p>



<h4>Museum Services Coordinator</h4>



<p>Kennesaw State University, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178598819&amp;utm_source=11_07_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178598819&amp;utm_source=11_07_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Senior Researcher</h4>



<p>Fors Marsh, USA (Remote)</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/7bW9Z3UvTY">https://t.co/7bW9Z3UvTY</a></p>



<h4>Communications/Marketing and Events Contractor</h4>



<p>Religions for Peace, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.rfp.org/careers/">Careers – Religions for Peace (rfp.org)</a></p>



<h4>Editorial Assistant</h4>



<p>IGI Global, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/SY6erCD5gz">https://t.co/SY6erCD5gz</a></p>



<h4>Associate Continuing Education Producer</h4>



<p>Continued, USA (Remote)</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/u4cBO3wibx">https://t.co/u4cBO3wibx</a></p>



<h4>Director of Research &amp; Innovation</h4>



<p>National Center for Learning Disabilities &amp; Education, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/2XyHS4xguP">https://t.co/2XyHS4xguP</a></p>



<h4>Program Managers (Center for Research on Reproduction &amp; Women’s Health)</h4>



<p>University of Pennsylvania, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/OmLrhcdeh3">https://t.co/OmLrhcdeh3</a></p>



<h4>Research Analyst</h4>



<p>RealTime Talent, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/bcpDS1ttfO">https://t.co/bcpDS1ttfO</a></p>



<h4>Writing Editor</h4>



<p>Cybersecurity &amp; Infrastructure Security Agency, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/GkQgosOzak">https://t.co/GkQgosOzak</a></p>



<h4>Media Editorial Assistant, Sciences</h4>



<p>W.W. Norton &amp; Company, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/19BO9qoRf5">https://t.co/19BO9qoRf5</a></p>



<h4>Program Assistant</h4>



<p>Great Lakes St. Lawrence Governors &amp; Premiere, USA (Remote)</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/ubGvRRt4vW">https://t.co/ubGvRRt4vW</a></p>



<h4>Curator of Provenance</h4>



<p>Princeton University, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178593039&amp;utm_source=11_02_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178593039&amp;utm_source=11_02_23&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=JobAgentEmail</a></p>



<h4>Executive Assistant – Event Manager for Graduate School</h4>



<p>Hook College, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178591287&amp;AAEmail=134746&amp;MatchType=0&amp;utm_source=10_31_2023&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=AAEmail">https://www.higheredjobs.com/details.cfm?JobCode=178591287&amp;AAEmail=134746&amp;MatchType=0&amp;utm_source=10_31_2023&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=AAEmail</a></p>



<h2>Fellowships:</h2>



<h4>2024-25 James Weldon Johnson Institute Dissertation Fellowship</h4>



<p>Deadline: January 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://apply.interfolio.com/135758">https://apply.interfolio.com/135758</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>“You Can Be Anything”: Imagining and Interrogating Barbie in Popular Culture</h4>



<p>Deadline: January 31, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://x.com/popcultureune/status/1721723696031948951?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw">https://x.com/popcultureune/status/1721723696031948951?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw</a></p>



<h4>Doing Anything with Anthropology</h4>



<p>Deadline: November 13, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/GrJWlA6T8z">https://t.co/GrJWlA6T8z</a></p>



<h4>Out of Europe: Studying Religion(s) in Interconnected Worlds</h4>



<p>Deadline: December 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=a78592b64d&amp;e=ea2dc4a949">https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=a78592b64d&amp;e=ea2dc4a949</a></p>



<h2>Conferences/Speakers:</h2>



<h4>SMR Sumer Institute with Julia Kristeva “The Feminine in an Age of Anthropological Transformation”</h4>



<p>Olympiada Greece</p>



<p>Date: September 8-15, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/116398">https://philevents.org/event/show/116398</a></p>



<h4>The Opening of Mecca and The Closure of Violence</h4>



<p>Online</p>



<p>Date: November 9, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://twitter.com/stanford_repocu/status/1720213685380296950?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw">https://twitter.com/stanford_repocu/status/1720213685380296950?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw</a></p>



<h4>Raising our Tribal Voice for Justice: An Indigenous Theological Revolution</h4>



<p>Melbourne, Australia</p>



<p>Date: February 5-8, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=5e64d9ffa7&amp;e=ea2dc4a949">https://aasr.us20.list-manage.com/track/click?u=66ad6971e58faa2afa4a0216c&amp;id=5e64d9ffa7&amp;e=ea2dc4a949</a></p>



<h2>Miscellaneous:</h2>



<h4>Institute for Critical Social Inquiry 2024 Summer Seminars</h4>



<p>Deadline: December 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/E90YuUcadu">https://t.co/E90YuUcadu</a></p>



<h4>Religions for Peace Internships</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.rfp.org/careers/">Careers – Religions for Peace (rfp.org)</a></p>



<h4>JASR Book Review Editor (2-year appointment)</h4>



<p>More Information: Rosemary Hancock (<a href="mailto:rosemary.hancock@nd.edu.au">rosemary.hancock@nd.edu.au</a>), Milad Milani (<a href="mailto:m.milani@westernsydney.edu.au">m.milani@westernsydney.edu.au</a>), and David Newheiser (<a href="mailto:David.newheiser@acu.edu.au">David.newheiser@acu.edu.au</a>)</p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1699511826601378</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
