<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 03:07:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 03:07:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ January 3, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Textures of Change: Social Imaginaries, Narratives, and the Possibility of Politics</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103582</link>
						<description><p>The New School for Social Research Philosophy Department is hosting our annual Graduate Student Conference April 13-15th 2023 in person in New York City.  </p>
<p>This year’s topic is <strong>Textures of Change: Social Imaginaries, Narratives, and the Possibility of Politics</strong>.   </p>
<p><u><strong>Keynote Speakers:</strong></u></p>
<p>María Pía Lara (<em>Universidad Autónoma Metropolitana</em>)</p>
<p>Fanny Söderbäck (<em>Södertörn University</em>)</p>
<p>Eva Von Redecker (<em>Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin</em>)</p>
<p>It has become common for political theorists and philosophers to insist on the necessity of new imaginaries and narratives. Crises of authority, financial meltdowns, and environmental disasters compel us to look for alternative frameworks and practices. While the urgency of this claim is undeniable, the conceptual ground for the creation of new imaginaries and narratives is still unclear. How do we define imaginaries and narratives in relation to our political and social life? How can they become normative and generate conceptual and practical shifts? And who is in a position to shape, direct, and take ownership of these emergent conceptions?  </p>
<p>This conference focuses on the current debate on political imaginaries and narratives to investigate some of these questions. As a starting point, we propose to challenge standard Marxist or epistemological approaches to the topic that either interpret imaginaries and narratives as ideological projections (a product of false consciousness) or merely as individual, cognitive faculties. Rather, we suggest thinking about imaginaries and narratives as larger sensuous and embodied practices that re-orient material structures of domination and allow for a reflective rearticulation of collective demands. In particular, we set out to clarify: the meaning of “imaginaries” and/or “narratives” as forms of sense-making; their ability to shift existing discourses and power relations; the way in which they foster different ways of feeling, seeing, acting-in, and experiencing the world in a time of crisis; the way in which they are embedded in artistic and literary practices; and the way in which they address—or fail to address—marginalized subjects.</p>
<p>We invite papers that focus on the concepts of “social imaginary” and “narrative,” as well as on the connection between the two, and on their political and ethical implications. It is our conviction that a critical understanding of these concepts can only emerge from attending to how they are practically embodied and situated in our practices. In this spirit, we welcome, in addition to papers aimed at conceptual clarification, papers that provide specific accounts of alternative forms of praxis, including (but not limited to) leftist, feminist, anti-racist, decolonial, abolitionist, indigenous, environmentalist, and utopian imaginaries and narratives.</p>
<p>We are accepting submissions of up to <strong>4000</strong> words. Please also submit a brief academic bio.</p>
<p>Please contact socialimaginarynarrative@gmail.com with any queries or submissions. </p>
<p>The deadline is<strong> January 3rd, 2023</strong>  </p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664861824360174</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ April 13, 2023 -  April 15, 2023] Conference or similar: Textures of Change: Social Imaginaries, Narratives, and the Possibility of Politics</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103578</link>
						<description>Venue: 6 E 16 St<br/><br/><p>The New School for Social Research Philosophy Department is hosting our annual Graduate Student Conference April 13-15th 2023 in person in New York City.  </p>
<p>This year’s topic is <strong>Textures of Change: Social Imaginaries, Narratives, and the Possibility of Politics</strong>.   </p>
<p><u><strong>Keynote Speakers:</strong></u></p>
<p>María Pía Lara (<em>Universidad Autónoma Metropolitana</em>)</p>
<p>Fanny Söderbäck (<em>Södertörn University</em>)</p>
<p>Eva Von Redecker (<em>Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin</em>)</p>
<p>It has become common for political theorists and philosophers to insist on the necessity of new imaginaries and narratives. Crises of authority, financial meltdowns, and environmental disasters compel us to look for alternative frameworks and practices. While the urgency of this claim is undeniable, the conceptual ground for the creation of new imaginaries and narratives is still unclear. How do we define imaginaries and narratives in relation to our political and social life? How can they become normative and generate conceptual and practical shifts? And who is in a position to shape, direct, and take ownership of these emergent conceptions?  </p>
<p>This conference focuses on the current debate on political imaginaries and narratives to investigate some of these questions. As a starting point, we propose to challenge standard Marxist or epistemological approaches to the topic that either interpret imaginaries and narratives as ideological projections (a product of false consciousness) or merely as individual, cognitive faculties. Rather, we suggest thinking about imaginaries and narratives as larger sensuous and embodied practices that re-orient material structures of domination and allow for a reflective rearticulation of collective demands. In particular, we set out to clarify: the meaning of “imaginaries” and/or “narratives” as forms of sense-making; their ability to shift existing discourses and power relations; the way in which they foster different ways of feeling, seeing, acting-in, and experiencing the world in a time of crisis; the way in which they are embedded in artistic and literary practices; and the way in which they address—or fail to address—marginalized subjects.</p>
<p>We invite papers that focus on the concepts of “social imaginary” and “narrative,” as well as on the connection between the two, and on their political and ethical implications. It is our conviction that a critical understanding of these concepts can only emerge from attending to how they are practically embodied and situated in our practices. In this spirit, we welcome, in addition to papers aimed at conceptual clarification, papers that provide specific accounts of alternative forms of praxis, including (but not limited to) leftist, feminist, anti-racist, decolonial, abolitionist, indigenous, environmentalist, and utopian imaginaries and narratives.</p>
<p>We are accepting submissions of up to <strong>4000</strong> words. Please also submit a brief academic bio. </p>
<p>Please contact socialimaginarynarrative@gmail.com with any queries or submissions. </p>
<p>The deadline is<strong> January 3rd, 2023</strong>  </p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664861824360173</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ October 19, 2022 -  October 21, 2022] Conference or similar: 2nd IEF International Colloquium ROADS TO CARE, 19th-21st October 2022 (FLUC - Faculty of Arts and Humanities of the University of Coimbra)</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103586</link>
						<description>Venue: Faculdade de Letras, Largo da Porta Férrea<br/><br/><p>The extreme vulnerability of humans and contemporary societies, recently laid bare by the Covid-19 pandemic, has led to extreme poverty, famine and numerous sorts of inequality, injustice, and exploitation affecting a vast proportion of the global human population. Different and unexpected forms of vulnerability felt worldwide urge philosophy and philosophers to reflect upon the present situation and to take action towards finding humane and well-reasoned answers to some of today’s most pressing problems. To this end, and in line with its core commitment to the “philosophy of care,” the IEF aims to foster an interdisciplinary dialogue between philosophers and all of those who, in their own fields of inquiry and expertise, are engaged in taking care of the Earth and its inhabitants by doing their utmost to mitigate the perils currently threatening our planetary household. A precise definition of the nature, aims and methods of a “philosophy of care” has yet to be established, but its scope has widened to encompass major challenges, notably the promotion of inclusive and democratic societies, gender equality, climate and environmental sustainability, cultural, artistic and human heritage, and universal access to high-quality and affordable healthcare and education. These are the fundamental issues we hope to address in this colloquium.</p>
<p>In its 2nd edition, the colloquium will also pay tribute to Maria de Lourdes Pintasilgo (1930-2004), former Portuguese prime-minister and a pioneering contributor to the development of the philosophy of care, whose life and work will be evoked by a special discussion panel. Apart from papers associated with the colloquium’s four main sections (see below), we also welcome contributions on M. L. Pintasilgo’s thought and legacy, broadly construed.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664861824360172</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ January 12, 2023 -  December 16, 2023] Conference or similar: One-year Interdisciplinary Cross-Training Project for Philosophers of Religion</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103594</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p>One-year Interdisciplinary Cross-Training Project in Psychology for Philosophers, Theologians and researchers working in Religious Science. Application deadline November 15, 2022.</p>
<p>The team of instructors is led by Prof. Markus Quirin (Psychology, Technical University of Munich) and Prof. Godehard Brüntrup (Philosophy of Mind, Munich School of Philosophy).</p>
<p>Participation is free of charge, successful applicants will receive a personal stipend/scholarship of up to 10.000 EUR (professors) or up to 5.000 EUR (others).</p>
<p>Location: hybrid format, online and Munich, Germany.<br/><br/></p>
<p>Brief Description of the Project:</p>
<p>The Cross-Training Project (CTP) is aimed at theologians, philosophers and scholars in religious studies who are working on questions of Christian theology and who want to become more competent in dealing with empirical psychological research. The program will be executed under professional supervision in small learning groups within two semesters. Individual supervision might be possible on demand and under certain circumstances. The thematic focus will be on "personality growth". Topics such as self- realization, autonomy, openness, self-determination, emotion regulation, integration, authenticity, and personality systems approaches will serve as bridges between scientific and humanistic questions. </p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 05:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664861824360171</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ May 11, 2023 -  May 14, 2023] Conference or similar: 2023 Annual Meeting of the Heidegger Circle</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103530</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p>The Heidegger Circle invites submissions of papers and proposals of panels on any aspect of Heidegger’s thought.</p>
<p>Paper submissions: The papers – to be included, if accepted, in the Proceedings of the annual meeting – should not exceed 4000 words (excluding 150-word abstract, footnotes, and references), with a reading time of 30 minutes (or approximately 75% of the written text). Papers should be prepared for blind review and submitted with a separate cover sheet that includes contact information (e-mail suffices) and affiliation if applicable. Authors who submit papers to the Heidegger Circle annual meeting are welcome to revise and expand their essays and submit them to Gatherings: The Heidegger Circle Annual.</p>
<p>Panel proposals: Panels include three presenters each making a brief (approximately ten minute) presentation on the panel topic, allowing significant time for discussion. Panel proposals should include (a) the panel title and a 150-word abstract of the panel topic, and (b) the titles and a 150-word gloss for each panelist’s comments. These proposals should be prepared for blind review with a separate cover sheet including contact information (e-mail suffices), names, and affiliations of the panelists.</p>
<p>Formatting: submissions should be single-spaced, 12 point font size, Times New Roman font, 1” margins on all sides, footnotes (10 point font), no endnotes, in .doc or .docx version (no PDFs, please).</p>
<p>Please send submissions/proposals to Ben Crowe (bcrowe@bu.edu) with the words “HC 2023 submission” in the Subject line. Deadline for paper submissions and panel proposals: January 15. Please direct any other inquiries to D. Dahlstrom (dahlstro@bu.edu), Dept. of Philosophy, Boston University, Boston, MA 02215.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664689024689352</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ March 31, 2023] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103522</link>
						<description>Publication Name: "The Polish Journal of the Arts and Culture. New Series" - issue 2/2023<br/><br/><p><em><strong>The Polish Journal of the Arts and Culture. New Series </strong></em> is a peer-reviewed academic journal devoted to in-depth reflection on culture in all its manifestations throughout  different circles and civilisations over the centuries. The interdisciplinary profile of the journal opens the door to cooperation with philologists, historians of religion, philosophers, cultural anthropologists and all who – in their research – focus on cultural phenomena using their own tools of interpretation.<br/><br/>Apart from academic papers we also accept yet unpublished translations from works in their original languages (or parts thereof) representing the ancient and contemporary literature of individual cultures, as well as book reviews, conference reports, and discussion of publications or events important to the wider discourse of cultural studies.<br/><br/>Currently, <strong><em>The Polish Journal of the Arts and Culture. The New Series</em></strong> (published by the Centre for Comparative Studies of Civilisations of the Jagiellonian University) is available in electronic format. We invite to visit our website: http://www.ejournals.eu/PJACNS. It receives 20 points on the list of scientific journals of the Polish Ministry of Science and Higher Education. The articles of the Journal are indexed/abstracted in the following databases: Google Scholar, ERIH Plus, PBN, CEEOL.<br/><br/>***<br/>The journal publishes articles in Polish and English (in special cases, the editors may consider publishing an article in another language).<br/><br/>Proposals for articles should be sent to: pjac@uj.edu.pl. Check the ‘Instructions for authors’ on our website for more details.<br/><br/>The deadline for the submission of manuscripts (full papers, .doc files) scheduled for the issue 2/2023 is March 31, 2023.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664689024689351</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ October 12, 2022 -  October 14, 2022] Conference or similar: Intentionality as Tendency</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103502</link>
						<description>Venue: Residenzplatz 2<br/><br/><p>Intentionality, in phenomenology, is understood as one of the central features of consciousness, in particular as that which defines the structure of acts. A perception, a judgment, an act of will, or a feeling are intentional insofar as they are directed at objects or states of affairs. The characterization of intentional consciousness as object-directedness has been reassessed and adjusted in the developmentof the phenomenological movement: for instance, with Husserl’s analyses of temporality and the passive syntheses, Heidegger’s discussion of mood, and Merleau-Ponty inquiry into the different forms of behavior and bodily intentionality. That said, the characterization of intentionality as object-directedness is still often taken for granted, although the mentioned analyses also motivate the view that intentionality is not primarily, let alone exclusively, to be understood as directedness at a determinate object.</p>
<p>In the texts written around the years 1913/14, Husserl explicitly concentrates on the distinction between object-directed and nonobject-directed intentionality and works intensively on the characterization of their relation. Thus, he not only develops his phenomenological investigations of consciousness by shedding light on the structures of object-directed acts (as we can see, for instance in Ideas I), but rather extends the focus of his inquiry by also investigating the intentional processes that do not seem to already have a defined object. Husserl uses the notion of ‘tendency’ to refer to the process-like intentionality that is not (yet) directed at a determinate object. Crucially, he often indicates that the indeterminate tending-towards should be seen as the most basic and encompassing mode of being of consciousness. The structures of accomplishment of intentionality as tendency are partly discussed in the manuscripts Husserl wrote for the revision of the Sixth Logical Investigation (notably Hua XX/2) and later in the Analyses Concerning Active and Passive Synthesis (Hua XI and XXXI) as well as in the manuscripts collected by Landgrebe in the work Experience and Judgment. But the most extensive analyses of intentionality as tendency - embracing the doxastic, volitional, and affective dimension of conscious life - can be found in the recently published Studien zur Struktur des Bewusstseins (Hua XLIII).</p>
<p>The aim of this workshop is to systematically and historically investigate the characterization of intentionality as a tendency. Presentations will evaluate the systematic function of the analyses of intentionality as a tendency in the different fields of conscious experience, focusing on how Husserl’s analyses in the newly published Studien relate to alternative analyses on indeterminate intentionality, particularly to be found in the other phenomenological movements (e.g. the Munich and Göttingen circles or post-Husserlian phenomenology) as well as in the fields of philosophy of psychology and psychoanalysis. </p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 05:37:10 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664602635313589</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ October 27, 2022] Talk or similar: Exploring the Divine: Eastern Christian Perspectives on God</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103510</link>
						<description>Venue: 215 5th Street<br/><br/>Speakers at this event: <br/>Joshua Matthan Brown (Messiah College)<br/>Beau Branson (Brescia University)<br/>Tyler McNabb (St. Francis University)<br/>Joshua Brown (University of Birmingham)<br/>Tyler McNabb (University of Macau)<br/><br/><p>Marietta College is pleased to invite three scholars for a panel discussion regarding Eastern Christian conceptions of God and religious knowledge.  Among other things, panelists will address such topics as contemporary arguments for the nonexistence of God, the nature of the divine, the metaphysics of action, religious experience, and contemporary epistemology ... importantly, there will be pizza!</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 05:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664602635313588</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Newberry Seminar on Religion and Culture in the Americas, October 14, 2022</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11082274/newberry-seminar-religion-and-culture-americas-october-14-2022</link>
						<dc:creator>Malachy R. McCarthy</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Seminar</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-09-30T00:00:00-04:00">September 30, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-17T00:00:00-04:00">October 17, 2022</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Illinois</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Mexican History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>Religion and Culture in the Americas Seminar</span></span></span></b></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span>Friday, October 14, 2022 </span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span>3:00-4:30 pm Central Time</span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span>Virtual Seminar, Register for link</span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span><span>Toward Spiritual Motherhood and Racial Affirmation: Whiteness and Mexico’s Upper-Class Católicas, 1937-38</span></span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span><span>Ricardo Alvarez-Pimentel, Baylor University</span></span></b></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>This paper examines how, during the late 1930s, Mexico’s upper-class laywomen used Catholic magazines and religious pedagogical materials to construct a collective sense of whiteness grounded in racial paternalism. It analyzes moralization campaigns geared toward indigenous domestic workers and demonstrates how elite women used the language of morality, religious orthodoxy, and spiritual “motherhood” to develop a uniquely “feminine” white identity. By adopting racialized perceptions of Catholic social action, Mexican católicas affirmed their power within the domestic sphere. At the same time, they used the unspoken language of race to assert themselves as spiritual agents before the Church.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>Respondent</span></span></span></b><span><span><span>: Maggie Elmore, Sam Houston State University</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>This event is free, but all participants must register in advance and space is limited. To register and request a copy of the pre-circulated paper, click </span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><a href="https://reg.learningstream.com/reg/event_page.aspx?ek=0057-0014-4adbb580c8f9489c9b2863e28c83c6e4" rel="nofollow">here</a></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span>. Please do not request a paper unless you plan to attend.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>Sponsors</span></span></span></b><span><span><span>: the Cushwa Center for the Study of American Catholicism at the University of Notre Dame, the McGreal Center at Dominican University, the History Department at Loyola University, the University of Chicago Divinity School, University of Illinois at Chicago, and Wheaton College</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><a href="mailto:scholarlyseminars@newberry.org">scholarlyseminars@newberry.org</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:scholarlyseminars@newberry.org">scholarlyseminars@newberry.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://newberry.org/10142022-ricardo-alvarez-pimentel-baylor-university" target="_blank">https://newberry.org/10142022-ricardo-alvarez-pimentel-baylor-university</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 17:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664602635313587</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FEATURED JOB: Assistant Professor of Judaism- Northwestern University</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11060530/featured-job-assistant-professor-judaism-northwestern</link>
						<dc:creator>Kendra Fuller</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Home Office Notices (Jobs, Reviews)</div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Illinois</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The Religious Studies Department and The Crown Family Center for Jewish and Israel Studies seek to make a full-time, tenure-track appointment at the rank of Assistant Professor in Judaism (specialization open) with an expected start date of September 1, 2023. Successful candidates will have solid basis in classical Judaism, demonstrate teaching excellence, and combine their research interests with questions of theory and method in the study of religion and contribute to the graduate and undergraduate programs of the Religious Studies Department. The position has a 4-course annual teaching load. Applicants must have earned a Ph.D. by the time of appointment, or shortly thereafter.</p><p>To apply, please upload in PDF format a cover letter, 3 letters of recommendation, CV, and writing sample no longer than 25 pages. Applications must be submitted online and will be given primary consideration if received by November 1, 2022.<br/><br/>For details on preparing the application and applying online <a href="https://religious-studies.northwestern.edu/about/open-faculty-positions/judaism-search-2022.html" rel="nofollow">click here</a>. Questions about the position can be addressed to <a href="mailto:relst-chair@northwestern.edu">relst-chair@northwestern.edu</a>.</p><p><em>Northwestern requires all staff and faculty to be vaccinated against COVID-19, subject to limited exceptions. For more information, please visit our </em><a href="https://www.northwestern.edu/coronavirus-covid-19-updates/index.html" rel="nofollow"><em>COVID-19 and Campus Updates</em></a><em> website. Northwestern University is an Equal Opportunity, Affirmative Action Employer of all protected classes, including veterans and individuals with disabilities. Women, racial and ethnic minorities, individuals with disabilities, and veterans are encouraged to apply.</em></p><hr/><p>To submit YOUR job posting, please visit the H-Net Job Guide:<a href="https://www.h-net.org/jobs" rel="nofollow"> https://www.h-net.org/jobs</a></p><p>Featured jobs receive an added boost on H-Announce and H-Net’s social media channels.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><table><tr><td><p><a href="mailto:religious-studies@northwestern.edu">religious-studies@northwestern.edu</a></p></td></tr></table></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php" target="_blank">https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php?id=64094</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 17:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664516225712920</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Fully funded PhD Studentship at the Universities of Edinburgh &amp; Glasgow, UK: “Judaica in Scotland, 1817 – Present: Objects of Faith, Migration and Identity”</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11056082/fully-funded-phd-studentship-universities-edinburgh-glasgow-uk</link>
						<dc:creator>K. Hannah Holtschneider</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Grant</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-01-30T00:00:00-05:00">January 30, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Historic Preservation, Immigration &amp; Migration History / Studies, Jewish History / Studies, Modern European History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>Fully funded AHRC SGSAH CDA Studentship: “</span></span></span></b><span><span><span><span>Judaica in Scotland, 1817 – Present: Objects of Faith, Migration and Identity</span></span></span></span><b><span><span><span>”</span></span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>Application deadline</span></span></span></b><span><span><span> - 5pm on Monday 30 January 2023</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>Award</span></span></span></b><span><span><span> – Annual stipend of £16,062 per year and tuition fees for 3.5 years (FTE). Open to Home and International students </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>PhD</span></span></span></b><span><span><span> – Religious Studies</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The University of Edinburgh, the University of Glasgow and National Museums Scotland are seeking a doctoral student for an AHRC-funded Collaborative Doctoral Award, “<span>Judaica in Scotland, 1817 – Present: Objects of Faith, Migration and Identity</span>”. The project has been awarded funding by the Scottish Graduate School for Arts and Humanities (SGSAH) and will be supervised by Dr Hannah Holtschneider (College of Arts, Humanities and Social Sciences, University of Edinburgh), Dr Mia Spiro (School of Critical Studies, University of Glasgow), and Dr Calum Robertson (Curator, Modern and Military History, National Museums Scotland).</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The studentship will commence on 11 September 2023. We warmly encourage applications from candidates who <span>have an academic background in history, art or material culture studies, or a cognate discipline. Applicants will be expected to show a strong interest in Jewish history and cultural heritage and/or the history and material culture of immigration in Scotland. </span>This is an extraordinary opportunity for a strong PhD student to explore their own research interests, while exploring <span>opportunities to develop a career in either academia or the museums, galleries and archives sector.</span> The studentship is available full or part time, subject to Student Route visa requirements.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The student will be based in the School of Divinity, at the New College campus of the University of Edinburgh, but will also spend considerable time in the School of Critical Studies at the University of Glasgow, and at National Museums Scotland in Chambers Street. There will be a period of funded work internship at National Museums Scotland, which will involve hands-on work with collections, as well as public engagement work.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The award will include a number of training opportunities offered by SGSAH, including their Core Leadership Programme and additional funding to cover travel between partner organisations and related events. This studentship will also benefit from training, support, and networking via the School of Divinity (University of Edinburgh) and the School of Critical Studies (University of Glasgow). The student will be expected to participate in training for collections and museum specific skills at National Museums Scotland.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>Project Details</span></span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>This project investigates objects of Jewish religious observance (Judaica) from the establishment of the first Jewish community in Scotland in 1817 to the present. This will create a richer understanding of the story of Scotland’s Jewish communities, their local, national and international networks, and their place in broader Scottish society. Judaica are found in both religious and domestic settings, and reflect the stories of those who commissioned or acquired them, the environments in which they were made, and relationships between client and maker. Therefore, Judaica represent key evidence to help construct a more nuanced picture of Jewish life.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The aims and objectives of this research project are: </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>To undertake a systematic investigation of the origins of Judaica in Scotland. </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>To explore how stylistic choices communicate cultural and religious identifications.  </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>To apply these findings to the broader contextual knowledge of Jewish communities in Scotland to create a better understanding of inter- and intra-communal, national, and transnational exchanges.</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>To apply this knowledge to the development of collections at NMS that represent religious diversity in Scotland. </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>To inform the interpretation of faith, migration and identity as it applies to minority religious and ethnic groups in anticipation of the reconsideration of the Scotland galleries.</span></span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span> </span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The prevailing historiography of migration in modern Scotland has focused on two balancing narratives: the Scottish diaspora and Christian immigrants that have challenged Scotland’s Presbyterian hegemony. Newer examinations of the experiences of migrant groups, however, reveal a diversity of perspectives on nineteenth and twentieth century Scottish society and the nation’s transcultural connections. <i>Judaica in Scotland </i>showcases the diversity of Scotland’s populations by using material evidence to provide important insights into Jewish religious and social structures between the establishment of Scotland’s first Jewish community in 1817 and now. Jewish communities have always been small in number, yet their substantial impact on Scottish life continues to add to the rich heritage and vibrancy of Scottish religious and cultural life. The various waves of Jewish migration responded not only to persecution in central and eastern Europe, but also to opportunities that led to new beginnings in Scotland. </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>An emerging scholarly interest in the peripheral Jewish communities of the UK shows the importance of understanding the movement of people and ideas, processes of acculturation, and creation and maintenance of religious identities in these contexts. Notably, however, few studies critically examine and incorporate material evidence. The study of material culture nevertheless offers unique opportunities to better understand the nature of Jewish life in Scotland. Judaica – the broad term for objects related to Jewish ritual observance – plays a central role in the life of many Jews in both public and domestic settings. It reflects the story of the Jewish people and exhibits religious and cultural specificities that cast a light on the nature of Jewish experience in Scotland and the wider world. An understanding of what links Jewish devotional objects in Scotland to those who manufacture, import and use them can reveal a range of unexplored interconnections, whether social, economic, religious, cultural or aesthetic.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The key research questions are:</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Where did and does Judaica in Scotland originate? And what are the relationships between the origin of an object and to how it is understood and used?</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>What can the creation and circulation of Judaica tell us about Jewish/non-Jewish relations in Scotland?</span></span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>To what extent can we speak of identifiably or uniquely Scottish Judaica?</span></span></span> </span></span></span></li></ul><p> </p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>Eligibility</span></span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>At the University of Edinburgh, to study at postgraduate level you must normally hold a degree in an appropriate subject, with an excellent or very good classification (equivalent to first or upper second class honours in the UK), plus meet the entry requirements for the specific degree </span></span></span><a href="https://www.ed.ac.uk/studying/postgraduate/degrees/index.php?r=site/view&amp;edition=2022&amp;id=66" rel="nofollow"><span><span><span>programme</span></span></span></a><span><span><span>. In this case, applicants should offer a UK masters, or its international equivalent, with a mark of at least 67% (or equivalent) in your coursework and your dissertation of at least 10,000 words.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The AHRC also expects that applicants to PhD programmes will hold, or be studying towards, a Masters qualification in a relevant discipline; or have relevant professional experience to provide evidence of your ability to undertake independent research. Please ensure you provide details of your academic and professional experience in your application letter.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Experience in the study of religious history and/or Jewish history and of material culture will be of benefit to the project.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>Application Process</span></span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The application will consist of a single Word file or PDF which includes:</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>a brief cover note that includes your full contact details together with the names and contact details of two referees (1 page).</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>a letter explaining your interest in the studentship and outlining your qualifications for it, as well as an indication of the specific areas of the project you would like to develop (2 pages).</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>a curriculum vitae (2 pages).</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>a sample of your writing – this might be an academic essay or another example of your writing style and ability.</span></span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p> </p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>Applications should be emailed to <a href="mailto:pgawards@ed.ac.uk">pgawards@ed.ac.uk</a> no later than 5pm on Monday 30 January 2023.</span></span></span></b><span><span><span> Applicants will be notified if they are being invited to interview by Tuesday 24 May. Interviews of shortlisted candidates will take place at a mutually convenient time via Microsoft Teams. The successful applicant will make an online admissions application for a PhD Religious Studies in the School of Divinity, University of Edinburgh.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>Queries</span></span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>If you have any queries about the application process, please contact: </span></span></span><a href="mailto:pgawards@ed.ac.uk"><span><span><span>pgawards@ed.ac.uk</span></span></span></a></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Informal enquiries relating to the Collaborative Doctoral Award project can be made to Dr Hannah Holtschneider, </span></span></span><a href="mailto:h.holtschneider@ed.ac.uk"><span><span><span>h.holtschneider@ed.ac.uk</span></span></span></a><span><span><span>, Dr Mia Spiro, </span></span></span><a href="mailto:Mia.Spiro@glasgow.ac.uk"><span><span><span>Mia.Spiro@glasgow.ac.uk</span></span></span></a><span><span><span>, or Dr Calum Robertson, </span></span></span><a href="mailto:ca.robertson@nms.ac.uk"><span><span><span>ca.robertson@nms.ac.uk</span></span></span></a><span><span><span>.  </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>Further Information</span></span></span></b><br/><span><span><span>This project will primarily be collections-based, and the successful candidate will be expected to examine and record a broad range of Jewish ritual objects. The focus will be on Jewish collections across Scotland, such as the Scottish Jewish Archives Centre and repositories held by religious organisations, places of worship, and private collections. Data collected from the analysis of objects will relate to design, production and exchange. This information will be used to construct an understanding of Judaica in Scotland and its relevance to the relationships among Jewish communities and wider Scottish society.  </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>In addressing the research questions, the project will investigate a range of ceremonial art and ritual objects found across Scotland. The candidate will thereby work with a range of stakeholders to produce the first systematic study of Judaica in Scotland and unlock this important body of evidence of Scottish Jewish life. Exploring material evidence from the 1800s to the present will enhance understandings of the story of Jews in Scotland, and will inform the future interpretation of objects of minority religions in Scotland at NMS, particularly as the organisation begins the reconsideration of the Scotland galleries.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>As part of the project, the candidate will have the opportunity to identify gaps in NMS collections and develop thinking around the collection of historical and contemporary faith-related objects in Scotland. This will ensure that NMS continues to collect and interpret objects that reflect the diversity of Scottish society in the past and present.</span></span></span> <span><span><span>They will also be required to familiarise themselves with Jewish museums in the United Kingdom and Europe in order to establish typological differences and similarities with material examined in Scotland. This may require research trips to institutions such as the Jewish Museum London, the Manchester Jewish Museum, and the Jewish Historical Museum in Amsterdam.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Tracing the history of the objects in the wider context of Jewish and Scottish cultural and religious history will necessarily entail an application of current theoretical approaches in the interpretation of material culture. Thereby the student will develop their competence in archival research and the study of the history and provenance of objects. Researching and recording object biographies will also be instrumental in analysing the cultural context within which the material was created and used.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr Hannah Holtschneider, Senior Lecturer in Jewish Studies, University of Edinburgh, UK</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:h.holtschneider@ed.ac.uk">h.holtschneider@ed.ac.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.ed.ac.uk/profile/hannah-holtschneider" target="_blank">https://www.ed.ac.uk/profile/hannah-holtschneider</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 17:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664516225712919</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ December 13, 2022] Conference or similar: Saint Francis' Legacy of Peace for Our Times</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103438</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p>We are living in complex times and contexts that affect our perception of many areas of life, from security, politics, economics, ecology to ecclesiology. The search for solutions in the spiritual and intellectual Franciscan tradition has accompanied European history for almost 800 years. The conference aims to recall the impulses from Franciscan sources and to contextualize them in the problems of today's globalized world. The conference is sponsored by the St. Francis Ways Project. In addition to physical journeys (camino), the project team try to find inspiration in the figure of St. Francis of Assisi virtually, through encounters of people whom Francis inspires to understand the good and beautiful human life. The planned conference is based on the conviction that the physical and virtual ways to St. Francis lead to a meaningful goal.</p>
<p><strong>December 13, 2022</strong></p>
<p>On-line conference</p>
<p>https://www.saintfrancisways.eu/</p>
<p>The specific online platform and access will be sent to participants.</p>
<p>Papers on the following topics/areas are welcome:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Franciscan quest for peace</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Francis and the encounter with suffering</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Philosophical inspirations of the Franciscan tradition</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The Franciscan tradition and art</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Francis as an inspiration for ecclesiology (the field hospital church)</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Papers on related topics will also be considered.</p>
<p><strong>Deadline for abstracts:</strong></p>
<p>October, 31, 2022</p>
<p>Abstracts for Papers must clearly articulate the significance of the work, and show evidence of clear results. Preliminary reports on work in progress will not be considered.</p>
<p>Abstracts Submission Details</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>All abstracts to be submitted via email: jan.hrkut@ku.sk</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Abstracts must be submitted in English.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Abstracts must not exceed 1500 characters.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>There is no fee for submitting an abstract.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>• Abstracts should not contain any tables or figures. The use of abbreviations and acronyms should be kept to a minimum.</p>
<p>Authors will be informed about acceptance of their abstracts until November 15, 2022.</p>
<p>Honorary Chair of the Conference:                                                                                      Mons. Paolo Giulietti (Archbishop of Lucca, Italy)</p>
<p>Conference Manager:                                                                                                     Raffaella Rossi (Saint Francis Ways, Terni, Italy)</p>
<p>Research Executive:                                                                                                               Jan Hrkut (Catholic University, Ruzomberok, Slovakia)</p></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664429828318016</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ December 13, 2022] Conference or similar: Saint Francis' Legacy of Peace for Our Times</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103438</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p>We are living in complex times and contexts that affect our perception of many areas of life, from security, politics, economics, ecology to ecclesiology. The search for solutions in the spiritual and intellectual Franciscan tradition has accompanied European history for almost 800 years. The conference aims to recall the impulses from Franciscan sources and to contextualize them in the problems of today's globalized world. The conference is sponsored by the St. Francis Ways Project. In addition to physical journeys (camino), the project team try to find inspiration in the figure of St. Francis of Assisi virtually, through encounters of people whom Francis inspires to understand the good and beautiful human life. The planned conference is based on the conviction that the physical and virtual ways to St. Francis lead to a meaningful goal.</p>
<p><strong>December 13, 2022</strong></p>
<p>On-line conference</p>
<p>https://www.saintfrancisways.eu/</p>
<p>The specific online platform and access will be sent to participants.</p>
<p>Papers on the following topics/areas are welcome:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Franciscan quest for peace</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Francis and the encounter with suffering</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Philosophical inspirations of the Franciscan tradition</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The Franciscan tradition and art</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Francis as an inspiration for ecclesiology (the field hospital church)</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Papers on related topics will also be considered.</p>
<p><strong>Deadline for abstracts:</strong></p>
<p>October, 31, 2022</p>
<p>Abstracts for Papers must clearly articulate the significance of the work, and show evidence of clear results. Preliminary reports on work in progress will not be considered.</p>
<p>Abstracts Submission Details</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>All abstracts to be submitted via email: jan.hrkut@ku.sk</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Abstracts must be submitted in English.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Abstracts must not exceed 1500 characters.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>There is no fee for submitting an abstract.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>• Abstracts should not contain any tables or figures. The use of abbreviations and acronyms should be kept to a minimum.</p>
<p>Authors will be informed about acceptance of their abstracts until November 15, 2022.</p>
<p>Honorary Chair of the Conference:                                                                                      Mons. Paolo Giulietti (Archbishop of Lucca, Italy)</p>
<p>Conference Manager:                                                                                                     Raffaella Rossi (Saint Francis Ways, Terni, Italy)</p>
<p>Research Executive:                                                                                                               Jan Hrkut (Catholic University, Ruzomberok, Slovakia)</p></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664429828318015</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP | Panel &quot;Spiritual Practices, Arts, and Communal Resilience in the Anthropocene Asia&quot; at ASLE + AESS 2023 Conference: Reclaiming the Commons</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11053367/cfp-panel-spiritual-practices-arts-and-communal-resilience</link>
						<dc:creator>Mankun Liu</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-07-09T00:00:00-04:00">July 9, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-07-12T00:00:00-04:00">July 12, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Oregon</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Art, Art History &amp; Visual Studies, Indigenous Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Theatre &amp; Performance History / Studies, Asian History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><b><span>Call for Papers</span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><a href="https://www.asle.org/calls-for-papers/asle-2023-spiritual-practices-arts-resilience-anthropocene-asia/" rel="nofollow"><b><span>Panel: Spiritual Practices, Arts, and Communal Resilience in </span></b><b><span>the </span></b><b><span>Anthropocene Asia</span></b></a></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>at</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><a href="https://www.asle.org/conference/biennial-conference/" rel="nofollow"><span>ASLE + AESS 2023 Conference: Reclaiming the Commons</span></a></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>July 9-12, 2023 in Portland, Oregon</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><b><span>Deadline</span></b><span>: 5 December 2022</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>This panel highlights the role of Asian animist traditions and spiritual practices in the counter-worlding of the Anthropocene. Taking contemporary visual and performing arts as a vantage point of observation, it </span><span>explores what common grounds are </span><span>being </span><span>formed </span><span>among today’s arts</span><span>, community resilience, environmental stewardship</span><span>, and ontological inquiries</span><span> when artists </span><span>work with</span><span> local communities </span><span>in practicing and politicizing</span><span> ritual dancing, chanting, rhyming, object-making, trance, healing, and worshiping, among other</span><span> spiritual traditions. </span><span>We seek </span><span>insightful interpretations of such alliance </span><span>from multiple ontological</span><span>, </span><span>sociopolitical, and ecospiritual perspectives</span><span>—f</span><span>or example, how </span><span>it</span> <span>enliven</span><span>s</span><span> diverse cosmological worlds in Asia and their biocultural manifestations in local ecosystems</span><span>;</span> <span>what ways of mediation between humans, nonhuman species, potent geographies, and incorporeal beings </span><span>it</span><span> offer</span><span>s</span><span>; how such mediations shape the experience and expressions of more-than-human sociality</span><span>;</span><span> and </span><span>how these processes </span><span>empower local communities’ political and ethical responses to the Anthropocenic climate change, biocultural extinction, and other forms of slow violence.</span> <span>The panel encourages scholars, art practitioners, activists, and community members from Asia to work collaboratively in bringing spiritual issues into </span><span>visibility and </span><span>intelligibility.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>The theme of this panel may be addressed in relation to, but not limited by, the following issues:</span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span>Comm</span><span>un</span><span>al, ecological, and cosmopolitical roles of spiritual practices</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Inheritance and transformation of indigenous and folk spiritual traditions </span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Intersections between contemporary artistic media and spiritual mediumship</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>The spiritual</span><span> and </span><span>more-than-human turn of visual </span><span>and performing </span><span>art</span><span>s</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Spiritual practices as means of more-than-human/biosemiotic communication</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Spiritual and artistic mediation of diverse cosmological/ontological worlds</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Spirits, afterlives, and nonlives</span> <span>as historical and political agents of the Anthropocene</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Channeling materiality and spirituality in ecoartistic analyses</span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span>Please submit your proposal for a 15-minute presentation (within 300 words) and a brief bio (within 200 words) by <strong>5 December 2022</strong> to be considered for the panel. Submissions and questions can be directed to </span></span><span><span><a href="mailto:artsnecospirituality@gmail.com"><span>artsnecospirituality@gmail.com</span></a></span></span><span><span>. </span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><span><span><span><span><span>Mankun Liu, PhD candidate, City University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong;</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Pranab K Mandal, PhD candidate, Jadavpur University, India</span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:artsnecospirituality@gmail.com">artsnecospirituality@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.asle.org/calls-for-papers/asle-2023-spiritual-practices-arts-resilience-anthropocene-asia/" target="_blank">https://www.asle.org/calls-for-papers/asle-2023-spiritual-practices-arts-resilience-anthropocene-asia/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 17:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664429828318014</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – September 28th, 2022</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-september-28th-2022/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find a couple of job listings, two Call for Papers, and links to multiple Fellowship opportunities.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 38!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Assistant Professor, Religious Studies (Full-time, Tenure-Track)</h4>



<p>Fairfield University, US</p>



<p>Deadline: October 17<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://ffd.wd1.myworkdayjobs.com/en-US/EmploymentOpportunities/job/Fairfield-CT/Assistant-Professor--Religious-Studies_JR0001458-1">Assistant Professor, Religious Studies (myworkdayjobs.com)</a></p>



<h4>Lecturer in Religious Studies at the University of Amsterdam (Possibility of Renewal)</h4>



<p>University of Amsterdam, Netherlands</p>



<p>Deadline: October 23, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/Docent-Religiewetenschappen/754949402/?fbclid=IwAR2KdhlRgxnTF7XnqoOVmc7jqwu5Xf5RD9X9-wT5VRwv4ERKQPscjZQuxzQ">Lecturer Religious Studies (uva.nl)</a></p>



<h2>Call for Paper:</h2>



<h4>The Heidelberg Center for American Studies Interdisciplinary American Studies Ph.D. Conference</h4>



<p>University of Heidelberg, Germany</p>



<p>Deadline: November 15, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.hca.uni-heidelberg.de/spring/applicationspring_en.html">Application – Heidelberg Center for American Studies (HCA) (uni-heidelberg.de)</a></p>



<h4>2022 Graduate Student Book Review Colloquium on Islamic and Middle Eastern Studies</h4>



<p>Virtual</p>



<p>Deadline: October 1, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://themaydan.com/2022/08/2022bookreviewcolloquium/">[CFA] 2022 Graduate Student Book Review Colloquium on Islamic and Middle Eastern Studies-Virtual-December 8, 2022 – Maydan (themaydan.com)</a></p>



<h2>Fellowships:</h2>



<h4>Centre for Studies in Religion and Society</h4>



<p>University of Victoria</p>



<p>Multiple Fellowship opportunities ranging from Graduate student to Post-doc to Special Interests.</p>



<p>Deadline: Various depending on program choice</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.uvic.ca/research/centres/csrs/fellowships-awards/index.php">Fellowships &amp; awards – University of Victoria (uvic.ca)</a></p>



<h4>Postdoctoral Fellow in Humanities</h4>



<p>Asian University for Women, Bangladesh</p>



<p>Deadline: January 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10948597/featured-job-postdoctoral-fellow-humanities-andrew-w-mellon">FEATURED JOB: Postdoctoral Fellow in Humanities (Andrew W. Mellon Fellows)- Asian University for Women | H-Announce | H-Net</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664429828318013</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>SPIRITUAL PRACTICES, ARTS, AND COMMUNAL RESILIENCE IN THE ANTHROPOCENE ASIA</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/09/26/spiritual-practices-arts-and-communal-resilience-in-the-anthropocene-asia</link>
						<dc:creator>mpranabk@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Wednesday, September 28, 2022 - 9:45am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Mankun Liu and Pranab K Mandal</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:artsnecospirituality@gmail.com">artsnecospirituality@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/ecocriticism-and-environmental-studies">ecocriticism and environmental studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/theatre">theatre</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/world-literatures-and-indigenous-studies">world literatures and indigenous studies</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>December 5, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>This ASLE + AESS 2023 CONFERENCE PANEL highlights the role of Asian animist traditions and spiritual practices in the counter-worlding of the Anthropocene. Taking contemporary visual and performing arts as a vantage point of observation, it explores what common grounds are being formed among today’s arts, community resilience, environmental stewardship, and ontological inquiries when artists work with local communities in practicing and politicizing ritual dancing, chanting, rhyming, object-making, trance, healing, and worshiping, among other spiritual traditions. We seek insightful interpretations of such alliance from multiple ontological, sociopolitical, and ecospiritual perspectives—for example, how it enlivens diverse cosmological worlds in Asia and their biocultural manifestations in local ecosystems; what ways of mediation between humans, nonhuman species, potent geographies, and incorporeal beings it offers; how such mediations shape the experience and expressions of more-than-human sociality; and how these processes empower local communities’ political and ethical responses to the Anthropocenic climate change, biocultural extinction, and other forms of slow violence. The panel encourages scholars, art practitioners, activists, and community members from Asia to work collaboratively in bringing spiritual issues into visibility and intelligibility.</p>
<p>The theme of this panel may be addressed in relation to, but not limited by, the following issues:</p>
<p>• Communal, ecological, and cosmopolitical roles of spiritual practices<br/>• Inheritance and transformation of indigenous and folk spiritual traditions<br/>• Intersections between contemporary artistic media and spiritual mediumship<br/>• The spiritual and more-than-human turn of visual and performing arts<br/>• Spiritual practices as means of more-than-human/biosemiotic communication<br/>• Spiritual and artistic mediation of diverse cosmological/ontological worlds<br/>• Spirits, afterlives, and nonlives as historical and political agents of the Anthropocene<br/>• Channeling materiality and spirituality in ecoartistic analyses</p>
<p>Please submit your proposal for a 15-minute presentation (within 300 words) and a brief bio (within 200 words) by 5 December 2022 to be considered for the panel. Submissions and questions can be directed to <a href="mailto:artsnecospirituality@gmail.com">artsnecospirituality@gmail.com</a>.</p>
<p>Conference venue: Oregon Convention Center, Portland, Oregon</p>
<p>Conference dates: July 9-12, 2023</p>
<p> </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 17:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664429828318012</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Permanently Withdrawn: Examining the Histories, Identities, and Representations of Black Nones in the U.S</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/09/26/permanently-withdrawn-examining-the-histories-identities-and-representations-of-black</link>
						<dc:creator>Jerry Rafiki Jenkins</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Wednesday, September 28, 2022 - 9:30am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Jerry Rafiki Jenkins/Palomar College</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:jjenkins@palomar.edu">jjenkins@palomar.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/african-american">african-american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/popular-culture">popular culture</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>December 16, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>A growing percentage of the American population is leaving the church and opting to let go of religious and spiritual frameworks to find social and personal meaning and even economic success, and this is true for African Americans who would have had no other option than to be “churched.” This development is noteworthy because much of what it means to be “black” in the United States, at least from a Western standpoint, is immersed in religious or spiritual frameworks that claim that people of African descent are inherently religious or spiritual. To be sure, it is often assumed that being religious is synonymous (ontologically) with being black and African. This essentialization of black culture is problematic because there is a growing number of black Americans who have chosen to set religion or spirituality aside, and in some cases, they are doing it openly as a matter of protest. Considering the changing trajectory of religious thought and expression in the United States, there are also many black Americans who have expressed interests in non-Abrahamic frameworks that do not include worshiping a deity such as Humanism, Pantheism, and the nontheist sects of Buddhism and Hinduism. Likewise, the US has seen an increase in organizations that are black and secular (e.g., Black Skeptics, Black Nonbelievers, Black Freethinkers, Black People Beyond Belief, and Affinis Humanity Coalition), and most of these groups have been established and managed by black women, who tend to be one of the most religious demographics in the US. These women have made it possible for those who are without reliance or dependence upon religion or god(s) to say so in public and in private. We believe that this organizational aspect is significant and represents a critical part of the legacy of the Civil Rights Movement that is often overlooked because of the role that Christianity <em>had</em> to play in the Movement’s mission. Consequently, there is an emerging cadre of writers, activists, and scholars who have been associated with these groups and are willing to be seen and heard as black nones or even atheists (e.g., Affinis, Norm Allen, Jamila Bey, Christopher Cameron, Candace Gorham, Sikivu Hutchinson, Anthony Pinn, Mandisa Thomas, Kim Veal, and Ayanna Watson).</p>
<p>We believe that this new wave of black expression is part of a larger social movement in the U.S. where individuals and collectives are unapologetically moving away from traditional religious expression. This collection is a clarion call that the terms for black expression and perhaps for social justice could take on greater depth and meaning for the next generation who may be less likely to embrace or stay loyal to traditional black religious and social frameworks that deny the full expression of their humanity. Thus, in this call for papers, we invite scholars, writers, artists, activists, former and current clergy, health professionals, and anyone interested in examining the identity of black Nones in America to submit abstracts for this collection. Given that some of the greatest cultural icons of America and black America, such as Octavia E. Butler, bell hooks, Langston Hughes, A. Phillip Randolph, Alice Walker, and many others did not stay committed to religious or spiritual frameworks that did not support the full humanity of black people, we seek works that will openly challenge dominant ways of thinking about the relationship between blackness and religiosity. We hope to edit and publish an anthology that will demonstrate that belief in a god is not a requirement for black advancement or for one to be authentically black, since blackness is multi-faceted and constantly evolving. </p>
<p><strong>Submissions:</strong> An abstract (250-500 words) is due December 15, 2022. If the abstract is accepted, the complete paper (3,500–6,500 words) or work of art is due August 1, 2023.  Please include your full name, institutional affiliation, tentative title, and email address (not included in the 250-500 text limit) at the beginning of your file. We ask that you upload your submissions to <a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1ndShB2WjLK9M4MxExACqxUpLUjsvgVLw">Black Nones CFP_2022 - Google Drive</a> and that your submissions, depending on the work, follow the guidelines of the MLA 9th edition. Please email any queries to either Jerry Rafiki Jenkins (Rafiki) (<a href="mailto:jjenkins@palomar.edu">jjenkins@palomar.edu</a>) or annalise fonza (<a href="mailto:ahfonza@cpp.edu">ahfonza@cpp.edu</a>). </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 17:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664429828318011</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New Podcast - En-Gender Conversations</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11039181/new-podcast-en-gender-conversations</link>
						<dc:creator>Jessica  Albrecht</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Online Digital Resources</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Colonial and Post-Colonial History / Studies, Indigenous Studies, Race / Ethnic Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The En-Gender Collective now publishes a podcast, called "En-Gender Conversations".</p><p>It is available on spotify, apple podcasts and via our feed (<a href="https://engenderacademia.com/en-gender-converstations-podcast/" rel="nofollow">https://engenderacademia.com/en-gender-converstations-podcast/</a>). </p><p>In the first season, "Feel Good Academia", we interviewed scholars who started projects within academia or at the brinks between academia and 'the outside world', such as writing groups, podcasts, youtube channels, etc. </p><p>Listen in to get inspired and meet amazing scholars!</p><p>The second season, "Gender in the discplines", focusses on early career scholars' research and highlights the challenges as well as the good parts we experience in academia. </p><p>If you want to join, please contact us.</p><p>If you want to help us, you can support us via our patreon page: <a href="https://www.patreon.com/Engender" rel="nofollow">https://www.patreon.com/Engender</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:engenderingthepast@gmail.com">engenderingthepast@gmail.com</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 17:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664343427948366</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>&quot;Contesting Authenticity in Literature, 1200-1700&quot; 2023 Conference</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/09/25/contesting-authenticity-in-literature-1200-1700-2023-conference</link>
						<dc:creator>rmenmuir@aol.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Monday, October 3, 2022 - 8:36am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Rebecca Menmuir / Institute of English Studies (IES) London</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:authenticity2023@gmail.com">authenticity2023@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/classical-studies">classical studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/medieval">medieval</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/renaissance">renaissance</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/translation-studies">translation studies</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>November 11, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>“CONTESTING AUTHENTICITY IN LITERATURE, 1200-1700”</strong></p>
<p>30-31 March 2023 / Senate House, University of London</p>
<p>Event details and further information can be found at &lt;authenticity2023.wordpress.com&gt;. Papers will be given in-person, and attendance will be hybrid.</p>
<p>This two-day conference will explore the concept of “contesting authenticity” in later medieval and early modern literature, including both the production and ongoing reception of texts of contested authenticity. Proposals are welcome which consider literature in any language, including translations.</p>
<p>Topics may include, but are not limited to:<br/>● Literary fakes, forgeries, and pseudo-texts;<br/>● Continuations and supplements;<br/>● Translation as (in)authentic;<br/>● Imitation/imitatio and authenticity;<br/>● Plagiarism vs forgery;<br/>● Issues of truth in literature (e.g. narrative authenticity);<br/>● The reception of medieval and early modern inauthentic texts;<br/>● The practice of contesting literary authenticity;<br/>● Scholarly practices and methodologies;</p>
<p>● Languages of (in)authenticity.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Types of proposals accepted:</strong></p>
<p>Individual paper proposals: please include a 150-300 word abstract.<br/>Panel proposal (3-4 speakers): please provide a panel title, brief overview of the panel theme, and a 150-300 word abstract for each paper.</p>
<p><strong>Please submit all abstracts to Rebecca Menmuir (<a href="mailto:authenticity2023@gmail.com">authenticity2023@gmail.com</a>) by </strong><strong>Friday 11th November 2022.</strong></p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 12:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1664343427948365</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
