<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 08:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 08:30:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>CfP - EASR 2023: Practices, tools, and ecology of magic-shamanic traditions across pre-modern and modern Monsoon Asia</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12099033/cfp-easr-2023-practices-tools-and-ecology-magic-shamanic</link>
						<dc:creator>Paolo E. Rosati</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-12-27T00:00:00-05:00">December 27, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-01-31T00:00:00-05:00">January 31, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Lithuania</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Anthropology, Asian History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, South Asian History / Studies, Southeast Asian History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><div><div><div><span><span>Dear all, if you would like to present a paper during the <span><b>European Association for the Study of Religion 2023 conference </b></span>in Vilnius (4th to 8th September), and it feets with the panel</span></span></div><div><span><span><span><b>Practices, tools, and ecology of magic-shamanic traditions across pre-modern and modern Monsoon Asia</b></span></span></span></div><div><span><span>please upload your proposal thorugh EASR 20223 website <span><a href="https://www.easr2023.org/call-for-papers/?fbclid=IwAR1LnLm0ahIhzdVOE2lhusU_nbjvc0luEbwavGOCPZvkiPeC7P7SLeefvik" rel="nofollow">https://www.easr2023.org/call-for-papers/</a></span></span></span><div><div> </div></div></div><div><span><span>deadline is on 31st January 2023</span></span></div><div><span><span>or fell free to contact me at <a href="mailto:paoloe.rosati@gmail.com">paoloe.rosati@gmail.com</a> (2-3 days before the deadline)</span></span></div><div> </div><div><div><strong><span>Paper proposals must consist of:</span></strong></div><ul><li><div><span>a paper title</span></div></li><li><div><span>the name/s and email address/es of author/s</span></div></li><li><div><span>a short abstract of fewer than 300 characters</span></div></li><li><div><span>a long abstract of fewer than 300 words</span></div></li></ul></div><div> </div><div><span><span><span><b>Short abstract:</b></span> This panel aims to shed light on tools, environments and ecology of magic-shamanic contexts in mainstream Indic, tantric, vernacular, and tribal religions across Monsoon Asia. Perspective authors are expected to focus on that practices often labelled as phenomena outside the mainstream religiosity.</span></span></div><div> </div><div><span><span><span><b>Abstract: </b></span>This panel considers Monsoon Asia as a geographical area—which includes the Indian subcontinent, Tibet, mainland and maritime Southeast Asia, and Southern China—where several religious practices are shared, hence, a socio-cultural unity of the region is marked. In fact, Indic mainstream (e.g. Buddhism, Hinduism, Jainism), tantric, vernacular, and tribal religions, share several socio-religious traits whose origin could be traced back to an ancient common, and complex substratum. The resilience of magic-shamanic elements is among these common traits.</span></span></div><div><span><span>This panel aims to shed light on that (material or intangible) instruments, which have been used as ritual, magic, or shamanic tools since pre-modern history of Monsoon Asia. Indeed, usually mastering magic and shamanic powers is closely related to meditation, yogic practices, severe penances, manipulation of bodily fluids, the consumption of intoxicating substances, the use of bones and skulls as talismans, the use of ashes, mantras, spells and spell-books, geometric diagrams (such as <span><i>maṇḍala</i></span>s and <span><i>yantra</i></span>s), music instruments (particularly drums and other percussions), etc. Panel’s papers discuss in depth the role of these and other tools in magic-shamanic contexts and how they affected practices such as ecstatic possession, shapeshifting, trance and other altered states of consciousness, healing and/or harmful capacities, alchemy, divination (such as scapulimancy and plastromancy) in mainstream, tantric, folk, and tribal traditions across pre-modern and modern Monsoon Asia. Furthermore, this panel invites to analyze the ecology of magic-shamanic contexts in order to better understand the role of the <span><i>locus sacer</i></span> as a sacred space where the practitioners can cross the borders with the supra-human world or may reach the enlightenment or other transcendental states.</span></span></div><div><span><span>Perspective authors are expected to use both empirical and theoretical methodology and to engage the subject with a multidisciplinary approach, considering disciplines such as textual studies, history, art history, archaeology, ethnography, anthropology, folkloric studies, religious studies, etc.</span></span></div></div></div></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Paolo E. Rosati, PhD</p><p><a href="mailto:paoloe.rosati@gmail.com">paoloe.rosati@gmail.com</a></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:paoloe.rosati@gmail.com">paoloe.rosati@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.easr2023.org/" target="_blank">https://www.easr2023.org/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 20:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1672814227157068</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – December 27th, 2022</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-december-27th-2022/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find 2 jobs, and a Call For Papers.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 34!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Robert H. N. Ho Family Foundation Program in Buddhist Studies – Public Scholars program</h4>



<p>Deadline: January 11, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.acls.org/competitions/the-robert-h-n-ho-family-foundation-buddhism-public-scholars/">The Robert H. N. Ho Family Foundation Buddhism Public Scholars – ACLS</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor: Department of Religious Studies – Focus on Buddhism and expertise in South and Southeast Asia (3-year teaching appointment, non-Tenure track, possibility of renewal)</h4>



<p>University of Virginia, US</p>



<p>Deadline: January 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.insidehighered.com/job/2642959/assistant-professor-general-faculty-department-of-religious-studies/">Assistant Professor, General Faculty – Department of Religious Studies job with University of Virginia | 2642959 (insidehighered.com)</a></p>



<h4>AAR/SBL Job Forum</h4>



<p><a href="https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search">https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search</a></p>



<h2>Call For Papers:</h2>



<h4><em>CrossCurrents </em>journal – “Queer Muslim Media”</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.aprilonline.org/cfps/">CFPs – April Online</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1672295825776266</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
