<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 12:31:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 12:31:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>American Academy of Religion - Eastern International Region Conference CFP</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11638349/american-academy-religion-eastern-international-region</link>
						<dc:creator>Chris Miller</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-01T00:00:00-04:00">November 1, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-01T00:00:00-05:00">February 1, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Canada</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Ontario</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Anthropology, Islamic History / Studies, Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Sociology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><b>2023 Eastern International Regional Meeting of the American Academy of Religion</b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b>May 6-7, 2023</b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b>Queen’s University </b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b>Kingston, Ontario K7L 3N6</b></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><b>Deadline for submissions is February 1, 2023</b></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span>The Eastern International Region of the AAR invites you to submit proposals for the 2023 Regional Meeting. The theme for the 2023 Conference</span> is <b>The Other, Persecution and Response. </b><span>We are interested in exploring how </span>logics of otherness express themselves in religious contexts and the responses that they elicit<span>, such as othering via persecution or otherness as self-identification, from theological perspectives to political ideologies and from media to text. </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Related topics could include approaches from queer studies, decolonial religions, and social movements; persecution-response intersection across Buddhism, Hinduism, Christianity, Islam, and other religions; creative re-conceptualizations of persecution and response in the study of religions, literary analysis, and popular culture; intersections between nationalism and gender, race, sexuality; the use of science in support of nationalist politics (e.g., eugenics); religion, violence, and extremism; the nature of religious change and secularization or fundamentalism across traditions. Proposals that do not relate to the 2023 conference theme are also welcome. All methodological approaches and areas of study are encouraged. We welcome papers that address these issues from a range of different academic disciplines and methods. </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Scholars from any region or association may submit a proposal. Only proposals received by the deadline will be considered for inclusion in the program. </span><span>Undergraduate-only panels are encouraged – please see instructions below. The Program Committee also welcomes proposals for non-traditional sessions such as roundtables, dialogues, book discussions, etc.</span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><b>FORMAT FOR PROPOSALS</b></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span>One-page abstract (250 words maximum) describing the nature of the paper or panel. </span></span></li><li><span><span>Cover page that includes the submitter’s full name, title, institution, status at the institution (undergraduate, graduate student, faculty, staff, etc.), phone number, and email address. </span></span></li><li><span><span>If you require technological support for your presentation/panel (such as an internet connection or audio and projection equipment), you must note this in your proposal.</span></span></li><li><span><span>For panel proposals, identify the primary contact person. </span></span></li><li><span><span>Proposals must be sent to <a href="mailto:eirexec@gmail.com">eirexec@gmail.com</a> by the February 1, 2023 deadline </span></span></li></ul><p> </p><p><span><span><b>ADDITIONAL INFORMATION</b></span></span></p><p><span><span>As a general rule, the Region discourages panels comprised of scholars from a single institution. Exceptions to this rule would include a presentation from a research team or a panel based on other types of collaborative research, or an undergraduate-only panel (see below).</span></span></p><p><span><span>Presentations are limited to 20 minutes, with 10 minutes allowed for questions. </span></span></p><p><span><span><b>EIR PARTNERS</b></span></span></p><p><span><span>The EIR will once again meet concurrently with SCRIPT (the Society for Comparative Research on Iconic and Performative Texts). Proposals for SCRIPT papers should respond to the call for papers at <a href="https:///C:/Users/jwwatts/Google%20Drive/J%20career/Conferences/EIR/www.script-site.net">www.script-site.net</a>.</span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><b>UNDERGRADUATE PANELS</b></span></span></p><p><span><span>The EIR welcomes submissions from undergraduates in the field of Religious Studies or on the theme of the conference. Presentations in undergraduate sessions must be 15 minutes long. Each proposal should contain the following in a single e-mail attachment in Word format:</span></span></p><ul><li><span><span>One-page abstract (300 words maximum) describing the nature of the paper or panel </span></span></li><li><span><span>Letter from a faculty member who has supervised the student’s work  </span></span></li><li><span><span>Cover page that includes the student’s full name, institution, phone number, e-mail, and mailing address. For panel proposals, identify the contact person </span></span></li></ul><p><span><span>Please send your proposal to <a href="mailto:eirexec@gmail.com">eirexec@gmail.com</a>. The deadline for Undergraduate Panel submissions is February 1, 2023.</span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><b>STUDENT PAPER COMPETITION</b></span></span></p><p><span><span>Graduate and undergraduate students in the Eastern International Region are invited to enter the student paper competition. Please note that to be eligible, the student must attend a college or university in the Eastern International Region (Ontario, Quebec, Western Pennsylvania and New York). The graduate student award and the undergraduate student award will be formally presented at the business meeting during the conference. </span></span></p><p><span><span>To enter the competition, please attach a short note to your proposal indicating that you wish to enter your paper into the contest. The deadline for proposals is February 1, 2023, and the final draft of the paper must then be submitted to Chris Miller, Regional Coordinator for the EIR at <a href="mailto:chris.miller@uwaterloo.ca">chris.miller@uwaterloo.ca</a> by April 1, 2023. To be eligible for this award the student must present the entire paper at the meeting, which means the paper and presentation must conform to the respective time limits.</span></span></p><p><span><span>For more information about the conference, visit our website (<a href="https://eiraar.org/" rel="nofollow">https://eiraar.org/</a>) or email us at <a href="mailto:eirexec@gmail.com">eirexec@gmail.com</a>. Any questions can also be directed to the EIR Coordinator, Chris Miller, at <a href="mailto:chris.miller@uwaterloo.ca">chris.miller@uwaterloo.ca</a>.  </span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Chris Miller</p><p>Regionally Elected Coordinator - EIR</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:eirexec@gmail.com">eirexec@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://eiraar.org/" target="_blank">https://eiraar.org/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 18:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1668062231404056</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>&quot;Confession, Loyalty, and National Indifference&quot; Forum Launch</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11646797/confession-loyalty-and-national-indifference-forum-launch</link>
						<dc:creator>Liliya Berezhnaya</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Event</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-16T00:00:00-05:00">November 16, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Borderlands, Contemporary History, European History / Studies, Eastern Europe History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>This is the online launch of the thematic forum "Confession, Loyalty, and National Indifference," (Ab Imperio, 2, 2022). The Forum includes five articles that address the problem of emerging collective identity through the entanglement of complementing and conflicting forms of groupness: religious, political, and ethnic. The introductory essay conceptually frames these studies in terms of national indifference and confessional ambiguity, underscoring the role of religious collective identities in forging other forms of groupness–ethnocultural and political.</p><p>16th November 2022, at 13:00 (GMT+1)</p><p>Participants:</p><p>Liliya Berezhnaya (University of Münster)<br/>Catherine Gibson (University of Tartu)<br/>Irina Paert (University of Tartu)<br/>Darius Staliūnas (Institute for Lithuanian History)<br/>James A. Kapaló (University College Cork)</p><p>Andrey Shishkov (University of Tartu)</p><p> </p><p>Registration link: <a href="https://fienta.com/online-discussion-confession-loyalty-and-national-indifference" rel="nofollow">https://fienta.com/online-discussion-confession-loyalty-and-national-indifference</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr. Liliya Berezhnaya, Westfälische Wilhelms-Universität Münster, Historisches Seminar - Abteilung für Osteuropäische Geschichte<br/>Telefon: 0251 / 83 24122 (Sekretariat), E-Mail: <a href="mailto:lbere_01@uni-muenster.de">lbere_01@uni-muenster.de</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:lbere_01@uni-muenster.de">lbere_01@uni-muenster.de</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://fienta.com/online-discussion-confession-loyalty-and-national-indifference" target="_blank">https://fienta.com/online-discussion-confession-loyalty-and-national-indifference</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 18:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1668062231404055</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Book presentation (online): 'Memory and Religion from a Post-Secular Perspective'</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11632923/book-presentation-online-memory-and-religion-post-secular</link>
						<dc:creator>Ewelina Szpak</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Event</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-14T00:00:00-05:00">November 14, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Poland</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Anthropology, Cultural History / Studies, Eastern Europe History / Studies, Holocaust, Genocide, and Memory Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Institute of European Network Remembrance and Solidarity invites for an <strong>online presentation of a book 'Memory and Religion from a Post-Secular Perspective'</strong> - one of three titles included in the <strong>book series “European Remembrance and Solidarity” </strong>launched in 2022, in cooperation with Routledge.</p><p>The meeting with editors and authors of the book <strong>will be held online on 14 November 2022 on 2:00 PM - 3:30 PM CET </strong>and <strong>hosted by Michał Łuczewski </strong>- professor at the Institute of Sociology at the University of Warsaw, former Deputy Director of the Center for Thought of John Paul II in Warsaw.<br/>During the discussion we will try to answer the following questions: does religion interact with cultural memory and contemporary historical politics? And if so, how the interactions between the religious and the secular produce new memory forms and content in the heterogenous societies of the present-day world?</p><p><em>The collective volume 'Memory and Religion from a Post-Secular Perspective', edited by Yuliya Yurchuk and Zuzanna Bogumił argues that religion is a system of significant meanings that have an impact on other systems and spheres of social life, including cultural memory.  The editors call for a postsecular turn in memory studies to provide a more reflective and meaningful approach to the constant interplay between the religious and the secular. This opens up new perspectives on the intersection of memory and religion and helps memory scholars become more aware of the religious roots of the language they are using in their studies of memory. The cases analysed demonstrate that religion has a significant impact on cultural memory, family memory, and the contemporary politics of history in secularized societies. At the same time, politics, grassroots movements, and different secular agents and processes have so much influence on the formation of memory by religious actors that even religious, ecclesiastic and confessional memories are affected by the secular</em>.</p><p>Join the seminar on Zoom: <a href="https://psu.zoom.us/j/96181831783?fbclid=IwAR3sxbMKlqT-7XVBRYJnWrySQbxdTzEnRZ5ht5JPSXdtxCLOJW44epi4ijU#success" rel="nofollow">link </a><br/>Learn more about the series: <a href="https://enrs.eu/project/ers-series%C2%A0" rel="nofollow">https://enrs.eu/project/ers-series </a></p></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 18:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667975831397719</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP: Drew University, Transdisciplinary Theological Colloquium, 17-19 March 2023 -- Haunted (by) Speech: Translating Religions and Religious Translations</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11622474/cfp-drew-university-transdisciplinary-theological-colloquium</link>
						<dc:creator>Michael Anderson</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-17T00:00:00-04:00">March 17, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-19T00:00:00-04:00">March 19, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>New Jersey</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Islamic History / Studies, Medieval and Byzantine History / Studies, Philosophy, Religious Studies and Theology, World History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The Drew University Graduate Division of Religion is pleased to announce its <strong>21st Transdisciplinary Theological Colloquium</strong> to be held <strong>March 17th to 19th</strong>. This year’s conversation will be centered around our conference theme:</p><p><strong><em>Haunted (by) Speech: Translating Religions and Religious Translations</em></strong></p><p><em>“What is it, then, to translate? Deep language learning of the original, straining to be haunted by it so it can be learned before reason.” — Gayatri Spivak</em></p><p>TTC 2023 is inspired by previous colloquia (Planetary Loves in 2007; Decolonizing Epistemologies in 2008; Life Under the Baobab Tree in 2017; and Trans: Human/Divine Bodies Beyond Boundaries in 2018). However, while these conferences considered the importance of “translation” in relation to postcolonial and decolonial theory, Africana studies, and gender and trans studies, this conference narrows its focus quite specifically on the problematic of “translation” itself. Indeed, we ask what is lost, but also what is gained in the act of translating religion.</p><p>Our starting point is translation theory and studies, the rich and vibrant field that takes into account questions of coloniality, cultural fluency, linguistic equivalence, and accented speech. To think about translation opens up the question of being haunted, possessed by, even surrendering to language and all of the cultural, political, and religious implications found within it. But, this process is one that is marked by risk, as the very act of translation prompts us to consider the enacting of wounds, the losses that manifest in the process. We acknowledge that the very form of this conference participates in monolingualism (namely, a particular form of English) in a U.S. based university, and thus, it is marked by the risk of another symbolic violence of translation in the transnational imbalance of power. We call attention to such limitations in hopes of generating a more thoughtful debate on these important issues. We hope this self-reflective awareness will be a consideration for participants.</p><p>In addition, we do not seek to remain solely within the realm of words and language. We also want to see what happens when “translation” moves into other registers, religious and interreligious registers that require us to think about the translation of beliefs, feelings, and thoughts into action or practice. We also turn to the problem of translation to consider what might not be translatable. Where might the procedures of equivalence and comparison become hegemonic practices that do not enact an appeal to “planetarity” but instead to power and control? As such, this conference seeks to consider how practices, ethics, and aesthetics of untranslatability might reroute or even upend such controlling grammars.</p><p>TTC invites papers from graduate students that explore the many dimensions of translation: its politics, methods, figures, concepts, and future directions, especially as these relate to the domain of religion. This year’s conference will be hybrid in its modality, and as such, we eagerly encourage submissions from those individuals who will present via Zoom as well as those who will be present on campus.</p><p>Proposals should be 200-300 words in length and include, as an attachment, a CV or brief bio that indicates the applicant’s institution, program, stage of completion, and area of focus/research interests. We welcome proposals for transdisciplinary papers as well as proposals for teaching sessions, activist engagement, art, or storytelling, and other creative approaches to engage the conference theme. <strong>Please submit your proposal to <a href="mailto:ttc@drew.edu">ttc@drew.edu</a> by January 15th in order to be considered.</strong> If accepted, presentations should be approximately 20 minutes in length (1,800-2,000 words).</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ttc@drew.edu">ttc@drew.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://drew.edu/theological-school/academics/doctor-of-philosophy/transdisciplinary-theological-colloquium/" target="_blank">https://drew.edu/theological-school/academics/doctor-of-philosophy/transdisciplinary-theological-colloquium/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 20:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667889431482579</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Announcing a new series from CEUPress &quot;Crisis, Conflict and Security in Central and Eastern Europe&quot;</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11621634/announcing-new-series-ceupress-crisis-conflict-and-security</link>
						<dc:creator>Liliya Berezhnaya</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Publications</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-07T00:00:00-05:00">November 7, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Eastern Europe History / Studies, Nationalism History / Studies, Peace History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Russian or Soviet History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Central European University Press<br/><span><strong>Announcing a new series from CEUPress </strong></span></p><p><span><strong>Crisis, Conflict and Security in Central and Eastern Europe</strong></span></p><p><strong>Series Editors:</strong><br/><strong>Heidi Hein-Kircher,</strong> Herder-Institute for Historical Research on East Central Europe, Marburg, Germany.<br/><strong>Liliya Berezhnaya,</strong> University of Münster, Germany; Central European University, Vienna, Austria; Catholic University of Leuven, Belgium.</p><p>Security, crisis and conflicts play a crucial role in the international relations of Central and Eastern European states and in internal affairs, between national, ethnic and religious groups. Crises, conflicts, security issues and their perceptions are closely linked to state building, nationalism, the fall of Soviet hegemony, as well as multi-ethnicity and multi-culturality in Central and Eastern Europe.</p><p>The series discusses the emergence, fostering and sustainability of conflicts and crises, as well as the perception of security problems and the attempts to create security from various perspectives in modern times. The series includes volumes written by scholars of various disciplines, but with a focus on history. It aims to provide interpretations and historical dimensions relating to the current triggers of in-security and conflicts in Central and Eastern Europe. Doing so, the series provides an innovative insight into current and urgent research problems.</p><p><br/><strong>Editorial Board:</strong></p><p><strong>Monika Baar,</strong> European University Institute, Italy Margarita Balmaceda, Seton Hall, Harvard Ukrainian Research Institute, USA<br/><strong>Werner Distler,</strong> University of Groningen, Netherlands<br/><strong>Andrea Gawrich, </strong>University of Giessen, Germany<br/><strong>Ana Ivasiuc,</strong> Maynooth University, Ireland<br/><strong>Jerzy Kochanowski</strong>, University of Warsaw, Poland Otá Konrad, Charles University Prague, Czech Republic<br/><strong>Klaus Richter,</strong> University of Birmingham, UK Olga Sezneva, University of Amsterdam, Netherlands<br/><strong>David Smith, </strong>University of Glasgow, UK<br/><strong>Darius Staliūnas,</strong> Institute for Lithuanian History, Lithuania<br/><strong>Andras Szalai</strong>, CEU Democracy Institute, Hungary</p><p><strong>Topics of relevance to the series might include:</strong></p><p>Nationalism and imperialism as triggers of conflict<br/>Migration, as a result of, or as a trigger of, crises<br/>Minority-majority conflicts<br/>Multi-ethnicity<br/>Religious conflicts<br/>Memory cultures, memory politics, memory wars<br/>Political, economic and societal transformation/transition<br/>Wars, flight and expulsion<br/>Social engineering as a tool for conflict prevention and resolution (such as deportations)<br/>Historicizing and conceptualizing the notions of “security”, “conflict” and “crisis” in Central and Eastern Europe</p><p> </p><p>Please, contact series editors for more information: <a href="mailto:lbere_01@uni-muenster.de">lbere_01@uni-muenster.de</a>; <a href="mailto:heidi.hein-kircher@herder-institut.de">heidi.hein-kircher@herder-institut.de</a></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr. Liliya Berezhnaya, Westfälische Wilhelms-Universität Münster, Historisches Seminar - Abteilung für Osteuropäische Geschichte<br/>Telefon: 0251 / 83 24122 (Sekretariat), E-Mail: <a href="mailto:lbere_01@uni-muenster.de">lbere_01@uni-muenster.de</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:lbere_01@uni-muenster.de">lbere_01@uni-muenster.de</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://ceupress.com/series/crisis-conflict-and-security-central-and-eastern-europe" target="_blank">https://ceupress.com/series/crisis-conflict-and-security-central-and-eastern-europe?fbclid=IwAR0azLcSggH_rB7f65MXnzGVLcX…</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 20:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667889431482578</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rethinking Islam &amp; The West: The Mizan Thesis</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11621079/rethinking-islam-west-mizan-thesis</link>
						<dc:creator>Neil Cunningham</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Event</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-27T00:00:00-05:00">November 27, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Arabic History / Studies, Islamic History / Studies, Middle East History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, World History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>You are invited to a truly unique event, taking place at 5:30pm in the Old Divinity School, St John’s college on November 27<sup>th</sup>. The subject is nothing less than the multiple crises facing us in the modern world, with the presentation of a game-changing new thesis which can help us make sense of it all.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>This thesis, known as the Mizan Thesis, has been developed by Cambridge Centre of Islamic Studies Visiting Fellow Ahmed Paul Keeler, and further refined in collaboration with a group of scholars based at the University of Cambridge. It aims to completely reframe our understanding of the challenges facing the modern world, with reference to the different trajectories of the Western and Islamic civilisations.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Through a dynamic multimedia presentation, the full implications of this challenging paradigm will be explored, providing participants with a clarifying new lens through which to view the contemporary world. We look forward to seeing you there.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p>Tickets (including Refreshments) - £15, £10 Students<br/>For more info and to book tickets:   <a href="https://bit.ly/MizanThesis" rel="nofollow">https://bit.ly/MizanThesis</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Neil Cunningham</p><p>Centre of Islamic Studies</p><p>University of Cambridge</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:cis@cis.cam.ac.uk">cis@cis.cam.ac.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.cis.cam.ac.uk/" target="_blank">https://www.cis.cam.ac.uk/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 20:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667889431482577</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>***DEADLINE EXTENDED*** CFP: &quot;Judaisms, Jewishness, and Time&quot; - Jewish Studies Graduate Association Conference (online)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11586469/deadline-extended-cfp-judaisms-jewishness-and-time-jewish</link>
						<dc:creator>Sabina Ali</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-14T00:00:00-05:00">November 14, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Anthropology, Art, Art History &amp; Visual Studies, Colonial and Post-Colonial History / Studies, Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p> </p><p> </p><p><span><strong>CFP: "Judaisms, Jewishness, and Time"</strong></span></p><p><span><strong>11th Annual Jewish Studies Graduate Association Conference (online)</strong><br/>Borns Jewish Studies Program<br/>Indiana University, Bloomington</span></p><p> </p><p><span><strong>Proposal Submission Deadline: November 14, 2022</strong></span></p><p>In <em>The Sabbath: Its Meaning for Modern Man</em> (1951), Abraham Joshua Heschel says that “Judaism is a religion of time aiming at the sanctification of time.” With Heschel’s reflection on the centrality of time to Judaism in mind, the Jewish Studies Graduate Students Association at Indiana University invites graduate student proposals for a conference on <strong>Judaisms, Jewishness, and Time</strong>. We invite participants to consider how might Jewish studies as a field be positioned to interrogate time as a concept. This conference will be held <strong>February 2-3, 2023, online</strong> with an optional in-person reception and closing event.</p><p>Proposals are encouraged to think through questions that relate to how contemporary studies of Jews, Judaisms, and Jewishness offer new perspectives or rescue old concepts in the understanding of time throughout history. How can Jewish studies illuminate questions about time? How do the societies, organizations, or figures we research deal with temporal problems? We welcome proposals that engage/discuss Judaisms, Jewishness, and time in myriad ways, such as memory, narrative, and mourning; history and historiography; modernity, coloniality, and the nation-state; indigeneity and deep time; calendars, materiality, monuments, and ritual; ecology and climate change; the experience of time and other phenomenological issues; messianism and prophecy; or other topics.</p><p>The conference is open to all graduate students working in Jewish studies and adjacent fields. As an interdisciplinary conference, we welcome papers from many fields, including but not limited to Religious Studies, Anthropology, Sociology, Music, Literature, Folklore, Film Studies, Visual and Performance Art, History, and Political Science. Also, we encourage the proposal of unconventional presentations, including visual, musical, and performance arts.</p><p>We are excited to announce that this year’s Lillian Solotkin Keynote Lecture, titled “Memory Citizenship: Migration and Holocaust Memory in Contemporary Germany,” will be given by Dr. Michael Rothberg, 1939 Society Samuel Goetz Chair in Holocaust Studies and Professor of English and Comparative Literature at the University of California, Los Angeles.</p><p><strong>Please send an abstract (maximum 300 words), a title for your presentation, and contact information, including name, email address, telephone number, and institution to <a href="mailto:jsgsacon@indiana.edu">jsgsacon@indiana.edu</a> by November 14.</strong> Abstracts will be evaluated based on quality and fit. Participants will be notified of acceptance by <strong>November 30</strong>. Papers will need to be submitted by January 9 for circulation among faculty respondents. Participants will have 20 minutes to present.</p><p>Please email questions to <strong><a href="mailto:jsgsacon@indiana.edu">jsgsacon@indiana.edu</a></strong>.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Sabina Ali<br/>Jewish Studies Graduate Student Association<br/>Borns Jewish Studies Program<br/>Indiana University, Bloomington</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:jsgsacon@indiana.edu">jsgsacon@indiana.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 20:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667889431482576</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ June 22, 2023 -  June 24, 2023] Conference or similar: Religious Faith and Meaning-Making</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104682</link>
						<description>Venue: Kretingos g. 36<br/><br/><p>Religious faith and its connection to meaning in life is a frequent object of study in the contemporary academy. It is studied in humanistic fields such as religious studies, history, and literature. It also occupies the attention of the social sciences, including in fields such as sociology, anthropology, cognitive science, and psychology. However, the work in humanistic disciplines on faith and meaning are not always informed by our best and most up to date scientific knowledge. The purpose of this workshop is to bring together a multidisciplinary group of scholars in order to examine the role that faith plays in meaning-making from a scientifically informed perspective. We invite abstracts of up to 500 words on the question: What role can and does religious faith play when evaluating, creating, and living out one’s sense of meaning in life?</p>
<p>This event will consist of a three-day workshop with presentations from schoalrs across philosophy, theology, and the social sciences.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 05:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667626626424200</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ January 31, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Religious Faith and Meaning-Making</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/104686</link>
						<description><p><strong>Call for Papers</strong></p>
<p><strong>Religious Faith and Meaning-Making</strong></p>
<p><strong>LCC International University, Lithuania </strong></p>
<p><strong>June 22-24, 2023</strong> </p>
<p>The Center for Faith and Human Flourishing at LCC International University, Lithuania is pleased to announce a call for papers to participate in a workshop on faith and meaning-making, to be held from June 22-24, 2023 in Klaipeda, Lithuania.</p>
<p>Religious faith and its connection to meaning in life is a frequent object of study in the contemporary academy. It is studied in humanistic fields such as religious studies, history, and literature. It also occupies the attention of the social sciences, including in fields such as sociology, anthropology, cognitive science, and psychology. However, the work in humanistic disciplines on faith and meaning are not always informed by our best and most up to date scientific knowledge. The purpose of this workshop is to bring together a multidisciplinary group of scholars in order to examine the role that faith plays in meaning-making from a scientifically informed perspective. We invite abstracts of up to 500 words on the question: What role can and does religious faith play when evaluating, creating, and living out one’s sense of meaning in life?</p>
<p>Specific topics include, but are not limited to:</p>
<p>·         The interaction between faith and meaning</p>
<p>·         How faith contributes to meaning</p>
<p>·         Scientifically informed approaches to faith and meaning</p>
<p>·         Connections between scientifically informed approaches and the philosophical or theological literature.</p>
<p>·         Empirical analyses of specific religious approaches to faith and meaning</p>
<p>·         Non-Western approaches to faith and meaning</p>
<p>Empirically informed approaches are particularly welcomed.</p>
<p><strong>Financial Considerations:</strong></p>
<p>Up to 2 participants will be eligible for an award that includes 4 nights accommodations in addition to lunches and dinners on conference days (travel funds cannot be provided).</p>
<p><strong>Publication Opportunity:</strong></p>
<p>Appropriate papers may be selected for inclusion in a volume edited by <a href="https://www.kirklougheed.com/">Kirk Lougheed</a> (LCC International University/University of Pretoria) which will be submitted for consideration in Brill’s Value Inquiry Book Series.</p>
<p><strong>Tentatively Confirmed Speakers Include:</strong></p>
<p>Arbiah Attoe (University of Witwatersrand)</p>
<p>Michael Cox (LCC International University)</p>
<p>Laird Edman (Northwestern College)</p>
<p>Joshua Harris (The King’s University)</p>
<p>Liz Jackson (Toronto Metropolitan University)</p>
<p>Kirk Lougheed (LCC International University/University of Pretoria)</p>
<p>Myron A. Penner (Trinity Western University)</p>
<p>Tricia van Dyk (LCC International University)</p>
<p><strong>Submission:</strong></p>
<p>Please submit an abstract of no more than 500 words, along with your CV to Kirk Lougheed at  <a href="mailto:kirklougheed@philosophy.com">p</a>hilosophy@kirklougheed.com by January 31, 2023.</p>
<p><strong>Contact:</strong></p>
<p>philosophy@kirklougheed.com</p>
<p>This workshop is generously funded by an Initiative Grant from the <a href="https://www.cccu.org/">CCCU</a>.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 06:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667626626424199</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The 20th Annual Religion Graduate Student Symposium at Florida State University</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/11/03/the-20th-annual-religion-graduate-student-symposium-at-florida-state-university</link>
						<dc:creator>ddb13</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Friday, November 4, 2022 - 10:46am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Religion Graduate Student Symposium at Florida State University</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:fsureligionsymposium@gmail.com">fsureligionsymposium@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/classical-studies">classical studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/graduate-conferences">graduate conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/theory">theory</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>December 1, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Call for Papers:<br/> The 20th Annual<br/> Religion Graduate Student Symposium at Florida State University</p>
<p>February 17 &amp; 18, 2023</p>
<p>Tallahassee, Florida </p>
<p> </p>
<p>This year’s symposium will center on the theme: “Sensational Religion” </p>
<p>This is our first in-person symposium since the beginning of the Sars-Cov2 global pandemic and we invite scholars to present papers addressing sensory aspects of the "new normal" for the study of religion. Previous symposia have featured scholars from a wide array of disciplines, universities, and areas. We invite papers from fields as varied as History, Anthropology, Political Science, Literature, Philosophy, Religious Studies, and Classics. </p>
<p>Joseph Winters, Duke University, Religious Studies and African American Studies, will deliver this year’s keynote address </p>
<p>Possible topics include, but are not limited to: </p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Sensing Religion </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Embodiment, Corporeality, &amp; </p>
<p>the Transhuman </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Religion &amp; Hip-hop </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Form and Feeling in Religious </p>
<p>Discourse </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Religion &amp; Material Culture </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Religion &amp; Sound </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Affect Theory </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Feeling Space, Building Religion </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Religion, Taste &amp; Foodways </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Existentialism </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Religion &amp; the Experiences of </p>
<p>Identity-Making: Race, Gender, Disability, Age, Class</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Passing, Hiding, and In/Visibility</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Religion, Disgust, and Heresy </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Exhaustion and Burnout in Religion and its Study</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Panic, Anxiety, and Emergency</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Feeling-Values and the Religious Experience</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Disgust, Pain, Pleasure, Fear, Terror</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Moral &amp; Ethics of Religious Beauty/Ugliness</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>State-Mediated Public Emotions </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Ethics of Eco-Aesthetics</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Presentations should be approximately 15 to 18 minutes in length and will receive faculty responses. In addition, every year respondents select the best graduate paper to receive the Leo F. Sandon Award, an endowed award named for the Religion Department's former chair. </p>
<p>Proposals including an abstract of approximately 300 words, a list of key terms, and institutional affiliation should be submitted by December 1, 2022 for review. Please submit proposals via this provided link: <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfC8WJlqAFXTBhdLELLFRcuw5-mypHoCrHHzWiMT3jvUiEMbQ/viewform?usp=sf_link">https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfC8WJlqAFXTBhdLELLFRcuw5-mypHo...</a> </p>
<p>Thank you for your interest. We look forward to hearing from you and hope to see you at the 2023 Graduate Student Symposium at Florida State University. </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 18:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667626626424198</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Papers: The 20th Annual Religion Graduate Student Symposium at Florida State University</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11569294/call-papers-20th-annual-religion-graduate-student-symposium</link>
						<dc:creator>Devin Burns</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-12-01T00:00:00-05:00">December 1, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Florida</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>American History / Studies, Anthropology, Classical Studies, Philosophy, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span>Call for Papers: </span></p><p><span>The 20th Annual Religion Graduate Student Symposium at Florida State University </span></p><p><span>February 17 &amp; 18, 2023 </span></p><p><span>Tallahassee, Florida</span></p><p>This year’s symposium will center on the theme: “Sensational Religion” This is our first in-person symposium since the beginning of the Sars-Cov2 global pandemic and we invite scholars to present papers addressing sensory aspects of the "new normal" for the study of religion. Previous symposia have featured scholars from a wide array of disciplines, universities, and areas. We invite papers from fields as varied as History, Anthropology, Political Science, Literature, Philosophy, Religious Studies, and Classics.</p><p>Joseph Winters, Duke University, Religious Studies and African American Studies, will deliver this year’s keynote address.</p><p>Possible topics include, but are not limited to:</p><p>• Sensing Religion</p><p>• Embodiment, Corporeality, &amp; the Transhuman</p><p>• Religion &amp; Hip-hop</p><p>• Form and Feeling in Religious Discourse</p><p>• Religion &amp; Material Culture</p><p>• Religion &amp; Sound</p><p>• Affect Theory</p><p>• Feeling Space, Building Religion</p><p>• Religion, Taste &amp; Foodways</p><p>• Existentialism</p><p>• Religion &amp; the Experiences of Identity-Making: Race, Gender, Disability, Age, Class</p><p>• Passing, Hiding, and In/Visibility</p><p>• Religion, Disgust, and Heresy</p><p>• Exhaustion and Burnout in Religion and its Study</p><p>• Panic, Anxiety, and Emergency</p><p>• Feeling-Values and the Religious Experience</p><p>• Disgust, Pain, Pleasure, Fear, Terror</p><p>• Moral &amp; Ethics of Religious Beauty/Ugliness</p><p>• State-Mediated Public Emotions</p><p>• Ethics of Eco-Aesthetics</p><p> </p><p>Presentations should be approximately 15 to 18 minutes in length and will receive faculty responses. In addition, every year respondents select the best graduate paper to receive the Leo F. Sandon Award, an endowed award named for the Religion Department's former chair. Proposals including an abstract of approximately 300 words, a list of key terms, and institutional affiliation should be submitted by December 1, 2022 for review.</p><p>Please submit proposals via this provided link: <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfC8WJlqAFXTBhdLELLFRcuw5-mypHoCrHHzWiMT3jvUiEMbQ/viewform?usp=sf_link" rel="nofollow">https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfC8WJlqAFXTBhdLELLFRcuw5-mypHo...</a></p><p> </p><p>Thank you for your interest. We look forward to hearing from you and hope to see you at the 2023 Graduate Student Symposium at Florida State University.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:fsureligionsymposium@gmail.com">fsureligionsymposium@gmail.com</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 18:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667540232558574</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Transcendent Transnationalism? Jewish History and Heritage Across Time and Space Call for Contributions to Volume 8 of the Yearbook of Transnational History</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11567425/transcendent-transnationalism-jewish-history-and-heritage</link>
						<dc:creator>Hernan  Tesler-Mabe</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-15T00:00:00-04:00">March 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Historic Preservation, Holocaust, Genocide, and Memory Studies, Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, World History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>CALL FOR PAPERS:<br/>Transcendent Transnationalism? Jewish History and Heritage <a name="_Hlk114777991">Across Time and Space</a></span></span></span></b></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Call for Contributions to Volume 8 of the <i>Yearbook of Transnational History</i> (published with Fairleigh Dickinson University Press/Rowman &amp; Littlefield) in spring 2025</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><a name="_Hlk114774022"><span><span><span>Hernan Tesler-Mabé </span></span></span></a><span><span><span>(Huron at Western) &amp; Shelley-Anne Peleg (University of Haifa, Israel) </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Although originated thousands of years ago from historical Israel and Judah, the Jewish people today are an ethnoreligious group and a nation that transcends physical borders and is spread throughout the world. Connected by faith, ethnicity, and culture, Jews possess a unique collective identity. The Jewish peoples are a universal phenomenon with a distinct story of multiculturalism, diversity, and constant renewal.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Jewish history and heritage can be found in tangible places and objects as well as intangible heritage such as shared practices, common themes, materials, and ideas. Jewish history and heritage manifests itself in different ways, crossing over time spans and bears numerous tangible and intangible connections. Jewish history and heritage is often not limited by national borders and, like the people it represents, connected as a Diaspora.  </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Crossing over time and borders, Jewish history and heritage includes themes that appear and disappear, layers of rituals and a combination of identities. It suggests changes over time and space. Therefore, Jewish history and heritage suggests a discussion unbounded by national concepts and theories<b> </b>crossing over time and spatial boundaries. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>This means that instead of dealing with a particular issue of a given nation, experts in the field of Jewish Studies are encouraged and obliged to engage in international debates and discussions that address understanding this heritage and these ideas. These frameworks focus on vast and various aspects.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The objective of this volume is to discuss these issues, through case studies and original research of Jewish issues from around the world, from various cultural and geographic settings. We welcome articles from academics, professionals, and advanced graduate students based upon a broad range of Jewish studies approaches. Topics might relate to one of the following topics:</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ol><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Conflicts or connections between Jewish monuments and sub features of Jewish history and heritage with local cultures and sites over the globe (e.g., the influences of specific Jewish features and characteristics and local cultures as manifested in art and architecture)</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Layers of Jewish history and heritage across time – changes and preserved Jewish features (e.g., development of symbols and structures) </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Common intangible rituals versus unorthodox traditions (e.g., practice &amp; living heritage, different interpretations …)</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>How do "others" view Jewish history and heritage (e.g., antisemitism and responses to antisemitism, Judaism as a culture in the diaspora and in Israel) </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Travels of Jewish history and heritage (e.g., Judaism moving with immigrants from one country to another, from Israel to the diaspora and from the diaspora to Israel).</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Historiographical engagements  </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Recent academic trends (e.g., Decolonizing the bible, Colonial histories, land and resources)</span></span></span></span></span></span></li></ol><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Interested contributors should submit a 250-500 word proposal abstract along with a short CV (2 pages max) by March 15, 2023 to Shelley-Anne Peleg (</span></span></span><a href="mailto:shelleypeleg@gmail.com"><span><span><span>shelleypeleg@gmail.com</span></span></span></a><span><span><span>) and Hernan Tesler-Mabé (<span><span><a href="mailto:hteslerm@huron.uwo.ca">hteslerm@huron.uwo.ca</a></span></span>) with the subject line “<b>Transcendent Transnationalism? Jewish History and Heritage Across Time and Space.</b>” Decisions on paper proposals will be made by April 15, 2023. Full papers (including Chicago style citations – endnotes and bibliography) should be between 5,000 to 10,000 words in length using American spelling, grammar, and punctuation conventions. Non-native English speakers should have their papers reviewed and edited by an English speaker prior to submission. Final paper drafts are due October 1, 2023.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><span><span><span>Shelley-Anne Peleg (</span></span></span><span><span><span><a href="mailto:shelleypeleg@gmail.com"><span><span><span>shelleypeleg@gmail.com</span></span></span></a></span></span></span><span><span><span>) and Hernan Tesler-Mabé (<span><span><a href="mailto:hteslerm@huron.uwo.ca">hteslerm@huron.uwo.ca</a></span></span>) </span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:hteslerm@huron.uwo.ca">hteslerm@huron.uwo.ca</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667540232558573</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>More Universal Than Catholicism? Mary Among Asian Religions</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11561780/more-universal-catholicism-mary-among-asian-religions</link>
						<dc:creator>Michel Chambon</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-01T00:00:00-05:00">February 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Singapore</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>East Asian History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, South Asian History / Studies, Southeast Asian History / Studies, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The figure of Mary, mother of Jesus Christ, has long been present among Asian people. Scholars have extensively explored how Asian Catholics use their local culture and national context to translate the features and meaning of this religious figure (Cruz 2015). However, Mary has also crossed religious boundaries and been integrated into the continent’s various religious traditions. Among Filipino-Chinese Catholics, Mary can be juxtaposed to and identified with Chinese deities like Mazu and Guanyin (Dy 2014). In Japan, she has long embraced the attributes of the bodhisattva Kannon (Habito 1994). In India, Indonesia, and Pakistan, Marian shrines attract thousands of Hindu and Muslim pilgrims (Bloomer 2018, Laksana 2014). And in Trinidad, Hindu migrants come to worship Mary as a representation of the goddess Kali (Tsuji 2020). Across Asian people, places, and traditions, Mary stands as a pan religious figure.</p><p> </p><p>Furthermore, ways to approach and engage with her vary tremendously among people of different faiths. Often, Mary is made present through the display of images and statues with artistic, ethnic, and gender particularities which call for critical attention (Habito 2014, Ninh 2017). Those statues can become the center of larger rituals including material offerings, collective pilgrimages, and chanting ceremonies. Rooted in broader cultural meanings, these practices involve various modes of subjective and bodily engagement. And for some healing rituals and counseling sessions, Mary can even be encountered through highly codified possession (Bloomer 2018). </p><p>​</p><p>This workshop investigates the many ways Mary is understood and engaged by Asian people around the world. It explores how Buddhists, Hindus, Muslims, and Asian devotees from various faiths approach her. It discusses the rituals, collective practices, and artistic expressions they deploy in relation to her. At a more theoretical level, this workshop seeks to question what those Marian devotions say about the notions of religion, migration, interreligious relations, gender, and popular religiosity.</p><p>​</p><p>While this workshop seeks contributions from social scientific and historical perspectives, paper presenters are invited to consider the following questions to frame the investigations addressed at the conference:</p><p>• How do Asian communities perceive and display Mary? What do these activities reflect with regard to religion, gender roles, ethnic identity, etc. across time and space? </p><p>• How are specific forms of Mary localized across places where Asians live? What are the material and ritual practices involved in this geographic translation of Mary?  </p><p>• How does Mary cross or reinforce boundaries between ethnic, religious and economic groups?  Which kind of inter-religious dialogues are mediated through her? How is Mary used to negotiate boundaries between different types of Christian communities? </p><p>• Which kind of bodily and subjective engagements are promoted through Marian practices? Who are the religious experts guiding and regulating those engagements?  </p><p>• How do Asian clergies, religious experts, and civil authorities respond to the various forms of Mary? In what ways is Mary promoted and endorsed by the continent’s civil and religious institutions? How are some manifestations of Mary despised, sidelined, or condemned by various kinds of authorities?  </p><p>​</p><p>As part of the Asian Marianism pilot research project, this online conference is jointly organized by the <a href="http://www.isac-research.org/" rel="nofollow">Initiative for the Study of Asian Catholics</a> (ISAC) – an initiative hosted by the Asia Research Institute, National University of Singapore – and the <a href="https://www.marianstudies.ac.uk/" rel="nofollow">Centre for Marian Studies</a>, St Mary’s University, Twickenham, London, UK.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Paper proposals should include a title, an abstract (250 words maximum) and a brief personal biography of 100 words for submission, including your location to indicate your time zone. Please send it as a word document file to <a href="mailto:asianmary2023@gmail.com">asianmary2023@gmail.com</a> by 1 February 2023. Successful applicants will be notified by mid-March 2023.</p><p>Please also include a statement confirming that your paper has not been published previously, it is not committed elsewhere, and that you are willing to revise your paper for potential inclusion in a special publication (in collaboration with the workshop organizers and other participants).</p><p>Panel presenters will be required to submit drafts of their papers (6,000 words) by 1 May 2023. These drafts will be circulated to fellow panelists and discussants in advance. Drafts need not be fully polished. Indeed, we expect that presenters will be open to feedback from fellow participants.</p><p>For any inquiry, please contact Catherine O'Brien at <a href="mailto:asianmary2023@gmail.com">asianmary2023@gmail.com</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:asianmary2023@gmail.com">asianmary2023@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.isac-research.org/asianmary2023" target="_blank">https://www.isac-research.org/asianmary2023</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 17:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667540232558572</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>&quot;Victorian Gothic and the Occult&quot; Edited Collection</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/10/31/victorian-gothic-and-the-occult-edited-collection</link>
						<dc:creator>KirstinMills</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, November 3, 2022 - 11:41am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Kirstin A. Mills (Macquarie University)</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:kirstin.mills@mq.edu.au">kirstin.mills@mq.edu.au</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/science-and-culture">science and culture</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/victorian">victorian</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>December 31, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>The Victorian era, and the Nineteenth Century more broadly, witnessed a flourishing of interest in the supernatural, spiritualism, magic, and the physical and psychological sciences, which culminated in the emergence of occult beliefs, practices and societies. During this period also, the Gothic literature and art that had taken hold of the public imagination in the Romantic period continued to haunt the Victorian era, emerging in new forms that often embraced and experimented with ideas of occultism. Nineteenth-century occultism has received much critical attention, particularly in relation to its role in bringing about the apogee of British and American occultism in the early twentieth century. Yet while occult phenomena is generally accepted within Gothic fiction alongside other supernatural elements like ghosts, witches and vampires, the particular relationship between the Victorian Gothic and the emerging occult beliefs and practices in this period requires closer attention.</p>
<p>This edited book, intended for the Palgrave Gothic series published by Palgrave/Springer, seeks to examine this relationship, exploring the lines of connection, influence and contention between the Gothic and Occult in the Victorian period. It aims to consider the ways that the Victorian Gothic was shaped by – and in turn perhaps influenced or stoked – occult beliefs and practices in the period. Chapters should aim to address the Gothic as a genre or mode in the Victorian period, exploring: how the Victorian interest in the occult augments, extends, updates or challenges the Gothic mode; the impact, if any, of the Gothic on the Victorian Occult, even as an avenue for deploying and experimenting with occult ideas; and the potential wider uses that the Victorian Gothic makes of occultism for social and/or political commentary.</p>
<p>This volume takes a broad temporal view of the Victorian period, beginning with its early-nineteenth-century origins as it moved out of the Romantic period, and ending with its transition into the early-twentieth-century art forms that both drew on and rebelled against their forbears. It also aims to consider Gothic occultism not only in Britain but also in its global manifestations, interrogating particularly the imperial and colonial forces shaping the genre’s development.</p>
<p>Possible topics include but are by no means limited to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Spiritualism, Theosophy, Theology, Religion</li>
<li>Specific Occult Orders and Societies (e.g. Hermetic Order of the Golden Dawn; Society for Psychical Research; The Ghost Club; Freemasonry)</li>
<li>Ghosts, Mediums, Seances, Automatic Writing, Clairvoyance, Fortune-telling etc</li>
<li>Occult ‘sciences’ and pseudoscience, medicine, technology</li>
<li>Witches and witchcraft, Mages and magic, Alchemy, Astrology</li>
<li>Vampires, psychic vampires, werewolves and monsters</li>
<li>Arcane knowledge, philosophy, ‘secret’ or ‘lost’ texts</li>
<li>Raising the Dead, Life and Death boundaries</li>
<li>Victorian Occultism’s appropriation of and/or exchange with other cultures, e.g. Egyptian, Chinese, Indian etc</li>
<li>Race, imperialism and post-colonial narratives</li>
<li>Women and the occult (women authors, women occult figures, women in the occult, women characters, New Women)</li>
<li>Gothic Occultism as a space through which to explore alternatives to mainstream narratives e.g. class, gender, heterosexuality, monogamy, etc</li>
<li>The natural world, the environment, eco-Gothic/eco-horror</li>
<li>Art and visual culture</li>
<li>Aestheticism, Decadence, Fin-de-siecle Gothic</li>
<li>Crime and Occult Detective Gothic</li>
<li>Rural/Folk Gothic</li>
<li>Periodicals, magazines, popular fiction</li>
<li>Animals and the Occult</li>
<li>Space and Place</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Please submit abstracts of c.500 words and brief (c. 100-words) biographies for consideration to Dr Kirstin Mills (Macquarie University) <a href="mailto:kirstin.mills@mq.edu.au">kirstin.mills@mq.edu.au</a> by 31st December 2022. If accepted, completed articles are expected to be c.6000 words and will be due 31st October 2023. </strong>This volume is intended for the Palgrave Gothic series published by Palgrave/Springer.</p>
<p><strong>Abstracts due:</strong> 31st December 2022</p>
<p><strong>Completed articles due:</strong> 31st October 2023</p>
<p><strong>Enquiries to:</strong> Dr Kirstin Mills (Macquarie University) – <a href="mailto:kirstin.mills@mq.edu.au">kirstin.mills@mq.edu.au</a></p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 01:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1667540232558571</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
