<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 12:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 12:19:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>Mahabharata Epic Across Asia Ancient Indian Knowledge System Transcending Spatio-Temporal Boundaries</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/05/18/mahabharata-epic-across-asia-ancient-indian-knowledge-system-transcending-spatio</link>
						<dc:creator>NAVIN PANDEY</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Saturday, May 20, 2023 - 6:26am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div> The English and Foreign Languages University, Hyderabad </div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:azadikaamritmahotsaveflu2023@gmail.com">azadikaamritmahotsaveflu2023@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/international-conferences">international conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/world-literatures-and-indigenous-studies">world literatures and indigenous studies</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>May 25, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><em>"The greatest event of our age is the meeting of cultures, meeting of civilizations, meeting of different points of view, making us understand that we should not adhere to any one kind of single faith, but respect diversity of belief. Our attempt should always be to cooperate, to bring together people, to establish friendship and have some kind of a right world in which we can live together in happiness, harmony and friendship. Let us therefore realize that this increasing maturity should express itself in this capacity to understand what other points of view are’?"-</em> Dr. Sarvepalli Radhakrishnan.</p>
<p>The main aim of this conference is not to establish any truth rather to confirm our perpetual journey to explore truth. This conference will explore Mahābhārata and the intellectual-historical genres and matters discussed in it in new ways in the light of recent thinking and research on this epic. Mahābhārata has diffused into not only Indian life but also in the life of entire South Asia to such an extent that every aspect of life in this region is influenced by it directly or indirectly. Contrary to popular belief that it is a Hindu religious text, it has been adopted and adapted by almost all cultures, communities and have attracted scholars from all religions and regions.</p>
<p>The discussion and analysis of the philosophical and theological texts that form an integral part of Mahābhārata have received a considerable critical attention from the scholars around the world. Furthermore, creative writers from different cultural, religious and ethnic backgrounds across time and space have adapted sometimes just a fragment and sometimes the whole of Mahābhārata for their creative writings that expended the epic and added to its ever-expanding meaning. For instance, Angelika Malinar’s Rājavidyā: Das königliche Wissen um Herrschaft und Verzicht. Studien zur Bhagavadgītā examines many themes and complications of epic philosophy and theology, particularly as refracted through the prism of the Bhagavad Gītā. The Nārāyaṇīya Studien of Peter Schreiner, Angelika Malinar, et al., base their arguments on the doctrines of the Gītā and include the philosophy of Vaiṣṇava Purāṇas, on the other hand Johannes Bronkhorst’s Greater Magadha: Studies in the Culture of Early India analyze texts and explore the historical development usually regarded as anterior to the Mokṣadharmaparvan. These works and some others raise a number of themes and ideas that will help in investigation and interrogation of issues related to philosophy, gender, caste, history, geography, ethics, and many more in the Mahābhārata.</p>
<p><strong>Mahābhārata Across South Asia</strong></p>
<p>The Mahabharata spread through the sub-continent and in all of South East Asia. In Myanmar (Burma), Thailand, Cambodia, Malaysia, and Indonesia, the Mahabharata gave birth not only to important literary works, but also to theatrical expressions intimately linked to national cultures. In the Malay version, Hikayat perang Pandawa jaya, the epic remains close to the Panji cycle and serves as support to shadow theatre. The Javanese version of the Mahabharata, called Bharatayudha (The Bharata War), and the Arjunavivaha (Arjuna’s Wedding), is used in live theatre (wayang wong or orang) as well as in puppetry and shadow theatre. In Bali, each episode gives rise to independent performances where we find the same titles of Bharatayudha and Arjunavivaha, etc. In all of these countries, the Mahabharata contributes in creating a communication between different religious ideals and synthesizes cultural values.</p>
<p>Mahabharata and stories based on this epic are extremely popular in Muslim-majority Indonesia because the Hindu epics are part of the country’s culture. For centuries, many parts of the Indonesian archipelago were majority-Hindu. By the 7th century CE, Hindu-Buddhist kingdoms dominated both Java and Sumatra — Indonesia’s two most populous islands. References to the epics are everywhere in Java — the language, the street signs, the political commentary. In Jakarta, many buses are painted with lurid advertisements for an energy drink called Kuku Bima, which promises Bhima-like endurance. An enormous statue of Krishna leading Arjun into battle dominates the roundabout in front of the Monas, the country’s main nationalist monument. There is a nationwide charitable foundation for twins named the Nakula and Sadewa Society. And one of the country’s bestselling novels, Amba, uses the story of Bhishma and Shikhandi (a later incarnation of Amba) to talk about Indonesia’s purges of communists in the mid-1960s. Wayang kulit, a form of shadow-puppet theatre that features tales from the Mahabharata and the Ramayana, can draw tens of thousands to performances in rural Java.</p>
<p>There are Malay versions of the Mahabharata, some of which probably entered Malay as abbreviated prose renditions of the Old Javanese Bhratayuddha. The earliest, Hikayat Perang Pandawa Jaya, ‘The tale of the war of the victorious Pandawa’, was composed sometime between the late 14th and early 16th century, and is mentioned in the Bustan al-salatin of Nuruddin al-Raniri composed in Aceh in 1638.</p>
<p><strong>Sub themes:</strong></p>
<p>1. Mahābhārata during ancient period<br/> 2. Mahābhārata during colonial period<br/> 3. Mahābhārata during Mughal period<br/> 4. Mahābhārata and Buddhism<br/> 5. Mahābhārata and Jainism<br/> 6. Mahābhārata and tribal cultures<br/> 7. Linguistic study of Mahābhārata<br/> 8. Mahābhārata and ethics<br/> 9. Mahābhārata and philosophy<br/> 10. Mahābhārata outside India<br/> 11. Sociological study of Mahābhārata<br/> 12. Mahābhārata’s adaptations in other languages<br/> 13. Contemporary adaptations of Mahābhārata<br/> 14. Mahābhārata in other art forms like drama, painting, puppet shows etc.<br/> 15. Mahābhārata and Cinema<br/> 16. Mahābhārata in Indonesia, Cambodia, Laos, Thailand, Burma, Malaysia and other countries<br/> 17. Philosophy of Gita<br/> 18. Different aspects of Gita</p>
<p><strong>Important Information:</strong></p>
<p>Last date to submit Abstract: 25 May 2023<br/> Last Date to Submit Full Paper for Publication: 31 July 2023<br/> Conference Email Id: <a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/azadikaamritmahotsaveflu2023@gmail.com">azadikaamritmahotsaveflu2023@gmail.com</a><br/> All inquiries should be sent to the conference email id or 8897048598 (Dr Jai Singh)<br/> Submit abstracts through the Google Form Link: <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdt_ttpBFkypWH_7Hwdf5L0mhU-pNVS-E5Cp_UpGOvHD6Nd_w/viewform?usp=sf_link">https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdt_ttpBFkypWH_7Hwdf5L0mhU-pNVS-E5Cp_UpGOvHD6Nd_w/viewform?usp=sf_link</a></p>
<p><strong>Registration Fee:</strong></p>
<p>Rs 4500 with Accommodation<br/> Rs 1500 without Accommodation (Conference Lunch will be provided)<br/> Rs 500 for Online Presentation</p>
<p>Deposit registration fee online in the following account:<br/> Name of account holder: The English and Foreign Languages University, Hyderabad<br/> Account number: 62122901303<br/> IFSC Code: SBIN0021106<br/> Name of the Bank: State Bank of India, EFL University Branch, Hyderabad</p>
<p>In case of any difficulty in depositing the Registration Fee please contact:<br/> 8897048598 (Dr Jai Singh)</p>
<p><strong>Publication:</strong></p>
<p>Papers will be submitted to Peer Reviewed Journals with ISSN Number, processing charges if any will be paid by the participant directly to the Journal.</p>
<p> </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 20:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1684647423510377</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Poetics of American Speech according to Beat Generation Poet Lew Welch</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/05/15/the-poetics-of-american-speech-according-to-beat-generation-poet-lew-welch</link>
						<dc:creator>Charles Upton</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Friday, May 19, 2023 - 11:52am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Charles Upton</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:cupton@qx.net">cupton@qx.net</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/poetry">poetry</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/world-literatures-and-indigenous-studies">world literatures and indigenous studies</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>August 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p align="center"><strong>The Poetics of American Speech</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>according to Beat Generation Poet Lew Welch</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong> </strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>by Charles Upton</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>[Excerpted from <em>Giving Myself Away</em>, an autobiography-in-progress;</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>submitted for consideration to CONTEMPORARY POETRY, Volume 6]</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong> </strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong> </strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>I: The Art of Poetic Recitation </strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>as taught by Lewis Barrett Welch</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>I was tutored, briefly but intensively, in the art of reciting poetry by my poetic mentor, Beat Generation poet Lew Welch, whose doctrine was: “Language is Speech”. In terms of recitation, this largely translates as “Straight Talk”, thus (ideally) avoiding both emotive theatricality and “clinical” neutrality in the oral presentation of poetry. Lew’s theory as to how poetry should be recited was based on his studied reproduction of prevailing American speech patterns, particularly when they arise from situations where the speech has some real work to do. That it was not simply a form of “method acting”, a reliance upon one’s uncultivated, pre-artistic emotional subjectivity, but rather a true art, or artifice, is indicated by the following lines from his poem “For Joseph Kepecs”:</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The poem is not the heart’s cry</p>
<p>(Though it seems to be if you have craft enough)</p>
<p>The poem is made to carry the heart’s cry</p>
<p> </p>
<p>As for the sound of speech with real work to do, Lew tells the story of the day he took a group tour through a California winery. As he strolled from point to point with the others, listening to the sleepy drone of the tour guide reciting a spiel he’d performed a thousand times before, suddenly the man’s voice changed: “<em>Who’s kid is that!?</em>” In this necessary, immediate and appropriate response to the situation at hand—an out-of-control child about to fall into a vat of wine—Lew heard the clear contrast between living speech and dead speech: heard it so clearly and permanently that it became a principle and a paradigm.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Lew’s “tutorials” for Language-is-Speech are found mostly in his “Passenger Poems”, as well as in “Din Poem” and elsewhere. In “Din Poem” an example of Straight Talk, also known as “everyday utilitarian speech in interpersonal situations”, appears as follows:</p>
<p> </p>
<p>NEVER. NEVER PUT THE GOD-DAMN CAMERA IN THE</p>
<p>GLOVE COMPARTMENT. I TOLD YOU AND TOLD YOU TO</p>
<p>NEVER PUT THE GOD-DAMN CAMERA IN THE GLOVE</p>
<p>COMPARTMENT. SO WHAT DO YOU DO? YOU PUT THE</p>
<p>GOD-DAMN CAMERA IN THE GLOVE COMPARTMENT.</p>
<p>AND ITS’S STOLEN! SEE?</p>
<p> </p>
<p>If you can read this overheard or “found poem” out loud—presumably a husband’s admonishment to a careless wife—and make it sound as it really would sound or actually did sound, then (as Lew would say), you can correctly recite poetry that is composed in American English.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Lew’s “Passenger Poems” are found poems from the period when he was a cab driver, overheard American speech from some of the fares in the back seat of his cab. Here’s one from a nurse, presumably a middle-aged woman disappointed with life, who now feels free to issue her complaint—half to herself, half before a witness she knows she will likely never meet again—in the anonymous intimacy of a taxi cab:</p>
<p> </p>
<p>I don’t like cats kittens are alright I guess</p>
<p>you can love ‘em when they’re little, like people,</p>
<p>but then they grow up and take advantage of you</p>
<p> </p>
<p>and how can you love ‘em any more?</p>
<p> </p>
<p>            The voice begins hurried and matter-of-fact, quickly lapsing into a self-pity that still falls shy of full disclosure, though its import is obvious enough—a self-pity likely fueled by alcohol, thus the cab. Anyone who can recite these lines correctly, based on either an unconscious memory or a clear and conscious memory of how one or more Americans have spoken in similar circumstances, can correctly recite poetry written in American English. (This, and the rest of Lew’s tutorials, can and should be practiced by American poets who seriously want to learn their craft.)</p>
<p> </p>
<p>            And when it comes to Straight Talk in English language poetry, the two consummate masters are John Donne and Frank Sinatra. Donne was not so much composing or reciting “poetry” as he was <em>talking</em>—thus the correct way to recite him is to just forge ahead, saying what he said, rhyme and meter be damned. Likewise Sinatra “talks” his songs rather than crooning them, which is one of the things that made him the greatest of the Italian-American pop singers. Plenty of great blues singers and jazz singers also know that art. (When Lew first heard Jim Morrison sing, he compared him to Sinatra.)</p>
<p> </p>
<p>            Just because Poetry is Speech, however, poetic recitation need not be didactic or conversational in tone. Speech that is both passionate and accurate can be, in fact must be, truly <em>sung</em>. I will never forget the night when Lew Welch “sang” me the Yeats poem “Byzantium”. He truly rendered it as High Poetry, with consummate elocution, yet he never inadvertently wandered outside the walls of what is actually possible for standard American speech when functioning at white heat.  Tight, slow, resonant, sonorous, incantory, deliberate—better than the interesting but nonetheless easily-bested magical sing-song of Dylan Thomas—he imprinted that poem indelibly on my memory: <em>stamped</em> me with it. One would “naturally” think, of course, that the high bardic declamation of Yeats in his “Byzantium”, perhaps the most musically and symbolically dense and substantial of all his poems, could never be read in the same voice as “NEVER PUT THE GODDAMN CAMERA IN THE GLOVE COMPARTMENT”. One, however, would be wrong.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>            In his book <strong><em>How I Work as a Poet</em></strong>, Lew says: “My job [includes] learning how to become the kind of man who has something of worth to say”. Only if you have something that you really think is worthwhile saying, not just some language-contraption you’ve strung together with bits of twine and paper-clips, will you have a chance to recite it <em>as if</em> you really meant it. This, however, will not absolve you of the need to learn the <em>art</em> of reciting it as if you really meant it. As with depth of character, so with poetic expression: you will need both the native capacity for it and the correct and appropriate cultivation of that capacity so it won’t go to waste. Thus we can confidently assert, in Aristotelian terms, that the correct recitation of poetry requires two things, the Matter and the Form: some thing that is really worth saying and the craft necessary to say it <em>as if</em> you really meant it, an art which still has to be learned and perfected—even if, in all sincerity, you already do really mean it.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> Neither sincerity nor style, when taken alone, are enough. Without sincerity, style will fail; without style, sincerity will not “come across.” A man chatting up a woman will fail if he has only the Form, meaning an accomplished style of approach (“That’s a great line,” says the Muse, “how many other women have you tried that one on?”), or only the Matter, meaning real attraction and/or affection, since the woman knows that if the man does not have the courage to say what he really means with clarity and beauty, he will likely prove inadequate in other ways.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>            So, yes, there is a third element necessary for the correct recitation of poetry: courage. The poet reciting either his or her own works or those of another will fail miserably if he or she is not really willing to put him- or herself emotionally on the line; this is part of what Ezra Pound meant when he said “more poets fail through lack of character than through lack of talent.” In the recitation of poetry, emotive theatricality and clinical neutrality, fake emotion vs. suppressed emotion, are two opposing ways of avoiding the moment of confrontation with sincere emotion, otherwise known as the Moment of Truth.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The full danger and rigor of this confrontation is classically expressed by Federico Garcia Lorca in his essay “The <em>Duende</em>: Theory and Divertissement”. Dietrich Bonhoeffer wrote a book about the Christian resistance to Hitler called <strong><em>The Cost of Discipleship</em></strong>; Lorca’s essay on the <em>Duende</em> might well have been titled “The Cost of Poetry.” Lew remarked on how many modern poets have died young of alcoholism, suicide, drug addiction; he himself ended his life at 44 as an alcoholic suicide. According to Lorca, the <em>Duende</em> is the dark, chthonic power behind all true poetry, true song, true flamenco or true bullfighting; he tells us that “the <em>Duende</em> will not approach at all if he does not see the possibility of violent death”; when I quoted this definition to a Sufi of my acquaintance, he said: “The <em>Duende</em> is <em>al-Jallal</em>, the Majesty of God.” A perfect expression of the quality of the <em>Duende</em> can be found in the following poem by Ibn al-Qabturnuh, a poet of Muslim Andalusia:</p>
<p> </p>
<p>I remembered Sulayma when the passion</p>
<p>   of battle was as fierce</p>
<p>as the passion of my body when we parted.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>I thought I saw, among the lances, the tall</p>
<p>   perfection of her body,</p>
<p>and when they bent toward me, I embraced them.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>            Dealing with the <em>Duende</em>, with emotional sincerity, requires the virtue of emotional asceticism, an ability to “hold one’s feeling” that is akin to the capacity to hold one’s liquor. This art is becoming increasingly rare in our time, which may be why contemporary violinists can scrape away at an astronomical rate (they call it “virtuosity”) but seem unable to render emotional subtlety or sweetness; they likely fear that if they were to attempt this they would collapse, musically speaking, into slobbering emotional drunks—and they are probably right. It was this quality of emotional asceticism, this <em>continence</em> in the realm of feeling, that W. B. Yeats attempted to express in his notion (from <strong><em>A Vision</em></strong>) of <em>the antithetical tincture </em>(aristocratic and passionate), which is opposed to the <em>primary tincture</em> (democratic and sentimental). Lew Welch’s closest approach to this virtue was his technique, when reciting poetry, of inclining his head so that the tears that flooded his eyes would not blear his vision but drop on the page instead; in other words, he had trained himself to <em>weep without sobbing</em>, which is not an easy thing to do. I can usually only accomplish this if I am able to cause myself physical pain, as for example by driving a ball-point pen into my thigh while reciting. (Lew’s next lesson, which he did not complete, would have been to train himself to <em>feel</em> without <em>drinking</em>.)</p>
<p> </p>
<p>            Emotional sincerity has nothing to do with song vs. speech, lyrical musicality vs. dry prosiness, Dylan Thomas’ “Do not go gentle into that good night” vs. Robert Frost’s “Good fences make good neighbors.” It can be found or missed in opera; it can also be found or missed in a condemning judge’s stark intonation of “<em>and may God have mercy on your soul</em>.” The question is, can you stand the sincerity of the feeling—stand <em>next to</em> it as a clear detached observer—while simultaneously standing <em>in</em> it as the one fully bearing the weight of it? If you can’t then you’d better get off the stage.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>            In poetry, emotion is the Matter, since it can only arise when the poet or the one reciting the poem has been touched by a profound truth, on whatever level that truth may manifest; it is also the Energy that fuels both composition and recitation. The Form is that which contains the Energy, allows it to <em>form itself</em>, prevents it from being wasted, and lets it be transmitted. As William Blake said in <strong><em>The Marriage of Heaven and Hell</em></strong>,</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Energy is the only life and is from the Body</p>
<p>and Reason is the bound or outward circumference of Energy.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>            Those poets who can tap the depth and specific quality of the Energy both demanded and invoked by the Matter, and still keep this Energy within Reason, within the Form not imposed upon it but intrinsic and proper to it—those who can be exquisitely careful, as in a Zen tea ceremony, not to spill a drop of it—can recite poetry as it should be recited. And, because Language is Speech, the poet who can recite well will probably be able to write well too, since his language is not a visual thing to him, as it is nowadays with those who text instead of talking, but fully inhabits his body, moves it, and therefore has the power to either save his life or take it away, depending upon whether he or not he <em>cheats</em>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>I will end this essay with one of the justifications that are unfortunately made necessary by the contemporary social mores. The timid, Neo-Puritanical college-educated reader will, of course, have noted the plethora of gender-specific pronouns in this essay, as well as the clear bias toward the masculine ones, toward the poet as “he”. I believe this practice can be justified by considering this essay partly as an historical exhibit, since I received my direct transmission of poetry-lore from Lew Welch in the late 60’s and early 70’s, and partly as a map of a particular psycho-physical formation. Poetry, to Lew Welch, was profoundly heterosexual, likely more so than to any other poet of his generation (Gary Snyder possibly excepted), a generation in which few women of any stature rose to prominence—Denise Levertov being by far the finest exception—and which also included many gay male writers. The heterosexual male model of poetry is certainly not the only one, nor is it necessarily the greatest one, as witness Sappho, Emily Dickinson, Walt Whitman and Allen Ginsberg. But it <em>is</em> a model, a distinct design, a specific configuration of energy that must operate according to its own laws. Lew understood a man’s speech as expressive of his essential masculinity—a masculinity that only exists, however, in a polar relationship with an essentially feminine energy, or force, or figure, without which no poetic expression (on the traditional heterosexual model) is possible: namely, the Muse. And while the power of the Muse essentially envelopes, and profoundly moves, and in this sense dominates the male poet, this in no way undermines his expressive and intentional masculinity. On one occasion Lew expressed this truth to me with undeniable clarity when he told me, “the Muse doesn’t [practice oral sex on you]”. She <em>invokes</em> the male poet’s expressive power, his active intent; she doesn’t drain this power or usurp this intent. And it’s entirely apt in this context to remember Lew Welch’s cogent warning, from “Leo, in Absence of Fire”, to the heterosexual Muse-inspired male poet about the occupational hazards of this approach to his art: “Anyone who confuses his mistress with his muse is asking for real trouble from both of them”.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>I believe that the poetic Muse, for Lew Welch, incarnated the power of <em>listening</em>, without which speech, no matter how passionate or how accurate, hurls itself ineffectually against a stone wall. As William Blake put it in <strong><em>The Marriage of Heaven and Hell</em></strong>, “the Prolific would cease to be Prolific unless the Devourer, as a sea, received the excess of his delights”; this is an expression of the <em>tantra</em> of poetic composition and recitation, precisely. On the other hand, according to contemporary gender mythology—which to my mind is profoundly sexist—<em>speaking</em> is active and represents authority, or <em>authorship</em>, while <em>listening</em> is passive and therefore represents a condition of relative oppression. This just goes to show how wrongheaded today’s notions of both power and gender can be. A fundamental principle is missing in the idea that listening is a form of oppression—the principle that <em>listening is judgment</em>. The Ear of the Muse is rigorous, demanding, and not to be sidestepped, tricked or cheated: if she detects incompetence, insensitivity, evasion, lying or any other form of cowardice in the male poet’s offering to her, she will <em>immediatel</em>y deny him—by which I mean, deny his living human body—the energy it needs to take the next full breath. Simply stated, if a male poet, operating according to the heterosexual model of poetry, does not make the sacrifices necessary to perfect his art, to both become the kind of person who is worth listening to, and to learn how to say something <em>as if</em> <em>he really meant it</em>, then that art will shorten his life. His liaison with the Muse, as dramatized in “The Ballad of Thomas Rymer” (Child 37, C, B &amp; A) is a contract which must be fulfilled to the letter. Therefore:</p>
<p> </p>
<p>American poets, learn your job;</p>
<p>Write whatever irks the mob;</p>
<p>Stomp these wimps who fear to <em>mean</em>,</p>
<p>Whose sole craft is to make the scene.</p>
<p>Born yesterday, to the world they go;</p>
<p>“Born again” they’ll never know.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Cast a slim eye</em></p>
<p><em>On dusk, on dawn:</em></p>
<p><em>Driver, drive on.</em></p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p align="center"><strong>Freedom from the World of Words</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Beyond the strictly performance-oriented and “crafty” aspects of the poetic art, one of the central goals of Lew’s curriculum was to create “freedom from the world of words”—a strange thing, one might think, for a poet to teach; yet that teaching was central to his own particular brand of “perceptual Buddhism”, and was perfectly in line with the Buddhist aphorism, “to name something is to kill it.” As Lew declared:</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Those who live in the world of words</p>
<p>Kill us</p>
<p>Who seek union with what goes on whether I look at it or not.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>“Union with what goes on whether I look at it or not” was Lew’s way of talking about what it might be like to reach absolute objectivity, remembering Frithjof Schuon’s observation that “in order to attain objectivity it is necessary to die a little”, and in the understanding that the world of words, our obsession to <em>name</em> things, always veils absolute objectivity by introducing the subjective element. He well understood that one of the main elements in <em>Sangsara</em>, the world of illusion-producing-suffering—if not the lynch-pin of the whole thing—is the universal human tendency to mistake the names of things for the things themselves, after which we see the things themselves only through the lens of those names, thus his doctrine that “only poets know that words don’t mean anything.” When words cease—at least as the labels we stick on things, the frames-of-perception created by language—what does the world look like? The answer is: <em>Energy</em>. The world-beyond-words is what the Hindus call Shakti—another name for the Great Goddess, known to inspired lyric poets as the Muse. That Energy is the Matter half of the Form-and-Matter pair from Aristotle’s famous hylomorphic theory—which, when the two are married, beget what is called “substantial form”, as when the <em>matter</em> of a poem, what the poet wants to say, is perfectly united with the <em>form</em> of the poem, the best and only way of saying it. All Matter, for the poem or for a life, is drawn from the reservoir of universal Energy, the universal potentiality for experience, otherwise known as the Cosmos. But the Form of the poem, of the life—the <em>soul</em> of it—comes purely from God through the unseen world. There is no way to predict what shape that form will take until it appears; it’s all already there in the first moment of creation, but it only fully reveals itself as the poem is composed, or the life lived out.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>For Lew—though he wouldn’t have said it this way—the idea was make the world of <em>language</em> part of the Matter, not the Form, to avoid the trap of expecting your words to do your talking for you by realizing that <em>words</em> don’t mean anything, <em>you</em> do. (The question then becomes: do the words, your intent to speak them, and the form that intent takes, come from <em>you</em>, your ego, or simply <em>through</em> you from beyond you, from inspiration—which ultimately means, from the First Speaker Himself? It could be that Lew Welch’s inability to answer this question is what ultimately ended his life?)</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Lew worked to turn words into matter rather than form by comparing human language to the virtually-formless din made by a treeful of blackbirds, and gave us exercises to help us make this transformation, composed (for example) of all the found poems and samples of American speech he exhibits in his “Din Poem”:</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Hi, man, what’s happening? See you people later.</p>
<p>Hi, man, what’s happening? See you people later.</p>
<p>Hi, man, what’s happening? See you people later.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>If William Carlos Williams, the mentor of many of the Beat poets (including Lew), could say “no ideas but in things” (a very Aristotelian poetic), Lew did him one better by maintaining that “words are things, not ideas”, thereby leaving no way for Form and Meaning to arrive but from somewhere beyond language entirely.</p>
<p align="center"><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>Two Riddles</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>            </strong>As a further step toward producing freedom from the world of words, Lew composed three <em>riddles</em>—“The Rider Riddle”, “The Riddle of Bowing”, and “The Riddle of Hands”—whose answers are entirely concrete. The solutions to these riddles are <em>not ideas</em>; they are nothing that the world of words could conceive of or understand—consequently nobody affected by “the philosopher disease” will be able to solve them. I’m leaving out “The Rider Riddle” here because it leads somewhere else, toward Shamanism; it’s basically a way of finding your spirit helper or totem animal. (I’ll get back to this riddle when the time comes to tell to the story of Lew’s death and continuance.) But the other two are more like <em>koans</em>. They can’t be figured out by thinking about them; the only way to solve them is to let go of all philosophical and symbolic thinking, and make your mind as <em>concrete</em> as possible. Lew says about them: “They are Koans for beginners, making no claim for Perfect Enlightenment, but those who solve them will discover a deep spiritual insight.” Unlike <em>koans</em>, however, they have explicit answers that can be told—but shouldn’t; they should only be confirmed. Both The Riddle of Bowing and The Riddle of Hands have only one right answer.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>As an introduction to these I’ll give you the riddle from one of Lew’s major poems, “Wobbly Rock”, along with its correct solution, just to show you what I mean by “concrete”, and to introduce that riddle I need to say (in Lew’s words) that Wobbly Rock is “a real rock/ (believe this first)/ resting on actual sand at the surf’s edge:/ Muir Beach, California….Hard common stone/ Size of the largest haystack/ It moves when hit by waves/ Actually shudders”. Lew used to sit on that rock to meditate; it has a precisely square little step or cleft on it that makes a perfect meditation seat (half lotus). I’ve meditated there myself. Imagine how sitting in meditation on a huge boulder that rocks back and forth as the waves strike it—<em>k-CHUNK</em>,<em> k-CHUNK</em>—could teach, in a completely visceral, non-conceptual way, the Buddhist principles of universal <em>anitya</em>—Impermanence—and universal <em>shunyata—</em>Emptiness.And, paradoxically, you can only realize the <em>anitya</em> part of it, universal motion, if you become perfectly <em>still</em>—if, as Lew puts it, you “sit real still and keep your mouth shut.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Here’s the riddle:</p>
<p> </p>
<p align="center"><em>Dychymig Dychymig: </em>(riddle me a riddle)</p>
<p align="center"> </p>
<p>                                                         Waves and the sea. If you</p>
<p>                                                         take away the sea</p>
<p> </p>
<p>                                                   Tell me what it is</p>
<p> </p>
<p>This riddle brings together two (not unrelated) things that Lew liked to do: play with language, and point to the world beyond language, the <em>real</em> world. The solution is: If you take away “the sea” from “Waves and the sea,” you get “Waves and,” which, to the ear, is also “wave-sand”. So the solution is something anyone who has seen a sandy ocean beach has seen: the pattern of waves, or ripples, left by the ebbing tide in the drying sand. The whole conceptual universe of permanence vs. change, stationary vs. moving, Form vs. Matter is thus reduced to a single concrete visual image, available to anyone who’s ever walked on a sandy beach. Subtract the word-play, and this is the precise mind that can solve the following two riddles. (I could add that “The Riddle of Hands” and “The Riddle of Bowing” have to do with <em>jiriki </em>and<em> tariki</em>—two terms taken from Zen, denoting “self-power” and “other-power”<em>—</em>but this is a later conceptual gloss; it’s not really a hint but only a smoke-screen, a misdirection.) And so:</p>
<p align="center"><strong><em> </em></strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong><em> </em></strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong><em>The Riddle of Bowing</em></strong></p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p>In every culture, in every place and time, there has always been a religion, and in every one of these religions there has always been the gesture of bowing so fully that the <br/> forehead strikes the ground.</p>
<p> Why is this?</p>
<p> (There is only one right answer to this riddle)<br/> ________________________________________________</p>
<p> COMMENTARY BY THE RED MONK</p>
<p> <em>Sooner or later the gesture is necessary no matter which way you go. Suzuki bows with so much confidence we all feel bold.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p align="center"><strong><em>The Riddle of Hands</em></strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>In every culture, in every place and time, there has always been a religion, and in every one of these religions, there has always been the gesture of hands clasped together, as Christians do to pray, in order to signify something important.</p>
<p> Why is this?</p>
<p> (There is only one right answer to this riddle)<br/> ________________________________________________</p>
<p> </p>
<p>COMMENTARY BY THE RED MONK:</p>
<p> <em>The gesture has but one source. Who would think to pick his nose, or cross his eyes at such a moment?</em></p>
<p><em><br/> The man who claims to feel power between his hands is lost in forms and ideas. The man who clasps his hands and waits will never see the light.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Lew comments:</p>
<p> </p>
<p>It is no accident that people, everywhere, have always clasped their hands that way, for those purposes. Think about it. Why not any of the millions of other gestures and stances? Why, always, this one?</p>
<p>             The Riddle of Bowing is much easier of the two.  Try that first and use the same Mind to try to solve Hands.</p>
<p>             But please don't waste my time by telling me that Bowing shows respect for the earth or that you are vulnerable to a great power or you are submitting to something. I haven't got time for that baby-talk.</p>
<p>             Lew told me the answer to “Bowing”, and I solved “Hands” by myself, my answer later confirmed by his common-law wife Magda Cregg after Lew’s suicide. Whoever wants to crack these riddles must conquer the Monkey Mind and get cured of the Philosopher Disease. The one who thinks he or she has solved one or both of them is invited to apply to me, since I am empowered to say “pass” or “fail”.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p align="center"><strong>Poets and their Dilemma</strong></p>
<p align="center"> </p>
<p>Ezra Pound once said: “Poets are the antennae of the race.” It’s been my experience, however, that we are actually more like “the mine-canaries of the race”, the ones who first pick up all the toxic influences and cultural diseases that will later spread throughout society; if the poet sitting next to you keels over, you’d better put on your face mask and go into quarantine as quickly as possible. As poets, our psychic immune-systems are in a generally weakened condition, something that is both an occupational hazard and a necessary element in the particular kind of sensitivity necessary to the art. Those of us who survive their various infections with minds and bodies relatively intact will have built rare immunities—not to mention the fact that we sometimes become world-class diagnosticians.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>            The pure quest for experience, which pretty well describes the greater part of lyric poetry, always involves sin, which leads either to repentance or to the denial of God. But can we really recognize sin without experience? The <em>shari’ah</em>, the Sacred Law of Islam, or any moral code based on Revelation, says that we can. Yet is not every saint, in some sense, a repentant sinner? The Law does not absolve you of experience, of the pure quest of the ego, the <em>nafs</em>, for its own self-expression, but it does show you how to recognize that misguided and <em>errant</em> quest, even in actions that seemed entirely pure and un-self-interested. First the Law discovers sin, then the Remembrance of God absolves it—which is why the genre known as “Confessions of the Reformed Rake”, like the one by St. Augustine, will always have its place. William Blake said, in his “Proverbs of Hell” from <strong><em>The Marriage of Heaven and Hell</em></strong>, “If the Fool would persist in his folly he would become Wise”—wise enough to leave that folly behind. He also said, “The Road of Excess leads to the Palace of Wisdom”, simply because “You never know what is enough until you know what is more than enough.” “Hell” to Blake, at least in that fairly early poem from which these quotes are taken, was not the Kingdom of Evil but the Kingdom of Energy and Experience, which is why he said of his master John Milton, author of the great <strong><em>Paradise Lost</em></strong>—both of them born under the sign of Sagittarius, as I was—that Milton was “a true poet, and of the Devil’s party without knowing it.” Goethe, in his <strong><em>Faust</em></strong>, the great theological treatise on the Romantic spirit, was wrong to say that pure experience alone, whose patron and guide is the Devil himself, will lead to salvation<em> without repentance</em>, without the painstaking discovery of sin and the painful purification from the bonds of it. Likewise the surah “The Poets” of the Holy Qur’an tells us: <em>Shall I inform you upon whom the devils descend? They descend on every sinful, false one. They </em>[the sinners]<em> listen eagerly, but most of them </em>[both the sinners and the devils, the Jinn, whom the pre-Islamic poets of Arabia claimed to be inspired by]<em> are liars. As for the poets, the erring follow them. Hast thou not seen how they stray in every valley, and say that which they do not? Save those who believe and do good works, and remember Allah much, and vindicate themselves after they have been wronged?</em> To <em>say</em> something but not <em>do</em> it is to extend the name and image of Reality into imaginative forms that one has neither the power, the integrity, nor the <em>right</em> to fully realize. It is to create phantasms, to go into debt to Reality Itself, and thereby to wrong oneself, sometimes mortally. Poetry is boast, only action is proof; to <em>know</em> more than you can <em>be </em>or<em> do</em> is to be ravished, and then sorely punished, by the Reality on whose ground you have trespassed without invitation, purely on the basis of arrogance and self-will. The poet who <em>vindicates</em> him- or herself after having inflicted great self-wrong is the one who has paid, with spiritual warfare and the suffering of the Greater Jihad, the debt he or she incurred when arrogantly claiming the power of Divine creative speech—speech whose function is <em>to say what is</em>—and has thereby become a <em>siddiq</em>, an honest human being. This is what it is to be “as good as your word”.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 22:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1684561023495332</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ June 16, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Humans and Other Animals: Multifaith Responses to the Significance and Symbolism of Animals in Science and Religion Dialogue</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/111562</link>
						<description><p><strong>**UPDATED DEADLINES AND CFP**</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Deadline for abstract submission MIDNIGHT 16th June 2023</li>
<li>Deadline for RESIDENTIAL conference registration MIDNIGHT 6th August 2023</li>
<li>Deadline for NON-RESIDENTIAL conference registration 23rd August 2023</li>
</ul>
<p>The committee invites submission of papers under TWO categories (1) those that address the SIGNIFICANCE AND SYMBOLISM OF NON-HUMAN ANIMALS within the science and religion dialogue. (2) OPEN CALL for papers relating to any area of SCIENCE AND RELIGION dialogue - (preference given to those addressing matters related to creation, identity, and biological sciences).</p>
<p>The committee welcome submissions from all faith perspectives and authors are invited to address the theme from a range of perspectives. For more details see https://www.srforum.org/srf-conference-2023-cambridge</p>
<p>The animal and religions dialogue has been growing over the last 25 years, the aim of this conference is to bring this broadening area of scholarship to dialogue with the science-religion arena through two broad strands:</p>
<p><em><strong>Strand 1: </strong></em>Perhaps viewed as the most prevalent interaction of science, religion and human-animal interactions, this strand focuses on ethical and environmental issues raised by anthropocentric views of the relationship. Thus includes but is not limited to matters of ecology, stewardship, and animal ethics (broadly construed and may relate to matters of urbanisation and conservation as well as animal-human relations).</p>
<p><em><strong>Strand 2: </strong></em>The second strand recognises the broader implications of scientific and interdisciplinary approaches to non-human animals on wider areas of theological enquiry. This strand examines the new perspectives that can be bought to the science-religion conversation through critical engagement with “the animal” adding further depth, theory, or methodology to our theological discussion. This includes bestiaries, mythology, and fables, the relationship(s) between humans and animals, Incarnation and embodiment, Ritual / proto-religious behaviour in animals and textual and ritual meanings of animal bodies.</p>
<p><em><strong>Strand 3 : </strong></em>OPEN CALL - papers relating to any area of SCIENCE AND RELIGION dialogue - (preference given to those addressing matters related to creation, identity, and biological sciences).</p>
<p>ABSTRACTS should be between 150- 500 words and submitted by email (<a data-key="122">see website for details</a>). Subject to sufficient submissions the committee will aim to have even representation across the three strands. Please note in your submission which strand you are submitting under.</p>
<p><u><strong>Keynote Speakers and Titles</strong></u></p>
<p>31st August 2023: The Gowland Public Lecture 2023 by Dr Suzanna Millar (responder tbc)<strong> From larvae to Leviathan: Living with animals in the book of Job </strong></p>
<p>1st September 2023: Conference Dinner with Speaker TBC</p>
<p>Confirmed Keynote Speakers:</p>
<ul>
<li>Opening Keynote by SRF Vice President Dr Celia Deane-Drummond: <strong>We See in a Glass Darkly: Exploring the Hermeneutics of Virtue and Vice Beyond the Species Boundary</strong></li>
<li>Dr Margaret B. Adam: <strong>Should Commodities Flourish? Farmed Animals, Christian Ethics, and Veterinary Behavioural Science</strong></li>
<li>Dr Louis Caruana SJ: <strong>Future togetherness: drawing inspiration from Teilhard de Chardin </strong></li>
<li>Dr Alexander Hall: <strong>Explorations of the non-human in global histories of evolution and religion</strong></li>
<li>Dr Anne Solomon: <strong>Animals and ancient religion: What can prehistoric art tell us?</strong></li>
<li>Dr Peter Altmann: Title TBC</li>
</ul></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1684474623789929</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ July 31, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Phenomenology, Reality and Essences</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/111526</link>
						<description><p>In phenomenology, a standard way to make claims about reality is through the identification of invariant features of and in experience, traditionally called “essences”. Phenomenology as essence intuition, eidetic variation or eidetic reduction raises fundamental questions concerning, among other things, the ontological structure of reality, the status of essences, their normativity, the relationship to empirical sciences and the nature of the phenomenological a priori in general.</p>
<p>This conference has two aims: (1) To establish a fuller picture of the manifold ways in which essence intuition has been understood by phenomenologists historically. How was phenomenology as an eidetic science conceived in and especially outside of Husserl’s writings? (2) To inquire if the idea of essence intuition, broadly construed, might still be considered a viable way of doing phenomenology, especially in light of recent interdisciplinary developments in various fields of phenomenology.</p>
<p>For more information please visit: </p></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 05:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1684388229351246</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ November 16, 2023 -  November 17, 2023] Conference or similar: Phenomenology, Reality and Essences</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/111522</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p>In phenomenology, a standard way to make claims about reality is through the identification of invariant features of and in experience, traditionally called “essences”. Phenomenology as essence intuition, eidetic variation or eidetic reduction raises fundamental questions concerning, among other things, the ontological structure of reality, the status of essences, their normativity, the relationship to empirical sciences and the nature of the phenomenological a priori in general.</p>
<p>This conference has two aims: (1) To establish a fuller picture of the manifold ways in which essence intuition has been understood by phenomenologists historically. How was phenomenology as an eidetic science conceived in and especially outside of Husserl’s writings? (2) To inquire if the idea of essence intuition, broadly construed, might still be considered a viable way of doing phenomenology, especially in light of recent interdisciplinary developments in various fields of phenomenology.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 05:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1684388229351245</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ June 4, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Fake Faiths: God, Beliefs and the Rationality of Assent</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/111446</link>
						<description><p>University of Lucerne (Switzerland)</p>
<p>Master’s programme <em>Philosophy, Theology and Religions </em>(PhilTeR)</p>
<p><strong>Call for Papers</strong></p>
<p>Undergraduate Philosophy Conference <a name="_Hlk134191968"></a></p>
<p><strong><em>Fake Faiths: God, Beliefs and the Rationality of Assent</em></strong></p>
<p>We invite undergraduate philosophy and theology students to submit abstracts for the undergraduate section of the philosophy conference organized by the team of the <a href="https://www.unilu.ch/en/faculties/faculty-of-theology/institutes-and-research-units/theirs/online-masters/">Online Master’s in Philosophy, Theology and Religion</a> of the University of Lucerne. <a name="_Hlk134192063"></a>The conference will take place in Lucerne from July 3rd to July 5th, with the undergraduate section on July 5th.</p>
<p><a name="_Hlk134192093"></a>Speakers include: G. Ventimiglia (Lucerne), K. Dormandy (Innsbruck), , R.T. Mullins (Lucerne), T. Scrutton (Leeds), , and Amber Griffioen (Duke University).</p>
<p><a name="_Hlk134192540"></a>We welcome papers on any topic in the philosophy of religion, although preference will be given to contributions within the field of epistemology and faith. Possible topics include, but are not limited to:</p>
<p>·         Epistemological issues related to religious belief</p>
<p>·         Rationality and justification for belief in God</p>
<p>·         Arguments for and against the existence of God</p>
<p>·         Religious pluralism and diversity</p>
<p>·         The role of religious experience in belief formation</p>
<p>·         The relationship between faith and reason</p>
<p>·         The ethics of religious belief and practice</p>
<p>We cordially invite abstracts of up to 500 words for papers suited for a 30-minute presentation, either on Zoom or in-person.</p>
<p>The <strong>deadline</strong> for abstract submission is <strong>June 4th</strong>, and we kindly ask that you include your name, the presentation title, institution, and contact information along with your submission to <a name="_Hlk134192379"></a><strong>philter.researchconference2023@gmail.com</strong></p>
<p><a name="_Hlk134192683"></a>We prioritize inclusivity and diversity, and therefore preference will be given to undergraduate students from underprivileged groups, in accordance with the University of Lucerne’s standard policy.</p>

 </description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1684215433324425</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ July 3, 2023 -  July 5, 2023] Conference or similar: Fake Faiths: God, Beliefs and the Rationality of Assent</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/111442</link>
						<description>Venue: Frohburgstrasse 3<br/><br/><p><strong>Call for Papers</strong></p>
<p>Undergraduate Philosophy Conference <a name="_Hlk134191968"></a></p>
<p><strong><em>Fake Faiths: God, Beliefs and the Rationality of Assent</em></strong></p>
<p>We invite undergraduate philosophy and theology students to submit abstracts for the undergraduate section of the philosophy conference organized by the team of the <a href="https://www.unilu.ch/en/faculties/faculty-of-theology/institutes-and-research-units/theirs/online-masters/">Online Master’s in Philosophy, Theology and Religion</a> of the University of Lucerne. <a name="_Hlk134192063"></a>The conference will take place in Lucerne from July 3rd to July 5th, with the undergraduate section on July 5th.</p>
<p><a name="_Hlk134192093"></a>Speakers include: G. Ventimiglia (Lucerne), K. Dormandy (Innsbruck), , R.T. Mullins (Lucerne), T. Scrutton (Leeds), , and Amber Griffioen (Duke University).</p>
<p><a name="_Hlk134192540"></a>We welcome papers on any topic in the philosophy of religion, although preference will be given to contributions within the field of epistemology and faith. Possible topics include, but are not limited to:</p>
<p>·         Epistemological issues related to religious belief</p>
<p>·         Rationality and justification for belief in God</p>
<p>·         Arguments for and against the existence of God</p>
<p>·         Religious pluralism and diversity</p>
<p>·         The role of religious experience in belief formation</p>
<p>·         The relationship between faith and reason</p>
<p>·         The ethics of religious belief and practice</p>
<p>We cordially invite abstracts of up to 500 words for papers suited for a 30-minute presentation, either on Zoom or in-person.</p>
<p>The <strong>deadline</strong> for abstract submission is <strong>June 4th</strong>, and we kindly ask that you include your name, the presentation title, institution, and contact information along with your submission to <a name="_Hlk134192379"></a><strong>philter.researchconference2023@gmail.com</strong></p>
<p><a name="_Hlk134192683"></a>We prioritize inclusivity and diversity, and therefore preference will be given to undergraduate students from underprivileged groups, in accordance with the University of Lucerne’s standard policy.</p>

 </description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1684215433324424</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CfP: Religion and Technology in an era of Rapid Digital and Climate Change</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12831019/cfp-religion-and-technology-era-rapid-digital-and-climate</link>
						<dc:creator>Joseph Satish</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-11-21T00:00:00-05:00">November 21, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-11-23T00:00:00-05:00">November 23, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>India</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Environmental History / Studies, History of Science, Medicine, and Technology, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><div> </div><div> </div><div><b>Religion and Technology in an era of Rapid Digital and Climate Change</b><br/>(RaTiRDaCC 2023)<br/>Organized by: RWTH Aachen University (Germany) and IIT Madras (India)<br/>November 21-23, 2023, IIT Madras, INDIA</div><div> </div><div><b>Call for Papers </b>(<em>Abstract deadline: 23 May 2023</em>)</div><div>Papers are invited (from early researchers, post-doctoral scholars, Faculty and practitioners), for an International Conference to be held from November 21 to 23, 2023 at the Indian Institute of Technology Madras, Chennai, India. This conference aims to discuss the interplay and adaptation strategies in, and between, the realms of religion and technology in an age of tremendous transformations. Among the transformations, we particularly wish to emphasize the rapid developments with regard to the digital world and the climate, and the considerable global changes and challenges they have produced. We think of ‘religion’ in this context as a key source for value-based solutions, and of ‘technology’ as a specific approach to the world. We regard religion and technology as mirror image twins and thus envisage projects on the changing forms of impacts through both of them.</div><div> </div><div>Recent trends in religious studies have emphasized “material religion” - with focus on the material elements of practice rather than just on theological or doctrinal matters. This turn opens up the way for the history of technology productively to intervene in a number of ways. Historians can illuminate the way objects exist in public performances of religious identity and belonging, and the changes in religion and religious practices, riding on technological advances (like online darshans/meditations, social-media channels, online groups, ‘Apps’, etc.). Beyond organized mainstream religions, papers can also look at the interface of technology and the ‘magical’ (acts, spirit possession, black magic), and other so-called 'demonic' work. Others may put the spotlight on the architecture of religious structures, the spiritual character of engineering works, the changing light, sound and other aesthetic elements, and how these changes reshape public participation both in terms of religion and technological usage and challenges. Ethical challenges like loss of privacy, anxiety about the human person’s distinctiveness and dignity, and mankind’s handling of the environment need to be discussed too with regard to increasing digitization and climate change. With the above broad lineaments, proposals can relate themselves to any of the following specific themes:</div><div> </div><div><em>1. Religion and the Digital World</em> – the Digital as a method to capture and describe the world and our livelihoods; vast increase around the world in the use of telecommunication and digital technologies for promotion of both traditional and new-age faiths – their increased valency especially amidst the Covid-19-induced restrictions on physical gatherings; ways in which pilgrimages have been transformed due to the new digital facilities (from travel planning to booking darshans); theological/philosophical re-orientations and reflections centered on these new openings.</div><div> </div><div><em>2. Technology and Religion in the Context of Climate Change</em> – possible solutions to the challenge of climate change from religion/theology; their distinctiveness from secular thought/debates; how climate change has impacted on the self-understanding of religions, their dogmatic, social and moral positions; the climate discourse as a modern form of apocalypticism; practical manifestation of ecological sensitivity - influencing the building of mosques, churches, and temples; influence of local communities and indigenous knowledge systems.</div><div> </div><div><em>3. Artificial Intelligence</em> – philosophical and spiritual/theological reflections touching on fundamental questions of Being, Consciousness and the (Post)human; parallelism in the ‘transcendence’ sought to be attained by spiritual efforts/exercises and those wrought by new spatial categories like ‘metaverse’ (going beyond our understandings of the ‘cyberworld’), and other such ontological questions and dilemmas.</div><div> </div><div><em>4. Technology and Religious scholarship/pedagogy</em> – from printing press to online theology classes; role of technology in preservation of religious materials and creation of religious repositories like digitisation of palm leaf manuscripts, building devotional hymns database; the regional variations in approach and content; the various innovative practices in creation, delivery and marketing; the subjectivity of technology and its power to include and exclude.</div><div> </div><div><em>5. Representation of Religious-Technological life worlds</em> – in literature, arts and films including science fiction/ climate fiction; representations of knowledge in policies and practices affecting the lives on the ground.</div><div> </div><div>In terms of methodology, it is hoped that the various proposals and papers would throw forth a rich mix of different approaches and source materials - including intercultural theology, oral history, decolonizing research methodologies, archival work, textual and media analysis, ethnographic research, social analysis, theoretical formulations and ethical/philosophical reflections.</div><div> </div><div>To submit a paper proposal, please send the following information on a single-sided document in English, before <strong>23 May 2023</strong> to <a href="mailto:ratirdacc23@gmail.com"><strong>ratirdacc23@gmail.com</strong></a>.</div><div><ul><li>A provisional Title and the Theme Number it would fit under (nos. 1 to 5 – see above)</li><li>Full name and academic post/institutional affiliation of the author/s</li><li>Full postal and email-addresses</li><li>An outline of about 400 words, highlighting the relevance of the paper to the conference themes, or other forms of interaction between technology and religion, and the main contribution/argument of the proposed paper</li><li>5-10 keys words</li></ul><div>Information about the acceptance of a paper will be given by end of May 2023 together with guidelines for the paper and its presentation and the Registration fee payment mode. [A nominal registration fee of Rs.500 (15 USD for international participants) is payable].  Complete papers must be received by 25 August 2023. Papers (along with session schedule), will be made available for pre-reading to registered participants. Some of the papers presented at the Conference will be chosen for further expansion and inclusion in a special issue of a relevant journal of high international standing, or in an Edited Volume. (Presentation of paper in the Conference does not automatically guarantee publication).</div><div> </div><div>Most of the outstation speakers will be provided accommodation from 20th November to the evening of 24th November 2023 in the IITM Guest House at a nominal cost of Rs 500 to 1000 per night depending on the size and occupancy (single/double) of the room. Participants who are unable to travel can participate online. Travel or other forms of financial assistance, if any, will be announced if adequate funds are raised.</div><div> </div><div><strong>TIMELINE</strong><br/>Deadline for submission of Abstracts – May 23 2023<br/>Intimation about selected Abstracts - May 30<br/>Deadline for submission of first Drafts - Aug 25<br/>Conference: Nov 21 - 23, 2023<br/>Intimation about Papers selected for Publication – Dec 3 2023<br/>Resubmission of the selected Papers [for Peer Review] - Jan 10 2024</div><div> </div></div></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>John Bosco Lourdusamy<br/>Dept. of Humanities and Social Sciences<br/>IIT Madras, Chennai 600 036, INDIA</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ratirdacc23@gmail.com">ratirdacc23@gmail.com</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 18:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1684215433324423</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>“It Takes a Village”</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12830178/%E2%80%9Cit-takes-village%E2%80%9D</link>
						<dc:creator>Lauren Lemley</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Event</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-07T00:00:00-04:00">June 7, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Government and Public Service, Public Policy, Sociology, Religious Studies and Theology, Social Work</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span>Join us for a virtual film screening </span><span>of the movie <em>It Takes A Village</em></span><span> and a discussion with Rev. Dr. Jamesetta Ferguson, Rev. Dr. Patrick Duggan, and Sandra Acosta, moderated by Rev. Dr. Stephen Ray, Jr.  </span></p><p><span>Produced by the United Church of Christ’s Church Building &amp; Loan Fund, <em>It Takes A Village</em> tells the inspiring story of the creation of the Village at West Jefferson, also known as MOLO Village, which opened in 2021 in Louisville, Kentucky. The 30,000-square, $7 million project was the first investment in decades in the long-neglected Russell neighborhood in Louisville’s West End. Built on a former church parking lot, MOLO Village houses social services, businesses, a bank branch, a restaurant, and more.</span></p><p><span>Hear how the vision of Rev. Dr. Jamesetta Ferguson, pastor of St. Peter’s UCC in Louisville, came to be a reality through her work with Rev. Dr. Patrick Duggan, Executive Director of the UCC Church Building &amp; Loan Fund, and Sandra Acosta, Principal of the AIM Development Group, a New York-based firm which helps for-profit businesses, not-for-profit organizations, and municipalities seeking to conceptualize and implement site specific developments or broader housing, neighborhood and economic development initiatives. </span></p><p><span><em>It Takes A Village</em> reveals the important ways in which the UCC Church Building &amp; Loan Fund, which Congregationalists founded 170 years ago, is working with municipalities and urban planners to repurpose and develop church properties to serve urban audiences and advance the mission of the church in the 21st century.</span></p><p><span>The event is free to all, but registration is required via this link: <a href="https://us06web.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_SSiJauwySDKFnp7iXuYpZw" rel="nofollow">https://us06web.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_SSiJauwySDKFnp7iXuYpZw</a>.</span></p><p><span>After registering, you will receive a confirmation email containing information about joining the webinar.</span></p><p><span>For more information, please email <a href="mailto:info@14beacon.org?subject=It%20Takes%20a%20Village">info@14beacon.org</a>.</span></p><p><br/><span><strong>SPEAKER BIOS</strong></span></p><p><span><strong>Rev. Dr. Jamesetta Ferguson</strong> is the Pastor, St. Peter’s United Church of Christ and President &amp; CEO, of Molo Village CDC, in Louisville, Kentucky.</span></p><p><span><strong>Rev. Dr. Patrick G. Duggan</strong> is Executive Director of the UCC Church Building &amp; Loan Fund and Senior Pastor at the Congregational Church at South Hempstead, New York.</span></p><p><span><strong>Sandra Acosta</strong> is a Principal at AIM Development Group, Corp., a Planning and Real Estate Development Consulting firm, that was the Development Consultant for The Village @ West Jefferson project.</span></p><p><span><strong>Rev. Dr. Stephen G. Ray Jr.</strong> is the Senior Minister at the historic United Church on the Green, New Haven, CT. Prior to this call he served as the 13th President of Chicago Theological Seminary and a past President of the Society for the Study of Black Religion. Ray had a distinguished career in theological education as holder of two endowed chairs and published broadly in the areas of religion and African-American Studies.</span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Lauren Lemley<br/>Communications Manager<br/>Congregational Library &amp; Archives</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:info@14beacon.org">info@14beacon.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.congregationallibrary.org/events/ittakesvillage" target="_blank">https://www.congregationallibrary.org/events/ittakesvillage</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 18:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1684215433324422</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
