<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 12:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 12:22:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>EXTENDED Theophron Journal of Christian Studies: Vice, Virtue, &amp; Conflict</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12297888/extended-theophron-journal-christian-studies-vice-virtue</link>
						<dc:creator>Cameron  Hurta</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-26T00:00:00-05:00">February 26, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Classical Studies, Philosophy, Religious Studies and Theology, Peace History / Studies, Intellectual History</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Taken narrowly, vice and virtue comprise both central considerations of virtue ethical theories and peripheral considerations of any sophisticated normative ethics—that is, all plausible normative ethics will comment on vice and virtue in some manner. Taken broadly, the terms relate to goodness and badness, righteousness and evil, morality and depravity, inculcation and elimination. In each of these conjunctions, conflict stands at the forefront. Similar tensions manifest across theory and lived experience, from disagreement and wars to schisms and debates on the very existence of God. The interplay of vice, virtue, and conflict, then, occasions inquiry into the facets of life in a broken world and faith in the One who alone is perfect.</p><p>With this topic in mind, we invite undergraduate and graduate students, as well as early-career post-docs, to submit to Theophron’s spring 2023 issue. Scholarship from all fields, particularly philosophy, theology, history, and biblical studies, is welcome.</p><p>Possible topics include but are certainly not limited to:</p><ul><li><p>●  Epistemology of Religious or Moral Disagreement</p></li><li><p>●  Virtue’s Role in Christian Discipleship across Traditions</p></li><li><p>●  Prophetic &amp; Apostolic Responses to Political-Religious Tensions</p></li><li><p>●  Moral Arguments for God’s Existence</p></li><li><p>●  Interpretations of Old Testament Conflict Narratives</p></li><li><p>●  Just War Theory &amp; Pacifism in World War II</p></li><li><p>●  Early Church Understandings of Spiritual Conflict</p></li><li><p>●  Historical Christian Responses to Global Strife</p></li><li><p>●  Metaethics and Theories of Sin</p></li><li><p>●  Protestant, Catholic, &amp; Orthodox Views of Vice</p><p>Submission Instructions<br/>Submissions should be between 4,000–6,500 words (not including abstract), conform to the Chicago Manual of Style (17th edition), and be original, unpublished works prepared for double- blind peer review. Please include an abstract of no more than 250 words, uploading the entire manuscript in both PDF and .docx formats at <a href="http://www.theophron.org/submissions.%C2%A0Do" rel="nofollow">www.theophron.org/submissions. Do</a> not place your name or any identifying information on the submitted manuscript—author identities will remain anonymous to reviewers and editors until after final acceptance/rejection decisions.</p><p>Extended: Submissions received by February 26, 2023, will be considered for publication. Direct all questions to <a href="mailto:submissions@theophron.org">submissions@theophron.org</a>.<br/>Visit theophron.org for all live calls for papers, including our year-round, open-topic call.</p></li></ul></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:submissions@theophron.org">submissions@theophron.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="http://www.theophron.org/submissions" target="_blank">http://www.theophron.org/submissions</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 19:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675751828293479</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The war in Ukraine and its impact on ethno-religious minorities in the region</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12283754/war-ukraine-and-its-impact-ethno-religious-minorities-region</link>
						<dc:creator>Nadia  Zasanska</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Workshop</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-05-04T00:00:00-04:00">May 4, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-05-05T00:00:00-04:00">May 5, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Germany</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Borderlands, Ethnic History / Studies, Humanities, Political Science, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Russia's war against Ukraine, which began in 2014 with the annexation of Crimea and the war in the Donbas, and escalated into a full-scale attack in February 2022, was a challenge to the entire system of international relations that has developed since the end of World War II. Researchers and politicians are analyzing the events of the past 20 years, trying to see retrospectively the key moments and signs that had predetermined the current development of the situation. Analyses of Putin's rhetoric, the memory politics of the Great Patriotic War in Russia, and the formation of the Russian lobby in the West are all becoming the subject of intense academic debate.</p><p>Likewise, the internal Ukrainian processes – the reactions of society and the state to the challenges of Russian aggression – arouse more and more research interest from various aspects. Russia's war against Ukraine has had the most dramatic impact on the lives of Ukrainians: tens of thousands killed and wounded, millions of refugees and internally displaced persons, economic paralysis, and enormous damage to infrastructure. Experts agree that it will take decades to overcome the various destructive consequences of the war. At the same time, they acknowledge that the war had a significant impact on the values and identity of Ukrainians, becoming a catalyst for the formation of the Ukrainian nation and horizontal ties, rethinking established social, gender, and other roles. These macro-social processes are already the subject of research by anthropologists, sociologists, political scientists, and other scholars.</p><p>This workshop will examine how the war affected Ukraine's ethno-religious minorities, their identities, religious and cultural practices, and value orientations. We invite abstracts focusing on the transformations in the life of ethno-religious minorities after the annexation of Crimea and the beginning of the war in Donbas, and, in particular, after the full-scale Russian offensive in February 2022. The list of topics for discussion is not limited to the following:</p><p>- Identity, intragroup dynamics, and value orientations of ethno-religious minorities in Ukraine under conditions of war.</p><p>- Russia's war in Ukraine and ethno-religious minorities' migration and displacement.</p><p>- Religious affiliation and connections to transnational religious networks and Ukrainian minorities' migration trajectories.</p><p>- Religious and cultural practices of ethno-religious minorities in Ukraine and their transformations after 2014.</p><p>- Digitalization of religious and cultural practices of ethno-religious minorities in Ukraine in war-divided communities.</p><p>- Ukrainian ethno-religious minorities participation in the war: mobilization, narratives, resources.</p><p>- Intercultural communication in war, majority-minority relations, etc.</p><p>This project aims to produce a collective volume on the war in Ukraine and its impact on ethno-religious minorities in the region. We see its implementation as a two-stage process. In the first stage, we will organize a workshop at the European Center for Minority Issues (ECMI) in Flensburg, Germany, in May 2023 to gather experts in the field. The ECMI will cover the travel expenses and accommodation of the experts during the workshop. In the second stage, we plan to publish an edited volume on ethno-religious minorities in Ukraine during the war.</p><p>The ECMI is co-editing a book series devoted to minority studies entitled Routledge Advances in Minority Studies (RAMS), where the collection will be hosted. Publication of the volume is scheduled for late 2023 – early 2024. We invite researchers to send an abstract for proposed papers (250–300 words) and a short bio-note (max. 100 words) by 20 March 2023 to: <a href="mailto:nadia.zasanska@uni-flensburg.de">nadia.zasanska@uni-flensburg.de</a> and <a href="mailto:murelmira@aias.au.dk">murelmira@aias.au.dk</a>. More detailed information on papers including a style guide will be sent at a later stage. Complete papers of about 6,000 – 8,000 words should be submitted by 29 September 2023.</p><p>Workshop convenors:</p><p>Dr. habil. Kyriaki Topidi (Head of Culture and Diversity Cluster / Senior Researcher, European Centre for Minority Issues (ECMI), Dr. Elmira Muratova (Aarhus University, Denmark), Dr. Nadia Zasanska (Europa-Universität Flensburg, Germany)</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr. Nadia Zasanska, Research Fellow, Europa-Universität Flensburg, Germany</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:nadia.zasanska@uni-flensburg.de">nadia.zasanska@uni-flensburg.de</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.ecmi.de/infochannel/detail/call-for-papers-the-war-in-ukraine-and-its-impact-on-ethno-religious-minorities-in-the-region" target="_blank">https://www.ecmi.de/infochannel/detail/call-for-papers-the-war-in-ukraine-and-its-impact-on-ethno-religious-minorities-i…</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 19:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675751828293478</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Webinar GEPJ - A. Klein “Religion and Politics in Contemporary Japan” February 10, 2023 (10:00-12:00 CEST)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12291749/webinar-gepj-klein-%E2%80%9Creligion-and-politics-contemporary-japan%E2%80%9D</link>
						<dc:creator>Ioan Trifu</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-10T00:00:00-05:00">February 10, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>East Asian History / Studies, Government and Public Service, Japanese History / Studies, Political Science, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Dear colleagues,</p><p><em>Our apologies for cross-posting</em>.</p><p>The French research group on State and Politics in Japan (GEPJ) is very pleased to announce its next seminar (in English):</p><p><u><strong>Axel Klein</strong></u> (University of Duisburg-Essen) will be giving a talk titled</p><p>“<strong>Religion and Politics in Contemporary Japan</strong>”</p><p><em>Date, Time</em>: <strong>February 10th (Friday), 10:00-12:00 (CEST, UTC +1:00) / 18:00-20:00 (JST)</strong></p><p>You are all cordially invited to this event.</p><p>The seminar poster is available for download at: <a href="https://seiji.hypotheses.org/664" rel="nofollow">https://seiji.hypotheses.org/664</a></p><p>The seminar will take place <strong>online</strong> via Zoom. </p><p><strong>Please use this form to register: <a href="https://forms.gle/piLfMDHLj8HvY5f9A" rel="nofollow">https://forms.gle/piLfMDHLj8HvY5f9A</a> </strong></p><p>We look forward to welcoming you !</p><p>All the best,</p><p>Ioan Trifu (INALCO) </p><p>Arnaud Grivaud (Paris City University)</p><p>Xavier Mellet (Waseda University)</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Ioan Trifu</p><p>INALCO (Institut National des Langues et Civilisations Orientales)</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ioan.trifu@gmail.com">ioan.trifu@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://seiji.hypotheses.org/" target="_blank">https://seiji.hypotheses.org/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 18:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675751828293477</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Applications for the DFG Research Training Group GRK 2833 „East Asian Futures“ (EAF)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12290157/call-applications-dfg-research-training-group-grk-2833-%E2%80%9Eeast</link>
						<dc:creator>Christine Moll-Murata</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Fellowship</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-01T00:00:00-05:00">February 1, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-31T00:00:00-04:00">March 31, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Social Sciences, Religious Studies and Theology, Linguistics, East Asian History / Studies, Literature</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><blockquote>The DFG Research Training Group GRK 2833 „East Asian Futures“<br/>at Ruhr University Bochum and University of Duisburg-Essen,<br/>Germany, solicits applications for its doctoral programme:<br/><br/>For doctoral researchers, seven DFG-funded positions (0.75 FTE) and<br/>six affiliated fellowships<br/>For postdocs, one full DFG-funded position and three affiliated<br/>fellowships.<br/><br/>The application period starts on 1 February 2023. Deadline for<br/>applications: 31 March 2023. Start of the programme: 1 October 2023.<br/><br/>The interdisciplinary Research Training Group GRK 2833 will<br/>investigate East Asian projections and conceptions of the future:<br/>how they emerged, on what premises they were based, and how they<br/>have been and continue to be applied to the paradigmatic fields of<br/>(1) language, religion, and ideology, (2) self and society, (3)<br/>resources and technology, and (4) sovereignty and governance. The<br/>temporal focus is on the modern and contemporary periods.<br/><br/>The relevant fields of research are  Sinology/Chinese Studies,<br/>Japanese Studies, Korean Studies and/or further disciplines with a<br/>strong focus on East Asia, such as Social Sciences (Political<br/>Science, Economics, Sociology), History, Religious Studies,<br/>Linguistics, Literary Studies.<br/>Further information on the research programme is given here: <a href="https://east-asian-futures.de/program/" rel="nofollow">https://east-asian-futures.de/program/</a><br/>For details on the application process and requirements, please refer to the EAF website at<br/><br/><a href="https://east-asian-futures.de/call-doctoral-researcher/" rel="nofollow">https://east-asian-futures.de/call-doctoral-researcher/</a>  and <a href="https://jobs.ruhr-uni-bochum.de/jobposting/d743a4357b33fe8c19d6ebd1f95ded0fba109bb30?ref=homepage" rel="nofollow">https://jobs.ruhr-uni-bochum.de/jobposting/d743a4357b33fe8c19d6ebd1f95ded0fba109bb30?ref=homepage</a></blockquote><blockquote><br/><a href="https://east-asian-futures.de/call-post-doc/" rel="nofollow">https://east-asian-futures.de/call-post-doc/</a>   and <a href="https://jobs.ruhr-uni-bochum.de/jobposting/540b9582ee9191c11c1c2c219f732d1d4d99a6a40?ref=homepage" rel="nofollow">https://jobs.ruhr-uni-bochum.de/jobposting/540b9582ee9191c11c1c2c219f732d1d4d99a6a40?ref=homepage</a></blockquote><blockquote><br/><a href="https://east-asian-futures.de/call-affiliated-fellowships/" rel="nofollow">https://east-asian-futures.de/call-affiliated-fellowships/</a><br/><br/><a href="https://east-asian-futures.de/call-affiliated-fellowship-post-doc/" rel="nofollow">https://east-asian-futures.de/call-affiliated-fellowship-post-doc/</a><br/><br/>and feel free to contact us at <a href="mailto:application@east-asian-futures.de">application@east-asian-futures.de</a><br/><br/>Please upload your application as explained under<br/><a href="https://east-asian-futures.de/requirements/" rel="nofollow">https://east-asian-futures.de/requirements/</a> onto the application<br/>platform. Please do not send applications via email or mail.<br/><br/>**************************************************************************<br/><br/>Research Training Group GRK 2833 „East Asian Futures“ (EAF)<br/>Ruhr University Bochum<br/>Faculty of East Asian Studies<br/>Universitätsstr. 134<br/>44799 Bochum<br/>Germany<br/><a href="https://east-asian-futures.de/general-information/" rel="nofollow">https://east-asian-futures.de/general-information/</a><br/><a href="mailto:info@east-asian-futures.de">info@east-asian-futures.de</a></blockquote></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Christine Moll-Murata</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:info@east-asian-futures.de">info@east-asian-futures.de</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://east-asian-futures.de/application/" target="_blank">https://east-asian-futures.de/application/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 18:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675751828293476</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Workshop Digital Humanities and Inquisitorial Studies (Lisbon, 22-23 June, 2023)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12289617/workshop-digital-humanities-and-inquisitorial-studies-lisbon</link>
						<dc:creator>Carla Vieira</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-19T00:00:00-05:00">February 19, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Portugal</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Digital Humanities, Spanish and Portuguese History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Early Modern History and Period Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>This colloquium marks the end of the exploratory research project "The Transcription of the Processes of the Portuguese Inquisition (1536-1821)" (TraPrInq), funded by FCT, in which, for 18 months, a Luso-Brazilian team of paleographers created an artificial intelligence model based on machine learning for the automatic transcription of the processes of the Portuguese Inquisition. The present colloquium responds to a double need: to make a methodological evaluation of the results of the project, and to explore the horizons and possibilities of digital palaeography, which has seen a marked development in the last decade. </p><p>The colloquium is therefore open to proposals for papers from researchers interested in these topics.</p><p>The paper proposed, to be submitted to: <a href="mailto:traprinq@gmail.com">traprinq@gmail.com</a> until February, 19, should not exceed 20 minutes, covering the two fields in question, both (a) digital practices in the study of primary sources and (b) field studies. It is advisable to find out about the current project by consulting the two reference sites. Special attention will be given to proposals that can advance the subsequent phase of this project, i.e. the creation of structures or the use of existing platforms for large-scale transcription and editing of documentary collections, institutional collaboration with the archives that hold these collections, etc.</p><p>Fields: a) Digital Palaeography, Digital Humanities, HTR for historical documents; b) Inquisitorial Studies, Early Modern Studies.</p><p>Modality: in presence and online.</p><p>Scientific Committee:</p><ul><li>João Batista Bottentuit (Universidade Federal do Maranhão, Brasil)</li><li>Isabel Drumond Braga (Universidade de Lisboa)</li><li>Cristina Costa Gomes (Universidade de Lisboa)</li><li>Günter Mühlberger (Innsbrück Universität)</li><li>José Alberto Tavim (Universidade de Lisboa)</li></ul></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:%20traprinq@gmail.com"> traprinq@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://traprinq.mozellosite.com/" target="_blank">https://traprinq.mozellosite.com</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 18:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675751828293475</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ June 8, 2023 -  June 10, 2023] Conference or similar: Phenomenology: Linguistic or Eidetic?</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/107550</link>
						<description>Venue: Universitätsplatz 3<br/><br/><p>The alternative alluded to in the conference title is that between what J. L. Austin called "linguistic phenomenology" (Philosophical Papers, p. 182), broadly conceived as synonymous with "ordinary language philosophy (= OLP), and phenomenology as founded by Edmund Husserl. In this later sense, "phenomenology" is meant to include figures like Eugen Fink, Adolf Reinach or Merleau-Ponty, but also influential secessionists like Heidegger or Derrida. The former tradition is understood as including the likes of Wittgenstein, Ryle, Alan R. White or Cavell. Papers will either cut across the traditions or be basic in a way that makes them relevant for both of them. The following topics have been suggested for discussion:<br/><br/>(1) “S is p” – A Basic Structure of Judgement?<br/><br/>(2) The “Natural Attitude” vs. the Ordinary<br/><br/>(3) Transcendental Subjectivity vs. the “We” of OLP<br/><br/>(4) Voice and Subjectivity<br/><br/>(5) The Inner and the Outer</p>
<p>The first half-day (starting on Thursday, 8 June 2023, 3:30 pm) will be a hybrid event. On Friday and Saturday, the workshop will be held in presence only. No formal registration is required, but let me know if you wish to attend by sending an email to bernhard.ritter AT uni-graz.at</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 06:37:10 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675406228352680</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ June 26, 2023 -  June 30, 2023] Conference or similar: Gratitude</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/107570</link>
						<description>Venue: 1235 University Blvd<br/><br/><p>In this seminar we will explore gratitude as a fundamental moral disposition without which no one can really be happy. <br/>Our culture today is fraught by questions about gratitude. How do we receive in gratitude the goods of our own traditions despite their evils, of which we are increasingly aware? Can we cultivate gratitude in a social-media world of envy, isolation, and self-assertion? Why should we be grateful in the midst of great suffering?<br/><br/>In this seminar, we will attempt to answer these questions and to offer gratitude as an antidote to other challenges, such as feelings of loneliness, resentment, envy, and the self-hatred that oppresses so many today. We will show how gratitude guards against despair, and resists the nihilist attitude that fails to see the value of anything.<br/><br/>Ultimately, we will propose gratitude as an essential condition of human happiness and human flourishing.  In so doing, we will explore the relations between gratitude and contemplation, stewardship, and material creation; between gratitude and wonder, creativity, and invention; between gratitude and beauty, hope, and joy; and between gratitude, self-love, and the love of God.   The seminar will draw on ideas in from the history of philosophy, medieval philosophy, contemporary virtue theory, phenomenology, and personalism, as well as aesthetics and poetics.   Several keynote addresses will be given by <br/><br/>—John F. Crosby, Professor Emeritus at Franciscan University and author of The Selfhood of the Human Person and The Personalism of John Henry Newman<br/>—Jonathan J. Sanford, President at the University of Dallas, author of Before Virtue: Assessing Contemporary Virtue Ethics<br/>—Mark Spencer, professor at the University of St. Thomas (MN), author of The Irreducibility of the Human Person: A Catholic Synthesis <br/>—James Matthew Wilson, Professor in the MFA program at University of St. Thomas (Houston), author of The Vision of the Soul: Truth, Goodness, and Beauty in the Western Tradition<br/><br/>A full list of faculty can be found on the event website.  </p>
<p>For more information and to apply, please visit https://hildebrandproject.org/event/gratitude-2023-summer-seminar/</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 06:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675406228352679</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ June 26, 2023 -  June 30, 2023] Conference or similar: Gratitude</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/107570</link>
						<description>Venue: 1235 University Blvd<br/><br/><p>In this seminar we will explore gratitude as a fundamental moral disposition without which no one can really be happy. <br/>Our culture today is fraught by questions about gratitude. How do we receive in gratitude the goods of our own traditions despite their evils, of which we are increasingly aware? Can we cultivate gratitude in a social-media world of envy, isolation, and self-assertion? Why should we be grateful in the midst of great suffering?<br/><br/>In this seminar, we will attempt to answer these questions and to offer gratitude as an antidote to other challenges, such as feelings of loneliness, resentment, envy, and the self-hatred that oppresses so many today. We will show how gratitude guards against despair, and resists the nihilist attitude that fails to see the value of anything.<br/><br/>Ultimately, we will propose gratitude as an essential condition of human happiness and human flourishing.  In so doing, we will explore the relations between gratitude and contemplation, stewardship, and material creation; between gratitude and wonder, creativity, and invention; between gratitude and beauty, hope, and joy; and between gratitude, self-love, and the love of God.   The seminar will draw on ideas in from the history of philosophy, medieval philosophy, contemporary virtue theory, phenomenology, and personalism, as well as aesthetics and poetics.   Several keynote addresses will be given by <br/><br/>—John F. Crosby, Professor Emeritus at Franciscan University and author of The Selfhood of the Human Person and The Personalism of John Henry Newman<br/>—Jonathan J. Sanford, President at the University of Dallas, author of Before Virtue: Assessing Contemporary Virtue Ethics<br/>—Mark Spencer, professor at the University of St. Thomas (MN), author of The Irreducibility of the Human Person: A Catholic Synthesis <br/>—James Matthew Wilson, Professor in the MFA program at University of St. Thomas (Houston), author of The Vision of the Soul: Truth, Goodness, and Beauty in the Western Tradition<br/><br/>A full list of faculty can be found on the event website.  </p>
<p>For more information and to apply, please visit https://hildebrandproject.org/event/gratitude-2023-summer-seminar/</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 06:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675406228352678</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ April 22, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Shaikh al-Ishraq and the Modern World</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/107542</link>
						<description><p>The Institute of Suhrawardi’s Wisdom in collaboration with some academic centers organizes an international conference to reread the thoughts of Shaikh al-Ishraq. Rereading Suhrawardi's thoughts is of great importance for the new generation who live in a different world from Suhrawardi's time. There is no need to say that in this rereading, due to the critical nature of the modern world, there may be some criticisms of those ideas. This international conference, which will be held in person and online in March 2023, originates from the view that original premodern intellectual traditions can be the source of insight and inspiration for contemporary human being in solving his/her complicated problems.</p>
<p>Conference Chairman:   Gholamreza Aavani (Professor Emeritus, Iranian Research Institute of Philosophy, Iran)</p>
<p>Scientific Secretary: Mohsen Javadi (Professor, University of Qom, Iran)</p>
<p>Executive Secretary: Roohollah Fadaei (Ph. D Graduate, Tarbiat Modares University, Iran)</p>
<p>Venue: The Academy of Sciences of Iran</p>
<p>Conference issues:</p>
<p>Shaikh al-Ishraq &amp;</p>
<p>•             Aesthetics</p>
<p>•             Angelology</p>
<p>•             Anthropology</p>
<p>•             Comparative Studies</p>
<p>•             Contemporary Studies</p>
<p>•             Epistemology</p>
<p>•             Ethics</p>
<p>•             Logical Innovations</p>
<p>•             Meaning of Life</p>
<p>•             Metaphysics</p>
<p>•             Mystical Epistemology</p>
<p>•             Natural Philosophy</p>
<p>•             Political Philosophy</p>
<p>•             Symbolic, Allegorical, and Metaphorical Literature</p>
<p>•             Theology</p>
<p>We are honored to host some of well-known Suhrawardi scholars in the scientific board:</p>
<p>•             Adamson, Peter (Ludwig Maximilian University of Munich)</p>
<p>•             Amin Razavi, Mehdi (University of Mary Washington)</p>
<p>•             Hennig, Boris (Toronto Metropolian University)</p>
<p>•             /Kaukua, Jari (University of Jyväskylä)</p>
<p>•             Marcotte, Roxanne (University of Quebec)</p>
<p>•             Mousavian, Seyed N. (Loyola University Chicago)</p>
<p>•             Rizvi, Sajjad (University of Exeter)</p>
<p>•             Walbridge, John (Indiana University)</p>
<p>•             Uluc, Tahir (Necmettin Erbakan University)</p>
<p>Important Dates</p>
<ul>
<li>Abstract submission deadline: March 6, 2023</li>
<li>Notification of acceptance: March 11, 2023</li>
<li>Paper submission deadline: April 22, 2023</li>
<li>Announcement of the selected papers and presentations’ schedule: May 6, 2023</li>
<li>Conference date: May 13, 2023- May 14, 2023</li>
</ul>
<p>Only Ph. D holders and postgraduate students may submit abstracts and papers.</p>
<p>Conference website, submissions and registration: <a href="http://ishraqconference.ir/">http://ishraqconference.ir/</a></p>
<p>Abstract Features:</p>
<p>·        Abstracts should be no less than 250 words in length and no more than 300.</p>
<p>·         Abstracts should be followed by 3 to 5 keywords.</p>
<p>Paper Features:</p>
<p>·        Papers should be no less than 1500 words in length and no more than 2000.</p>
<p>·        Whole text should be typed in Times New Roman font (font size: 11 for body and 9 for endnotes and bibliography).</p>
<p>·        All titles and subtitles in the paper should be arranged numerically (English numbers not Roman).</p>
<p>·        All marginal but useful and important notes should be mentioned as endnotes not footnotes.</p>
<p>·        All references (in-text and reference list) should follow the 16th edition of Chicago citation style.</p>
<p>The conference will be held both virtually and in person.</p>
<p>The conference registration and participation are free of charge. Nevertheless, Participants are responsible for organizing and paying their own travel costs to the venue of the conference as well as for their accommodation. For any further information about the conference and traveling to Iran, contact us: <a href="file:///C:/Users/Admin/OneDrive/%D9%87%D9%85%DA%A9%D8%A7%D8%B1%DB%8C%20%D8%B9%D9%84%D9%85%DB%8C%20%D8%A8%D8%A7%20%D8%AF%DA%A9%D8%AA%D8%B1%20%D8%A7%DA%A9%D8%A8%D8%B1%DB%8C/%D9%87%D9%85%D8%A7%DB%8C%D8%B4%20%D8%B4%DB%8C%D8%AE%20%D8%A7%D8%B4%D8%B1%D8%A7%D9%82/%D9%81%D8%B1%D8%A7%D8%AE%D9%88%D8%A7%D9%86/ishraqconference@gmail.com">ishraqconference@gmail.com</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 06:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675406228352677</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ February 26, 2023] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/107574</link>
						<description>Publication Name: EXTENDED: Vice, Virtue, &amp; Conflict (Theophron Spring 2023)<br/><br/><p>Taken narrowly, vice and virtue comprise both central considerations of virtue ethical theories and peripheral considerations of any sophisticated normative ethics—that is, all plausible normative ethics will comment on vice and virtue in some manner. Taken broadly, the terms relate to goodness and badness, righteousness and evil, morality and depravity, inculcation and elimination. In each of these conjunctions, conflict stands at the forefront. Similar tensions manifest across theory and lived experience, from disagreement and wars to schisms and debates on the very existence of God. The interplay of vice, virtue, and conflict, then, occasions inquiry into the facets of life in a broken world and faith in the One who alone is perfect.</p>
<p>With this topic in mind, we invite undergraduate and graduate students, as well as early-career post-docs, to submit to Theophron’s spring 2023 issue. Scholarship from all fields, particularly philosophy, theology, history, and biblical studies, is welcome.</p>
<p>Possible topics include but are certainly not limited to:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>●  Epistemology of Religious or Moral Disagreement</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>●  Virtue’s Role in Christian Discipleship across Traditions</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>●  Prophetic &amp; Apostolic Responses to Political-Religious Tensions</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>●  Moral Arguments for God’s Existence</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>●  Interpretations of Old Testament Conflict Narratives</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>●  Just War Theory &amp; Pacifism in World War II</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>●  Early Church Understandings of Spiritual Conflict</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>●  Historical Christian Responses to Global Strife</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>●  Metaethics and Theories of Sin</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>●  Protestant, Catholic, &amp; Orthodox Views of Vice</p>
<p>Submission Instructions<br/>Submissions should be between 4,000–6,500 words (not including abstract), conform to the Chicago Manual of Style (17th edition), and be original, unpublished works prepared for double- blind peer review. Please include an abstract of no more than 250 words, uploading the entire manuscript in both PDF and .docx formats at www.theophron.org/submissions. Do not place your name or any identifying information on the submitted manuscript—author identities will remain anonymous to reviewers and editors until after final acceptance/rejection decisions.</p>
<p>Extended: Submissions received by February 26, 2023, will be considered for publication. Direct all questions to submissions@theophron.org.<br/>Visit theophron.org for all live calls for papers, including our year-round, open-topic call.</p>
</li>
</ul></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 06:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675406228352676</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>International Conferences on Pliny the Elder: Medicine, Magic, and Religion</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/01/31/international-conferences-on-pliny-the-elder-medicine-magic-and-religion</link>
						<dc:creator>rui@campus.ul.pt</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, February 2, 2023 - 3:23pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Centre for Classical Studies, University of Lisbon, Portugal</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:pliniusbimillenary@gmail.com">pliniusbimillenary@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/classical-studies">classical studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/international-conferences">international conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>March 31, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>International Conferences on<br/>
</p><p align="center"><strong>Pliny the Elder: Medicine, Magic, and Religion</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>In 2023 the world will celebrate the bimillenary of the birth of Pliny the Elder, who is a widely known author but not studied as much as he deserves. Despite the general interest shown in Pliny and his <em>Natural History</em>, there is still much to explore in his work. Examples of important titles of Plinian scholarship include the monograph of Beagon (1992) and her commentary on Book 7 of the <em>Natural History </em>(2005); Doody’s monograph on the reception of Pliny’s <em>Natural History </em>(2010); the edited volume of Gibson and Morello (2011); and the edited volume of Traina and Vial-Logeay (2022).</p>
<p> </p>
<p>In order to foster further investigation of Pliny and explore themes and issues that have not yet been fully investigated, the Centre for Classical Studies of the School of Arts and Humanities of the University of Lisbon, in collaboration with the Sapienza Università di Roma, is organising two international conferences on the theme ‘Pliny the Elder: Medicine, Magic, and Religion’ to be held during the autumn of 2023.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The main goal of these conferences is to study the books of Pliny’s <em>Naturalis Historia </em>that have particular significance in three areas that frequently intersect: medicine, magic, and religion. Researchers and scholars of Pliny and of these areas are invited to submit abstracts for papers to be delivered at these conferences. Speakers are encouraged to employ philological, historical, historico-religious, and anthropological approaches in their presentations, which may investigate any of the following (or other) topics:</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Pliny and medicine</p>
<ul>
<li>Pliny’s sources;</li>
<li>medical areas are covered;</li>
<li>the reception of Pliny in ancient, medieval and Renaissance medicine. </li>
</ul>
<p> Pliny and magic
</p><ul>
<li>views of Pliny on magic;</li>
<li>practices;</li>
<li>(possible) relation to medicine and/or religion. </li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p>Pliny and religion</p>
<ul>
<li><em>superstitio </em>and <em>prodigia</em>;</li>
<li>Pliny and ancient religion;</li>
<li>deities, rituals and religious practices.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p>Proposals for a 20-minute presentation should be sent to <a href="mailto:pliniusbimillenary@gmail.com">pliniusbimillenary@gmail.com</a> by 31 March 2023. Abstracts should have a maximum of 300 words and include a short biographical note with academic affiliation(s) and main publications (100 words).</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Provisional places and dates for these conferences are Lisbon (19-20 October 2023) and Rome (9-10 November 2023). The organisers plan to host the presentation of papers on medicine in Lisbon and papers on magic and religion in Rome. These places and dates will be confirmed so that participants can make appropriate travel plans well in advance of the conferences.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The working languages for these conferences will be English and Italian.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Organising Committee
</p><p>Gabriel Silva</p>
<p>Giorgio Ferri</p>
<p>Paolo Garofalo</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Scientific Committee
</p><p>Claudia Beltrão (U. Rio de Janeiro)</p>
<p>Fabrizio Bigotti (U. Würzburg, CSMBR [Centre for the Study of Medicine and the Body in the Renaissance])</p>
<p>Valérie Bonet (U. Aix-Marseille)</p>
<p>Jean-Christophe Courtil (U. Toulouse)</p>
<p>Gabriel Silva (U. Lisboa)</p>
<p>Jane Draycott (U. Glasgow)</p>
<p>Giorgio Ferri (Sapienza U. Roma)</p>
<p>Rodrigo Furtado (U. Lisboa)</p>
<p>Gian Luca Gregori (Sapienza U. Roma)</p>
<p>Paolo Garofalo (U. Lisboa)</p>
<p>Patricia Gaillard-Seux (U. Angers)</p>
<p>Ana Lóio (U. Lisboa)</p>
<p>Bernardo Mota (U. Lisboa)</p>
<p>Valérie Naas (U. Sorbonne)</p>
<p>Vivian Nutton (U. College London)</p>
<p>Maria Cristina Pimentel (U. Lisboa)</p>
<p>Celia Sánchez Natalías (U. Zaragoza)</p>
<p>Federico Santangelo (U. Newcastle)</p>
<p>Giusto Traina (U. Sorbonne)</p>
<p>Anne Vial-Logeay (U. Rouen)</p>
<p>Andrew Wallace-Hadrill (U. Cambridge)</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Bibliography
</p><p>Beagon, M. (1992), <em>Roman Nature. </em><em>The Thought of Pliny the Elder</em>. Oxford.</p>
<p>Beagon, M. (2005), <em>The Elder Pliny on the Human Animal: Natural History, Book 7</em>. Oxford.</p>
<p>Doody, A. (2010), <em>Pliny’s Encyclopedia: The Reception of the </em>Natural History. Cambridge.</p>
<p>Gibson, R., Morello, R. (eds., 2011), <em>Pliny the Elder: Themes and Contexts</em>. Leiden/Boston.</p>
<p>Traina, G., Vial-Logeay, A. (eds., 2022), <em>L’inventaire du monde de Pline l’Ancien. Des colonnes d’Hercule aux confins de l’Afrique et de l’Asie</em>. Bordeaux.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p>This activity is funded by Portuguese national funds through FCT – Fundação para a Ciência e a Tecnologia, I.P., in the framework of the unit/project UIDB/00019/2020</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 09:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675406228352675</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Reconceptualizing Religion in Early African American Literature</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/01/27/reconceptualizing-religion-in-early-african-american-literature</link>
						<dc:creator>pyonk</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, February 2, 2023 - 3:02pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>2024 MLA Convention</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:donaldho@andrew.cmu.edu">donaldho@andrew.cmu.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/african-american">african-american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>March 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>How do 18th and 19th century Black writers reconceptualize religion beyond the nation-state? How do they utilize religious concepts such as celebration, prophecy, apocalpyse, etc. to critique and think outside the boundaries of the nation-state?</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Please send abstract and brief bio to: <a href="mailto:donaldho@andrew.cmu.edu">donaldho@andrew.cmu.edu</a> or <a href="mailto:kbp5545@psu.edu">kbp5545@psu.edu</a> </p>
<p>Deadline: March 15th</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 14:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675406228352674</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>IAEP 2023 CFP</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/01/26/iaep-2023-cfp</link>
						<dc:creator>iaepsecretary@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, February 2, 2023 - 3:01pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>International Association for Environmental Philosophy</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:iaepsecretary@gmail.com">iaepsecretary@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/graduate-conferences">graduate conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/international-conferences">international conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/science-and-culture">science and culture</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>March 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>CALL FOR PROPOSALS<br/>INTERNATIONAL ASSOCIATION FOR ENVIRONMENTAL PHILOSOPHY</p>
<p>Twenty-Seventh Annual Meeting 14–16 October 2023 Toronto, ON, Canada</p>
<p>The IAEP Executive Committee is excited to announce our annual meeting, immediately following SPEP, in Canada’s largest city Toronto.</p>
<p>Keynote Speaker Stephanie LeMenager</p>
<p>University of Oregon</p>
<p>IAEP invites proposals for individual papers as well as organized panels on any aspect of environmental philosophy. Papers in areas touching on LeMenager’s work–the anthropocene, resource exploration, feminist and interdisciplinary approaches to environmental philosophy, etc.—would certainly be welcome.</p>
<p>Papers should be limited to 20 minutes reading time, but presenters will have an additional 20 minutes for discussion following their paper.</p>
<p>We plan on offering a remote option for those unable to attend in person, but don’t know yet what the connectivity will be like at the conference venue. Please let us know if you are only able to attend remotely and we will do our best to accommodate.</p>
<p>Individual Paper proposals: Please send a single-spaced Word document (prepared for blind review) including a proposal (500–600 words) PLUS a short abstract (75–100 words, for the conference program). In the body of the email, please include detailed contact information (including physical and electronic addresses) and academic affiliation(s) of the author(s).</p>
<p>Panel proposals (max. 3 papers): Please send one single-spaced Word document (prepared for blind review) including a title for the panel followed by titles, proposals and both paper proposals (500–600 words) and short abstracts (75–100 words) for each paper as described above. The body of the email should include contact information and affiliations for each author. Paper proposals will also be judged individually and may be accepted individually without acceptance of the entire panel.</p>
<p>ALL SUBMISSIONS and ENQUIRIES should be sent to <a href="mailto:iaepsecretary@gmail.com">iaepsecretary@gmail.com</a>.</p>
<p>Authors may submit only one proposal for consideration. Papers previously published or under review for publication will not be accepted. Accepted authors must be members of IAEP and registered for the conference by 1 September 2023 or they will be removed from the program.</p>
<p>$250 PRIZE FOR BEST STUDENT ESSAY: Students, please indicate in your email if you wish to be considered for this prize. The winner will be announced during the conference.</p>
<p>DEADLINE for submissions: 15 March 2023.</p>
<p>NOTICE OF DECISION: Early May 2022.<br/>Information about IAEP and membership is available at <a href="http://www.environmentalphilosophy.org/">www.environmentalphilosophy.org</a>.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 04:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675406228352673</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Dialogo_FSV 2023 : International Virtual Conference on Freedom, Human Rights, Global Crises, Solidarity &amp; Values</title>
			<link>http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=171583&amp;copyownerid=62583</link>
						<description>International Virtual Conference on Freedom, Human Rights, Global Crises, Solidarity &amp; Values  [http://www.dialogo-conf.com/] [May 20, 2023 - May 28, 2023]</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 06:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675319827857378</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>&quot;Buddhist-inflected Sovereignties Across the Indian Ocean: A Pali Arena, 1200–1550,&quot; a talk by Anne M. Blackburn</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12280486/buddhist-inflected-sovereignties-across-indian-ocean-pali</link>
						<dc:creator>Liyu Hua</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-03T00:00:00-05:00">February 3, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>New York</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Asian History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, South Asian History / Studies, Southeast Asian History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Friday, February 3, 2023 at 12:00pm to 1:00pm</p><p>Virtual Event<br/>Please join Cornell's Society for Buddhist Studies for a virtual talk by Prof. Anne M. Blackburn, the Old Dominion Foundation Professor in the Humanities here at Cornell.</p><p>In her research, Prof. Blackburn works at the intersection of Buddhist institutional history, political economy, intellectual history, and literature. She focuses on intellectual-political centers in what is now Sri Lanka (formerly Lanka) during the 2nd millennium A.D., locations in what are now Burma, Thailand, and India, and the circulatory processes that shaped these connections. Prof. Blackburn’s latest book, Buddhist-inflected Sovereignties Across the Indian Ocean: A Pali Arena, 1200-1550 (supported by an ACLS fellowship), will be published by the University of Hawai’i Press in Fall 2023.</p><p>The talk is sponsored by the GPSA-FC and the Department of Asian Studies, and is open to all interested.</p><p>Dial-In Information</p><p><a href="https://bit.ly/3SFKusi" rel="nofollow">https://bit.ly/3SFKusi</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Erin Kotmel</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:buddhiststudies@cornell.edu">buddhiststudies@cornell.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://events.cornell.edu/event/buddhist-inflected_sovereignties_across_the_indian_ocean_a_pali_arena_12001550_a_talk_by_anne_m_blackburn" target="_blank">https://events.cornell.edu/event/buddhist-inflected_sovereignties_across_the_indian_ocean_a_pali_arena_12001550_a_talk_b…</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 18:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675319827857377</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Applications: &quot;Revisiting Religion &amp; Place in Light of Environmental, Legal, and Indigenous Studies&quot; a residential institute for higher ed faculty—Deadline:3/3/2023</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12278476/call-applications-revisiting-religion-place-light</link>
						<dc:creator>Rebecca Bultman</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Summer Program</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-05T00:00:00-04:00">June 5, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-23T00:00:00-04:00">June 23, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Virginia</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology, Environmental History / Studies, Law and Legal History, Indigenous Studies, Teaching and Learning</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><b><span>Rethinking Religion and Place in Light of Environmental, Legal, and Indigenous Studies</span></b></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><b><span>A Three-week Residential Institute for Higher Education Faculty</span></b></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Application Deadline: March 3, 2023, 11:59PM EST</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><b><u><span>Details</span></u></b></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span>Stipend: $2,850, plus books purchased for participants</span></span></li><li><span><span>Date: June 5-23, 2023</span></span></li><li><span><span>Location: University of Virginia, Charlottesville, VA</span></span></li><li><span><span>Completed applications must be submitted through the <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSd3eDljeKwqAGT_8mb9xgvJ8ESUU5ccvOxAYYDdTVGvPNIRRw/viewform?usp=sf_link" rel="nofollow">online portal</a> no later than 11:59pm Eastern Standard Time on March 3, 2023</span></span></li><li><span><span>Notifications will be sent via email by April 3, 2023</span></span></li><li><span><span>Contact program manager Rebecca Bultman at <a href="mailto:rdd6aw@virginia.edu">rdd6aw@virginia.edu</a> with program inquires</span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The National Endowment for the Humanities: Democracy Demands Wisdom and the <a href="https://religionlab.virginia.edu/" rel="nofollow">Religion, Race &amp; Democracy Lab</a> (RRD) at the University of Virginia are pleased to announce <b>“Revisiting Religion and Place in Light of Environmental, Legal, and Indigenous Studies,”</b> a three-week residential institute for higher education faculty to be held in <b>Charlottesville, VA</b> from <b>June 5-23, 2023</b>.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The Institute seeks to bring together 26 faculty and advanced graduate students in religious studies and related fields from across the United States for an immersive exploration of critical new perspectives on the theme of “place.” Given recent, dramatic advances on the study of place in the environmental humanities, social sciences, legal studies, and indigenous studies, the time is ripe for rethinking place as a fundamental feature of the study of religion.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The RRD, affiliate of the College and Graduate School of Arts &amp; Sciences’<a href="https://democracyinitiative.virginia.edu/" rel="nofollow"> Democracy Initiative</a>, will lead the project, with Professors <a href="https://religiousstudies.as.virginia.edu/martien-halvorson-taylor" rel="nofollow">Martien Halvorson-Taylor</a> and <a href="https://religiousstudies.as.virginia.edu/kurtis-r-schaeffer" rel="nofollow">Kurtis Schaeffer</a>, Co-Directors of the Religion, Race &amp; Democracy Lab.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The goals of the summer institute are:</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ol><li><span><span><span>To introduce scholars in religious studies and related fields to the enormously productive re-thinking of the idea of “place” that has occurred across disciplines in recent years.</span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span>To help scholars of religion to make better use of both substantivist and constructivist theories of place and space in religion.</span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span>To assist scholars in developing a richer and more nuanced understanding of the opportunities and pitfalls that come with using the category of “place” in thinking and teaching about diverse manifestations of human engagement with the world.</span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span>To strengthen participants’ teaching and research through critical pedagogical reflection and workshops</span></span></span></li></ol><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>One of the primary activities of the Institute will be close reading and discussion of important contemporary scholarship on the study of place, exploring the concept’s multifaceted physical, social, civic, spiritual, and legal dimensions. These discussions will be complemented both by conversations with noted experts and by pedagogy workshops driven largely by our participants’ research and teaching aims. The other primary activity of the institute, taking seriously the topic of religion and place, will be field-based engagements at local sites representing rich and relevant themes explored throughout the Institute.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Participants will receive a stipend of $2,850 at the conclusion of the program.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>More information about the program, including information on guest speakers, fieldwork site, travel &amp; lodging, can be <a href="https://religionlab.virginia.edu/revisiting-religion-and-place/" rel="nofollow">here</a>.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><b><u><span>Application Requirements</span></u></b></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The deadline for applications is <b>March 3, 2023</b>.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The application requires <b>a short CV </b>(.PDF or .DOCX format; 2 pages max.) and responses to the following prompts:</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ol><li><span><span><span>Please address your interest in the program (400 words max.)</span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span>Please address any intersections between your teaching and research and the themes of the program (400 words max.)</span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span>Please reflect on any past academic experiences that you can leverage for the success of the program (300 words max.)</span></span></span></li></ol><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Applicants will be notified by <b>April 3, 2023</b>. Selected applicants will have until <b>April 14, 2023</b> to accept or decline the offer.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Once an applicant has accepted an offer to attend any NEH Summer Program (Seminar, Institute, or Landmark), they may not accept an additional offer or withdraw in order to accept a different offer.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Project applicants who accept an offer to participate are expected to remain during the entire period of the program and to participate in its work on a full-time basis. If a participant is obliged through special circumstances to depart before the end of the program, it shall be the recipient institution’s responsibility to see that only a pro rata share of the stipend is received or that the appropriate pro rata share of the stipend is returned if the participant has already received the full stipend.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>More information about participant eligibility can be found <a href="https://www.neh.gov/sites/default/files/inline-files/Eligibility%20Criteria%20for%20Summer%20Seminars%20and%20Institutes%20for%20Higher%20Education%20Faculty.pdf" rel="nofollow">here</a>.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The Institute will adhere to the <a href="https://www.neh.gov/grants/principles-civility#:~:text=conducted%20without%20partisan%20advocacy%3B,%2C%20disability%2C%20or%20racial%20bias." rel="nofollow">NEH Principles of Civility</a>.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><i>Endowment programs do not discriminate on the basis of race, color, national origin, religion, sexual orientation, disability, or age. For further information, write to the Equal Opportunity Officer, National Endowment for the Humanities, 400 7th Street, SW, Washington, DC 20024. TDD: 202-606-8282 (this is a special telephone device for the Deaf).</i></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><b><span><a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSd3eDljeKwqAGT_8mb9xgvJ8ESUU5ccvOxAYYDdTVGvPNIRRw/viewform?usp=sf_link" rel="nofollow">Apply Here</a></span></b></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Rebecca Bultman, University of Virginia</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:rdd6aw@virginia.edu">rdd6aw@virginia.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://religionlab.virginia.edu/revisiting-religion-and-place/" target="_blank">https://religionlab.virginia.edu/revisiting-religion-and-place/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 18:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675319827857376</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – February 1, 2023</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-february-1-2023/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find 5 jobs, 4 fellowships, 1 grant, 18 Call for Papers, and an online talk about religion public scholarship.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 32!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Columbia University Sheng Yen Postdoctoral Fellowship in Chinese Buddhism</h4>



<p>Columbia University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: March 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php?id=64972">H-Net Job Guide</a></p>



<h4>Postdoctoral Research Associate Buddhist Philosophy (1-year appointment, possibility of renewal)</h4>



<p>Princeton University, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://puwebp.princeton.edu/AcadHire/apply/application.xhtml?listingId=28321">https://puwebp.princeton.edu/AcadHire/apply/application.xhtml?listingId=28321</a></p>



<h4>Full-Time Lectures in Culture and Society, School of Humanities and Communication Arts</h4>



<p>Western Sydney University, Australia</p>



<p>Deadline: February 19, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://uws.nga.net.au/cp/index.cfm?event=jobs.jati&amp;returnToEvent=jobs.home&amp;jobID=D1B64ABB-C2B5-6525-5966-D14AC774F910&amp;audienceTypeCode=EXTiFRAME&amp;UseAudienceTypeLanguage=1">https://uws.nga.net.au/cp/index.cfm?event=jobs.jati&amp;returnToEvent=jobs.home&amp;jobID=D1B64ABB-C2B5-6525-5966-D14AC774F910&amp;audienceTypeCode=EXTiFRAME&amp;UseAudienceTypeLanguage=1</a></p>



<h4>Part-Time Lectures in Culture and Society, School of Humanities and Communication Arts</h4>



<p>Western Sydney University, Australia</p>



<p>Deadline: February 19, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://uws.nga.net.au/cp/index.cfm?event=jobs.jati&amp;returnToEvent=jobs.home&amp;jobID=D1B64ABB-C2B5-6525-5966-D14AC774F910&amp;audienceTypeCode=EXTiFRAME&amp;UseAudienceTypeLanguage=1">https://uws.nga.net.au/cp/index.cfm?event=jobs.jati&amp;returnToEvent=jobs.home&amp;jobID=D1B64ABB-C2B5-6525-5966-D14AC774F910&amp;audienceTypeCode=EXTiFRAME&amp;UseAudienceTypeLanguage=1</a></p>



<h4>Ethics Institute Operations and Program Manager (Full Time)</h4>



<p>Northeastern University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: NA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://northeastern.wd1.myworkdayjobs.com/careers/job/Boston-MA-Main-Campus/Operations-and-Program-Manager_R111187">https://northeastern.wd1.myworkdayjobs.com/careers/job/Boston-MA-Main-Campus/Operations-and-Program-Manager_R111187</a></p>



<h4>AAR/SBL Job Forum</h4>



<p><a href="https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search">https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search</a></p>



<h2>Fellowships:</h2>



<h4>Sydney Jewish Museum Research Fellowship</h4>



<p>Sydney, Australia</p>



<p>Deadline: March 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://sydneyjewishmuseum.com.au/research-fellowships/">https://sydneyjewishmuseum.com.au/research-fellowships/</a></p>



<h4>Massachusetts Historical Society Research Fellowships (3 available)</h4>



<p>Deadline: Varies depending on which you apply to</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12226946/research-fellowships-massachusetts-historical-society-2023">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12226946/research-fellowships-massachusetts-historical-society-2023</a></p>



<h4>Gerda Henkel Fellowships (5-month appointments)</h4>



<p>Centre for Advanced Study Sofia, Bulgaria</p>



<p>Deadline: March 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12250002/20232024-call-applications-gerda-henkel-fellowships">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12250002/20232024-call-applications-gerda-henkel-fellowships</a></p>



<h4>Louisville Institute Doctoral Fellowship</h4>



<p>Louisville, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: March 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: https://t.co/j5Cg9kcHWC</p>



<h2>Grants:</h2>



<h4>ASMEA Research Grants</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://mailchi.mp/asmeascholars/16annual-conference-1387189">https://mailchi.mp/asmeascholars/16annual-conference-1387189</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>Arendt Studies, Volume 7</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/107029">https://philevents.org/event/show/107029</a></p>



<h4>In the Name of God: A Voice for War, a Call for Peace</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 7, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12226582/call-papers-name-god-voice-war-call-peace">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12226582/call-papers-name-god-voice-war-call-peace</a></p>



<h4>Women in Buddhism: Religion, Politics, and the Arts</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 3, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12227919/women-buddhism-religion-politics-and-arts">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12227919/women-buddhism-religion-politics-and-arts</a></p>



<h4>Us and Them: Phenomenological Perspective in Dialogue</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/107049">https://philevents.org/event/show/107049</a></p>



<h4>Theology, Religion, and Dungeons &amp; Dragons</h4>



<p>Deadline: February 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=171332&amp;copyownerid=179289">http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=171332&amp;copyownerid=179289</a></p>



<h4>Religion and Spirituality in Everyday Life</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=171418&amp;copyownerid=173363">http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=171418&amp;copyownerid=173363</a></p>



<h4>Women in Religion: From Spiritual Leadership to Female Empowerment</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=171400&amp;copyownerid=108478">http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=171400&amp;copyownerid=108478</a></p>



<h4>“Gender, Sexuality, and State Violence: International Perspectives on Institutional and Intersectional Justice”</h4>



<p>Deadline: September 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/journal/societies/special_issues/SFMS2NTQYX">https://www.mdpi.com/journal/societies/special_issues/SFMS2NTQYX</a></p>



<h4>“Doctor Virtualis” no. 19 ‘Fragments of Order and Disorder in the Middle Ages</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/107141">https://philevents.org/event/show/107141</a></p>



<h4>NAASR 2023 Annual Meeting: Exploring the Transdisciplinary “Ecology” of Scholarship in the Study of Religion</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 23, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://naasr.com/">https://naasr.com/</a></p>



<h4>Journal of Religious Minorites Under Muslim Rule</h4>



<p>Deadline: Rolling acceptance</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12256336/cfp-journal-religious-minorities-under-muslim-rule">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12256336/cfp-journal-religious-minorities-under-muslim-rule</a></p>



<h4>Global Christianities and Global Literatures</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/01/23/global-christianities-and-global-literatures">https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/01/23/global-christianities-and-global-literatures</a></p>



<h4>AAR 2023 Annual Meeting</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/1h4mfhdilj">https://t.co/1h4mfhdilj</a></p>



<h4>Jesus Christ Superstar Call for Papers: AAR 2023</h4>



<p>Deadline: February 24, 2023</p>



<p>More Information:  <a href="https://t.co/Ash1hQOFmH">https://t.co/Ash1hQOFmH</a></p>



<h4>The Reception of Egypt and the Ancients in Theosophy and Related Esoteric Currents</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://theosophicalhistoryconference.eu/?page_id=3344">https://theosophicalhistoryconference.eu/?page_id=3344</a></p>



<h4>17<sup>th</sup> Annual Society for Ricoeur Studies Conference</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/107257">https://philevents.org/event/show/107257</a></p>



<h4>Beyond Accommodations: “Crippling” Possibilities in Higher Education</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://twitter.com/alansmartino/status/1619000613492367361?s=12&amp;t=922yHltya3rIImlYXK41bA">https://twitter.com/alansmartino/status/1619000613492367361?s=12&amp;t=922yHltya3rIImlYXK41bA</a></p>



<h4>American Catholic Historical Association Annual Meeting</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information:  <a href="https://t.co/U0QpwFJrHy">https://t.co/U0QpwFJrHy</a></p>



<h2>Miscellaneous:</h2>



<h4>The Scholar of Religion in the Public Sphere</h4>



<p>Online: <a href="https://t.co/hjiFlQfK4N">https://t.co/hjiFlQfK4N</a></p>



<p>Date: Feb 9<sup>th</sup>-10<sup>th,</sup> 2023</p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1675319827857375</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
