<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 12:19:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 12:19:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ March 30, 2023] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/109329</link>
						<description>Publication Name: New Moderate Narratives in Times of Extremism - Call for abstracts<br/><br/><p><strong>13th BRAGA MEETINGS ON ETHICS AND POLITICAL PHILOSOPHY</strong>  </p>
<p>June 15 and 16, 2023 | Braga, Portugal   <strong></strong></p>
<p><strong>Website</strong>: <a target="_blank" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://13bragameetings.weebly.com/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1679262520074000&amp;usg=AOvVaw3p2xWKyZYwF9bLXEDBDB2H">https://13bragameetings.weebly.com/</a>     <strong></strong></p>
<p><strong>Invited speakers</strong>:   </p>
<p><strong>DANIELE ARCHIBUGI  </strong><em>/// CNRS and Birkbeck College</em><strong><br/>HELEN FROWE  </strong><em>/// Stockholm University</em><br/><strong>MATHIAS THALER</strong> <em>///</em> <em>University of Edinburgh<br/></em><strong>MIHAELA MIHAI </strong><em>/// University of Edinburgh</em><br/><strong>NADIA URBINATI </strong> <em>/// </em> <em>Columbia University</em><br/><strong>RICHARD BELLAMY </strong> <em>/// </em> <em>University College London</em><br/><strong>SILJE LANGVATN</strong> <em>///</em> <em>University of Bergen</em><br/><strong>STUART WHITE</strong> <em>/// </em> <em>University of Oxford</em>  </p>
<p>Call for abstracts to constitute a panel on "New Moderate Narratives in Times of Extremism" at the <a target="_blank" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://13bragameetings.weebly.com/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1679262520075000&amp;usg=AOvVaw2x7tAluDhF9L9475G7pbk9">Braga Meetings on Ethics and Political Philosophy</a></p>
<p>Convenor: Pedro Góis Moreira (<a target="_blank" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://tcu.academia.edu/PedroMoreira&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1679262520075000&amp;usg=AOvVaw2Y_ghwAm-t9afa-vAZMqIt">https://tcu.academia.edu/PedroMoreira</a>) <a target="_blank">pedrogoismoreira@gmail.com</a>  </p>
<p>The 90s opened a time of optimism for proponents of constitutional democracy who were vividly discussing the possibilities of public deliberation and rational dialogue. However, these last few years have seen the re-emergence of radical and antagonistic forms of politics - populism, nativism, and left activism. We currently find ourselves in "an <em>interregnum</em>: a period of crisis during which several tenets of the [political] consensus (...) are challenged" and where "a solution to the crisis is not yet in sight" (Mouffe, 2018).  </p>
<p>This "crisis of liberalism" sets the tone of the discussions on the left and on the right. On the left, debates have centered around radical democracy, left populism, and on the means to further radicalize democracy (Mouffe 2018, de la Torre and Srisa-nga 2021). Radical democrats claim that they seek to reform liberalism rather than reject it, yet they are often more explicit about what they reject in liberalism than about what they wish to retain. On the right, many have been more candid, calling themselves "postliberals" (Deneen 2018) and embracing populist (Benoist 2017) or nationalist (Hazony 2022) alternatives.  </p>
<p>Liberal and moderate responses to these developments have been markedly defensive. On the one hand, several works have taken a critical approach to populism (Müller 2016, Urbinati 2019) and identity politics (Fukuyama 2018). On the other hand, there have been talks of how a militant democracy (Malkopoulou and Kirshner 2019) could be deployed to contain the extremes. But here, too, the discussion is more about the defensive response that liberals should adopt against the extremes.  </p>
<p>The questions that seem to be missing are the sort of new narratives and new self-understanding that moderates should develop in response to the extremes. In the 1930s, several liberal landmarks emerged, not just as critiques, but as insightful and original reaffirmations of the open society (Lippmann 1937, Popper 1944). What, then, is extremism and what unites it? What is moderation (Craiutu 2023)? What conceptions of democracy and politics should moderates develop in response to the extremes (Muller 2021)? The panel welcomes contributions related (but not limited) to the following questions:</p>
<ul>
<li>What is extremism? What is moderation? How should we understand and frame this binary historically and philosophically?</li>
<li>What new conceptions of democracy and politics should moderates develop in response to the extremes?</li>
<li>What are the potential benefits and shortcomings of extremism/moderation? For instance, can extremism act as a "corrective"? Does moderation have depoliticizing tendencies?</li>
<li>What are some of the rhetorical tactics of extremism (e.g., demonization) and how can moderates counter them? Should moderates adopt militant democracy?</li>
</ul>
<p>  <strong>Submission Guidelines:</strong> </p>
<p>To apply, please send an email to <a target="_blank">Pedrogoismoreira@gmail.com</a> with the following items by <strong>Thursday, 30 March</strong>: name, affiliation, email, short bio (max 300 words), abstract title, abstracts (max 500 words), and five keywords.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 05:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679204240483989</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ September 7, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Post-Pandemic Condition: Biopolitics in the Aftermath of the COVID-19</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/109293</link>
						<description><p><strong>C</strong><strong>all for </strong><strong>P</strong><strong>apers</strong><strong>: International Conference </strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Post-Pandemic Condition: </strong><strong>Biopolitics in the </strong><strong>Aftermath of the </strong><strong>COVID-19</strong><strong></strong></p>
<p>Conference Date: 7 September, 2023</p>
<p>National Gallery of Art, Konstitucijos pr. 22, Vilnius</p>
<p>The conference ‘Post-Pandemic Condition: Biopolitics in the Aftermath of the COVID-19’ revisits the concept of biopolitics by asking how the pandemic has redefined the political field and what new concepts and prospects it can offer for conceptualising our post-pandemic condition. </p>
<p>The worldwide health crisis caused by the COVID-19 pandemic has undoubtedly signalled the need to reconsider, modify, and even transform the notion of biopolitics. Numerous attempts to do so were ranging from nearly apocalyptic visions of entirely ‘negative’ biopolitics, such as Giorgio Agamben’s collection of brief essays <em>Where Are We Now?</em> (2021), to surveillance-friendly ‘positive’ biopolitics, exemplified by Benjamin Bratton’s <em>The Revenge of the Real</em> (2021). Most of these, however, were published at the very peak of the pandemic, and therefore mostly based on different approaches of national governments towards the management of the pandemic and their implementation, and not the consequences of the pandemic biopolitics itself. </p>
<p>Roughly three years after the breakout of the pandemic, it is time to revisit the notion of biopolitics itself and to question its viability in the aftermath of COVID-19. Many theoreticians emphasize that the pandemic cannot be separated from the existing social and political conditions which include nationalism, racism, global inequality, poverty, violence against women and LGBTQ+ people, and environmental destruction. In enduring pandemic times these conditions were radicalised and made even more unbearable. At the same time theoreticians express a need to overcome these radical inequalities and reimagine a ‘shared or common world’ (Judith Butler), ‘the world in common’ (Achille Mbembe) that would ensure a universal right to live.</p>
<p>The universal right to live belongs to the universal community of earthly inhabitants, human and nonhuman. This implies that the conventional model of individual rights and freedoms should be revisited in favour of communal forms of existence. As Judith Butler points out, the term ‘pandemic’ derives etymologically from <em>pan-demos</em>, all the people, or people everywhere, or something that crosses over or spread over and through the people (<em>What World Is This?,</em> p. 5). Thus the post-pandemic condition implies that thinking about the insular and autonomous individual should be abandoned since every individual discovers itself in the position of interconnectedness and encroachment. The post-pandemic condition forces us to rethink ourselves in terms of common immunity (Roberto Esposito), the transindividual (Etienne Balibar), or holobiont (Bruno Latour), and to acknowledge our debt to global ecology.     </p>
<p>Key areas of inquiry could include but are by no means limited to: </p>
<p>• pandemic and paradigmatic shifts within and beyond the notion of biopolitics; </p>
<p>• political, economic, racial, and social implications of pandemic biopolitics; </p>
<p>• new philosophical, political and social imaginaries; </p>
<p>• the individual “self” and other forms of communal existence; </p>
<p>• immunity and immunization VS community-oriented approaches after the pandemic; </p>
<p>• individual rights and freedoms VS universal right to live; </p>
<p>• post-pandemic governmentality VS environmentality;</p>
<p>• ecological crisis, biopolitics, and the Anthropocene;</p>
<p>• affective and artistic expressions of the post-pandemic condition.</p>
<p>Conference format: in person </p>
<p><strong>Submission guidelines: </strong></p>
<p>Deadline for abstract submission: 1 June 2023</p>
<p>Notification of acceptance: 10 June 2023</p>
<p>Conference dates: 7 September 2023</p>
<p>An abstract (300 words) with a short biography should be sent to the organizers: denis.petrina@LKTI.LT</p>
<p>The conference is organized by the Lithuanian Culture Research Institute</p>
<p>and the Research Council of Lithuania. </p>
<p>The conference will take place in the National Gallery of Art, Konstitucijos pr. 22, Vilnius.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 05:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679117829065216</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ September 7, 2023] Conference or similar: Post-Pandemic Condition: Biopolitics in the Aftermath of the COVID-19</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/109289</link>
						<description>Venue: Konstitucijos pr. 22<br/><br/><p><strong>C</strong><strong>all for </strong><strong>P</strong><strong>apers</strong><strong>: International Conference </strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Post-Pandemic Condition: </strong><strong>Biopolitics in the </strong><strong>Aftermath of the </strong><strong>COVID-19</strong><strong></strong></p>
<p>Conference Date: 7 September, 2023</p>
<p>National Gallery of Art, Konstitucijos pr. 22, Vilnius</p>
<p>The conference ‘Post-Pandemic Condition: Biopolitics in the Aftermath of the COVID-19’ revisits the concept of biopolitics by asking how the pandemic has redefined the political field and what new concepts and prospects it can offer for conceptualising our post-pandemic condition. </p>
<p>The worldwide health crisis caused by the COVID-19 pandemic has undoubtedly signalled the need to reconsider, modify, and even transform the notion of biopolitics. Numerous attempts to do so were ranging from nearly apocalyptic visions of entirely ‘negative’ biopolitics, such as Giorgio Agamben’s collection of brief essays <em>Where Are We Now?</em> (2021), to surveillance-friendly ‘positive’ biopolitics, exemplified by Benjamin Bratton’s <em>The Revenge of the Real</em> (2021). Most of these, however, were published at the very peak of the pandemic, and therefore mostly based on different approaches of national governments towards the management of the pandemic and their implementation, and not the consequences of the pandemic biopolitics itself. </p>
<p>Roughly three years after the breakout of the pandemic, it is time to revisit the notion of biopolitics itself and to question its viability in the aftermath of COVID-19. Many theoreticians emphasize that the pandemic cannot be separated from the existing social and political conditions which include nationalism, racism, global inequality, poverty, violence against women and LGBTQ+ people, and environmental destruction. In enduring pandemic times these conditions were radicalised and made even more unbearable. At the same time theoreticians express a need to overcome these radical inequalities and reimagine a ‘shared or common world’ (Judith Butler), ‘the world in common’ (Achille Mbembe) that would ensure a universal right to live.</p>
<p>The universal right to live belongs to the universal community of earthly inhabitants, human and nonhuman. This implies that the conventional model of individual rights and freedoms should be revisited in favour of communal forms of existence. As Judith Butler points out, the term ‘pandemic’ derives etymologically from <em>pan-demos</em>, all the people, or people everywhere, or something that crosses over or spread over and through the people (<em>What World Is This?,</em> p. 5). Thus the post-pandemic condition implies that thinking about the insular and autonomous individual should be abandoned since every individual discovers itself in the position of interconnectedness and encroachment. The post-pandemic condition forces us to rethink ourselves in terms of common immunity (Roberto Esposito), the transindividual (Etienne Balibar), or holobiont (Bruno Latour), and to acknowledge our debt to global ecology.     </p>
<p>Key areas of inquiry could include but are by no means limited to: </p>
<p>• pandemic and paradigmatic shifts within and beyond the notion of biopolitics; </p>
<p>• political, economic, racial, and social implications of pandemic biopolitics; </p>
<p>• new philosophical, political and social imaginaries; </p>
<p>• the individual “self” and other forms of communal existence; </p>
<p>• immunity and immunization VS community-oriented approaches after the pandemic; </p>
<p>• individual rights and freedoms VS universal right to live; </p>
<p>• post-pandemic governmentality VS environmentality;</p>
<p>• ecological crisis, biopolitics, and the Anthropocene;</p>
<p>• affective and artistic expressions of the post-pandemic condition.</p>
<p>Conference format: in person </p>
<p><strong>Submission guidelines: </strong></p>
<p>Deadline for abstract submission: 1 June 2023</p>
<p>Notification of acceptance: 10 June 2023</p>
<p>Conference dates: 7 September 2023</p>
<p>An abstract (300 words) with a short biography should be sent to the organizers: denis.petrina@LKTI.LT</p>
<p>The conference is organized by the Lithuanian Culture Research Institute</p>
<p>and the Research Council of Lithuania. </p>
<p>The conference will take place in the National Gallery of Art, Konstitucijos pr. 22, Vilnius.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 05:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679117829065215</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Yin-Cheng Lecture Series: Prof. Meir Shahar on the Chinese Beef Taboo</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12576186/yin-cheng-lecture-series-prof-meir-shahar-chinese-beef-taboo</link>
						<dc:creator>Yizhuo Li</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-04-11T00:00:00-04:00">April 11, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Asian History / Studies, Chinese History / Studies, Cultural History / Studies, East Asian History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><b>Yin-Cheng Distinguished Lecture Series on Buddhism at the University Cambridge </b></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span>On April 11, Prof. Meir Shahar (Tel Aviv University) will share with us insights from his ongoing research with a lecture on the Indian origins of the Chinese beef taboo. This lecture is part of the Yin-Cheng Distinguished Lecture Series on Buddhism, which is generously supported by the Tzu Chi Foundation and organised at the University of Cambridge by Dr Noga Ganany. This event is taking place only <u>in person</u> (a recording of the lecture will be made available at a later date). Please come and join us!  </span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><b>The Indian Buddhist Origins of the Chinese Beef Taboo</b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b>Speaker:</b> Prof. Meir Shahar (Tel Aviv University)</span></span></p><p><span><span><b>Discussant:</b> Dr Gregory Scott</span></span></p><p><span><span><b>Host:</b> Dr Noga Ganany</span></span></p><p><span><span><b>Date: </b>11th April (Tuesday) 2023</span></span></p><p><span><span><b>Time:</b> 14:00 BST </span></span></p><p><span><span><b>Venue:</b> Room 8-9, Faculty of Asian and Middle Eastern Studies (Sidgwick Avenue, Cambridge, CB3 9DA)</span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><u>Abstract</u></span></span></p><p><span><span>During the late-imperial period, the beef taboo was widely propagated in China. Many people (especially in South China) refrained from consuming the meat of buffaloes and oxen (both species being referred to by same term: niu). The dietary prohibition was related to the divinity of the animal. Legend had it that that the ox (and/or buffalo) was a Buddhist deity who descended from Heaven for the express purpose of pulling the plow. The animal was a god who sacrificed itself for its owner’s sake. Eating if flesh was not only thankless, it was blasphemous.</span></span></p><p><span><span>In this paper, I trace the origins of the late-imperial Chinese beef taboo to ancient India. I argue that Buddhism served as a vehicle introducing the Indian inviolability of the cattle to China. The sanctity of the Chinese ox/buffalo derived from the divinity of the Indian cow. The paper highlights the role of Buddhism in bringing Indian civilization to bear upon Chinese culture and religion. It also reveals a neglected aspect of Buddhist dietary practice. At least in certain times and places, Buddhist clerics advocated the inviolability of the cattle as distinct from other animal species. They refrained from consuming beef as distinct from other meats.  </span></span></p><p> </p><p><u><span><span>About the Speaker</span></span></u></p><p><span><span>Meir Shahar is the Shoul N. Eisenberg Chair for East Asian Affairs at Tel Aviv University. He is the author of numerous books on Chinese religion, including <i>Crazy Ji: Chinese Religion and Popular Literature</i> (1998); <i>Oedipal God: The Chinese Nezha and his Indian Origins</i> (2015); and <i>The Shaolin Monastery: History, Religion, and the Chinese Martial Arts</i> (2008), which has been translated into many languages. Meir Shahar is currently completing a book titled <i>Kings of Oxen and Horses: Draft Animals, Buddhism, and Chinese Rural Religion</i>. </span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><u>About the Yin-Cheng Distinguished Lecture Series</u></span></span></p><p><span><span>Launched in September 2021, the Yin-Cheng Distinguished Lecture Series (<span>印證佛學傑出學術系列講座</span>) is a collaborative, multi-university partnership between Peking University, Columbia University, Princeton University, Harvard University, University of British Columbia, University of Oxford and University of Cambridge. The Lecture Series is established in honour of Venerable Cheng-yen <span>證嚴</span>, founder of Tzu Chi, and her mentor Yinshun <span>印順</span> (1906–2005), with the goal of promoting topics in Buddhist studies.</span></span></p></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 19:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679117829065214</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Silber-Obrecht Lecture in Interfaith and Interreligious Studies</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12576184/silber-obrecht-lecture-interfaith-and-interreligious-studies</link>
						<dc:creator>Benjamin Sax</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-04-25T00:00:00-04:00">April 25, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Maryland</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><a href="https://icjs.org/silber-obrecht-lecture/" rel="nofollow">The Silber-Obrecht Lecture</a>, the first endowed lectureship in the emerging field of Interreligious and Interfaith Studies, is a semiannual three-day academic residency at the <a href="http://icjs.org/" rel="nofollow">Institute for Islamic, Christian, and Jewish Studies</a> in Baltimore. The lectureship aims to advance the field of study by presenting new and creative work by a senior scholar and interreligious practitioner.</p><p>The inaugural Silber-Obrecht Lecture, to be held from April 25-27, 2023 at Loyola University Maryland, will be delivered by <a href="https://projects.iq.harvard.edu/francisclooney" rel="nofollow">Francis X. Clooney, S.J.,</a> a theologian at the Harvard Divinity School and a leader in the field of <a href="https://hds.harvard.edu/news/2022/07/18/being-catholic-interreligiously" rel="nofollow">interreligious studies</a>. </p><p><a href="https://www.american.edu/cas/faculty/pathak.cfm" rel="nofollow">Shubha Pathak, Ph.D., Ph.D., </a>associate professor in the Department of Philosophy and Religion at American University in Washington D.C. will offer her response to Dr. Clooney’s lecture.</p><p>You can register <a href="https://icjs.org/silber-obrecht-lecture/" rel="nofollow">here</a>. </p><p>The endowed lecture, managed and sponsored by ICJS, will be held in partnership with five Baltimore educational institutions: Goucher College, the SNF Agora Institute at Johns Hopkins University, Loyola University Maryland, Morgan State University’s Center for Religion and Cities, and St. Mary’s Seminary &amp; University.</p><p>The Silber-Obrecht Lecture is named in honor of Sidney and Jean Silber and Charles F. and Margaret M.H. (Peggy) Obrecht in recognition of their longtime commitment to improving interreligious relationships and understanding.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Benjamin Sax, Institute for Islamic, Christian, and Jewish Studies </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:bsax@icjs.org">bsax@icjs.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://icjs.org/silber-obrecht-lecture/" target="_blank">https://icjs.org/silber-obrecht-lecture/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 19:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679117829065213</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Open Call for Papers| Siyabonana: The Journal of Africana Studies| Summer 2023 Issue</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12573647/open-call-papers-siyabonana-journal-africana-studies-summer</link>
						<dc:creator>Sekhmet Maat</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-31T00:00:00-04:00">March 31, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>African American History / Studies, African History / Studies, Latin American and Caribbean History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><i>Siyabonana: The Journal of Africana Studies</i> is an open access online peer-reviewed academic journal that publishes original research and creative intellectual work on key issues within the discipline of Africana Studies and across the global African world. Pan-African in scope, the journal publishes research articles, essays, commentaries, institutional reports, book reviews, oral histories/interviews, and other creative work that utilizes African-centered theories, methodologies, and approaches to not only examine critical issues, but to present solutions within all areas of Africana Studies, including the humanities, arts, and sciences. It simultaneously provides intellectual space for discourse about community social justice activist work and liberation struggles on the continent and within African world communities. Accepting intellectual and creative work from diverse scholars, activists, writers, and artists who resemble the Editorial Board’s diverse training and scholarship, <i>The Journal of Africana Studies</i> intentionally positions itself as an inclusive and affirming discipline-based African-centered entity. Timely and radical intellectual research and creative pieces on the prison industrial complex; Africana/Black digital humanities; Africana genders and sexualities and Africana queer theory; the Black radical tradition; political prisoners; Africana/Black Psychology; mental health, nutrition, and holistic health; the African/Black Aesthetic; Africana spiritual philosophy; Black liberation theology; and Afrofuturism and Afropessimism are, therefore, also welcome.</p><p><b>General Submission Guidelines</b></p><p><i>Siyabonana</i> encourages longer essays and research articles, as well as oral histories, institutional reports, book reviews, commentaries, and creative works. Essays, research articles, reports, and oral histories/interviews should not exceed 10,000 words; review essays, film reviews, and commentaries should not exceed 3,000 words; and book reviews should not exceed 1700 words. The length of all creative work will be determined on a case-by-case basis.</p><p>​Manuscripts should be submitted as a Microsoft Word document, double spaced, written in Times New Roman, size 12 font, and adhere to the most recent edition of the Chicago Manual of Style, APA Publication Manual, or MLA Handbook in terms of format and citation.</p><p>​At the top of your submission, please include the following information in this order:</p><ol><li>Title of article (in Bold)</li><li>Author’s first name and last name, highest degree (ex.  Kwame Martin, Ph.D.)</li><li>Email address</li><li>Academic title (ex. Associate Professor of Sociology)</li><li>Department (ex. Department of Sociology and Social Work)</li><li>University (ex. University of Cape Coast)<ul><li>Repeat for all authors​</li></ul></li><li>Abstract<ul><li>Include a 150-200 word abstract under the heading Abstract.</li></ul></li><li>Keywords<ul><li>Include 3 to 5 keywords that best reflect the content of the manuscript under the heading Keywords</li></ul></li></ol><p> </p><p><b>Peer Review Process:</b></p><p>The journal has a double-blind peer review process. For all submissions, other than book reviews, the author’s name will be removed from the submission during the review process, and the author will not be informed about who reviewed their submission. We will attempt to have at least two reviewers from the editorial board and/or volunteer external reviewers comment on the academic quality of the submission, and submit a review report to the author.</p><p><b>​Final Submission Date: </b>March 31, 2023</p><p><b>Submit Submissions Here:</b><a href="https://www.journalofafricanastudies.com/submissions" rel="nofollow">https://www.journalofafricanastudies.com/submissions</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.journalofafricanastudies.com/call-for-papers" target="_blank">https://www.journalofafricanastudies.com/call-for-papers</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 19:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679117829065212</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Books! &quot;Bibles: Instruments of Colonialism?&quot; Wednesday, 3/22, noon CDT, 5 p.m. GMT</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12572716/books-bibles-instruments-colonialism-wednesday-322-noon-cdt-5</link>
						<dc:creator>Marian J. Barber</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Event</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-22T00:00:00-04:00">March 22, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Texas</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Arabic History / Studies, British History / Studies, Colonial and Post-Colonial History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Early Modern History and Period Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Please join the <strong>British, Irish and Empire Studies</strong> program at the University of Texas at Austin for the sixth session in "Books!," our Spring 2023 <strong>virtual </strong>speaker series, Wednesday, March 22, at noon CDT, 5 p.m. GMT. The topic is "Bibles: Instruments of Colonialism?"</p><p>This session will feature a discussion of Bibles in history by scholars <strong>Eryn M. White of Aberystwyth University</strong> and <strong>Heather Sharkey of the University of Pennsylvania.</strong> White will address <strong>"The Bible in Welsh: Unintended Salvation?"</strong> while Sharkey will explore <strong>"British Arabic Bibles: Global Histories, Local Books."</strong> <strong>Martha G. Newman </strong>of UT-Austin's History and Religious Studies departments will chair.</p><p>Registration is required. Please use this link:</p><p><strong><a href="https://utexas.zoom.us/meeting/register/tJUtcOmuqTMqGdLBeWffEJhi8pLc-tzII4ZW" rel="nofollow">https://utexas.zoom.us/meeting/register/tJUtcOmuqTMqGdLBeWffEJhi8pLc-tzII4ZW</a></strong></p><p>White writes: "The publication of the Welsh Bible in 1588, the greatest achievement of Renaissance scholarship in Wales, has often been cited as responsible for saving the Welsh language but government backing for this development has also been described as ‘colonial’ in its intentions. Can a single book have so much impact? In this paper, I will argue that the positive impact on the language may have been unintended by the authorities and owed more to a group of committed Welsh humanists who took advantage of the political context of the time."</p><p>Sharkey adds: "Between 1908 and 1965, the British and Foreign Bible Society (BFBS) published Bible translations in nine forms of North African Arabic.  In the wake of decolonization, Arab critics accused the BFBS and British powers of having used these Bibles as a tool of imperialism – to break up and weaken Arabs by propagating linguistic distinctions among them.  These British Arabic Bibles, I argue instead, reflected not a conscious tactic of divide and rule, but rather evangelical impulses and historical experiences from the British Isles and North America."</p><p>For more detail, please visit the BIES website, <a href="https://liberalarts.utexas.edu/bies/" rel="nofollow">https://liberalarts.utexas.edu/bies/</a>.</p><p>Questions? Please contact BIES staff at <a href="mailto:Marian.Barber@austin.utexas.edu">Marian.Barber@austin.utexas.edu</a>.</p><p>Next up: "Race and Literature," Wednesday, April 5.<br/> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Marian J. Barber, PhD, Assistant to the Director, British, Irish and Empire Studies, The University of Texas at Austin</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:Marian.Barber@austin.utexas.edu">Marian.Barber@austin.utexas.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://liberalarts.utexas.edu/bies/" target="_blank">https://liberalarts.utexas.edu/bies/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 18:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679117829065211</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFA: Journal for the Study of Radicalism</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12572231/cfa-journal-study-radicalism</link>
						<dc:creator>Morgan Shipley</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Publications</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-11-15T00:00:00-05:00">November 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Social Sciences, Humanities, Cultural History / Studies, Anthropology, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><i>JSR: Journal for the Study of Radicalism</i>—an academic journal published by Michigan State University Press—announces a call for articles and book reviews.</p><p>We are interested in groundbreaking articles on themes or topics ranging from anarchism and communalism to utopian communities. We are especially interested in contributions on radical communal groups and utopian efforts from the early modern period onward.  Potential topics could include Oneida Community, the Icarians, the Amana Colonies, Diggers, Fruitlands, Fountain Grove, a utopian community of the 1960s or 1970s, Rajneeshpuram, temporary autonomous zones, religiously inspired utopian (or ultimately dystopian) communities, or similar topics. Historically focused explorations are welcome, and we are also interested in explorations from other approaches and methodologies. Other topics concerning radical groups or individuals across the political spectrum are also welcome.</p><p>Completed articles due by November 15, 2023; contact editors at <a href="mailto:jsrmsu@gmail.com">jsrmsu@gmail.com</a> for queries. </p><p><i>Background</i></p><p>The <i>Journal for the Study of Radicalism</i> engages in serious, scholarly exploration of the forms, representations, meanings, and historical influences of radical social movements. With sensitivity and openness to historical and cultural contexts of the term, we loosely define "radical," as distinguished from "reformers," to mean groups who seek revolutionary alternatives to hegemonic social and political institutions, and who use violent or non-violent means to resist authority and to bring about change. The journal is eclectic, without dogma or strict political agenda, and ranges broadly across social and political groups worldwide, whether typically defined as "left" or "right." We expect contributors to come from a wide range of fields and disciplines. We especially welcome articles that reconceptualize definitions and theories of radicalism, feature underrepresented radical groups, and introduce new topics and methods of study.</p><p>Submissions should be 20-30 pages in length, in .doc format, and conform to Chicago Manual of Style endnotes. Please include a one-paragraph abstract. Images for possible use in an article should be 300 dpi. Authors are responsible for requesting and receiving permission to reprint images for scholarly use.</p><p>See <a href="https://msupress.org/journals/journal-for-the-study-of-radicalism/%C2%A0for" rel="nofollow">https://msupress.org/journals/journal-for-the-study-of-radicalism/ for</a> more information.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><em>Background</em></p><p><em>JSR</em>’s primary purpose is to serve as a venue for fine scholarship in this developing academic field. We expect scholarly contributors to come from a wide range of perspectives and disciplines, and we especially welcome articles that reconceptualize definitions and theories of radicalism, feature underrepresented radical groups, and introduce new topics and methods of study. We seek articles that make a clear larger point, and that offer a real contribution to the field.</p><p><i>Journal Editor</i><br/>Arthur Versluis, Michigan State University</p><p><i>Journal Associate Editor</i><br/>Morgan Shipley, Michigan State University</p><p><i>Editorial Board</i><br/>Constance Bantman, University of Surrey<br/>Michael Barkun, Syracuse University<br/>Colin Beck, Pomona College<br/>Steven Biel, Harvard University<br/>Pero Dagbovie, Michigan State University<br/>Daniel Farber, University of Kansas<br/>Tor Egil Førland, University of Oslo<br/>Scott Henkel, University of Wyoming<br/>Ariel Hessayon, Goldsmiths College, University of London<br/>Richard Bach Jensen, Louisiana Scholars’ College, Northwestern State University<br/>Alex Khasnabish, Mount Saint Vincent University<br/>Ruth Kinna, Loughboro University<br/>Ann Larabee, Michigan State University<br/>Martha Lee†, University of Windsor<br/>Michael Loadenthal, Miami University<br/>Jean-François Mayer, Religioscope Institute<br/>Mick (Michael) Smith, Queens University</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:%20jsrmsu@gmail.com"> jsrmsu@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://msupress.org/journals/journal-for-the-study-of-radicalism/" target="_blank">https://msupress.org/journals/journal-for-the-study-of-radicalism/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 18:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679117829065210</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Music of the Spheres in Akbarian Sufism. Monday Majlis Online on Monday the 20th of March, 17:00-18:30 (UK time), with Dunja Rašić</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12569805/music-spheres-akbarian-sufism-monday-majlis-online-monday-20th</link>
						<dc:creator>Nikola Pantic</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-20T00:00:00-04:00">March 20, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Arabic History / Studies, Islamic History / Studies, Middle East History / Studies, Philosophy, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><b>Abstract</b></p><p>As per tradition, no human could hear the music of the spheres save for Pythagoras. Ibn Arabī, however, claimed to have heard this music each time he prayed. My presentation examines how the Pythagorean concept of the music of the spheres has been interpreted and reinterpreted in Akbarian Sufism - with a special emphasis on Ibn Arabī’s notion of <i>samāʿ</i> and the modes of recreating the music of the spheres in Sufi gatherings.</p><p><b>Bio</b></p><p>Dunja Rašić earned her Ph.D in Islamic Studies at the Free University Berlin. Her primary research field is medieval intellectual history, with a focus on Akbarian cosmology, philosophical Sufism and the Islamic philosophy of language. She is currently working on her second book, which is focusing on jinn doubles and the problem of evil in Akbarian Sufism.</p><p>In the spirit of the label ‘Majlis’ and also to make the talks even more interesting, we are experimenting with a new format presenting the topic discussed by our speaker as embedded in their own research journey. Please come and enjoy the talks and the discussions. If you’d like to be included in the CSI (Centre for the Study of Islam (Institute of Arab and Islamic Studies, University of Exeter) mailing list, please contact the CSI Manager: Sarah Wood (<a href="mailto:s.a.wood2@exeter.ac.uk">s.a.wood2@exeter.ac.uk</a>).</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><b>Registration is required. Register please on this link:</b></p><p><a href="https://eur03.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Funiversityofexeter.zoom.us%2Fmeeting%2Fregister%2FtJUqfuqspjkoEtzAqcRCIMAE45m3Zb0Nytym&amp;data=05%7C01%7CI.T.Kristo-Nagy%40exeter.ac.uk%7C4339700aac94453d93c908db2571aef2%7C912a5d77fb984eeeaf321334d8f04a53%7C0%7C0%7C638144942421145770%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=Ru8Wtu74B7IcJ4WAtHWvHKA1reaHyx3gbjCypQa4Woo%3D&amp;reserved=0" rel="nofollow">https://Universityofexeter.zoom.us/meeting/register/tJUqfuqspjkoEtzAqcRCIMAE45m3Zb0Nytym</a></p><p>For further details, contact Sarah Wood (<a href="mailto:s.a.wood2@exeter.ac.uk">s.a.wood2@exeter.ac.uk</a>).</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:s.a.wood2@exeter.ac.uk">s.a.wood2@exeter.ac.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://universityofexeter.zoom.us/meeting/register/tJUqfuqspjkoEtzAqcRCIMAE45m3Zb0Nytym" target="_blank">https://Universityofexeter.zoom.us/meeting/register/tJUqfuqspjkoEtzAqcRCIMAE45m3Zb0Nytym</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1679031427995633</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Newberry Seminar on Religion and Culture in the Americas, March 31, 2023</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12565923/newberry-seminar-religion-and-culture-americas-march-31-2023</link>
						<dc:creator>Malachy R. McCarthy</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Seminar</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-15T00:00:00-04:00">March 15, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-04-02T00:00:00-04:00">April 2, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Illinois</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>American History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><strong>Newberry Library Scholarly Seminars</strong></p><p><strong>Religion and Culture in the Americas Seminar</strong></p><p><strong>Friday, March 31, 2023</strong></p><p><strong>3:00-4:30 pm Central Time</strong></p><p><strong>Virtual Seminar, Register for link</strong></p><p> </p><p><strong>“Placing the “Eternal Child”</strong></p><p><strong>Andrew Walker-Cornetta, Georgia State University</strong></p><p> </p><p>Studies of Catholic material culture often describe how holy objects “reduce social distance between people” (McDannell 2005). It is a truism: relics, shrines, and various ampullae suture communities together across time and space. This paper is about a set of objects that, in addition to fostering human relationships, have also worked to sever them. It focuses on a cluster of shrines and chapels at Catholic institutions for people with cognitive disabilities in the mid-twentieth century U.S. and analyzes these objects as previously unexplored technologies of institutionalization. It asks how these media worked to justify the social segregation of disabled persons while simultaneously spurring what the anthropologists Faye Ginsburg and Rayna Rapp have dubbed “new kinship imaginaries” (Rapp and Ginsburg 2011) in the postwar era.</p><p>This event is free, but all participants must register in advance and space is limited. To register and request a copy of the pre-circulated paper, click here. Please do not request a paper unless you plan to attend.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Emily Altman, Newberry Library</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:scholarlyseminars@newberry.org">scholarlyseminars@newberry.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.newberry.org/calendar/andrew-walker-cornetta-georgia-state-university" target="_blank">https://www.newberry.org/calendar/andrew-walker-cornetta-georgia-state-university</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 18:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1678945030247685</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – March 15, 2023</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-march-15-2023/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find 1 new job opportunity, 1 fellowship, 3 awards, 6 Call for Papers, and 7 upcoming conferences/speakers.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 33!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Associate Director of Research at Boniuk Institute for the Study and Advancement of Religious Tolerance</h4>



<p>Rice University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: March 23, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="http://www.rraweb.org/2763-2/">http://www.rraweb.org/2763-2/</a></p>



<h4>AAR/SBL Job Forum</h4>



<p><a href="https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search">https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search</a></p>



<h2>Fellowships:</h2>



<h4>Max Weber Center for Advanced Cultural and Social Studies (5 Ph.D. fellowship positions available, 3 year positions)</h4>



<p>University of Erfurt, Germany</p>



<p>Deadline: April 14, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: Dr. Elisabeth Begemann (<a href="mailto:elisabeth.begemann@uni-erfurt.de">elisabeth.begemann@uni-erfurt.de</a>)</p>



<h2>Awards:</h2>



<h4>John Gilmary Shea Prize</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/wrE6j2n5Uo">https://t.co/wrE6j2n5Uo</a></p>



<h4>Helen &amp; Howard R. Marraro Prize in Italian History</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/wrE6j2n5Uo">https://t.co/wrE6j2n5Uo</a></p>



<h4>John Tracy Ellis Dissertation Award</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/wrE6j2n5Uo">https://t.co/wrE6j2n5Uo</a></p>



<h2>Call For Papers:</h2>



<h4>American Catholic Historical Association Annual Meeting</h4>



<p><strong>New Deadline: March 24, 2023</strong></p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/U0QpwFJrHy">https://t.co/U0QpwFJrHy</a></p>



<h4>Margins and Peripheries</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/xSSOarbVar">https://t.co/xSSOarbVar</a></p>



<h4>Religion, Empowering or Oppressing</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://sssreligion.org/annual-meeting/call-for-papers/">https://sssreligion.org/annual-meeting/call-for-papers/</a></p>



<h4>Apocalyptic Nostalgia: Cold War Imagery in Popular Culture</h4>



<p>Deadline: July 13, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/PYp8KBHxXC">https://t.co/PYp8KBHxXC</a></p>



<h4>Visual Lived Religion: Towards a <em>camera-based </em>Approach to the Empirical Study of Religion</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 20, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: Srdjan Sremac <a href="mailto:s.sremac@vu.nl">s.sremac@vu.nl</a> and Johan Roeland <a href="mailto:j.h.roeland@vu.nl">j.h.roeland@vu.nl</a>.</p>



<h4>Catholic Record Society Summer Conference</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 14, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.crs.org.uk/conferences">https://www.crs.org.uk/conferences</a></p>



<h2>Conferences:</h2>



<h4>Book Webinar on <em>Digital Religion. The Basic</em>s</h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>Date: March 20, 2023 1-2 pm CST</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://bit.ly/3y3WYRE">https://bit.ly/3y3WYRE</a></p>



<h4>Religion and the Politics of National Identity Webinar</h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>Date: March 20, 2023 2 pm CET</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/nm6MVyyxni">https://t.co/nm6MVyyxni</a></p>



<h4>Eastern International Region 2023 Annual Meeting</h4>



<p>Queens University, Canada</p>



<p>Date: May 5-7, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/Za6TcwpXQJ">https://t.co/Za6TcwpXQJ</a></p>



<h4>Beyond the Black/White Binary: Research on Race and Congregations</h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>Date: April 13, 2023 2pm CST</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/tQzf04LWW1">https://t.co/tQzf04LWW1</a></p>



<h4>European Research Network on Global Pentecostalism</h4>



<p>University of Heidelberg, Germany</p>



<p>Date: February 9-4, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="http://www.glopent.net/">http://www.glopent.net/</a></p>



<h4>Anarchists, Communists, and Women: Congregational Missions to Polish Immigrants in 20<sup>th</sup> Century America</h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>Date: March 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12518313/anarchists-communists-and-women-congregational-missions-polish">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12518313/anarchists-communists-and-women-congregational-missions-polish</a></p>



<h4>What Girls Learn in Jewish Families</h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>Date: March 15, 2023 1-1:30 ET</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12423352/what-girls-learn-jewish-families">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12423352/what-girls-learn-jewish-families</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1678945030247684</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP The Afterlife in Popular Culture (special issue of the The Australasian Journal of Popular Culture)</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/03/13/cfp-the-afterlife-in-popular-culture-special-issue-of-the-the-australasian-journal-of</link>
						<dc:creator>angelique.nairn@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Wednesday, March 15, 2023 - 3:31pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Angelique Nairn and Justin Matthews (Auckland University of Technology)</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:angelique.nairn@aut.ac.nz">angelique.nairn@aut.ac.nz </a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/film-and-television">film and television</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/popular-culture">popular culture</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>October 13, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>CFP The Afterlife in Popular Culture (special issue of the The Australasian Journal of Popular Culture)</p>
<p>Due to the great interest in the Depicting the Afterlife edited collection, we have arranged to co-edit a special issue of The Australasian Journal of Popular Culture set for publication in early 2024.</p>
<p>The theme remains the same:</p>
<p>As Garrett (2015) contends, popular cultural representations of the afterlife are a means of imaginatively and creatively grappling with the unknown. These representations can offer explanations about life after death or the in-between, to rationalize the existential, support and challenge religious doctrines, and entertain and educate so that society might live life to the fullest or feel assured that there is something more. </p>
<p>According to O’Neil (2022), at their crux, these representations hinge on hope and the prospect of happiness, permeable boundaries that see a blurring of ‘here’ and ‘there,’ self-determination as key to understanding the afterlife, and acts of sacrifice and love that forge the conditions of eternal happiness. These ideas about the afterlife construct perceptions of morality and religion: what one must do now to reap the benefits once one has passed over.</p>
<p>These popular cultural representations, then, present “a range of narratives, consumer choices, moral dispositions and selected rituals of conduct” (Saenz, 1992, p. 43), which people “may adopt, adapt, criticize or reject as components in our implicit knowledge” (Dant, 2012, p. 24). With media such as <em>The Good Place, Upload, The Inbetween, Afterlife of the Party, Coco, Soul, Reaper, Elsewhere, If I Stay, and Boo Bitch </em>(to name but a few), focused on the afterlife, it seems timely to explore the messages promulgated in such texts about morality and/or religion. This is especially given media can prompt questioning and reasoning that aids self-reflection (Hawkins, 2001) and integrates people into an established order offering models of appropriate ways of being (Krijen &amp; Verboord, 2016).</p>
<p>Therefore, this special issue aims to explore representations of morality and/or religion in 21st-century popular cultural texts that feature and emphasize the afterlife. It asks how the afterlife is understood but moreover, how are people encouraged to live their lives? Such aims will inevitably consider what place (if any) religion has in shaping popular cultural texts and understandings of the beyond, and what perceptions of morality are favoured and guide character story arcs. Ultimately this special issue will contribute to a continued and growing discussion on the representations of morality, religion, and the afterlife in contemporary society.</p>
<p>Possible topics might include, but are not limited to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Moral motivation/reasoning and life after death</li>
<li>Dichotomies of Heaven and Hell</li>
<li>Representations of the ‘soul’</li>
<li>Cultural differences in constructions of the afterlife</li>
<li>Depictions/constructions of the spiritual realm</li>
<li>Ghosts, the paranormal, and the afterlife</li>
<li>Religious motifs in texts that feature the afterlife</li>
<li>Representations of Supreme Being(s)</li>
<li>Notions of suffering and reward in the afterlife</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Full articles are required by 13th October 2023 and are to be emailed to me or my co-editor (Justin Matthews) directly</strong>. Articles should be 5-6k words in length. More information about the AJPC in general can be found here:   </p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.intellectbooks.com/the-australasian-journal-of-popular-culture" target="_blank">https://www.intellectbooks.com/the-australasian-journal-of-popular-culture</a>  </li>
</ul>
<p>Contact information:</p>
<p>Associate Professor Angelique Nairn: <a href="mailto:angelique.nairn@aut.ac.nz">angelique.nairn@aut.ac.nz</a></p>
<p>Senior Lecturer Justin Matthews: <a href="mailto:justin.matthews@aut.ac.nz">justin.matthews@aut.ac.nz</a></p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1678945030247683</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>2023 Undergraduate and Graduate Humanities Conference. In Person and Via Zoom</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/03/08/2023-undergraduate-and-graduate-humanities-conference-in-person-and-via-zoom</link>
						<dc:creator>ycabreraortega@rockford.edu</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Wednesday, March 15, 2023 - 3:20pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Rockford University</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:XFoleVarela@Rockford.edu">XFoleVarela@Rockford.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/classical-studies">classical studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/pedagogy">pedagogy</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>March 18, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p dir="ltr"></p>
<p> </p>
<p dir="ltr">Call for Papers</p>
<p> </p>
<p dir="ltr">2023 Rockford University </p>
<p dir="ltr">3rd Annual Undergraduate Student Conference</p>
<p dir="ltr">“Celebrating the Interdisciplinary Humanities”</p>
<p dir="ltr">Friday and Saturday, March 31th and April 1st, 2023</p>
<p dir="ltr">In-Person and Zoom Presentations</p>
<p> </p>
<p dir="ltr">The Department of Languages, Philosophy, Religion, and Cultures and the Department of Education at Rockford University invite you to submit a proposal (abstract) to participate in the 3rd Annual Undergraduate Student Conference “Celebrating the Interdisciplinary Humanities” to be held both in person and via Zoom, on Friday and Saturday, March 31st and April 1st, 2022. Students are invited to present their research papers in any area of the Humanities with special emphasis on interdisciplinary connections. This conference will discuss cultural, theological, literary, and philosophical inquiry across time periods, genres, and cultural traditions. We encourage students to participate by presenting papers about humanistic thought, literary production, performance, and/or theological writings over time. This is an invitation to discuss together how ideas, words, and cultures emerge, change, and are connected. Presentations, abstracts, proposals, and papers in either English or Spanish are welcome.</p>
<p> </p>
<p dir="ltr">Presentations can be from any discipline and about any area of the Humanities. Students will present their work in the form of 10-to-15-minute oral presentations (the equivalent of a 4-6 page double-spaced paper) as part of a traditional panel with a faculty member and undergraduate student as discussants. Students can submit individual proposals or proposals for panels of 3 or 4 papers. All participants and attendees will be asked to register for this two-day event, but registration is free. </p>
<p> </p>
<p dir="ltr">The three best papers presented will be awarded as follows:</p>
<p> </p>
<p dir="ltr">- First place award: $150 and publication of the paper in our academic journal Deinós.</p>
<p dir="ltr">- Second place award: $100 and publication of the paper in Deinós.</p>
<p dir="ltr">- Third place award: $50 and publication of the paper in Deinós.</p>
<p> </p>
<p dir="ltr">Please note: The awarded students will have until June 1st to submit their papers to be published.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Papers addressing, but not limited to, the following topics are welcome:</p>
<p> </p>
<ul>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">World Literature and the Arts</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Global Histories, Art Histories</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Literature, Politics, and Emotions</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Theater and Performance Studies</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Literature and Art in Ancient Greece and Rome</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Slavery in Antiquity</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Gender in Antiquity and Today</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Classical Reception</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Graphic Novels </p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Film Studies</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Reception Studies</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">National Identity Issues in Today’s World</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Migration Studies, Memory Studies</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Etymology and/or Vocabulary Building</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Spanish Linguistics</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Hispanic and U.S. Latino Literature and Culture</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Philosophy (Ethics, Logic, Applied Philosophy, History of Philosophy) </p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Religious Studies and World Religions</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Connections between Religion and Literature, Pop-culture, Science, or Society</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Scripture and Interpretation</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">The Humanities in K-12 Classrooms</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Cultural Identity and Bilingual Education </p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Interdisciplinary approaches to the Humanities (Humanities and Medicine, Humanities and Business, Humanities and Sports, Natural and Social Sciences and the Humanities, etc.) </p>
</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p dir="ltr">Individual presentation proposals (abstracts) of no more than 250 words must be submitted via email by March 18th to conference organizer Dr. Xabier Fole Varela at <a href="mailto:xfolevarela@rockford.edu">xfolevarela@rockford.edu</a>. Please be sure to include the following information.</p>
<p> </p>
<p dir="ltr">For individual proposals:</p>
<p> </p>
<ul>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Name of the student and contact information (email address)</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Affiliation - what college or university the student attends</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Title of the presentation</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">An abstract of no more than 250 words</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p dir="ltr">Panel proposals of 3 or 4 presentations should be submitted with the following information: </p>
<p> </p>
<ul>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">The title of the panel </p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">The organizer's name and contact information (email address)</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">The names of the panelists and their contact information (email addresses)</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Panelists’ affiliations - what colleges or universities the students attend</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Abstract of each paper in the panel - no more than 250 words each</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p dir="ltr">For more information, please contact conference organizer Dr. Xabier Fole Varela at <a href="mailto:xfolevarela@rockford.edu">xfolevarela@rockford.edu</a>. </p>

<p dir="ltr"></p>
<p> </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 23:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1678945030247682</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Papers: William James Studies Fall 2023 Issue</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/03/06/call-for-papers-william-james-studies-fall-2023-issue</link>
						<dc:creator>shawn.welch101@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Wednesday, March 15, 2023 - 3:25pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>William James Studies</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:shawn.welch101@gmail.com">shawn.welch101@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/general-announcements">general announcements</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/science-and-culture">science and culture</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>June 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p dir="ltr">Call for Papers: William James Studies</p>
<p> </p>
<p dir="ltr">The William James Society and its peer-reviewed journal William James Studies invite article submissions from scholars with diverse interests and approaches to the life and work of William James. We are particularly interested in articles that reflect William James’s work (psychology, philosophy, metaphysics, etc.) as it intersects with modern concerns and interpretive contexts. The William James Society is a multidisciplinary professional society that supports the study of, and communication about, the life and work of James and his ongoing influence in the many fields to which he contributed. William James Studies can be found on several subscription databases, including the Modern Language Association.</p>
<p dir="ltr">We welcome submissions that examine James and pragmatism’s relationship to current issues in contemporary society, especially those with interdisciplinary perspectives with possible orientations toward history, politics, economics, American studies, or religious studies. Papers might examine any number of the following:</p>
<p dir="ltr">* James and the theory and practice of literary interpretation</p>
<p dir="ltr">* James and his relationship to modernism, realism, and other literary genres</p>
<p dir="ltr">* James and nineteenth and/or early twentieth-century aesthetic movements</p>
<p dir="ltr">* James's philosophies of psychology, pragmatism, religion, and literary authors/texts</p>
<p dir="ltr">* James and contemporary interpretive contexts, including critical race theory, feminism, queer theories, ecocriticism, religious studies, game studies, and archival approaches </p>
<p dir="ltr">For consideration for the fall 2023 issue, please submit articles with abstracts by June 1, 2023. </p>
<p dir="ltr">To submit, please review the WJS submissions guidelines here: (<a href="https://williamjamesstudies.org/submission-information/">https://williamjamesstudies.org/submission-information/</a>). </p>
<p dir="ltr">Submissions should outline a clear argument, identify relevant texts by James and others, and place their paper within a contemporary scholarly framework or conversation. All submissions will conform to a strict timetable for publication for the fall 2023 issue of William James Studies.  Please submit direct queries or questions to General Editor Shawn Welch at: (<a href="mailto:shawn.welch101@gmail.com">shawn.welch101@gmail.com</a>) or <a href="mailto:editor@williamjamesstudies.org">editor@williamjamesstudies.org</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 23:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1678945030247681</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ September 20, 2023 -  September 22, 2023] Conference or similar: Beunruhigungen der Normalität/Unsettling Normality</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/109141</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p>Der Kongress widmet sich dem breiten Spektrum von Normen, Normalität und Abweichung, Widerfahrnis und Grenzsituation, Krankheit und Psychopathologie. Damit trägt er der besonderen Ausrichtung der Heidelberger Phänomenologie auf die philosophische Psychiatrie Rechnung. Der Titel des Kongresses bringt zum Ausdruck, dass wir die Phänomenologie der Normalität – also des Erwarteten und Unerwarteten, des Optimalen und Unvollkommenen, des Unauffälligen und Abweichenden, des Vertrauten und Fremden, des Gesunden und Kranken – als eine grundlegende Besinnung auf Beunruhigungen und Herausforderungen verstehen können, die wir in der Gegenwart erleben.</p>
<p>Leitend ist dabei zum einen die Annahme, dass Normalität nicht als eine bloß statistische Größe aufgefasst werden kann, sondern sich aus der inhärenten Struktur der Erfahrung heraus verstehen lässt, deren Tendenzen zur Konsistenz und Typizität die Phänomenologie herausarbeitet. Zum anderen gehen wir davon aus, dass sich Normalität gerade aus der Abweichung und Infragestellung, also von Widerfahrnissen und Grenzsituationen her aufklären lässt. Schließlich wollen wir im Sinne einer kritischen Phänomenologie gesellschaftliche Prozesse der Normalisierung untersuchen, die als Bewältigungsstrategien in der der Auseinandersetzung mit dem Fremden und Abweichenden zu verstehen sind.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 05:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1678858628272516</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>International Conference on the Middle Ages 2023 | Religions in Medieval Urban Europe</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12535058/international-conference-middle-ages-2023-religions-medieval</link>
						<dc:creator>Ricardo  Cordeiro</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-15T00:00:00-05:00">February 15, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-04-30T00:00:00-04:00">April 30, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Portugal</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>European History / Studies, Islamic History / Studies, Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Urban History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Religion pervaded the medieval city and the lives of its citizens. Indeed, the city was frequently, in one way or another, crucial in the expansion of different religions, perhaps most notably Judaism, Christianity, and Islam. Cities harboured their first religious communities and their principal buildings in turn giving rise to topographies of the sacred comprising specific establishments associated both with serving the spiritual needs of the faithful and with accommodating various forms of religious life, all of which mediated and facilitated divine favour. In addition to the sacralisation of space, time itself underwent a parallel transformation becoming delineated by a calendar of feast-days and acts of worship commemorating the most important moments in each religious tradition and frequently highlighting feast-days especially connected to a particular host or home city and the powers there established. Such “urban” feasts could include celebration of the city’s celestial patrons and the most important events in its history – occasions capable of galvanizing an entire community. Further, differentiated time was imposed, guiding daily life between days of work and days dedicated to God which were to be sanctified and which included moments of exultation and exuberance, contrasting with times of penance.</p><p>The city was also the place of demonstrations of dissent and the presence of religious minorities, which both ecclesiastical and lay powers tried to contain and control, thereby preserving the power of the prevailing religious orthodoxy. At the same time, religion became an arena in which competing powers sought to affirm and legitimise themselves, a place of dispute over the possession of goods – sacred or profane -, of contests over offices and benefices, and of strategies aimed at achieving exclusive access to and dominion over sacred powers in broader strategic manoeuvring. There were also squabbles over congregations, influence, spaces, and times, which involved a variety of actors qualified to intercede both for the living and for the dead (and to perpetuate the memories of the latter), including monks, canons, mendicant orders, secular clergy, and even hermits or “religious women.”</p><p>The subject of religiosity in the medieval urban world encompasses a great multiplicity of themes which readily mingle the Christian, Islamic and Jewish worlds in seeking to understand how religion shaped the way in which the civic space was constructed and understood, the powers that converged in it, and the rituals and practices that guided the daily lives of inhabitants.</p><p>Accordingly, this year (2023) on <strong>5th -7th October</strong>, the Institute of Medieval Studies (FCSH; Nova University, Lisbon) and the City Council of Castelo de Vide will host the <strong>VIII International Conference on the Middle Ages</strong>, entitled: <strong>Religions in Medieval Urban Europe</strong>. With a focus on Christian, Islamic and Jewish Europe, researchers from any scientific discipline (History, Archaeology, History of the Art, Literature, among others) are invited to present proposals for sessions and/or individual presentations suitable for inclusion in the following thematic panels:</p><p>1. Topography of the sacred in the urban space: rhythms and strategies of implantation, spaces, constructions.<br/>2. Materiality of religious life and its impact on the urban space: places of worship, conventual dependencies and enclosures, strategies for heritage management.<br/>3. Religious institutions and their impact on urban religious life: preaching and teaching, sacramental life, welfare practices, devotions, intercession for the dead.<br/>4. Faces of religion: religious institutions and their members<br/>5. Intervention of power in religious life: strategies and tensions.<br/>6. Memory of the dead and the logics of social affirmation in the urban context: spaces, practices and strategies of inhumation and sponsorship.<br/>7. Different forms of religious life in the medieval city<br/>8. Experience of religious spaces in the city.<br/>9. Confraternal practice and charity in the medieval urban context<br/>10. Pilgrimages and religious feasts in the city<br/>11. Religious art in urban contexts<br/>12. Religion and the city: representations in medieval memorial texts<br/>13. Religious minorities in different urban contexts<br/>14. Religions in urban contexts: coexistence, tensions, and conflicts<br/>15. Religious dissent and contestation in the city<br/>16. Proposals for religious reform in the city<br/>17. Religions in medieval Castelo de Vide</p><p>The Conference will comprise 4 plenary sessions featuring researchers invited by the organizing committee, along with separate thematic panels. Each panel will be made up of three paper presentations and will be 60 minutes long. Researchers wishing to participate are requested to submit proposals for whole panels and/or individual papers, the latter being arranged by the organizing committee into coherent panels. The Conference includes a full cultural program with guided tours, Conference Dinner, and a public Book Launch to present the published volume which brings together a selection of articles gathered from the VII International Conference of the Middle Ages and the Autumn School of October 2022.</p><p>Please note, the working languages of the Conference are: Portuguese, Spanish, French, and English.</p><p><strong>Keynote speakers:</strong></p><p>Confirmed</p><ol><li><ol><li><a href="https://www.cienciavitae.pt/portal/pt/991C-F0C7-930F" rel="nofollow"><strong>Filomena Andrade</strong> (Universidade Aberta)</a>, “As Ordens Mendicantes na construção da cidade medieval”.</li><li><a href="http://cchs.csic.es/es/personal/maribel.fierro" rel="nofollow"><strong>Maribel Fierro</strong> (Centro de Ciencias Humanas y Sociales – CSIC) </a>, “Disidencia religiosa y contestación en las ciudades de al-Andalus”.</li><li><a href="https://univ-paris8.academia.edu/MaximeLH%C3%A9ritier" rel="nofollow"><strong>Maxime l’Héritier</strong> ( Université Paris 8)</a></li></ol></li></ol><p><strong>Scientific committee:</strong></p><p>Adelaide Millán Costa (U. Aberta)<br/>Alberto García Porras (U. Granada)<br/>Antonio Collantes de Terán (U. de Sevilha)<br/>Antonio Malpica Cuello (U. de Granada)<br/>Arnaldo de Sousa Melo (U. do Minho)<br/>Beatriz Arizaga Bolumburu (U. de Cantábria)<br/>Catarina Tente (U. Nova de Lisboa)<br/>Chris Wickham (U. of Oxford)<br/>David Igual Luis (U.de Castilla-La Mancha)<br/>Denis Menjot (U. Lyon 2)<br/>Dominique Valérian (U. Paris 1 – Panthéon-Sorbonne)<br/>Eloísa Ramirez Vaquero (U. Pública de Navarra)<br/>Emilio Martín Gutiérrez (U. de Cadiz)<br/>Giovanna Bianchi (U. of Siena)<br/>Gregoria Cavero Domínguez (U. de León)<br/>Hermenegildo Fernandes (U. Lisboa)<br/>Hermínia Vilar (U. Évora)<br/>Iria Gonçalves (U. Nova de Lisboa)<br/>Isabel del Val Valdivieso (U. de Valladolid)<br/>Jean Passini (EHESS-Ecole des hautes études en sciences sociales)<br/>Jean-Luc Fray (U. Clermont Auvergne)<br/>Jesús Solórzano Telechea (U. de Cantábria)<br/>José Augusto Sottomayor-Pizarro (U. Porto)<br/>José Avelino Gutiérrez González (U. de Oviedo)<br/>José Manuel Nieto Soria (U. Complutense de Madrid)<br/>Juan Vicente Garcia-Marsilla (U. de València)<br/>Leslie Brubaker (U. of Birmingham)<br/>Louis Sicking (Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam/Universiteit Leiden)<br/>Luísa Trindade (U. de Coimbra)<br/>María Asenjo González (U. Complutense de Madrid)<br/>Maria Helena da Cruz Coelho (U. de Coimbra)<br/>Maria João Branco (U. Nova de Lisboa)<br/>Mário Barroca (U. do Porto)<br/>Michel Bochaca (U. de La Rochelle)<br/>Pere Verdés Pijuan (IMF-CSIC)<br/>Peter Clark (U. de Helsínquia)<br/>Philippe Bernardi (U. Paris 1 Panthéon-Sorbonne, LAMOP)<br/>Raphaella Averkorn (U. Siegen)<br/>Santiago Macias (U. Nova de Lisboa) –<br/>Sara Prata (U. Nova de Lisboa)<br/>Sauro Gelichi (U. Ca ‘Foscari de Veneza)<br/>Stéphane Péquignot (École Pratique des Hautes Études/Université PSL)<br/>Wim Blockmans (U. de Leiden)</p><p><strong>Organizing Committee:</strong><br/>Amélia Aguiar Andrade (IEM | NOVA FCSH)<br/>Gonçalo Melo da Silva (IEM | NOVA FCSH)<br/>Patrícia Martins (CMCV)</p><p><strong>Secretariat:</strong><br/>Mariana Pereira (IEM | NOVA FCSH)<br/>Ricardo Cordeiro (IEM | NOVA FCSH)</p><p><strong>Scholarships to be awarded by IEM:</strong><br/>The Institute for Medieval Studies will give scholarships to cost the conference fees. Applications will be reviewed by the organizing committee. It will be considered the academic merits of the candidates and the reasons expressed in the motivation letter.</p><p>Applicants must send the following documents to the email address <a href="mailto:imcv@fcsh.unl.pt">imcv@fcsh.unl.pt</a> :<br/>1) Curriculum vitae<br/>2) Motivation letter (1 page, A4)<br/>3) Paper proposal (relevance of the proposal for the knowledge of the conference theme. (max. 1 A4 page)</p><p><strong>Supporters:</strong> IEM – NOVA FCSH; CMCV; FCT; NOVA FCSH</p><p><strong>Transportation:</strong><br/>The organization will provide transport by coach for speakers from campus NOVA-FCSH-Castelo de Vide-campus NOVA-FCSH.</p><p>The registration pack for speakers includes coach transport from Lisbon Airport – Castelo de Vide – Lisbon Airport, lunch during conference days, guided tour of Castelo de Vide and Conference Dinner.</p><p>Deadline for proposals for panels and papers: <strong>until 30th April</strong><br/>Panels, Papers and Posters acceptance: <strong>7 May</strong></p><p><strong>Conference fees:</strong><br/>Speakers (general): 70 €<br/>University students (undergraduates, MA and PhD): 50 €<br/>IEM integrated researchers and students at NOVA FCSH: 40 €</p><p><strong>Submissions:</strong> <a href="https://idade-media.castelodevide.pt/en_GB/submissoes/" rel="nofollow">https://idade-media.castelodevide.pt/en_GB/submissoes/</a></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><strong>Conference E-mail:</strong> <a href="mailto:imcv@fcsh.unl.pt">imcv@fcsh.unl.pt</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:imcv@fcsh.unl.pt">imcv@fcsh.unl.pt</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://idade-media.castelodevide.pt/en_GB/" target="_blank">https://idade-media.castelodevide.pt/en_GB/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 17:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1678858628272515</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP The Afterlife in Popular Culture (special issue of the The Australasian Journal of Popular Culture)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12556769/cfp-afterlife-popular-culture-special-issue-australasian</link>
						<dc:creator>Angelique Nairn</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Publications</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-14T00:00:00-04:00">March 14, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-10-13T00:00:00-04:00">October 13, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Digital Humanities, Film and Film History, Journalism and Media Studies, Popular Culture Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span>CFP: The Afterlife in Popular Culture (special issue of the Australasian Journal of Popular Culture)</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Due to the popularity of the Depicting the Afterlife edited collection, we have arranged for a special issue of the Australasian Journal of Popular Culture on the same theme.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>As Garrett (2015) contends, popular cultural representations of the afterlife are a means of imaginatively and creatively grappling with the unknown. These representations can offer explanations about life after death or the in-between, to rationalize the existential, support and challenge religious doctrines, and entertain and educate so that society might live life to the fullest or feel assured that there is something more. </span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>According to O’Neil (2022), at their crux, these representations hinge on hope and the prospect of happiness, permeable boundaries that see a blurring of ‘here’ and ‘there,’ self-determination as key to understanding the afterlife, and acts of sacrifice and love that forge the conditions of eternal happiness. These ideas about the afterlife construct perceptions of morality and religion: what one must do now to reap the benefits once one has passed over.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>These popular cultural representations, then, present “a range of narratives, consumer choices, moral dispositions and selected rituals of conduct” (Saenz, 1992, p. 43), which people “may adopt, adapt, criticize or reject as components in our implicit knowledge” (Dant, 2012, p. 24). With media such as <i>The Good Place, Upload, The Inbetween, Afterlife of the Party, Coco, Soul, Reaper, Elsewhere, If I Stay, and Boo Bitch </i>(to name but a few), focused on the afterlife, it seems timely to explore the messages promulgated in such texts about morality and/or religion. This is especially given media can prompt questioning and reasoning that aids self-reflection (Hawkins, 2001) and integrates people into an established order offering models of appropriate ways of being (Krijen &amp; Verboord, 2016).</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Therefore, this collection aims to explore representations of morality and/or religion in 21st-century popular cultural texts that feature and emphasize the afterlife. It asks how the afterlife is understood but moreover, how are people encouraged to live their lives? Such aims will inevitably consider what place (if any) religion has in shaping popular cultural texts and understandings of the beyond, and what perceptions of morality are favoured and guide character story arcs. Ultimately this edited collection will contribute to a continued and growing discussion on the representations of morality, religion, and the afterlife in contemporary society.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Possible topics might include, but are not limited to:</span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span>Moral motivation/reasoning and life after death</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Dichotomies of Heaven and Hell</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Representations of the ‘soul’</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Cultural differences in constructions of the afterlife</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Depictions/constructions of the spiritual realm</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Ghosts, the paranormal, and the afterlife</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Religious motifs in texts that feature the afterlife</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Representations of Supreme Being(s)</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Notions of suffering and reward in the afterlife</span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>Full articles are required by 13<sup>th</sup> October 2023 and are to be emailed to me or Justin Matthews directly</span></span></span></b><span><span><span>. Articles should be 5-6k words in length. More information about the AJPC in general can be found here:   </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><a href="https://www.intellectbooks.com/the-australasian-journal-of-popular-culture" rel="nofollow"><span>https://www.intellectbooks.com/the-australasian-journal-of-popular-culture</span></a> </span></span></span> </span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span>Associate Professor Angelique Nairn: <a href="mailto:angelique.nairn@aut.ac.nz">angelique.nairn@aut.ac.nz</a></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Senior Lecturer Justin Matthews: <a href="mailto:justin.matthews@aut.ac.nz">justin.matthews@aut.ac.nz</a></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Associate Professor Angelique Nairn: <a href="mailto:angelique.nairn@aut.ac.nz">angelique.nairn@aut.ac.nz</a></p><p>Senior Lecturer Justin Matthews: <a href="mailto:justin.matthews@aut.ac.nz">justin.matthews@aut.ac.nz</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:angelique.nairn@aut.ac.nz">angelique.nairn@aut.ac.nz</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 17:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1678858628272514</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for papers: The 65th Annual Conference of the Catholic Record Society</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12553961/call-papers-65th-annual-conference-catholic-record-society</link>
						<dc:creator>Helen  Kilburn</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-04-14T00:00:00-04:00">April 14, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>British History / Studies, Cultural History / Studies, World History / Studies, Social History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><h2>The Catholic Record Society 65th Annual Conference</h2><p>The Catholic Record Society (CRS) is delighted to issue a call for papers for the annual conference which will take place at Hinsley Hall, Leeds UK from Monday 24th July to Wednesday 26th July 2023.</p><p>A Zoom livestream of the conference will be made available but speakers are expected to attend in person unless otherwise agreed with the Conference Director.</p><p>The conference attracts leaders in the discipline of British and Irish Catholic Studies, including the field of British and Irish Catholic diaspora. The conference has a long-standing reputation as a friendly and supportive platform for graduate students and early career researchers especially and we actively encourage proposals from these scholars, as well as established scholars and independent researchers in the field.</p><p>Our keynote speakers are Professor John Morrill, (University of Cambridge), Dr Ayshah Johnston, (Black Cultural Archives), and Dr Jamie Callison, (University of Agder). Their paper titles are as follows:</p><ul><li>Professor Morrill: <em>New technologies, new perspectives: Interrogating Oliver Cromwell and Catholics</em></li><li>Dr Johnston: TBC on the topic of the role of women religious in the nineteenth-century Caribbean</li><li>Dr Callison: “Fools to the World”: Transatlantic Connections in the Twentieth-Century Arts and Crafts and Retreats Movements.</li></ul><p><strong>Call for papers</strong></p><p>The Council are pleased to invite proposals for papers in the following formats:</p><ul><li>Themed panels of three 20-minute papers. Please indicate the panel organiser.</li><li>Individual 20-minute papers.</li><li>Work-in-progress 10-minute papers.</li></ul><p>Selected papers may be considered for peer review and publication in the society journal, <em><a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/british-catholic-history" rel="nofollow">British Catholic History</a> </em>(Cambridge University Press).</p><p>Submissions should include a 300 word abstract and a short CV for each speaker and be sent to: <a href="mailto:conferences@crs.org.uk">conferences@crs.org.uk</a> by Friday 14th April 2023.  We are committed to running an accessible conference and speakers should expect to provide slide decks for delegates who require the use of assistive accessibility software. Speakers with accessibility needs are asked to provide details of how we can offer support in their submission.</p><p><strong>Conference attendance</strong></p><p>All speakers are expected to register for the conference and attend in person. As such speakers will be prioritised for bursaries if they have limited-to-no access to institutional funding. We offer a residential package and day rate package for delegates attending in person at a cost of £108 and £44 per person, per day respectively. We endeavour to keep prices as low as possible; for this reason registration prices cover costs set by the conference venue and a small contribution towards bursaries for attendees with limited-to-no access to institutional funding only.</p><p><strong>Bursaries</strong></p><p>We are delighted to offer a small number of bursaries to defray the cost of attendance at the conference for graduate students, early career researchers, and independent scholars with limited access to institutional funding. We will consider applications for fully-funded attendance but so that the Society can assist as many delegates as possible, we ask that applicants consider applying for part-funded attendance if they can obtain funding elsewhere.</p><p>To apply, please provide a brief account of your research, the amount of any funding already available to you, and the cost of your attendance including registration and travel expenses. Applications should be emailed to <a href="mailto:conferences@crs.org.uk">conferences@crs.org.uk</a>.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr Helen Kilburn, Conference Director</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:conferences@crs.org.uk">conferences@crs.org.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.crs.org.uk/conferences" target="_blank">https://www.crs.org.uk/conferences</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 17:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1678858628272513</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The 2023 Silber-Obrecht Lecture in Interreligious and Interfaith Studies with Francis X. Clooney, S.J.</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12553960/2023-silber-obrecht-lecture-interreligious-and-interfaith</link>
						<dc:creator>John Rivera</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-04-25T00:00:00-04:00">April 25, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-04-26T00:00:00-04:00">April 26, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Maryland</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Borderlands, Islamic History / Studies, Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, South Asian History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The inaugural Silber-Obrecht Lecture in Interreligious and Interfaith Studies, to be held from April 25-26, 2023 at Loyola University Maryland, will be delivered by <a href="https://projects.iq.harvard.edu/francisclooney" rel="nofollow">Francis X. Clooney, S.J.,</a> a theologian at the Harvard Divinity School and a leader in the field of <a href="https://hds.harvard.edu/news/2022/07/18/being-catholic-interreligiously" rel="nofollow">interreligious studies</a>.</p><p><a href="https://www.american.edu/cas/faculty/pathak.cfm" rel="nofollow">Shubha Pathak, Ph.D., Ph.D., </a>associate professor in the Department of Philosophy and Religion at American University in Washington D.C. will offer her response to Dr. Clooney’s lecture.</p><p>Both lectures are free and will be live streamed.</p><p>Lecture #1: "What is the State of the Emerging Field of Interreligious and Interfaith Studies?", with Francis X. Clooney, S.J., Tuesday, April 25, 2023, 7:00 PM – 8:30 PM EDT. Register for Zoom link: <a href="https://icjs.org/events/the-2023-silber-obrecht-lecture/" rel="nofollow">https://icjs.org/events/the-2023-silber-obrecht-lecture/</a></p><p>Lecture #2: "What is the Future of the Field?", with Francis X. Clooney, S.J. Response by Shubha Pathak, Ph.D., Ph.D. Wednesday, April 26, 2023, 4:00 PM – 7:00 PM EDT. Register for Zoom link: <a href="https://icjs.org/events/the-2023-silber-obrecht-lecture-2/" rel="nofollow">https://icjs.org/events/the-2023-silber-obrecht-lecture-2/</a></p><p>The Silber-Obrecht Lecture, the first endowed lectureship in the emerging field of Interreligious and Interfaith Studies, is a semiannual three-day academic residency in Baltimore. The lectureship aims to advance the field of study by presenting new and creative work by a senior scholar and interreligious practitioner. The endowed lecture, managed and sponsored by ICJS, is in partnership with five Baltimore educational institutions: Goucher College, the SNF Agora Institute at Johns Hopkins University, Loyola University Maryland, Morgan State University’s Center for Religion and Cities, and St. Mary’s Seminary &amp; University.</p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>John Rivera, Institute for Islamic, Chrsitian, and Jewish Studies</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:jrivera@icjs.org">jrivera@icjs.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://icjs.org/silber-obrecht-lecture/" target="_blank">https://icjs.org/silber-obrecht-lecture/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 17:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1678858628272512</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Summer Fellowship: Feinstein Center for American Jewish History, Temple University</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12553828/summer-fellowship-feinstein-center-american-jewish-history</link>
						<dc:creator>Ariella Werden-Greenfield</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Fellowship</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2024-03-31T00:00:00-04:00">March 31, 2024</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Pennsylvania</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>American History / Studies, Humanities, Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Social Sciences</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Temple University’s Feinstein Center for American Jewish History announces its annual summer fellowship to support research in the American Jewish experience. Predoctoral and postdoctoral scholars studying any area of American Jewish life are eligible for a grant of up to $4,000.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Applications for Feinstein’s 2023 summer fellowship should include a proposal of no more than five pages, a letter of recommendation, a CV, and a detailed budget of how funds will be used.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Materials are due by March 31, 2023. <br/>All application materials should be emailed to <a href="mailto:feinsteincenter@temple.edu"><span>feinsteincenter@temple.edu</span></a>. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>. . .</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><strong><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>2022 Fellows:</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></strong></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><b><i><span><span>Natalia Dubno Shevin</span></span></i></b><span><span>, PhD candidate at New York University</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><b><i><span><span>Uri Schreter</span></span></i></b><span><span>, PhD candidate at Harvard University</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:feinsteincenter@temple.edu">feinsteincenter@temple.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://liberalarts.temple.edu/research/labs-centers-and-institutes/feinstein-center-american-jewish-history/fellowships" target="_blank">https://liberalarts.temple.edu/research/labs-centers-and-institutes/feinstein-center-american-jewish-history/fellowships</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 17:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1678858628272511</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ April 27, 2023] Talk or similar: Book Launch of Anna Tomaszewska's &quot;Kant’s Rational Religion and the Radical Enlightenment</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/109125</link>
						<description>Venue: Grodzka 52<br/><br/>Speakers at this event: <br/>Anna Tomaszewska (Jagiellonian University)<br/>Stephen R. Palmquist (Hong Kong Baptist University)<br/>Diego Lucci (American University in Bulgaria)<br/>Wojciech Kozyra (University of Warsaw)<br/><br/><p>The team of the project "Between Secularization and Reform: Religious Rationalism in the Late 17th Century and in the Enlightenment" are pleased to invite you to a book launch of Anna Tomaszewska's "Kant's Rational Religion and the Radical Enlightenment. From Spinoza to Contemporary Debates" (Bloomsbury, 2022). </p>
<p>Tomaszewska challenges the view of Kant as attempting to merely reconcile faith and reason and reconceptualizes his religious thought along rationalist lines. By doing so, she opens up the possibility of understanding Kant in terms of the radical enlightenment originating with Spinoza rather than, as before, classifying him as a moderate enlightener.</p>
<p>The event consists of a presentation by the author, followed by three commentaries and a discussion. Commentators include Diego Lucci (American University in Bulgaria), Stephen Palmquist (Hong Kong Baptist University), and Wojciech Kozyra (University of Warsaw). </p>
<p>The hybrid event will take place on April 27th at 18:00 CET in Kraków, at Grodzka 52 Street, in room 5 at the Collegium Broscianum at the Institute of Religious Studies (Jagiellonian University). Registration is available online at the project website https://www.religiousrationalism.com/events</p>
<p>For more information concerning the book and the opportunity to purchase it at up to 20 % limited-time discount, visit https://www.bloomsbury.com/uk/kants-rational-religion-and-the-radical-enlightenment-9781350195844/.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 05:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1678772244083044</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>DEADLINE for ABSTRACTS EXTENDED TO  APRIL 15; Conference &quot;The social science of religion - Troeltsch, Weber, Simmel and others&quot; 1-2 June 2023</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12552843/deadline-abstracts-extended-april-15-conference-social-science</link>
						<dc:creator>Michal Warchala</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-01T00:00:00-04:00">June 1, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-02T00:00:00-04:00">June 2, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Poland</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>German History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Social Sciences, Sociology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span>CALL FOR PAPERS </span></span></p><p><span><span><i>The social science of religion: Troeltsch, Weber, Simmel and others</i></span></span></p><p><span><span>International Conference</span></span></p><p><span><span>June 1-2, 2023 Cracow, Poland </span></span></p><p><strong><span><span><span><span>Invited keynote speakers:</span></span></span></span></strong></p><p><span><span>Prof. Hans Joas (Humboldt-Universität)</span></span></p><p><span><span>Prof. Ulrich Schmiedel (Edinburgh University)  </span></span></p><p><span><span>Prof. Dominika Motak (Jagiellonian University)</span></span></p><p><span><span>The year 2023 sees the centenary of Ernst Troeltsch’s death. Finding this a good occasion to re-visit Troeltsch’s work together with its broader context the Chair for Sociology of Religion at the Pedagogical University of Cracow would like to invite for the international conference <i>The (social) science of religion: Troeltsch, Weber, Simmel and others</i>. The main idea of the conference is to acknowledge and re-consider Troeltsch’s (rarely appreciated) role within the “visionary company” of great social scientists dealing with religion in the early 20<sup>th</sup> century. What we attempt is broad and interdisciplinary reflection in which Troeltsch’s theological, philosophical and sociological approach together with the work of his contemporaries constitutes a point of departure. Submissions from sociologists, historians, theologians or philosophers are welcome. Different approaches to the main theme, both appreciative and critical, debates around heritage and questions of possible meanings that the “social science of religion” may have for (and in) our time – all this is of utmost interest to us. The list of possible topics includes:    </span></span></p><p><span><span><span>1) Troeltsch as a theologian and social scientist. Troeltsch has usually been treated as a theologian only while his contributions to social sciences or philosophy of religion have been overlooked or simply forgotten. But this is as much pigeonholing as treating Weber solely as a “classic of sociology”. In fact what both Troeltsch and Weber offer is a broad synthesis of theology, sociology, history and philosophy</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>2) </span></span></span><span><span><span>Troeltsch and his contemporaries – mutual inspirations and influences. Troeltsch has long been in the shadow of Weber and only recently was the importance of his work for social sciences and our reflection on modernity re-discovered. The same more or less can be said of Simmel.       </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>3) Troeltsch’s multidisciplinary “science of religion” among similar projects by Weber, Simmel Durkheim or James </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>4) Visions of modernity and secularization in the writings of Troeltsch, Max Weber, Georg Simmel, Émile Durkheim or William James: parallels and differences.      </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>5) Protestant Reformation in the writings of Troeltsch and Weber. The mutual influence of Troeltsch’s account of the birth of modernity out of the spirit of Protestantism and Weber’s theses about Reformation and capitalism is now indisputable. The question which may be asked today is which of these two accounts seem more relevant and inspiring from today’s perspective.  </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>6) Mutual interactions between theology and social sciences in Troeltsch and other representatives of the “science of religion”.</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>7) Religion, historical consciousness and the question of values in Troeltsch and in the social science of the early 20<sup>th</sup> century. </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>8) The question of “public function” and political responsibilities of both social science and theology according to Troeltsch, Weber, Simmel or James. </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><u>The conference will be held on 1-2 June 2023</u></b><b> </b>at the Pedagogical University of Cracow in Cracow, Poland. The precise venue will be announced later.  </span></span></p><p><span><span><u>Abstracts of max. 300 words</u> together with a short cv should be sent to: </span></span></p><p><span><span><b><a href="mailto:science.of.religion.conference@gmail.com">science.of.religion.conference@gmail.com</a></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><u>The deadline for abstracts is 15 April 2023</u></b><b>. </b>Authors will be notified of the acceptance of their submissions by <b>20</b> <b>April 2023</b>.  </span></span></p><p><span><span>Conference languages are English and Polish.</span></span></p><p><span><span><b><u>Fee options:</u></b></span></span></p><p><span><span>200 PLN/50 EUR – participation on-site </span></span></p><p><span><span>250 PLN/80 EUR – participation + lunches on June 1 and 2</span></span></p><p><span><span>300 PLN/100 EUR – participation + lunches + conference dinner on June 1</span></span></p><p><span><span>Abstract submitters are kindly asked to choose one of the options.  </span></span></p><p><span><span>All other costs, including transport and accommodation, should be covered separately by the participants. Cracow is a typical tourist city so there are plenty of accommodation options – the organizers will be happy to provide all necessary information but cannot make any bookings. </span></span></p><p><span><span>All queries concerning the conference should be addressed to the organizing committee at <b><a href="mailto:science.of.religion.conference@gmail.com">science.of.religion.conference@gmail.com</a></b>.  </span></span></p><p><span><span><u>Organizing committee:</u></span></span></p><p><span><span>Dr. Michał Warchala (chairman)                                                                  </span></span></p><p><span><span>Prof. Piotr Stawiński </span></span></p><p><span><span>Dr. Grzegorz Kubiński (conference secretary)</span></span></p><p><span><span>Dr. Maria Roginska </span></span></p><p><span><span>Dr. Bogdan Więckiewicz </span></span></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr. Michał Warchala </p><p>Pedagogical University of Cracow</p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:science.of.religion.conference@gmail.com">science.of.religion.conference@gmail.com</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 18:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1678772244083043</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Conference announcement: Accessibility, Archives, and Native American Boarding Schools: Pathways for Catholic History, March 24-25, 2023</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12537116/conference-announcement-accessibility-archives-and-native</link>
						<dc:creator>Patrick Hayes</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-24T00:00:00-04:00">March 24, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-25T00:00:00-04:00">March 25, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Arizona</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>American History / Studies, Archival Science, Childhood and Education, Native American History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>This two-day, hybrid conference brings together academic historians and archivists to discuss Native American Boarding Schools and the recorded legacy of the Catholic Church in their operation, roughly from 1819 to 1969. The conference is sponsored by the American Catholic Historical Association and is funded through the ACHA’s SHARP grant—a one-year project designed to place historians, archivists, and members of Native communities in conversation and collaboration.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Attendees at this two-day conference will hear from ten invited participants who were selected to present on their current or past work and the overarching theme of accessibility—to Catholic archival repositories, to new knowledge or understandings, to new issues affecting tribal histories, especially in relation to the Church, and so forth. They will present formal papers of 20 minutes in duration followed by questions and comments from the audience, both on-site and online. Over the course of two days, three contemplated sessions of an hour and a half each, plus another group round table will give closure to our conference. Registration details, along with the full program, may be found here:</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><a href="http://www.achahistory.org/sharp2023" rel="nofollow">www.achahistory.org/sharp2023</a></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Please save the dates: March 24-25, 2023. For further information, please contact the ACHA grant coordinator, Dr. Patrick Hayes (<a href="mailto:pjhayesphd@gmail.com">pjhayesphd@gmail.com</a>).</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Patrick Hayes, Ph.D.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Redemptorist Archives</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Philadelphia, PA</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Patrick Hayes</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:pjhayesphd@gmail.com">pjhayesphd@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="http://www.achahistory.org/sharp2023" target="_blank">http://www.achahistory.org/sharp2023</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 17:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1678772244083042</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
