<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 12:24:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 12:24:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>Mythology in Contemporary Culture at National Conference of PCA</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/11/23/mythology-in-contemporary-culture-at-national-conference-of-pca</link>
						<dc:creator>earth2k8@mac.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Sunday, November 27, 2022 - 3:45pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Popular Culture Association</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:earth2k8@mac.com">earth2k8@mac.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/film-and-television">film and television</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/popular-culture">popular culture</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>December 20, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p align="center"><strong>Mythology in Contemporary Culture </strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>Popular Culture Association National Conference</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>April 5-9, 2023</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>San Antonio Marriott Rivercenter, San Antonio, Texas</strong></p>
<p>The Mythology in Contemporary Culture area is dedicated to exploring mythological stories, figures and themes from all cultures and historical periods in all areas of popular culture. The frequent appearance of mythological motifs in popular culture speaks to the notion that mythologies, far from being relics of the past, continue to have significance. Contemporary revisionings and reinterpretations of mythological elements reflect the attitudes of current culture. Movies, television, computer games, comics, graphic novels, traditional literature, visual arts, performing arts, politics, blogs—the list goes on–-hold both explicit and implicit renderings of archetypes such as Thor and Athena and Kali, and of mythological narratives such as those found in bodies of sacred literature, classical Greek tragedies, and medieval Grail legends, to name only a few examples.</p>
<p>Proposals that pertain to the general theme of Mythology in Contemporary Culture are welcome. Potential presenters seeking inspiration for a paper topic might reflect on the mythological aspects of the Covid-19 pandemic or recent changes in governments around the world or about the many “-isms” that underlie discrimination of all kinds.</p>
<p>We will consider proposals for individual papers and/or panels organized around a theme. Sessions are 90 minutes, typically with four presenters per session.  Presentations should not exceed 15 minutes. </p>
<p>All submissions must be made through the conference submission site <a href="http://conference/">http://conference</a>. pcaaca.org. Potential presenters must be current, paid, members of the PCA to submit proposals for the conference.</p>
<p>For individual papers, please submit a title and 100-250 word abstract.  For themed paper sessions, each presenter should enter their own proposal; the chair should contact Dr. Rittenhouse with the title of the panel and the names of the presenters.</p>
<p>Questions about the <strong>Mythology in Contemporary Culture </strong>area may be directed to the Area Chairs:</p>
<p>Kate Rittenhouse  <a href="mailto:earth2k8@mac.com">earth2k8@mac.com</a></p>
<p>Lol Fow  <a href="mailto:efow@bmcc.cuny.edu">efow@bmcc.cuny.edu</a></p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 01:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1669607975235101</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Contemplative Practice and Writing about Race - ALA 2023</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/11/23/contemplative-practice-and-writing-about-race-ala-2023</link>
						<dc:creator>Andrew Ball</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Sunday, November 27, 2022 - 6:03pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>American Religion and Literature Society</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:bedelapiedra@gmail.com">bedelapiedra@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/african-american">african-american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/poetry">poetry</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>January 6, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Contemplative Practice and Writing about Race</p>
<p>The American Religion and Literature Society (ARLS) invites papers for a panel at the 2023 American Literature Association Conference, May 25-28, 2023 in Boston. </p>
<p>More than three decades into the writing of his long-anticipated Hickman Novel, Ralph Ellison told an interviewer that the book’s composition represented his effort to achieve “a pause for contemplation of the moral significance of the history we’ve been through.” Taking Ellison’s words as inspiration, this panel will seek to generate a wide-ranging exploration of the ways in which contemplative practices of all kinds have helped American authors of different backgrounds depict, illuminate, and transform racial experience, consciousness, structures, and history. What role does reflection on the human self’s nature, situatedness, antecedents, and interconnectedness play in the writer's struggle against racism? How have authors from different positionalities mobilized their search for increased awareness of divinity to reimagine racial identities, scripts, and relationships? What challenges do they face? What guidance does American literature—drawing on a host of widsom traditions, and perhaps even secular forms of mindfulness and meditation—offer the spiritual aspect of readers' anti-racist work?</p>
<p>Please submit an abstract and short bio to Benji de la Piedra (<a href="mailto:bedelapiedra@gmail.com">bedelapiedra@gmail.com</a>) by January 6, 2023.</p>
<p> </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 17:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1669607975235100</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Extended deadline:  Marilynne Robinson Society</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/11/21/extended-deadline-marilynne-robinson-society</link>
						<dc:creator>hapark1@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Sunday, November 27, 2022 - 3:23pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>American Literature Association Conference (ALA); Boston, MA; May 25-28, 2023</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:haein.park@biola.edu">haein.park@biola.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/twentieth-century-and-beyond">twentieth century and beyond</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>January 6, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>The Marilynne Robinson Society will be hosting a panel on a wide variety of topics connected to Robinson’s essays and novels at the annual conference of the American Literature Association.</p>
<p>The conference will take place in Boston, MA, May 25-28, 2023. </p>
<p>Please submit a 350-word proposal and short bio to <a href="mailto:haein.park@biola.edu">haein.park@biola.edu</a> by Friday, January 6, 2023.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 22:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1669607975235099</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Extended deadline: Marilynne Robinson, Jesus and John Wayne, and the American Evangelical Tradition</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/11/21/extended-deadline-marilynne-robinson-jesus-and-john-wayne-and-the-american</link>
						<dc:creator>hapark1@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Sunday, November 27, 2022 - 3:23pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>American Literature Association Conference (ALA); Boston, MA</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:haein.park@biola.edu">haein.park@biola.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/twentieth-century-and-beyond">twentieth century and beyond</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>January 6, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>The Marilynne Robinson Society and the American Religion and Literature Society (ARLS) will hold a joint panel at the annual American Literature Association Conference (May 25-28, 2022; Boston, MA).  We are seeking papers that examine the author’s relationship to American evangelicalism.  Robinson’s spiritual vision has been shaped by the writings of Jonathan Edwards, who is considered to be the founding father of American evangelicalism.  How does Robinson’s body of work lead us to think critically about the evangelical tradition in the United States?  How do her essays and novels, particularly <em>Gilead</em>, provide a counter-narrative to the discourses found in modern and contemporary American evangelicalism?  In what ways can they respond to the incisive diagnosis presented by Kristen Du Mez’s recent book, <em>Jesus and John Wayne</em>, a text that examines the connection between American evangelicalism, Christian nationalism, rugged masculinity, and political power? How might Robinson’s novels and essays in conversation with Du Mez’s <em>Jesus and John Wayne </em>illuminate our understanding of the evangelical tradition in the United States?  These are some of the questions that the panel seeks to address.
</p><p>Please submit a 350-word paper proposal and short bio to both <a href="mailto:haein.park@biola.edu" target="_blank">haein.park@biola.edu</a> and <a href="mailto:kludwig@bsu.edu" target="_blank">kludwig@bsu.edu</a> by January 6, 2023.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 22:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1669607975235098</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Negation</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/11/20/negation</link>
						<dc:creator>shornoh</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Sunday, November 27, 2022 - 3:09pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Brown University Department of German Studies</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:negation@brown.edu">negation@brown.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/classical-studies">classical studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/graduate-conferences">graduate conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/theory">theory</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>November 30, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Negation | Call for papers<br/>Graduate student conference, dept. of German Studies, Brown University | Feb. 17 &amp; 18, 2023 | in person</p>
<p>What “no” does, is not nothing. This proposition implies that we have understood what it is to say no, that its effects are predictable, and that it is involved with “doing,” with “being,” and with “things.” It also asks us to answer the question: what is “not-no,” and what is “yes”? Negation is not only not- positing, but, depending on the thinker, it is the engine of history, the enigma of the will, the guarantor or violator of being, the weapon of oppression, the foothold of theology, the urgent task of language.</p>
<p>We may provisionally qualify negation as abstraction from what is, or that which undoes any premise, posited thing, circumstance, or condition of existence. Yet we must also ask: can negation only be negatively given – what it is not, what it does not do – or can it itself be posited? can it avoid positing what it, in semblance, negates? That is to say: is negation contrary to position?</p>
<p>Further questions for exploration might include:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>–  What kinds of negation are there, and what, if anything, keeps them apart?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>–  What can negation do and undo? and what remains in the space of its ne plus ultra?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>–  What is non-being? Does it have being?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>–  Is there a ‘not’ that does not posit? (Or: a ‘not’ that posits ‘not’ not?)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>–  What kind of thing is nothing?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>–  In light of the Kantian separation between nihil privativum and nihil negativum, what kinds of</p>
<p>negation might, or might not, participate in what is?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>–  ¬¬P⇒P?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>–  What incisions do the smallest blades make – no, not, never, none, non-, -less, un-, a-, anti-,</p>
<p>dis-, in-, s-, k-, é- – ?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>–  What is the relation between negativity and difference? (sexual, racial, special, essential)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>–  What may be, beyond and before the letter, the negative relation between the apophantic and</p>
<p>apophatic?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>–  The question of negative theology, especially in its effects on the Bonaventurian itinerary – the</p>
<p>question, in other words, of the wayless way, “non”-way, or Holzweg.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>We invite papers that specifically detail how negation appears in works of literature, other media, or thought. Annihilation, removal, join, subsumption, substraction, disappearance, oblivion, forgetting, and stubbornness are zones of special interest.
</p><p>Writing often under a certain threat of negation, whether from inside or from without, the following writers, among many others, offer possible sites of citation that challenge and invite negation’s problems (and non-problems – or better, what has not yet been posited as “problem”): S. Beckett, G. Bruno, P. Celan, Duns Scotus, Eckhart, Hegel, Heidegger, Kant, Kristeva, Lacan, C. Lispector, A. Lorde, Marx, J.-L. Nancy, Nietzsche, J. Ortega y Gasset, Parmenides, Philo, Plato, Pseudo-Dionysius, Shakespeare, S. Sontag, M. de Unamuno, S. Weil, and U. Zürn.</p>
<p>Please send brief abstracts (250 words) to <a href="mailto:negation@brown.edu">negation@brown.edu</a>, along with a few lines of biography, by 30 November. Organized by Simon Horn, Ethan Lussky, and Jasmin Meier.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 18:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1669607975235097</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>200 Years of Johnson v. M’Intosh: Law, Religion, and Native American Lands</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/11/18/200-years-of-johnson-v-m%E2%80%99intosh-law-religion-and-native-american-lands</link>
						<dc:creator>adam@adamdjbrett.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Sunday, November 27, 2022 - 3:20pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Indigenous Values Initiative</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:info@indigenousvalues.org">info@indigenousvalues.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/rhetoric-and-composition">rhetoric and composition</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>January 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p> 
</p><p><a href="https://canopyforum.org/current-calls-for-submission/#submission-form">Submit by 1/15/2023</a></p>
<p>The Center for the Study of Law and Religion (CSLR) at Emory University, in partnership with the Indigenous Values Initiative (IVI), Syracuse University, and <em>Canopy Forum</em>, seeks short articles and multimedia submissions marking the 200th Anniversary of <em>Johnson v. M’Intosh,</em> 21 U.S. 543 (1823).</p>
<p>In its landmark <a><em>Johnson v. M’Intosh</em></a> decision, the U.S. Supreme Court reiterated a principle that was previously established in the Non-Intercourse Act of 1790, namely, that private citizens could not purchase lands from Native American Nations. As Chief Justice John Marshall’s opinion explained: “discovery gave title to government…[and] the sole right of acquiring the soil from the natives.”</p>
<p>Marshall’s allusion to the “Doctrine of Discovery” invoked a medieval theology of conquest, and a legacy of global exploitation, genocide, slavery, and despoliation. Originally formulated by the Papal curia, the doctrine espoused the inequality of Christians and non-Christians, and provided a basis for Euro-American hegemony and the domination of Indigenous Peoples and the land.</p>
<p>The <em>Johnson v. M’Intosh </em>holding adapted this doctrine into American legal practice, namely as a device by which the United States’ government could claim superior title to the land of North America, and reduce Indigenous ownership—with its legal, religious, cultural, and economic dimensions—to a mutable and dissolvable “aboriginal” or “Indian” title. The Doctrine as articulated by Marshall would become a foundational principle not only of U.S. property law and Federal Indian Law – cited favorably by the US Supreme Court as recently as the 2005 case of <em>City of Sherrill v. Oneida Indian Nation</em> – but also of Manifest Destiny and colonial expansion to the Pacific Ocean.</p>
<p>The year 2023 marks the 200th anniversary of <em>Johnson v. M’Intosh</em>. With the approach of this significant date, <em>Canopy Forum</em> invites short articles and multimedia presentations analyzing the impacts of the Doctrine of Discovery and/or <em>Johnson v. M’intosh </em>in U.S. law and international contexts. We further invite informed reflections on alternative ecologies, spiritualities, legal principles, and socio-economic systems articulated <a>in light of</a> the Doctrine’s history and legacy. Submissions may address questions such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>What is the legacy of <em>Johnson v. M’Intosh </em>in U.S. property law, Federal Indian law, and/or other areas of law?</li>
<li>What is the broader history of the “Doctrine of Discovery” in religious or political thought and practice?</li>
<li>To what extent is <em>Johnson v. M’Intosh</em> still “good law” in the Supreme Court’s recent jurisprudence?</li>
<li>How did/does the decision influence or reverberate in international, environmental, and/or property law?</li>
<li>How did <em>Johnson v. M’Intosh</em> influence the legal discourse of coloniality adopted by other jurisdictions in the Anglosphere?</li>
<li>To what extent, if any, does the Doctrine remain part of contemporary politics and popular culture?</li>
<li>What influence, if any, has the Doctrine had on American foreign policy over the last 200 years?</li>
<li>Submissions on other topics/questions are also welcome.</li>
</ul>
<p>Submissions that are received before January 15, 2023 are strongly preferred. Instructions and guidelines for written and multimedia submissions can be found <a href="https://canopyforum.org/submit/">here</a>.</p>
<p><strong>A methodological note from the Indigenous Values Initiative</strong></p>
<p>The Gä•sweñta’ (Two Row Wampum belt) is the earliest treaty between the Haudenosaunee Confederacy and the settler-colonists of Europe. The wampum belt is comprised of two purple rows of wampum beads running parallel with each other. The Haudenosaunee in their canoe and the Dutch in their boat would each travel down the river of life side by side with one another without interfering with one another. Sadly, the settler-colonial governments never understood that what links us all together is that our diversity of identities stems from being in proper relationship with the land. Therefore, a destructive wedge has undermined upholding this first treaty. We use the principles of the Two Row Wampum as a central organizing principle for this call for papers. We invite Indigenous and non-indigenous submissions.</p>
<p>The Indigenous Values Initiative’s “200 Years of Johnson v. McIntosh” project is supported by the <a href="https://www.hluce.org/grants/grants/200-years-of-johnson-v-mcintosh-indigenous-responses-to-the-religious-foundations-of-racism/">Henry Luce Foundation</a> and <a href="https://www.syracuse.edu/">Syracuse University</a>. Learn more at <a href="https://indigenousvalues.org/">https://indigenousvalues.org/</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><a href="https://canopyforum.org/submit/"><strong>Submit</strong></a>
</p><p><strong> </strong></p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 17:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1669607975235096</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New approaches to the mind in the early North</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/11/18/new-approaches-to-the-mind-in-the-early-north</link>
						<dc:creator>themindinthenorth</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Sunday, November 27, 2022 - 3:19pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Felix Lummer and Declan Taggart, University of Iceland</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:themindinthenorth@gmail.com">themindinthenorth@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/international-conferences">international conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/medieval">medieval</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/theory">theory</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>January 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>New approaches to the mind in the early North</strong></p>
<p>Date: 11th–12th May 2023</p>
<p><strong>Location:</strong> University of Iceland, Reykjavík, Iceland</p>
<p><strong>Keynote speakers: </strong>Prof. Sif Ríkharðsdóttir (Háskóli Íslands); Dr Stefka Georgieva Eriksen (Norsk institutt for kulturminneforsknings)</p>
<p>We are pleased to invite submissions to the two-day conference ‘New approaches to the mind in the early North’ from researchers exploring new approaches to the mind in the early history of the Nordic countries (400 CE to 1100 CE).</p>
<p>No historical source exists free of interpretation. Explaining past behaviours means considering the beliefs, motivations, desires, feelings and thoughts behind those behaviours, and so scholars necessarily hypothesize about the minds of both the creators of their sources and the people described within them. </p>
<p>Often the act of interpretation is guided by the investigator’s intuitions and assumptions. This can be done with success, yet is there a way to make the process of reasoning more secure by better understanding how the early Nordic mind itself operates? And can the study of past minds support research in the social sciences on the mind in the present day?</p>
<p>The organizers of this conference are especially interested in interdisciplinary approaches to the mind, incorporating theories from fields such as the cognitive sciences, psychology and anthropology. However, we are conscious that a wide range of approaches can be taken to this subject and would be open to other contributions. These might explore, for example: </p>
<ul>
<li>Differing gender and class valuations of the mind;</li>
<li>Differentiation between the mind and brain (and/or body);</li>
<li>Metaphorical conceptualizations of the mind or the brain; </li>
<li>Perceptions of intellect or emotion;</li>
<li>Mental illness and its treatment;</li>
<li>Interaction between mind and environment.</li>
</ul>
<p>Great progress has recently been made in Old Norse studies towards understanding the early medieval mind, particularly in research areas related to emotion and memory, and the goal of this conference is to extend that progress even further. We also hope to provide a limited bursary for travel for junior scholars (PG and ECR) to Iceland, though that is dependent on the level of external funding that can be achieved.</p>
<p><strong>General information:</strong> Presentations will be 20 minutes long and followed by a 10-minute discussion. There will be no registration fees. We hope to be able to hold the conference completely in-person but will make preparations in case this becomes impossible.</p>
<p>Please send your abstracts of ca. 200 words to Felix Lummer or Declan Taggart at <a href="mailto:themindinthenorth@gmail.com">themindinthenorth@gmail.com</a> by 15th January 2023.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 15:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1669607975235095</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Reminder: Special Issue on Memories of Antiquity</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/11/18/reminder-special-issue-on-memories-of-antiquity</link>
						<dc:creator>DrMadeleineScherer</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Sunday, November 27, 2022 - 3:05pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Memories of Antiquity Research Group </div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:memories.of.antiquity@gmail.com">memories.of.antiquity@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/classical-studies">classical studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/popular-culture">popular culture</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>December 1, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Special Issue on Memories of Antiquity  deadline for submissions: December 1, 2022 full name / name of organization: Memories of Antiquity Research Group (in affiliation with the Memory Studies Association at <a href="https://www.memorystudiesassociation.org/">https://www.memorystudiesassociation.org</a>)  contact email: <a href="mailto:memories.of.antiquity@gmail.com">memories.of.antiquity@gmail.com</a> 
</p><p><strong>CFP: Special Issue on Memories of Antiquity </strong></p>
<p>We invite prospective contributions for a special journal issue centred around modes of remembering antiquity (including the reception of ancient Greece, Rome, Egypt, the Near East, and other cultural contexts). </p>
<p>While the study of antiquity and its reception has always been a subject of scholarship, there still exists relatively little theoretical work on the ways in which reception operates in practice. In the West, classical works, images, narratives and characters have an extremely long- and wide-ranging diachronic and synchronic reception history, which should be approached with a set of tools that does not lose track of the ways in which reception histories shift with the times – with the meanings that are created anew at each point of reception, to paraphrase Charles Martindale’s well-known dichtum from <em>Redeeming the Text</em>: <em>Latin Poetry and the Hermeneutics of Reception</em> (1993).  </p>
<p>Both within and outside of the academy we are currently witnessing a growing interest in antiquity and its reception, evidenced both by the growth of Reception Studies as a discipline as well as the exploding catalogue of works in popular culture that engage with (especially Graeco-Roman) antiquity. Antiquity is everywhere – from the books in various university libraries, to the bestseller lists at Waterstones, to our TV screens and even gaming consoles. They are so prominent, and have been for such a long time that, as Astrid Erll already outlined in 2018, ‘[c]lassical receptions are essentially a form of cultural memory. There is a great and as yet largely untapped potential for a dialogue between the two fields’ (‘Homer: A relational mnemonhistory’, Memory Studies, p.283).</p>
<p>This special issue aims to get this dialogue started by approaching the study of classical reception through the lens of memory. We are not limiting the time periods or locations we are considering. Instead, we are interested in collecting a set of case wide-ranging studies that understand antiquity as a set of cultural memories, to explore the ways in which reception operates when considering the longue durée histories of classical myths, figures, and narratives. <br/> </p>
<p>We are particularly interested in the following areas of scholarship:</p>
<ul>
<li>Classical Reception Studies </li>
<li>Longue durée reception histories</li>
<li>Memory Studies</li>
<li>Egyptology</li>
<li>Biblical Studies </li>
<li>Ancient Near Eastern Studies </li>
<li>World literature</li>
<li>Contemporary culture and literature </li>
<li>National and Transnational histories</li>
</ul>
<p>We hope to collaborate with a range of scholars whose work is preoccupied with modes of remembrance (narrative <em>topoi</em>, memoryscapes, archaeologies of remembrance, travelling memory, oral memory, lieux de mémoire, etc.). We welcome traditional academic journal articles for a special issue that we are aiming at the Memory Studies Journal, which is affiliated with the Memory Studies Association that our research collective is part of.  (<a href="https://www.memorystudiesassociation.org/">https://www.memorystudiesassociation.org</a>)</p>
<p>If this project interests you, we ask that you submit an abstract of 250-400 words with a provisional title via email to <a href="mailto:memories.of.antiquity@gmail.com">memories.of.antiquity@gmail.com</a> by <strong>December 1, 2022</strong>.</p>
<p>Please don’t hesitate to reach out with questions or comments.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Prospective editors: </p>
<p>Madeleine Scherer; University of Warwick and University Centre Askham Bryan</p>
<p>Relevant publications: <br/><em>Classical Memories: The Underworld in the Twentieth Century</em> (DeGruyter, 2021) </p>
<p><em>A Quest for Remembrance: The Underworld in Classical and Modern Literature </em>(Routledge, 2020)</p>
<p>Jakob Schneider; Humboldt University  </p>
<p>‘Tiefe Brunnen und kein Ende: Notizen zur Rezeption und Wandlung der Gedächtnistheorie’(<em>Aegyptiaca - Journal of the History of Reception of Ancient Egypt</em>, 2020)</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 14:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1669607975235094</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Non-Cloistered Religious Women and Rome at the Aftermath of the Council of Trent. Journey in Archives (ISHWRA)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11813088/non-cloistered-religious-women-and-rome-aftermath-council</link>
						<dc:creator>Sarah Barthélemy</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Seminar</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-25T00:00:00-05:00">November 25, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Belgium</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Early Modern History and Period Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Cultural History / Studies, Italian History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>This coming Friday, 25 November at 4pm, we’ll be hosting in Brussels (Université Saint-Louis Bruxelles - room P30) this month’s ISHWRA seminar, when we’ll be joined by Dr Isabel Harvey (UCLouvain / GEMCA).</p><p>Recent historiography about non-cloistered religious women is based above all on the punctual luck of archives, as the wealth of an Inquisition trial or an autobiography, or on notarial institutional documentation of mainly economic nature. This documentation allows to reconstruct interesting cases, to contextualize them, but it is difficult to move away from the exceptionality of a person, a situation, or an institution rich enough to accumulate a number of notarial archives. I propose to look at another archive, the voluminous documentation of the Congregation of Bishops and Regulars, which will allow us to identify and hear the voices of others, those non-cloistered religious women who are considered neither saints nor heretics, and who did not live in a wealthy community in a large urban center. This presentation will detail the archival and methodological path to identify them and to gather information about their singular existences and experiences.</p><p>D﻿r Isabel Harvey is FNRS postdoctoral fellow at the Université catholique de Louvain.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><strong>T﻿his hybrid event will take place online and at Université Saint-Louis Bruxelles, 43 Boulevard du Jardin Botanique, Bruxelles, 1000 (room P30).</strong></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:sarah.barthelemy@durham.co.uk">sarah.barthelemy@durham.co.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/ishwra-seminar-november-2022-tickets-438918977477" target="_blank">https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/ishwra-seminar-november-2022-tickets-438918977477</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1669185431787870</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
