<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 20:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 20:01:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>DOUBTING PAUL: THE LEGACY OF THE DUTCH R 2023 : Call For Papers - DOUBTING PAUL: THE LEGACY OF THE DUTCH RADICAL SCHOOL </title>
			<link>http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=175129&amp;copyownerid=173363</link>
						<description>Call For Papers - DOUBTING PAUL: THE LEGACY OF THE DUTCH RADICAL SCHOOL </description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 05:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1688103429468868</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Episcopal Prayer Book Revision Special Issue Available to Public</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12887243/episcopal-prayer-book-revision-special-issue-available-public</link>
						<dc:creator>Matthew Payne</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Journal</div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The Historical Society of the Episcopal Church is pleased to make its special issue on Prayer Book revision available to the church and the public. <em><a href="https://hsec.us/AEH" rel="nofollow">Anglican and Episcopal History</a></em> is a quarterly, peer-reviewed journal published since 1932.</p><p>Readers can enjoy 5 peer-reviewed essays, 2 church reviews, and 22 book reviews. The June issue of <em>AEH</em> is also the first to include “Engaged History,” a new feature examining ways Anglican and Episcopal communities are encountering once buried history.</p><p>Prayer book studies include:</p><ul><li> “Remembering Our Baptism: Memoir of a Continuing Project” by <strong>William H. Petersen</strong>. The emeritus dean of Bexley Hall Seminary examines the “sea-change” related to the liturgy and theology of Baptism that occurred between 1949 and 1979 while pondering ways lessons learned during earlier eras of liturgical renewal might influence work today.</li><li><strong>Sylvia A. Sweeney</strong>, contributing editor of this issue is also professor of liturgics and homiletics at Bloy House in Los Angeles. She explores the understudied role of second wave feminism during development and ratification of the 1979 Book of Common Prayer in an essay titled “The Role of the 20<sup>th</sup> Century Women’s Movement in Liturgical Renewal in the Episcopal Church.”</li><li><strong>Juan M.C. Oliver</strong>, Custodian of the Book of Common Prayer between 2015 and 2022, outlines challenges Anglicans face and suggests standards to consider when translating liturgical materials in “Liturgical Translations in the Episcopal Church.”</li><li>“The History of Liturgical Revision in the Church of England and Its Implications for The Episcopal Church” by <strong>Shawn Strout</strong>, assistant professor of worship and associate dean of chapel at Virginia Theological Seminary, contextualizes ways proposed changes to redefine the prayer book in Article X of the Constitution of the Episcopal Church mirrors earlier moves in the Church of England.</li><li>The final study offers 8 guiding principles to counter anti-Judaism in liturgy and worship. The essay titled “Talking About Jews: Principles, Problems, and Proposals for Prayer Book Revision” is written by <strong>Daniel Joslyn-Siemiatkoski</strong>, an Episcopal priest and the Kraft Family Professor and Director of the Center for Christian-Jewish Learning at Boston College.</li></ul><p>In addition to these 5 peer-reviewed essays, church reviews take readers to a Sunday worship service at St. Paul’s, Clifton, in the Church of England’s Diocese of Bristol and to an ecumenical retreat of Lutherans, Anglicans, and Roman Catholics in northern Michigan.</p><p>This issue of <em>AEH</em> launches the journal’s new “engaged history” feature. Engaged History refers to collaborative projects undertaken by Anglican and Episcopal institutions that confront buried historical narratives. <strong>Robert Black</strong> illustrates ways St. Luke’s Episcopal Parish in Salisbury, North Carolina, has engaged with the legacy of race and racism as a barrier to Christian mission. This includes commissioning a new Pentecost icon to better illustrate the Beloved Community “…as it includes people of different shapes, sizes, ages, genders, races, and abilities all gathered around a table and receiving the gift of the Spirit.”</p><p>As always, readers enjoy a treasure trove of book reviews related to church history and Anglican scholarship, including:</p><ul><li><em>Privilege and Prophecy: Social Activism in the Post War Episcopal Church</em> by Robert Tobin | Reviewed by John L. Kater of Church Divinity School of the Pacific</li><li><em>The Book of Common Prayer: A Guide</em> by Charles Hefling | Reviewed by Sean Otto of the Anglican Diocese of Quebec</li><li><em>Mother Earth, Postcolonial and Liberation Theologies</em> edited by Sophia Chirongoma and Esther Mombo | Reviewed by Carla E. Roland Guzmán of General Theological Seminary</li><li><em>Iris Murdoch and Others: A Writer in Dialogue with Theology</em> by Paul S. Fiddes | Reviewed by Molly James of The Episcopal Church Center</li></ul><p><em>Anglican and Episcopal History</em> is published quarterly in March, June, September, and December. Full text articles are available through JSTOR.org and for members of the Historical Society of the Episcopal Church at <a href="https://hsec.us/AEH" rel="nofollow">hsec.us/AEH</a>.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><span><span><span><span><b>Matthew P. Payne,</b></span><span> </span><i>Director of Operations</i></span></span></span><br/><span><span><b><span><span><span>Historical Society of the Episcopal Church (HSEC)</span></span></span></b></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span>PO Box 1301, Appleton, WI 54912-1301 | ​(920) 383-1910</span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:administration@hsec.us">administration@hsec.us</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="http://hsec.us/aeh" target="_blank">http://hsec.us/aeh</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 19:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1688103429468867</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for applications for 2024 CRTA (Chinese Religious Text Authority) workshop in Paris</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12886991/call-applications-2024-crta-chinese-religious-text-authority</link>
						<dc:creator>Campo Daniela</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Workshop</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2024-01-04T00:00:00-05:00">January 4, 2024</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2024-01-07T00:00:00-05:00">January 7, 2024</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>France</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Asian History / Studies, Chinese History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><div><div><div><div><div><div><div><p><span><span>Dear friends and colleagues, </span></span></p><p><span><span>Please find below the link to the call for applications to the next CRTA (Chinese Religious Text Authority) workshop on reading late imperial and Republican Chinese religious texts, which will take place in Paris on January 4-7, 2024:</span></span></p><p><span><span><a href="https://frogbear.org/chinese-religious-texts-authority-crta-workshop/" rel="nofollow">https://frogbear.org/chinese-religious-texts-authority-crta-workshop/</a></span></span></p><p><span><span>Best regards, </span></span></p><p><span><span>The CRTA project</span></span></p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 19:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1688017036014091</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Papers for Early Career Scholars: “Islamic Tradition at the End of Late Antiquity: New Perspectives on Hadith, History, and Historiography”</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12886886/call-papers-early-career-scholars-%E2%80%9Cislamic-tradition-end-late</link>
						<dc:creator>Ana Davitashvili</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-07-31T00:00:00-04:00">July 31, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Germany</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Islamic History / Studies, Middle East History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Call for Papers for Early Career Scholars: “Islamic Tradition at the End of Late Antiquity: New Perspectives on Hadith, History, and Historiography” </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The ERC project “The Qurʾan as a Source for Late Antiquity” (QaSLA) has opened its call for papers for the conference <b>Islamic Tradition at the End of Late Antiquity: New Perspectives on Hadith, History, and Historiography, </b>to be held in <b>Tübingen, Germany, from July 8–10, 2024. </b></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The three-day conference aims at attracting contributions to the scholarly discourse on Islamic tradition and the late antique milieu, particularly studies that pursue connections between the hadith<i> </i>literature, Islamicate historiography, and Jewish and Christian traditions from the period of Islam’s emergence. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The conference </span></span></span><span><span><span>is oriented towards exploring new connections between Islam and the late antique milieu, while shifting the emphasis to the hadith, broadly defined. Can the hadith<i> </i>prove to be a reliable source for historical inquiry into the 7<sup>th</sup> century, despite its codification in the 9<sup>th</sup> century? And, if so, can other genres of hadith convey insights that contradict or confirm the <i>tafsīr </i>tradition? How might different methodological approaches to the hadith<i> </i>and improved analytical techniques shed new light on the Qurʾan and its environment? And how is the hadith, if at all,<i> </i>a witness to the existence of and the specific cultural and religious impact of Jewish, Christian, or other communities in Arabia? </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>While we are particularly interested in scholarly contributions that engage with the preceding questions, we welcome other avenues of inquiry into the hadith, Islamic late antiquity, and the interaction of Jews, Christians, and (other) Arabian peoples in and around the 7<sup>th</sup> century CE. By way of example, themes to be addressed include:</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>1. </span></span></span><span><span><span><span>Methodological approaches to the study of Muslim traditions: hadith, <i>tafsīr</i>, and <i>akhbār</i></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>2. Judeo-Christian elements in hadith, such as the <i>isrāʾīliyyāt</i>, and other Islamic literature</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>3. Interactions between Islamic and other late antique legal and juridical ideas</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>4. Portrayals of Jews and Christians in Islamic tradition</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Travel and accommodation expenses in Tübingen for the duration of the research symposium will be covered by QaSLA.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>This call for papers invites <b>Early Career Researchers</b> (PhD candidates and within five years of the award of the PhD). It seeks to promote outstanding research of early career scholars and bring them in conversation with established scholars of Hadith Studies and Late Antiquity as well as historians of early Islam. </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Please note that all proposals must include:</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Author name and affiliation</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>C.V.</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Paper title</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>250-word paper abstract (written in English)</span></span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Abstract Due: July 31st, 2023</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>For questions and proposals contact: </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Ana Davitashvili: </span></span></span><a href="mailto:ana.davitashvili@uni-tuebingen.de"><span><span><span>ana.davitashvili@uni-tuebingen.de</span></span></span></a></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Raashid Goyal: </span></span></span><a href="mailto:raashid.goyal@uni-tuebingen.de"><span><span><span>raashid.goyal@uni-tuebingen.de</span></span></span></a></span></span></span></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>For questions and proposals contact: </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Ana Davitashvili: </span></span></span><a href="mailto:ana.davitashvili@uni-tuebingen.de"><span><span><span>ana.davitashvili@uni-tuebingen.de</span></span></span></a></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Raashid Goyal: </span></span></span><a href="mailto:raashid.goyal@uni-tuebingen.de"><span><span><span>raashid.goyal@uni-tuebingen.de</span></span></span></a></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ana.davitashvili@uni-tuebingen.de">ana.davitashvili@uni-tuebingen.de</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 19:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1688017036014090</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FEATURED JOB: SUNY Buffalo - History Faculty (open-rank) - History of Science, Health, or Disability, with a focus on Africa</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12886652/featured-job-suny-buffalo-history-faculty-open-rank-history</link>
						<dc:creator>System Administrator</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Home Office Notices (Jobs, Reviews)</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-27T00:00:00-04:00">June 27, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>New York</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>African History / Studies, Environmental History / Studies, History of Science, Medicine, and Technology, Religious Studies and Theology, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The <a href="https://arts-sciences.buffalo.edu/history.html" rel="nofollow"><strong>Department of History</strong></a> at the University at Buffalo, The State University of New York, invites applications for TWO open-rank, tenure-track positions in African History.One position is open to all fields and this second position prioritizes Science, Health, or Disability broadly conceived, including intersections with religion, environment, gender, sexuality, etc. Salary and compensation will be competitive, commensurate with rank and achievement. A strong scholarly record and commitment to teaching are expected.<br/><br/>This search is part of a cluster of interdisciplinary hires in areas prioritized for investment and expansion by university leadership. Successful candidates will join a collegial and energetic department that is already home to active programs in medical humanities, Disability Studies, histories of race, gender and sexuality, and histories of empire and religion.<br/><br/>UB History faculty members are dedicated researchers and teachers eager to work with students in introductory surveys, upper-level undergraduate courses, and graduate seminars. Standard duties for academic-year (10-month) faculty at UB, an R1 University and AAU member institution, include maintaining a strong research program; teaching two courses per semester, including undergraduate courses and graduate seminars; mentoring undergraduate and graduate students, including training graduate students and advising PhD dissertations; and providing service to the Department and University.<br/><br/>We seek a colleague whose teaching, research, and service have prepared them to contribute to the Department and University’s commitment to equity and the inclusion of diverse students and audiences in higher education. We are especially interested in a candidate with experience supporting and mentoring a diverse student body.<br/><br/>Review of applications will begin October 2, 2023.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Ndubueze Mbah: Chair, Search Committee</p><p>Email: <a href="mailto:ndubueze@buffalo.edu">ndubueze@buffalo.edu</a></p><p>Phone: 716-645-8415</p></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php" target="_blank">https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php?id=65520</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 19:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1688017036014089</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – June 28, 2023</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-june-28-2023/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find 20 new job opportunities, 4 Call for Papers, 3 upcoming conferences/speakers, and 2 other submissions/events.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 32!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Academic:</h4>



<h4>Senior Lecturer in Sociology</h4>



<p>Karlstad University, Sweden</p>



<p>Deadline: August 31, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://kau.varbi.com/en/what:job/jobID:628936/iframeEmbedded:0/where:4">Senior lecturer in Sociology (varbi.com)</a></p>



<h4>Instructor in History (Full-time)</h4>



<p>Oregon State University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: July 29, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://jobs.oregonstate.edu/postings/139102">Oregon State University Jobs Portal | Instructor</a></p>



<h4>Postdoctoral Researcher in History and Philosophy of Physics/Science (2 positions available, 4-5 year appointment, Full-time)</h4>



<p>Utrecht University, Netherlands</p>



<p>Deadline: July 6, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.uu.nl/en/organisation/working-at-utrecht-university/jobs/two-postdoc-positions-in-history-and-philosophy-of-physics-or-science-08-10-fte">Two postdoc positions in History and Philosophy of Physics or Science (0.8 – 1.0 FTE) – Working at Utrecht University – Utrecht University (uu.nl)</a></p>



<h4>Research Assistant (Full-time, 3 positions available)</h4>



<p>Temple University, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://temple.taleo.net/careersection/tu_ex_staff/jobdetail.ftl?job=23001348&amp;lang=en&amp;source=JB-10222">https://temple.taleo.net/careersection/tu_ex_staff/jobdetail.ftl?job=23001348&amp;lang=en&amp;source=JB-10222</a></p>



<h4>Academic &amp; Research Specialist (Full-time, Masters degree preferred)</h4>



<p>The University of Chicago, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://uchicago.wd5.myworkdayjobs.com/External/job/Chicago-IL/Academic-and-Research-Specialist_JR22491-1">https://uchicago.wd5.myworkdayjobs.com/External/job/Chicago-IL/Academic-and-Research-Specialist_JR22491-1</a></p>



<h4>Program Coordinator (Full-time)</h4>



<p>Arizona State University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: July 14, 2023</p>



<p>More information: <a href="https://sjobs.brassring.com/TGnewUI/Search/Home/Home?partnerid=25620&amp;siteid=5494#jobDetails=4778884_5494">Program Coordinator | Arizona State University (brassring.com)</a></p>



<h4>Minerva Recruitment Job Listings Cite (with areas specifically tailored for Ph.D.)</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://minerva-recruitment.com/">Minerva Recruitment – Higher Education Graduate Jobs, UK &amp; Worldwide (minerva-recruitment.com)</a></p>



<h4>AAR/SBL Job Forum</h4>



<p><a href="https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search">https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search</a></p>



<h4>Non-Academic:</h4>



<h4>Academic Outreach Liaison</h4>



<p>APHL, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers-aphl.icims.com/jobs/1394/academic-outreach-liaison---martinez%2C-california/job?iis=Social+Networks&amp;iieid=pt16871812813029aa0c&amp;mobile=false&amp;width=686&amp;height=500&amp;bga=true&amp;needsRedirect=false&amp;jan1offset=-360&amp;jun1offset=-300">Academic Outreach Liaison – Martinez, California in | Careers at Silver Spring preferred, but possibility of remote work (icims.com)</a></p>



<h4>Monitoring, Evaluation, Research, and Learning Coordinator</h4>



<p>Women for Women International, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.womenforwomen.org/en/postings/95761e3c-6ec3-47d8-9d56-3bf25536937c">https://careers.womenforwomen.org/en/postings/95761e3c-6ec3-47d8-9d56-3bf25536937c</a></p>



<h4>People and Culture Officer</h4>



<p>University of Nottingham, UK</p>



<p>Deadline: July 3, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://hotdailytrends.com/2023/06/21/people-and-culture-officer/">https://hotdailytrends.com/2023/06/21/people-and-culture-officer/</a></p>



<h4>Research and Learning Coordinator</h4>



<p>Actions Against Hunger, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.actionagainsthunger.org/index.php/positions/view/652/">https://careers.actionagainsthunger.org/index.php/positions/view/652/</a></p>



<h4>Social Justice and Equity Editor</h4>



<p>McClatchy, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://jobs.jobvite.com/mcclatchy/job/oMlbnfwp">https://jobs.jobvite.com/mcclatchy/job/oMlbnfwp</a></p>



<h4>Associate Research Assistant</h4>



<p>Aderant, US</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers-aderant-na.icims.com/jobs/2519/associate-research-assistant/job?iis=Social+Networks&amp;iieid=pt16873860550119f1e5&amp;mobile=false&amp;width=656&amp;height=868&amp;bga=true&amp;needsRedirect=false&amp;jan1offset=-360&amp;jun1offset=-300">Associate Research Assistant (icims.com)</a></p>



<h4>Thought Leadership Analyst (Masters degree preferred)</h4>



<p>WittKieffer, USA (Remote)</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.appone.com/MainInfoReq.asp?R_ID=5542319">https://www.appone.com/MainInfoReq.asp?R_ID=5542319</a></p>



<h4>Office and Events Coordinator</h4>



<p>Princeton University, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://main-princeton.icims.com/jobs/17230/office-and-events-coordinator/job?hub=15&amp;mobile=false&amp;width=1050&amp;height=500&amp;bga=true&amp;needsRedirect=false&amp;jan1offset=-300&amp;jun1offset=-240">Office and Events Coordinator in Princeton, New Jersey | Careers at Princeton University (icims.com)</a></p>



<h4>Senior Program/Policy Specialist/Analyst – Disability Justice (2-year appointment)</h4>



<p>National Education Association, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://nea.wd1.myworkdayjobs.com/ExternalCareers/job/NEA-Headquarters/Senior-Program-Policy-Specialist-Analyst--Disability-Justice---Education-Policy---Implementation-Center_2023-00048-1?source=Linkedin">Careers at NEA (myworkdayjobs.com)</a></p>



<h4>Social Scientist – Evaluator (Ph.D. required)</h4>



<p>National Science Foundation, USA (Remote)</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.usajobs.gov/job/733317300">https://www.usajobs.gov/job/733317300</a></p>



<h4>Grant Management Specialist</h4>



<p>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.usajobs.gov/job/733374700">https://www.usajobs.gov/job/733374700</a></p>



<h4>Historian (Ph.D. required)</h4>



<p>National Park Service, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.usajobs.gov/job/733547900">https://www.usajobs.gov/job/733547900</a></p>



<h4>Jr. Instructional Support Specialist</h4>



<p>Phyton Talent Advisors, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/jobs/view/3641822404/">https://www.linkedin.com/jobs/view/3641822404/</a></p>



<h4>Instructional Specialist</h4>



<p>Alliance College-Ready Public Schools, USA</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://boards.greenhouse.io/homeoffice/jobs/5027686">Job Application for Instructional Specialist, Equitable School Practices at Alliance College-Ready Public Schools (Home Office) (greenhouse.io)</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>Sedes Sapientiae Symposium</h4>



<p>Deadline July 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/112542">https://philevents.org/event/show/112542</a></p>



<h4>Studies in Church History</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/8QeR0pMWoM">https://t.co/8QeR0pMWoM</a></p>



<h4>Feminist Theologies in American Literature</h4>



<p>Deadline: September 29, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12883762/feminist-theologies-american-literature">Feminist Theologies in American Literature | H-Announce | H-Net</a></p>



<h4>Deleuze and Guattari Studies Special Issue: “Deleuze and Kierkegaard: Thinking Difference, Thinking Existence”</h4>



<p>Deadline: November 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/112654">https://philevents.org/event/show/112654</a></p>



<h2>Conferences:</h2>



<h4>Exploring ‘rest’ in Ancient Jewish and Early Christian Contexts</h4>



<p>Netherlands</p>



<p>Date: July 4, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.ru.nl/over-ons/agenda/exploring-rest-in-ancient-jewish-and-early-christian-contexts">Exploring ‘rest’ in Ancient Jewish and Early Christian Contexts | Radboud Universiteit (ru.nl)</a></p>



<h4>Religious Leaders Track at Society for the Scientific Study of Religion Conference</h4>



<p>Salt Lake City, USA</p>



<p>Date: October 19-21, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/HVKcG084CI">https://t.co/HVKcG084CI</a></p>



<h4>Epistemic Injustice and Religious Identities</h4>



<p>Online</p>



<p>Date: March 2-7, 2024</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/112674">https://philevents.org/event/show/112674</a></p>



<h2>Miscellaneous:</h2>



<h4>China Regional Summer Program in Chinese Studies for 2023</h4>



<p>Online</p>



<p>Date: July 14-August 10, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/112534">https://philevents.org/event/show/112534</a></p>



<h4>American Catholic Historical Association Vice-President and 2 At-large Positions Nominations</h4>



<p>Deadline: June 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://twitter.com/achahistory/status/1673384969073205262?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw">American Catholic Historical Association on Twitter: “There is still time to nominate yourself or a colleague to serve the ACHA! Nominations should include, the nominee’s name and contact information and a 2-3 sentence explanation of the nomination, to Justin Poche at jpoche@holycross.edu by June 30, 2023! https://t.co/vy7Y3djqKh” / Twitter</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1688017036014088</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[Today] Conference talk or similar: Memories of Air</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/112702</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/>Speakers at this event: <br/>Giovanbattista Tusa (Universidade Nova de Lisboa)<br/><br/><p>In this talk, Giovanbattista Tusa suggests that we are currently witnessing a mutation, which disrupts the mythical imaginary that had confined viruses, climate change, and atmospheric turbulences to an immutable, celestial background. Western philosophy has based its perpetuation on ideas that have been built on an exploitable ground, endlessly manipulated, dissociated from a sky that has become increasingly uncertain and threatening, increasingly distant. The conclusions presented in this short presentation move in opposite direction to this disastrous separation, as Giovanbattista Tusa argues that the repression of this traumatic experience, is the cause of the perturbation that haunts our time. Disorientation pervades philosophy when the entire imaginary to which it had anchored its power to change the world seems to dissolve in the air; but precisely for this reason, philosophy must accept inhabiting the fluctuating disorientation of its own time, populated by intermittent and uncertain opportunities of experiencing differently the past and the future—to encounter different relationships with the times that change.</p>
<p>Keywords: ecology; climate change; philosophy.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 05:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1687930640203257</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CfP: Pentecostalism and Gender (GloPent Conference) - Submission Deadline 30 September 2023</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12886419/cfp-pentecostalism-and-gender-glopent-conference-submission</link>
						<dc:creator>Judith Bachmann</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-09-30T00:00:00-04:00">September 30, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Germany</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Colonial and Post-Colonial History / Studies, Cultural History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Social Sciences, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span>The 14</span><sup><span><span>th</span></span></sup><span> conference of the European Research Network on Global Pentecostalism (</span><span>GloPent</span><span>) will be held on 9-10 February 2024 at the University of Heidelberg, Germany.</span> </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>Conference Theme: Pentecostalism and Gender</span></span></span></b><b> </b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Pentecostalism's attitudes to gender are diverse. Historical research on Pentecostalism has acknowledged its attraction to the marginalized, regardless of gender. Political and social scientists frequently document the significant cultural and social influence exerted by Pentecostal churches on gender debates. Moreover, the theological perspectives on gender within the Pentecostal movement demonstrate substantial heterogeneity. </span> </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Additional academic research is required to understand how Pentecostals navigate gender-related issues in their day-to-day experiences. This involves placing emphasis on a nuanced understanding of their self-perceptions and practices.</span> </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>We invite contributions to our parallel panels, with a particular interest in papers that address the conference theme. Papers may present case studies or comparative analyses of gendered ideals and practices as well as adaptation and subversion strategies within Pentecostal communities. We seek insights on gender expectations: how are they conveyed, received, and implemented? How does gender affect the marginalized or powerful? Where do we find inconsistencies, fissures, or openings in the way gender is realized? Which future possibilities might these inconsistencies imply? We also welcome more conceptual and theoretically oriented papers considering the role of gender for the study of global Pentecostalism. </span> </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Keynote speakers are:</span> </span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span>Ezra </span><span>Chitando</span><span>, University of Zimbabwe</span> </span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Naomi Richman, University of Cambridge</span> </span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Brendan Jamal Thornton, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</span> </span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span>Submission pertaining to other topics will be considered as well, as long as they present ongoing or recently completed research. Proposals for entire panels (3-5 papers) are also welcome, but please contact the conference </span><span>organisers</span><span> before preparing your submission.</span> </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>If you should require on-site childcare, please let us know as soon as possible so that we may support you.</span> </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span>Submission deadline for abstracts (1300 characters max.): 30.09.2023 </span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>For the submission of abstracts, kindly use the link: </span><a href="https://limesurvey.urz.uni-heidelberg.de/index.php/661493?lang=en" rel="nofollow"><span>https://limesurvey.urz.uni-heidelberg.de/index.php/661493?lang=en</span></a></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Convenors: Judith Bachmann, Michael Bergunder, Anna Kirchner (Department of Religious Studies and Intercultural Theology, University of Heidelberg)</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:anna.kirchner@ts.uni-heidelberg.de">anna.kirchner@ts.uni-heidelberg.de</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.glopent.net/" target="_blank">https://www.glopent.net/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 17:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1687930640203256</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>“‘Nor thou nor thy religion dost controule, The amorousnesse of an harmonious Soule’: Rethinking Devotional Works and Practices in the British Isles (16th-18th c.)”</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/06/23/%E2%80%9C%E2%80%98nor-thou-nor-thy-religion-dost-controule-the-amorousnesse-of-an-harmonious-soule%E2%80%99</link>
						<dc:creator>jvanparys</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, June 27, 2023 - 2:25pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Université Paris Nanterre (CREA EA 370) - Université Clermont Auvergne (IHRIM-UMR 5317)</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:julie.vanparys_rotondi@uca.fr">julie.vanparys_rotondi@uca.fr</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/eighteenth-century">eighteenth century</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/international-conferences">international conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/renaissance">renaissance</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>September 30, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>                                               Call for papers </strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">“‘Nor thou nor thy religion dost controule, The amorousnesse of an harmonious Soule’: Rethinking Devotional Works and Practices in the British Isles (16th-18th c.)”</p>
<p dir="ltr">(Scroll down for the French version, scientific committee and selected bibliography)</p>
<p dir="ltr">A one-day preparatory seminar will take placeon April, 5th 2024 (as a hybrid event) to enable scholars to present their research. The conference will then take place at Université Paris Nanterre on 20-21 March, 2025. </p>
<p dir="ltr">This conference is organized jointly by Université Paris Nanterre (CREA EA 370) and Université Clermont Auvergne (Institut d’Histoire des Représentations et des Idées dans les Modernités, UMR 5317).</p>
<p dir="ltr">                                                                                                                                     ***</p>
<p dir="ltr">When John Donne published Devotions upon Emergent Occasions in 1624, he followed in the footsteps of a long tradition of devotional publications. Four hundred years later the concerns voiced by the English poet still resonate and invite one to think about the evolution and legacy of devotional works which have never ceased to appeal to both devout practitioners and lay readers alike. Such works convey the strong and complex nature of the relationship that the believer has with God. Indeed, devotion implies a series of religious observances, duties and actions, as well as a more inward-looking life, with a focus on keeping the soul in a disposition of piety and fervour. </p>
<p dir="ltr">The project will focus on a better understanding of how devotion lies at the intersection between expression, externalization and internalization. It can be mediated through physical actions, but also through the work of the soul, thus placing it at once in the spheres of the visible and the invisible. One is also led to think about how devotion can be displayed and grasped in texts, since verbal communication or silent worship can be echoed by gestures or visual representations through emblems or illuminations. </p>
<p dir="ltr">When focusing on the historical evolution of devotion through its textual expression, various approaches for further analysis emerge. First, the circulation of devotional publications was evidenced by Richard Whitford (c.1470-1543?), a monk who found success in the 1530s following his Werke for Housholders and Werke of Preparacion or of Ordinaunce unto Comunion or Howselyng, which focused on lay people’s deeds within their households. 1631 saw the publication of The Christians Daily Walk with God by Anglican author Henry Scudder (?-1652), and later editions included texts from nonconformist figures like John Davenport (1597-1670), John Owen (1616-1683) and Richard Baxter (1615-1691). These texts circulated extensively. Indeed, a German translation by Theodore Haak surfaced in Frankfurt five years after Scudder’s book had first been published in English. Several decades later, John Scott’s The Christian life from its beginning to its consummation in glory: together with the several means and instruments of Christianity conducing thereunto, with directions for private devotion and forms of prayer, fitted to the several states of Christians was first issued in 1681 before an expanded second edition was printed in 1683–87. These two instances raise some questions: what role did emendations play? What made some texts run through multiple editions compared to other devotional treatises? Secondly, such texts also draw attention to the changes in one’s life or historical events which could prevent devotion from being put into practice, or alter how it was defined or considered: the transformations introduced by the Reformation, the time of crisis during the Civil War, or the development of religious nonconformity, to name but a few examples. A third consideration which stands out are the specific allusions which can be encountered in some devotional manuals, such as Catholic figures – when reading Motives to Holy Living (Oxford, 1688), references to the Abecedaries composed by Spanish Franciscan friar Francisco de Osuna (1492-c.1540), and to St Teresa of Avila (1515-1582), can be found. What purpose did references to those names and sources serve? Furthermore, some books contained special prayers, for instance “A Prayer to be said by Merchants, Tradesmen, and Handicrafts men” in The Rule and Exercises of Holy Living (1650) by Jeremy Taylor (1613-1667). Similarly, emphasis can be put on primers – including  George Joye’s Ortulus Animae (1530), the first to be published in English, or William Marshall’s Goodly Primer (1535) – or other Protestant testimonies in use or circulation from the 1530s onwards.</p>
<p dir="ltr">This project seeks to analyse the devotional works which circulated from the early modern era to the end of the 18th century in terms of materiality, reception, and argumentation in the British Isles, with a possible extension to colonial America. Different types of formats will be considered: manuscripts, letters, diaries, printed texts. Scholars working on topics related to religious and social history, the history of ideas, textual studies, are invited to submit proposals.</p>
<p dir="ltr">With the objective of understanding these issues, suggested topics include, but are not limited to:</p>
<ul>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">the reception of devotional texts in the public and private spheres, including the description of the effects of devotional practices (conformist and non-conformist testimonies, conversion narratives... )</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">the argumentative structure of devotional texts, among other aspects, the role played by intertextual references (Scriptures, patristic and/or medieval texts, books of hours, primers…)</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">the circulation of devotional texts (manuscripts, personal correspondence, prayer books, girdle books...)</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">the materiality of devotional works (the role of printing and printers, how they could affect the layout of texts in books, the place of devotional texts and collections within the circulation of works in printed form, the addition of hand-written notes and emendations in printed books…)</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">comparisons between publications  from different denominations</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">the connection between devotional texts and political pamphlets and/or scientific documents. </p>
</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p dir="ltr">The languages of the conference are English and French.</p>
<p> </p>
<p dir="ltr">Participants are invited to submit a title, a 300-to-500-word abstract (25 minutes) and a short biographical notice jointly to Nicolas Bourgès: <a href="mailto:nbourges@parisnanterre.fr">nbourges@parisnanterre.fr</a>  and Julie VanParys-Rotondi: <a href="mailto:julie.vanparys_rotondi@uca.fr">julie.vanparys_rotondi@uca.fr</a> , before 30 September 2023.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>                                    Appel à communications </strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">« ‘Nor thou nor thy religion dost controule, The amorousnesse of an harmonious Soule’ : Repenser les productions et les pratiques dévotionnelles dans les îles Britanniques (XVIe-XVIIIe siècles) »</p>
<p dir="ltr">Une journée d’étude préparatoire aura lieu le 5 avril 2024, en format hybride, pour permettre aux chercheurs de présenter leur recherche. Elle prendra la forme d’un colloque qui se tiendra du 20 au 21 mars 2025 à la Maison de la Recherche de l'Université Paris Nanterre.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Ce projet est organisé conjointement par l’Université Paris Nanterre (CREA EA 370) et l’Université Clermont Auvergne (Institut d’Histoire des Représentations et des Idées dans les Modernités, UMR 5317).</p>
<p dir="ltr">                                                                                                                              ***</p>
<p dir="ltr">En 1624 parut Devotions upon Emergent Occasions,inscrivant l’œuvre John Donne dans une longue tradition de publications dévotionnelles.Quatre cents ans plus tard, les préoccupations énoncées par le poète anglais interrogent tout autant et invitent à une réflexion sur le cheminement et l’héritage des productions dévotionnelles. En effet, celles-ci n'ont jamais cessé d'attirer à la fois pratiquants et lecteurs laïcs tant ils traduisent la complexité et la force de la relation du croyant à Dieu. La dévotion, qui se caractérise par une série d'observances, de devoirs et d'actions religieuses, mais aussi une vie davantage centrée vers l’introversion tend vers le maintien de l’âme dans une disposition de piété et de ferveur.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Ce colloque vise une meilleure compréhension de la position de la dévotion située à l'intersection entre l’expression, l’extériorisation et l’intériorisation : elle peut se traduire dans des actes physiques comme par l’action de l’âme, relevant ainsi à la fois de la sphère du visible et de l'invisible. Ceci invite à envisager comment la dévotion peut être affichée et appréhendée dans les textes, la communication verbale ou le culte silencieux, accompagné ou non de gestes, ou comment elle peut être reprise par des représentations visuelles à travers des emblèmes ou des enluminures.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Lorsque l’on s’intéresse à l’évolution de la dévotion dans une perspective historique, on peut s’apercevoir de l’existence de certaines dynamiques. Un premier cas de figure concerne la circulation de publications dévotionnelles, comme l’illustrent celles du moine Richard Whitford (v.1470-1543?), qui rencontrèrent un succès certain dans les années 1530 à la suite de Werke for Housholders et Werke of PreparacionorOf Ordinaunce unto Comunion or Howselyng, qui se concentrent sur ce que les laïcs étaient tenus de faire dans leur foyer. En 1631, l’auteur anglican Henry Scudder (?-1652)publia The Christians Daily Walk with God pour la première fois, et les éditions ultérieures virent l’ajout de textes de figures non-conformistes telles que John Davenport (1597-1670), John Owen (1616-1683) et Richard Baxter (1615-1691). Ces textes circulèrent massivement ainsi que le montre une traduction allemande de Theodore Haak publiée à Francfort cinq ans après la première publication du livre de Scudder en anglais. Quelques décennies plus tard, The Christian Life from its Beginning to its Consummation in Glory: Together with the Several Means and Instruments of Christianity Conducing Thereunto, with Directions for Private Devotion and Forms of Prayer, Fitted to the Several States of Christians de John Scott (1638/9-1695) fut publié une première fois en 1681 avant qu’une deuxième édition augmentée ne paraisse en 1683–87. Ces deux exemples soulèvent quelques questions : quel rôle les corrections ont-elles joué ? Pourquoi certains écrits ont-ils connu plusieurs éditions au regard d’autres traités dévotionnels ? De tels textes invitent aussi à réfléchir aux événements de la vie ou aux bouleversements historiques qui ont pu empêcher de pratiquer cette dévotion, ou de modifier la manière dont elle a été définie ou perçue : les transformations qui ont suivi la Réforme, les temps de crise pendant la guerre civile, ou le développement de courants religieux dissidents, pour ne citer que quelques exemples. Un troisième point concerne les allusions précises que l’on peut rencontrer à la lecture de certains manuels de dévotion. Parmi ceux-ci, on peut citer les ouvrages qui renvoient à des figures catholiques : dans Motives to Holy Living (Oxford, 1688), il est fait référence aux Abécédaires composés par le frère franciscain espagnol Francisco de Osuna (1492-vers 1540), ainsi qu’à Sainte Thérèse d’Avila (1515-1582). Quel était l’objectif des références à ces noms et à ces sources ? De plus, certains livres contenaient des prières particulières, à l’instar de « A Prayer to be said by Merchants, Tradesmen, and Handicrafts men » dans The Rules and Exercises of Holy Living (1650) de Jeremy Taylor (1613-1667). De même, on peut s’intéresser aux primers, dont le premier en langue anglaise fut Ortulus Animae, publié par George Joye (1530), ou encore Goodly Primer de William Marshall (1535), ainsi que tout autre témoignage protestant utilisé, ou circulant, à partir des années 1530.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Ce projet cherche à analyser les productions dévotionnelles ayant circulé des prémices de la première modernité jusqu’à la fin du XVIIIe siècle en termes de matérialité, de réception, d’argumentation dans les îles Britanniques, et possiblement dans la jeune Amérique. Différents types de supports seront pris en compte : manuscrits, lettres, journaux, textes imprimés. Les chercheurs travaillant dans les domaines de l’histoire religieuse et sociale, de l’histoire des idées, des études textuelles, sont invités à soumettre leurs propositions. </p>
<p dir="ltr">Dans le but de comprendre ces points, les sujets suggérés ci-après pourront être abordés, sans s’y limiter :</p>
<ul>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">la réception des textes dévotionnels dans la sphère publique et privée, dont la description des effets sur les pratiques de dévotion (témoignages conformistes, non-conformistes, récits de conversion... )</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">la structure argumentative des textes dévotionnels, parmi lesquels le rôle joué par les références intertextuelles (la Bible, les textes patristiques et/ou médiévaux, les livres d’heures, les primers…)</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">la circulation des productions dévotionnelles (manuscrits, correspondance personnelle, livres de prières, girdle books…)</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">la matérialité des productions dévotionnelles (le rôle de l’imprimerie et des imprimeurs, la place des imprimeurs dans la mise en forme et la disposition des textes au sein des ouvrages, la place des textes dévotionnels et les anthologies au sein de la diffusion de l’imprimé, les ajouts de notes et modifications manuscrites dans les ouvrages imprimés…)</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">les comparaisons entre des productions provenant de différentes dénominations / différents courants religieux</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">les liens entre productions dévotionnelles et pamphlets politiques et/ou productions scientifiques.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p dir="ltr">Les langues du colloque sont le français et l’anglais.</p>
<p> </p>
<p dir="ltr">Les propositions de communications (25 minutes), d’une longueur de 300 à 500 mots (titre et résumé), assorties d’une courte notice bio-bibliographique, sont à adresser conjointement à Nicolas Bourgès : <a href="mailto:nbourges@parisnanterre.fr">nbourges@parisnanterre.fr</a>   et Julie VanParys-Rotondi : <a href="mailto:julie.vanparys_rotondi@uca.fr">julie.vanparys_rotondi@uca.fr</a>  pour le 30 septembre 2023.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Scientific Committee/ Comité scientifique:</p>
<p dir="ltr">Paula Barros (Université Paul-Valéry Montpellier 3)</p>
<p dir="ltr">Nicolas Bourgès (Université Paris Nanterre)</p>
<p dir="ltr">Yan Brailowsky (Université Paris Nanterre)</p>
<p dir="ltr">Myriam-Isabelle Ducrocq (Université Paris Nanterre)</p>
<p dir="ltr">Clotilde Prunier (Université Paris Nanterre)</p>
<p dir="ltr">Laurence Sterritt (Aix-Marseille Université)</p>
<p dir="ltr">Julie VanParys-Rotondi (Université Clermont Auvergne)</p>

<p dir="ltr">Selected bibliography /  Bibliographie indicative</p>
<p dir="ltr">CLARKE Elizabeth, DANIEL Robert W. (eds.), People and Piety: Protestant Devotional Identities in Early Modern England, Manchester: Manchester University Press, 2020.</p>
<p dir="ltr">COFFEY, John (ed.), Heart Religion: Evangelical Piety in England &amp; Ireland, 1690–1850, Oxford: Oxford University Press, 2016.</p>
<p dir="ltr">COLES, Kimberly Anne, Religion, Reform and Women’s Writings in Early Modern England, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 2008.</p>
<p dir="ltr">DUFFY, Eamon, Marking the Hours, English People and their Prayers, 1240-1570, New Haven, London: Yale University Press, 2006.</p>
<p dir="ltr">FANOUS, Samuel, GILLESPIE, Vincent (eds), The Cambridge Companion to Medieval English Mysticism (Cambridge Companions to Literature), Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 2011.</p>
<p dir="ltr">FELCH, Susan M., « English Women’s Devotional Writing: Surveying the Scene », ANQ: A Quarterly Journal of Short Articles, Notes, and Reviews, Vol. 24, n° 1-2, 2011, p. 118-130 </p>
<p dir="ltr">FORCLAZ Bertrand, MARTIN Philippe (eds.), Religion et piété au défi de la guerre de Trente ans, Rennes: Presses universitaires de Rennes, 2015. (troisième partie : “Piété et dévotion”)</p>
<p dir="ltr">GINN Richard, The Politics of Prayer in Early Modern Britain: Church and State in Seventeenth-Century England, London, New York: Tauris Academic Studies, 2007.</p>
<p dir="ltr">MARTIN Jessica, RYRIE Alec (eds.), Private and Domestic Devotion in Early Modern Britain [2012], London, New York: Routledge, 2016</p>
<p dir="ltr">NARVESON, Kate, Material Readings in Early Modern Culture: Bible Readers and Lay Writers in Early Modern England: Gender and Self-Definition in an Emergent Writing Culture, Abingdon: Ashgate Publishing Group, 2012. </p>
<p dir="ltr">WABUDA, Susan, LITZENBERGER, Caroline (eds)., Beliefs and Practice in Reformation England, Aldershot: Ashridge, 1998 </p>
<p dir="ltr">WHITE, Micheline (ed.), English Women, Religion, and Textual Production, 1500-1625, Farnham, Surrey : Ashgate, 2011.</p>
<p dir="ltr">YAMAMOTO-WILSON John R., “The Protestant Reception of Catholic Devotional Literature in England to 1700”, British Catholic History, volume 32, issue 1, May 2014, p. 67-90.</p>

</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 12:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1687930640203255</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Contact, Conflict, Concord between Europe and the Middle East in the Middle Ages</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/06/23/contact-conflict-concord-between-europe-and-the-middle-east-in-the-middle-ages</link>
						<dc:creator>mwgeorge.51@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, June 27, 2023 - 2:22pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Illinois Medieval Association</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:escobedo@aurora.edu">escobedo@aurora.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/medieval">medieval</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/online-conferences">online conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>August 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>Contact, Conflict, Concord between Europe and the Middle East in the Middle Ages</strong></p>
<p><strong>October 13, 3:00 pm Central</strong></p>
<p><strong>Online via Zoom</strong></p>
<p>Interactions between the Latin West and the Islamic World in the Middle Ages present myriad opportunities to explore contact, conflict, and concord. From literature to science, these cultures intertwined through the centuries. This session invites proposals that explore aspects of contact between Europe and the Middle East from any discipline of medieval studies. To submit, please send a proposal of no more than 300 words to Libby Escobedo, <a href="mailto:escobedo@aurora.edu" target="_blank">escobedo@aurora.edu</a> by August 15.</p>
<p>The session is online and completely free.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 12:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1687930640203254</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Feminist Theologies in American Literature - Call for Chapters</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/06/22/feminist-theologies-in-american-literature-call-for-chapters</link>
						<dc:creator>Andrew Ball</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, June 27, 2023 - 2:20pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Feminist Theologies in American Literature</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:andrew_ball@emerson.edu">andrew_ball@emerson.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/african-american">african-american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/gender-studies-and-sexuality">gender studies and sexuality</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>September 29, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>Feminist Theologies in American Literature</strong></p>
<p>Call for Chapters</p>
<p>The editor of a collection in development seeks completed chapters on literary expressions of feminist theology broadly construed. The scope of the volume is wide and inclusive. Chapters may focus on any religious tradition, historical period, genre, or form of American literature. We particularly welcome essays on works of literature</p>
<p>-       that examine the power, enfranchisement, ideas, and practices of women </p>
<p>-       that consider how religion subverts or reinforces androcentrism and patriarchy</p>
<p>-       that engage with the ways that gender relations inform women’s religious concepts, commitments, and experience</p>
<p>-       that focus on intersectionality and the lattice of power connecting religion, gender, class, sexuality, ethnicity, and race in American culture</p>
<p>-       that consider the religious aspects of embodied experience</p>
<p>-       that challenge normative concepts of the sacred, religious practice, and/or religious authority</p>
<p>-       that consider the role of religion in movements for women’s liberation</p>
<p>-       that concern women and religious community</p>
<p>-       that concern women and the environment, ecology, and non-human life</p>
<p>-       that represent women’s experience with indigenous religions</p>
<p>-       that represent non-western religious traditions in the U. S.</p>
<p>-       theological interpretations of literature that does not overtly thematize religion</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The chapters in the volume will feature diverse theoretical methodologies, including but not limited to queer theory, trans studies, new materialism, Afrofuturism, and cultural studies. Chapters can be on literature from pre-Columbian to contemporary America.</p>
<p>Chapters should be between 6k-10k words, include an abstract, and keywords. Authors are encouraged to include images with their manuscript.</p>
<p>Chapters are <strong>due by September 29</strong>. Early submissions are encouraged.</p>
<p>Applicants will receive a decision by October 13.</p>
<p>Once the final roster of contributors is established and we can fully describe the content of the book, it will be proposed to publishers. The full manuscript will be 80k-100k words. Allowing time for the peer-review process, the book will be contracted early in the Spring 2024 semester.</p>
<p>Potential contributors, please feel free to reach out with any questions or concerns.</p>
<p>Please send submissions to Andrew Ball (<a href="mailto:andrew_ball@emerson.edu">andrew_ball@emerson.edu</a>) <strong>by September 29.</strong></p>
<p> </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 21:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1687930640203253</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[Today -  July 5, 2023] Conference or similar: Levinas and The Anarchy of the Good Readings of Humanism of the Other | Levinas et l’anarchie du Bien Lectures d’Humanisme de l’autre homme</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/112690</link>
						<description>Venue: V. Putvinskio Str. 14, Kaunas, Lithuania<br/><br/><p>Paru en 1972, <em>Humanisme de l’autre homme</em> correspond à la période de pleine maturité de la pensée de Levinas, après la percée de <em>Totalité et infini.</em> L’ouvrage se compose de trois articles : « La signification et le sens » (1964), « Humanisme et an-archie » (1968) et « Sans identité » (1970). Levinas y affirme sa volonté de revendiquer à nouveau l’humanisme, contre la tendance générale de la philosophie française, mais dans la pleine connaissance des difficultés que cela comporte. Il y promeut un « nouvel humanisme », une nouvelle conception de la culture et du sens, du temps et de la subjectivité.  En rassemblant des jeunes chercheurs et des chercheurs confirmés autour d’<em>Humanisme de l’autre homme</em>, ce colloque international se voudrait une invitation à méditer sa contribution inouïe à la pensée de l’humain, tout en dévidant quelques fils issus de la pelote du texte.</p>
<p>Published in 1972, <em>Humanism of the Other </em>corresponds to the period of full maturity of Levinas' thought, after the breakthrough of <em>Totality and Infinity</em>. It consists in three papers: "Significance and Meaning" (1964), "Humanism and Anarchy" (1968) and "Without Identity" (1970). In it, Levinas affirms his desire to reclaim humanism, against the general trend of French philosophy, but in full knowledge of the difficulties that this would involve. He promotes a "new humanism", a new conception of culture and meaning, of time and subjectivity.  By bringing together both confirmed and young researchers around <em>Humanism of the Other</em>, this international conference is an invitation to meditate on his unprecedented contribution to the thinking of the human, while following some of the main threads of the text.</p>
<p><strong>Program</strong>: <a target="_blank">https://shorturl.at/sBORT</a></p>
<p><strong>Zoom registration/inscription:</strong> https://link.lsmu.lt/da0vegbqa5</p></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 05:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1687844236155896</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ March 6, 2024 -  March 7, 2024] Conference or similar: Epistemic Injustice and Religious Identities</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/112674</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p>The Canada Research Chair on Epistemic Injustice and Agency and the Canada Research Chair in Applied Epistemology are inviting submissions for the upcoming workshop: </p>
<p>“Epistemic Injustice and Religious Identities”</p>
<p>McGill University, March 6-7, 2024.</p>
<p><strong><br/></strong></p>
<p>Epistemic injustice and epistemologies of ignorance are powerful tools to uncover the epistemic dimensions of oppression and domination. These tools, developed by critical race theorists and feminist scholars, have exposed many ways in which the credibility and intelligibility of social groups can be linked to social power and how dominant groups can avoid resistant knowledge and silence knowers to preserve their privilege. </p>
<p>Miranda Fricker’s (2007) account of testimonial and hermeneutical injustice is now a common starting point to talk about epistemic injustice, and José Medina’s Epistemology of resistance (2013) offers an expanded, more contextualized and polyphonic account. From there, many other concepts have been developed to capture the complex and manifold epistemic wrongs that marginalized people can suffer, including testimonial quieting and smothering (Dotson 2011), willful hermeneutical ignorance (Pohlhaus 2012), hermeneutical domination (Catala 2015), agential epistemic injustice (Lackey 2020; Medina 2021), testimonial void (Carmona 2021), etc. Epistemologies of ignorance (Mills 1997; 2007; Tuana 2006; Sullivan and Tuana 2007) also have contributed to uncover the epistemic wrongs of domination and have many points of overlap with epistemic injustice. </p>
<p>Yet, in this rapidly growing literature little has been said about religion and how someone can suffer epistemic wrongs on the basis of one’s religious identity. Though some work has addressed how epistemic injustice can happen in the field of philosophy of religion (De Cruz 2020a; 2020b; Panchuk 2020b), within religious education classrooms (Moyaert 2019a; 2019b; Stones and Fraser-Pearce 2021; 2022; Strhan and Shillitoe 2022), in relation with religious trauma (Panchuk 2020a), more specifically because of someone’s religious identity (Kidd 2017; Lougheed 2020; Lynch 2022; Beauchamp 2023), and also how one can ignore one’s religious privilege (Markowitz and Puchner 2018; Ferber 2012), much work remains to be done. </p>
<p>This workshop is an invitation to remedy this lacuna and encourage scholars of epistemic injustice to engage with religious identity and scholars of religion to engage with epistemic injustice. It is also an opportunity to build a network of scholars interested in the topic.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 05:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1687844236155895</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ September 10, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Epistemic Injustice and Religious Identities</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/112678</link>
						<description><p>The Canada Research Chair on Epistemic Injustice and Agency and the Canada Research Chair in Applied Epistemology are inviting submissions for the upcoming workshop: </p>
<p>“Epistemic Injustice and Religious Identities”</p>
<p>McGill University, March 6-7, 2024.</p>
<p><strong><br/></strong></p>
<p>Epistemic injustice and epistemologies of ignorance are powerful tools to uncover the epistemic dimensions of oppression and domination. These tools, developed by critical race theorists and feminist scholars, have exposed many ways in which the credibility and intelligibility of social groups can be linked to social power and how dominant groups can avoid resistant knowledge and silence knowers to preserve their privilege. </p>
<p>Miranda Fricker’s (2007) account of testimonial and hermeneutical injustice is now a common starting point to talk about epistemic injustice, and José Medina’s Epistemology of Resistance (2013) offers an expanded, more contextualized and polyphonic account. From there, many other concepts have been developed to capture the complex and manifold epistemic wrongs that marginalized people can suffer, including testimonial quieting and smothering (Dotson 2011), willful hermeneutical ignorance (Pohlhaus 2012), hermeneutical domination (Catala 2015), agential epistemic injustice (Lackey 2020; Medina 2021), testimonial void (Carmona 2021), etc. Epistemologies of ignorance (Mills 1997; 2007; Tuana 2006; Sullivan and Tuana 2007) also have contributed to uncovering the epistemic wrongs of domination and have many points of overlap with epistemic injustice. </p>
<p>Yet, in this rapidly growing literature little has been said about religion and how someone can suffer epistemic wrongs on the basis of one’s religious identity. Though some work has addressed how epistemic injustice can happen in the field of philosophy of religion (De Cruz 2020a; 2020b; Panchuk 2020b), within religious education classrooms (Moyaert 2019a; 2019b; Stones and Fraser-Pearce 2021; 2022; Strhan and Shillitoe 2022), in relation with religious trauma (Panchuk 2020a), more specifically because of someone’s religious identity (Kidd 2017; Lougheed 2020; Lynch 2022; Beauchamp 2023), and also how one can ignore one’s religious privilege (Markowitz and Puchner 2018; Ferber 2012), much work remains to be done. </p>
<p>This workshop is an invitation to remedy this lacuna and encourage scholars of epistemic injustice to engage with religious identity and scholars of religion to engage with epistemic injustice. It is also an opportunity to build a network of scholars interested in the topic.</p>
<p><strong><br/><br/></strong></p>
<p>Possible topics include, but are not limited to: </p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Contexts in which certain religious identities are more at risk of suffering from epistemic injustice. </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Intersections of racial, gender, and religious identities and their impact on epistemic wrongs.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>(Dis)similarities of racial, gender and religious identities with regard to epistemic wrongs.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Specific religious identities that are more likely to suffer epistemic injustices.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Specific types of epistemic wrongs that religious persons can suffer.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Workings of religious ignorance in (secular) society.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Obstacles to the epistemic agency of religious persons in secular society.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How social structures and institutions impact a religious person’s epistemic agency.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How the lens of epistemic injustice and ignorance can shed light on issues of religion in the public sphere.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What would epistemic justice for religious persons require?</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><br/></strong></p>
<p>Confirmed Keynote Speaker: </p>
<p>Michelle Panchuk, Murray State University</p>
<p><strong><br/></strong></p>
<p>Format of the workshop: </p>
<p>This workshop will be held in person in Montreal, Canada. We will, however, have the possibility to accommodate speakers who would not be able to join in person with a hybrid format. We only ask that, in this case, you commit to attending the whole workshop. Each presenter will give a 25-minute presentation followed by 25 minutes of Q&amp;A. Please note that this is a pre-read workshop. All speakers are expected to have read the papers in advance.</p>
<p>We intend to publish a special issue (venue to be decided) building on this workshop. Since speakers will be encouraged to submit their work for the special issue, the material submitted here should not already have been published elsewhere, in whole or in part.</p>
<p><strong><br/></strong></p>
<p>Guidelines for submission: </p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Format: 500 words abstract, pdf or Word, prepared for anonymous review.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Please include in your email the following details: name, paper title, institutional affiliation (if applicable), contact information (email address), and whether you intend to participate in person or remotely.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Deadline for the submission of abstracts: September 10, 2023.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Successful applicants will be notified by October 15, 2023. (5000-6000 word papers will be expected by February 1, 2024)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Please, send your submissions, along with any question or concern, to gilles.beauchamp2@mail.mcgill.ca </p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Organized by: </p>
<p>Gilles Beauchamp (he/him), McGill University, Doctoral candidate </p>
<p>Maëlle Turbide (she/her), Université de Sherbrooke, Doctoral candidate</p>
<p><strong><br/><br/></strong></p>
<p>Bibliography</p>
<p>Beauchamp, Gilles. 2023. ‘Epistemic Injustice as a Ground for Religious Education in Public Schools’. Religious Education 118 (2): 119–32. https://doi.org/10.1080/00344087.2023.2181916.</p>
<p>Carmona, Carla. 2021. ‘Silencing by Not Telling: Testimonial Void as a New Kind of Testimonial Injustice’. Social Epistemology 35 (6): 577–92. https://doi.org/10.1080/02691728.2021.1887395.</p>
<p>Catala, Amandine. 2015. ‘Democracy, Trust, and Epistemic Justice’. The Monist 98 (4): 424–40. https://doi.org/10.1093/monist/onv022.</p>
<p>De Cruz, Helen. 2020a. ‘Philosophy of Religion From the Margins: A Theoretical Analysis and Focus Group Study’. In The Lost Sheep in Philosophy of Religion: New Perspectives on Disability, Gender, Race, and Animals, edited by Blake Hereth and Kevin Timpe, 31–54. Routledge Studies in the Philosophy of Religion 21. New York: Taylor &amp; Francis.</p>
<p>———. 2020b. ‘Seeking out Epistemic Friction in the Philosophy of Religion’. In Voices from the Edge. Oxford: Oxford University Press. https://doi.org/10.1093/oso/9780198848844.003.0002.</p>
<p>Dotson, Kristie. 2011. ‘Tracking Epistemic Violence, Tracking Practices of Silencing’. Hypatia 26 (2): 236–57. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1527-2001.2011.01177.x.</p>
<p>Ferber, Abby L. 2012. ‘The Culture of Privilege: Color-Blindness, Postfeminism, and Christonormativity’. Journal of Social Issues 68 (1): 63–77. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-4560.2011.01736.x.</p>
<p>Fricker, Miranda. 2007. Epistemic Injustice: Power and the Ethics of Knowing. Oxford ; New York: Oxford University Press.</p>
<p>Kidd, Ian James. 2017. ‘Epistemic Injustice and Religion’. In The Routledge Handbook of Epistemic Injustice, edited by Ian James Kidd, José Medina, and Gaile Pohlhaus, Jr., 386–96. Routledge Handbooks in Philosophy. London ; New York: Routledge, Taylor &amp; Francis Group.</p>
<p>Lackey, Jennifer. 2020. ‘False Confessions and Testimonial Injustice’. Journal of Criminal Law &amp; Criminology 110 (1): 43–68.</p>
<p>Lougheed, Kirk. 2020. ‘Epistemic Injustice and Religious Experience’. In The Lost Sheep in Philosophy of Religion: New Perspectives on Disability, Gender, Race, and Animals, edited by Blake Hereth and Kevin Timpe. Routledge Studies in the Philosophy of Religion 21. New York: Taylor &amp; Francis.</p>
<p>Lynch, Thomas. 2022. ‘Epistemic Injustice and the Veil: Islam, Vulnerability, and the Task of Historical Revisionism’. Culture and Religion 21 (3): 280–97. https://doi.org/10.1080/14755610.2022.2115524.</p>
<p>Markowitz, Linda, and Laurel Puchner. 2018. ‘Structural Ignorance of Christian Privilege’. International Journal of Qualitative Studies in Education 31 (10): 877–94. https://doi.org/10.1080/09518398.2018.1506180.</p>
<p>Medina, José. 2013. The Epistemology of Resistance: Gender and Racial Oppression, Epistemic Injustice, and Resistant Imaginations. Studies in Feminist Philosophy. Oxford ; New York: Oxford University Press.</p>
<p>———. 2021. ‘Agential Epistemic Injustice and Collective Epistemic Resistance in the Criminal Justice System’. Social Epistemology 35 (2): 185–96. https://doi.org/10.1080/02691728.2020.1839594.</p>
<p>Mills, Charles W. 1997. The Racial Contract. Ithaca, NY: Cornell University Press.</p>
<p>———. 2007. ‘White Ignorance’. In Race and Epistemologies of Ignorance, edited by Shannon Sullivan and Nancy Tuana, 11–38. SUNY Series, Philosophy and Race. Albany: State University of New York Press.</p>
<p>Moyaert, Marianne. 2019a. ‘Interreligious Hermeneutics, Prejudice, and the Problem of Testimonial Injustice’. Religious Education 114 (5): 609–23. https://doi.org/10.1080/00344087.2019.1610927.</p>
<p>———. 2019b. ‘Interreligious Learning, Ricoeur, and the Problem of Testimonial and Hermeneutical Injustice’. Journal of Nationalism, Memory &amp; Language Politics 13 (2): 205–23. https://doi.org/10.2478/jnmlp-2019-0014.</p>
<p>Panchuk, Michelle. 2020a. ‘Distorting Concepts, Obscured Experiences: Hermeneutical Injustice in Religious Trauma and Spiritual Violence’. Hypatia 35 (4): 607–25. https://doi.org/10.1017/hyp.2020.32.</p>
<p>———. 2020b. ‘That We May Be Whole: Doing Philosophy of Religion with the Whole Self’. In The Lost Sheep in Philosophy of Religion: New Perspectives on Disability, Gender, Race, and Animals, edited by Blake Hereth and Kevin Timpe, 55–76. Routledge Studies in the Philosophy of Religion 21. New York: Taylor &amp; Francis.</p>
<p>Pohlhaus, Gaile. 2012. ‘Relational Knowing and Epistemic Injustice: Toward a Theory of “Willful Hermeneutical Ignorance”’. Hypatia 27 (4): 715–35.</p>
<p>Stones, Alexis, and Jo Fraser-Pearce. 2021. ‘Some Pupils Should Know Better (Because There Is Better Knowledge than Opinion). Interim Findings from an Empirical Study of Pupils’ and Teachers’ Understandings of Knowledge and Big Questions in Religious Education’. Journal of Religious Education 69 (3): 353–66. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40839-021-00155-5.</p>
<p>———. 2022. ‘Is There a Place for Bildung in Preparing Religious Education Teachers to Support and Promote Epistemic Justice in Their Classrooms?’ Journal of Religious Education 70 (3): 367–82. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40839-022-00187-5.</p>
<p>Strhan, Anna, and Rachael Shillitoe. 2022. ‘The Experiences of Non-Religious Children in Religious Education’. Journal of Religious Education 70 (3): 261–72. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40839-022-00180-y.</p>
<p>Sullivan, Shannon, and Nancy Tuana, eds. 2007. Race and Epistemologies of Ignorance. SUNY Series, Philosophy and Race. Albany: State University of New York Press.</p>
<p>Tuana, Nancy. 2006. ‘The Speculum of Ignorance: The Women’s Health Movement and Epistemologies of Ignorance’. Hypatia 21 (3): 1–19. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1527-2001.2006.tb01110.x.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 05:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1687844236155894</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
