<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 12:21:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 12:21:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>Elders in Religions of Antiquity 2023 : REMINDER: Call For Papers - Elders in Religions of Antiquity</title>
			<link>http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=170259&amp;copyownerid=173363</link>
						<description>REMINDER: Call For Papers - Elders in Religions of Antiquity</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 06:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1669271829501588</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ December 10, 2022] Conference or similar: Online internationaler Workshop  &quot;Comenius’ Angelus Pacis im Kontext der Frühmoderne und dessen Beitrag zur heutigen Friedensethik&quot;</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/105297</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p><strong>Online internationaler Workshop</strong></p>
<p><strong>Comenius’ <em>Angelus Pacis</em> im Kontext der Frühmoderne und dessen Beitrag zur heutigen Friedensethik</strong></p>
<p><strong>10. Dezember 2022</strong></p>
<p>Anders als seine Pädagogik ist Johann Amos Comenius’ <em>Angelus Pacis</em> (1667) wenig rezipiert worden. Der Workshop will das Werk in einer philosophischen Perspektive darstellen, die es sowohl in der Tradition der frühneuzeitlichen Theorien des gerechten Krieges einordnet als auch systematisch analysiert. Denn die Erschließung dieser Schrift kann zur heutigen Debatte der Friedensethik einen wichtigen Beitrag leisten.<em> Angelus Pacis</em> beschränkt sich nicht auf die These, dass der ewige bzw. stabile Friede nur auf einer religiösen aufrechten Motivation beruhen dürfe, noch darf sich die Lektüre dieser Schrift auf eine theologisch orientierte Interpretation beschränken. Denn <em>Angelus Pacis</em> integriert rechtliche, rational-motivationale und teleologisch-geschichtliche Dimensionen des Friedensprozesses auf detaillierte Weise, weshalb es nicht nur aus religiöser Perspektive interessant, sondern auch für eine Auseinandersetzung mit den traditionellen vorherrschenden rechtsphilosophischen bzw. friedensethischen Theorien anschlussfähig ist. Der Workshop besteht aus sechs Beiträgen von internationalen Forschern jeweils mit anschließender Diskussion.</p>
<p><strong>Programm</strong>: https://philosophie-vechta.org/veranstaltungen/aktuell/</p>
<p><strong>Koordination</strong>:</p>
<p>Prof. Dr. Jean-Christophe Merle (Universität Vechta)</p>
<p>Dr. Anna Szyrwińska-Hörig (Universität Vechta)</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Freie Teilnahme, Voranmeldung erforderlich:</strong></p>
<p>jean-christophe.merle@uni-vechta.de</p>
<p>anna.szyrwinska@uni-vechta.de</p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 06:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1669185431787871</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Non-Cloistered Religious Women and Rome at the Aftermath of the Council of Trent. Journey in Archives (ISHWRA)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11813088/non-cloistered-religious-women-and-rome-aftermath-council</link>
						<dc:creator>Sarah Barthélemy</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Seminar</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-25T00:00:00-05:00">November 25, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Belgium</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Early Modern History and Period Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Cultural History / Studies, Italian History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>This coming Friday, 25 November at 4pm, we’ll be hosting in Brussels (Université Saint-Louis Bruxelles - room P30) this month’s ISHWRA seminar, when we’ll be joined by Dr Isabel Harvey (UCLouvain / GEMCA).</p><p>Recent historiography about non-cloistered religious women is based above all on the punctual luck of archives, as the wealth of an Inquisition trial or an autobiography, or on notarial institutional documentation of mainly economic nature. This documentation allows to reconstruct interesting cases, to contextualize them, but it is difficult to move away from the exceptionality of a person, a situation, or an institution rich enough to accumulate a number of notarial archives. I propose to look at another archive, the voluminous documentation of the Congregation of Bishops and Regulars, which will allow us to identify and hear the voices of others, those non-cloistered religious women who are considered neither saints nor heretics, and who did not live in a wealthy community in a large urban center. This presentation will detail the archival and methodological path to identify them and to gather information about their singular existences and experiences.</p><p>D﻿r Isabel Harvey is FNRS postdoctoral fellow at the Université catholique de Louvain.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><strong>T﻿his hybrid event will take place online and at Université Saint-Louis Bruxelles, 43 Boulevard du Jardin Botanique, Bruxelles, 1000 (room P30).</strong></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:sarah.barthelemy@durham.co.uk">sarah.barthelemy@durham.co.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/ishwra-seminar-november-2022-tickets-438918977477" target="_blank">https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/ishwra-seminar-november-2022-tickets-438918977477</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1669185431787870</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
