<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 12:22:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 12:22:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>FEATURED JOB: Faculty Fellow in Music and Sound Studies - New York University Arts and Science</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11954814/featured-job-faculty-fellow-music-and-sound-studies-new-york</link>
						<dc:creator>Erika Suchecki， H-Net Staff</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Home Office Notices (Jobs, Reviews)</div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>New York</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Music and Music History, Colonial and Post-Colonial History / Studies, Native American History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><strong>Faculty Fellow in Music and Sound Studies<br/>Department of Music<br/>New York University Arts and Science</strong><br/><br/>The Department of Music at New York University invites applicants for a Faculty Fellow position in the field of music and sound studies. We are looking for a superb scholar who will be a dynamic presence both in the classroom and the field. Their work should complement the research and methodologies of current faculty and bring fresh approaches to the study of musical and sonic practices. The initial appointment will be for one year beginning September 1, 2023, renewable annually for two additional years, subject to pending administrative and budgetary approval.<br/><br/>The successful candidate will be working at the cutting edge of interdisciplinary inquiry into histories of colonialism and processes of decolonization in music and sound studies. Within and alongside this broad area, we are especially interested in building strength in the following specializations: postcolonial studies; the Global South; Indigenous/Native American studies; religion and spirituality; and classical music historiography in relation to colonialism, imperialism, race, gender, and sexuality.<br/><br/>Responsibilities include teaching graduate and undergraduate courses in their areas of expertise - possibly including overseeing undergraduate independent studies. The teaching load will be three courses per annum. Service in the program might involve facilitating the department colloquium series.<br/><br/>Compensation:<br/>In compliance with NYC’s Pay Transparency Act, the annual salary for this position is $60,000. New York University considers factors such as (but not limited to) the scope and responsibilities of the position, the candidate’s work experience, education/training, key skills, internal peer equity, as well as market and organizational considerations when extending an offer.<br/><br/><strong>Qualifications:</strong><br/>Candidates must have completed their Ph.D. no earlier than January 2018 and no later than August 1, 2023. <br/><br/><strong>Application Instructions:</strong><br/>To apply, please submit a cover letter (including research and teaching interests), CV, names and contact information of three recommenders, a 20-30-page writing sample, a description of two dream courses (no more than 200 words each), and a statement of diversity and inclusion (no more than 400 words). As diversity is an important part of the NYU mission, for the latter statement we ask you to tell us how diversity figures into your past and present teaching, research, community engagement, and/or life experience, as well as how you would bring issues of diversity to bear on your teaching. Information about diversity statements may be found at <a href="http://as.nyu.edu/departments/facultydiversity/recruitment/diversity-statements.html" rel="nofollow">http://as.nyu.edu/departments/facultydiversity/recruitment/diversity-statements.html</a>.<br/><br/>Review of applications will begin on January 10, 2023, and will continue until the position is filled. Applications should be submitted through Interfolio: <a href="http://apply.interfolio.com/118347" rel="nofollow">http://apply.interfolio.com/118347</a>.<br/><br/><strong>Equal Employment Opportunity Statement</strong><br/>The Faculty of Arts and Science at NYU is at the heart of a leading research university that spans the globe. We seek scholars of the highest caliber, who embody the diversity of the United States as well as the global society in which we live. We strongly encourage applications from women, racial and ethnic minorities, and other individuals who are under-represented in the profession, across color, creed, race, ethnic and national origin, physical ability, gender and sexual identity, or any other legally protected basis. NYU is an equal opportunity/affirmative action employer and affirms the value of differing perspectives on the world as we strive to build the strongest possible university with the widest reach. To learn more about the Arts &amp; Science commitment to diversity, equity, and inclusion, visit <a href="https://as.nyu.edu/departments/facultydiversty.html" rel="nofollow">https://as.nyu.edu/departments/facultydiversty.html</a>.<br/><br/>EOE/Affirmative Action/Minorities/Females/Vet/Disabled/Sexual Orientation/Gender Identity.<br/><br/>For people in the EU, click here for information on your privacy rights under GDPR: <a href="http://www.nyu.edu/it/gdpr" rel="nofollow">www.nyu.edu/it/gdpr</a><br/><br/>NYU is an Equal Opportunity Employer and is committed to a policy of equal treatment and opportunity in every aspect of its recruitment and hiring process without regard to age, alienage, caregiver status, childbirth, citizenship status, color, creed, disability, domestic violence victim status, ethnicity, familial status, gender and/or gender identity or expression, marital status, military status, national origin, parental status, partnership status, predisposing genetic characteristics, pregnancy, race, religion, reproductive health decision making, sex, sexual orientation, unemployment status, veteran status, or any other legally protected basis. Women, racial and ethnic minorities, persons of minority sexual orientation or gender identity, individuals with disabilities, and veterans are encouraged to apply for vacant positions at all levels.<br/><br/>Sustainability Statement<br/>NYU aims to be among the greenest urban campuses in the country and carbon neutral by 2040. Learn more at <a href="http://nyu.edu/sustainability" rel="nofollow">nyu.edu/sustainability</a></p><hr/><p>To submit YOUR job posting, please visit the H-Net Job Guide:<a href="https://www.h-net.org/jobs" rel="nofollow"> https://www.h-net.org/jobs</a></p><p>Featured jobs receive an added boost on H-Announce and H-Net’s social media channels.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Review of applications will begin on January 10, 2023, and will continue until the position is filled. Applications should be submitted through Interfolio: <a href="http://apply.interfolio.com/118347" rel="nofollow">http://apply.interfolio.com/118347</a>.</p></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php" target="_blank">https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php?id=64753</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 20:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1670395029761169</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>EAJS Conference &quot;Branching Out. Diversity of Jewish Studies&quot;</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11946450/eajs-conference-branching-out-diversity-jewish-studies</link>
						<dc:creator>Saskia Doenitz</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-12-31T00:00:00-05:00">December 31, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Germany</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Cultural History / Studies, Digital Humanities, Jewish History / Studies, Literature, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Jewish Studies scholars do not only use interdisciplinary methods, but are also involved in multi-disciplinary networks, cooperating and communicating with colleagues from a wide variety of fields and geographical centers. At the same time, research into Jewish history, culture, languages and the like is not limited to Jewish Studies departments, creating yet wider networks and greater diversity.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The twelfth EAJS congress “Branching Out. Diversity of Jewish Studies”, taking place in Frankfurt/Main (Germany) on July 16<sup>th</sup> – 20<sup>th</sup> 2023, will showcase and celebrate that diversity which is such an integral part of Jewish Studies: it is reflected in research topics ranging from the Bible and ancient history to contemporary Jewish Thought and culture, in a multitude of different sources from all over the world, in methods and approaches from Archaeology to Digital Humanities, and the vast array of interdisciplinary networks and research approaches.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>We envision the subject of diversity also to be realized via the participants of the congress: from all different fields of Jewish Studies, from all over the world, from all ages and genders, from all academic levels, graduate student to senior scholar, but all united in the shared interest in Jewish Studies.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>In this inclusive sense, we welcome all colleagues working in Jewish Studies to participate in this exciting conference in Frankfurt!</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Please hand in your abstracts until <strong>December, 31st, 2022</strong> via our <strong>website</strong> (</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><a href="https://eajs-2023.eu/122291870/12th_EAJS_Congress" rel="nofollow">https://eajs-2023.eu/122291870/12th_EAJS_Congress</a>)</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>For further questions please check <a href="https://eajs-2023.eu/122291870/12th_EAJS_Congress" rel="nofollow">https://eajs-2023.eu/122291870/12th_EAJS_Congress</a></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>or</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span> <a href="https://www.eurojewishstudies.org/calls-for-papers/call-for-papers-twelfth-eajs-congress/" rel="nofollow">https://www.eurojewishstudies.org/calls-for-papers/call-for-papers-twelfth-eajs-congress/</a></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>or contact us via </span></span></span><a href="mailto:congress@eajs-2023.eu"><span><span><span>congress@eajs-2023.eu</span></span></span></a><span><span><span>.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>First information for EAJS-Emerge and Grants are now available!</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Information regarding Registration, Program, Accommodation, Travel, etc. will be added to this site shortly.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr. Saskia Dönitz</p><p>Seminar für Judaistik</p><p>Goethe-Universität Frankfurt</p><p><a href="mailto:doenitz@em.uni-frankfurt.de">doenitz@em.uni-frankfurt.de</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:congress@eajs-2023.eu">congress@eajs-2023.eu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://eajs-2023.eu/122291870/12th_EAJS_Congress" target="_blank">https://eajs-2023.eu/122291870/12th_EAJS_Congress</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 20:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1670395029761168</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ March 30, 2023 -  March 31, 2023] Conference or similar: Princeton Project in Philosophy &amp; Religion: 2023 Conference &quot;Philosophy, Religion and Existential Commitment&quot;</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/105706</link>
						<description>Venue: Princeton University<br/><br/></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 06:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1670308629597733</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ January 20, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Princeton Project in Philosophy &amp; Religion: 2023 Conference &quot;Philosophy, Religion and Existential Commitment&quot;</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/105710</link>
						<description><p><strong><em>Call for Abstracts</em></strong><strong><em> </em></strong></p>
<p><strong>2023 Conference (in person), Princeton Project in Philosophy &amp; Religion</strong></p>
<p><strong>Theme: “Philosophy, Religion and Existential Commitment”</strong></p>
<p><em>March 30-March 31, 2023</em></p>
<p>Keynotes:</p>
<p>Clare Carlisle (King’s College London)</p>
<p>Dean Zimmerman (Rutgers University)</p>
<p>The Princeton Project in Philosophy and Religion (3PR)invites submissions of 300-word abstracts for papers on any area or topic in philosophy of religion broadly-construed. We particularly welcome papers on the conference theme of “Philosophy, Religion and Existential Commitment”.</p>
<p>Abstracts of no more than 300 words should be prepared for blind review, accompanied by a separate document revealing author name and contact information, and be submitted by January 20, 2023 topppr@princeton.edu. Selected abstracts should be prepared for presentations of 30 minutes followed by 30 mins of Q&amp;A. Notification of acceptance can be expected by January 28, 2023.</p>
<p><em>3PR is a project of the University Center for Human Values at Princeton University.</em></p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 06:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1670308629597732</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>International conference: Sinicizing the Early Modern World: Histories and Interpretations Beyond Euro-Diffusionism</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11940978/international-conference-sinicizing-early-modern-world</link>
						<dc:creator>Adrian Masters</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-15T00:00:00-04:00">June 15, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-17T00:00:00-04:00">June 17, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Germany</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Chinese History / Studies, Early Modern History and Period Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Southeast Asian History / Studies, World History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Scholars have deeply researched Europe’s historical impacts upon China. A distinguished and decades-old - but still rather limited - field has undertaken research in the other direction, noting that China has also influenced its neighbors, Europe, and the wider world in turn. Nonetheless, this perspective remains dispersed, eclectic, and little-theorized. This gathering’s questions will extend in two directions: the historicization and theorization of what one might call ‘early modern Sinicization.’</p><p>Unearthing the many types of ‘reverse diffusionism’ in which Chinese practices spread to the world has rich explanatory promise, and may even be essential in achieving a more balanced understanding of causation in global history. On the one hand, this conference invites scholarship which explores how regions close and far from China transformed, adapted to, and struggled against Sinicization in the so-called early modern period, very roughly defined here as 1400-1800.</p><p>On the other hand, this conference also invites reflections on how to characterize ‘Sinicization’ itself. We also invite scholarship which poses major methodological, sociological, and even ethical questions about Sinicization, including:</p><p>• Which sociological categories should we use to describe these many tendencies and processes (‘creolization,’ ‘interculturation,’ ‘hybridization,’ ‘entanglement,’ ‘impact- response,’ ‘hegemony,’ ‘co-colonization,’ the ‘China-centered approach,’ etc.)?</p><p>• How to navigate the pratfalls of accidental Eurocentrism, uncritical Sinophilia, and<br/>essentialization of European and East Asian societies?</p><p>• How to include the stories of smaller polities, indigenous peoples, dynamic and creative<br/>individuals, and others caught between Europeanization, Sinicization, and other powerful<br/>social currents?</p><p><strong>DATES: </strong>15-17 June, 2023<br/><strong>INSTITUTION: </strong>University of Tübingen<br/><strong>LOCATION:</strong> Tübingen, Germany<br/><strong>LANGUAGE of presentations:</strong> English<br/><strong>APPLICATION DEADLINE:</strong> January 31, 2023<br/><strong>FORMAT:</strong> Hybrid; in-person and online </p><p><strong>ORGANIZERS: </strong>Prof. Dr. Renate Dürr, PD Dr. Philip Hahn, &amp;amp; Dr. Adrian Masters<br/><strong>SPONSORS:</strong> The German Research Foundation’s SFB 923-F04 and the University of Tübingen</p><p><em>Funding is available for travel and accommodations. This will be a hybrid event.</em></p><p><em>Scholars from all stages are invited to apply.</em></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr. Adrian Masters</p><p>University of Trier, Germany</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:adrianmmasters@gmail.com">adrianmmasters@gmail.com</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 21:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1670308629597731</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[IHGMS] Special Webinar Event: Antisemitism in the United States, a roundtable discussion with Professor Peter Beinart, Professor Lila Corwin Berman, and Rabbi Jill Jacobs, moderated by Alon Confino (12/13/22)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11922312/ihgms-special-webinar-event-antisemitism-united-states</link>
						<dc:creator>Alon Confino (IHGMS)</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Event</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-12-13T00:00:00-05:00">December 13, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Massachusetts</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Jewish History / Studies, Ethnic History / Studies, Race / Ethnic Studies, Race Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span>[The Institute for Holocaust, Genocide, and Memory Studies at UMass Amherst] Join</span></span><span><span> us on<b><span> <u>Tuesday, December 13, 2022, 12:00PM (EDT)</u> </span></b>for a special webinar event: <b><u>Antisemitism in the United States</u>,</b> <b>a roundtable discussion with Professor Peter Beinart, Professor Lila Corwin Berman, and Rabbi Jill Jacobs, moderated by Alon Confino</b>. This event will be held via ZOOM Webinar, registration is required to attend. <b><a href="https://umass-amherst.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_-hX4y2vtRGKaQBob2bBN1w" rel="nofollow">Register in advanced here</a></b>. For more information, visit our website at <span><a href="http://www.umass.edu/ihgms/" rel="nofollow">www.umass.edu/ihgms/</a></span> or contact us at <a href="mailto:ihgms@umass.edu">ihgms@umass.edu</a>. </span></span></span></span></p><p>Antisemitism has gained of late power and momentum in the United States in ways that most people, Jews and non Jews, could not have imagined possible. Implicit and explicit approval of antisemitism is tolerated or supported now by people with serious power. At the same time, there are fierce debates, particularly among Jews, about what exactly constitutes antisemitism. At the center of these debates are Zionism and Israel and Palestine: when does critique of Israel or Zionism cross the line into antisemitism? These two phenomena commingle to characterize the historical condition of antisemitism in today’s American society. Discussing these topics will be Peter Beinart, Lila Corwin Berman, and Jill Jacobs in a roundtable moderated by Alon Confino.</p><p> </p><p>Peter Beinart is Professor of Journalism and Political Science, City University of New York and editor at large of Jewish Currents.</p><p>Lila Corwin Berman is Murray Friedman Chair of American Jewish History, and Director of the Feinstein Center for American Jewish History, Temple University.</p><p>Rabbi Jill Jacobs is the CEO of T’ruah: The Rabbinic Call for Human Rights.</p><p>Alon Confino is Professor of History and Jewish Studies, Pen Tishkach Chair of Holocaust Studies, and Director of the IHGMS, UMass Amherst.</p><p> </p><p> </p><p>[This event is co-sponsored by: The Judaic and Near Eastern Studies Department at UMass, Amherst; and T’ruah: The Rabbinic Call for Human Rights]</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ihgms@umass.edu">ihgms@umass.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://umass-amherst.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_-hX4y2vtRGKaQBob2bBN1w" target="_blank">https://umass-amherst.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_-hX4y2vtRGKaQBob2bBN1w</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 20:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1670308629597730</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Midrash and the Literary</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/11/27/midrash-and-the-literary</link>
						<dc:creator>Andrew Ball</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Sunday, December 4, 2022 - 7:36pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>The American Religion and Literature Society</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:kludwig@bsu.edu">kludwig@bsu.edu </a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/theory">theory</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>January 6, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Midrash and the Literary</p>
<p>The American Religion and Literature Society (ARLS) invites papers for a panel at the American Literature Association Conference, May 25-28, 2023 in Boston.</p>
<p>We are seeking papers that explore the relevance of Midrash to contemporary literary criticism.</p>
<p>Midrash teaches that there exists not one authoritative meaning that we must discover but many possible meanings in whose unfolding we must participate. We see this happening in Talmud: a midrashic reader responds to a gap in the text by creating a narrative, which is, as Sandor Goodhart describes it, “a material extension” of the original text. The reader looks in between words, as well as in the space between God and man, in keeping with the rabbinic belief that meaning comes to be in dialogue between man and God. In this panel, we seek to consider how some of the attitudes and practices of ancient Midrash find echoes in contemporary theories of literary reading. Consider reader-response arguments that a text is not self-formulated but, rather, actualized through interpretation. Consider poststructuralist models in which the structure of language itself is interrogated and separated from the functioning of the literary.</p>
<p>We welcome papers that address questions including but not limited to:</p>
<ul>
<li>What critical approaches seem to take cues from or reinstate midrashic patterns? Or, where do you see correspondences between Jewish hermeneutics and secular criticism?
</li>
<li>How can an understanding of Midrash enrich our engagement with literary texts?
</li>
<li>How can the midrashic mode inform efforts to make meaning in a post-Holocaust, poststructuralist, or postmodern age, when structures of meaning have failed or been deconstructed?
</li>
<li>Does midrashic reading open up avenues for literary reading of sacred texts (as argued by Geoffrey Hartman)?
</li>
<li>What has been the lasting impact of what David Stern named “the midrash-theory connection” that was expressed during the 1980s? </li>
</ul>
<p>Please submit a 350-word paper proposal and short bio to <a href="mailto:kludwig@bsu.edu" target="_blank">kludwig@bsu.edu</a> by January 6, 2023.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 23:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1670222223675765</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ December 11, 2022] Talk or similar: Avatar: The Last Airbender and Philosophy Book Launch</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/105638</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/>Speakers at this event: <br/>Helen De Cruz (Saint Louis University)<br/>Nicole Fice (University of Western Ontario, Trent University)<br/>Isaac Wilhelm (National University of Singapore)<br/>Johnathan Flowers (Southern Illinois University - Carbondale, Worcester State University)<br/>Thomas Arnold (University of Heidelberg)<br/>Natalia Strok (Conicet)<br/>Barrett Emerick (St. Mary's College of Maryland)<br/>Audrey Yap (University of Victoria)<br/>Eric Schwitzgebel (University of California, Riverside)<br/>David Schwitzgebel (Institut Jean Nicod)<br/>Justin F. White (Brigham Young University)<br/>Brett Patterson (Clemson University)<br/>James William Lincoln (University of Kentucky)<br/>Dr Helen De Cruz (VU University Amsterdam)<br/>Nicole Fice<br/>Isaac Wilhelm (Rutgers University - New Brunswick)<br/>Johnathan Flowers<br/>Natalia Strok (Conicet)<br/>Barrett Emerick (St. Mary's College of Maryland)<br/>Audrey Yap (University of Victoria)<br/>Eric Schwitzgebel (University of California, Riverside)<br/>Justin F. White (Brigham Young University)<br/>Brett Patterson<br/>James William Lincoln (University of Kentucky)<br/><br/><p><em>Avatar: The Last Airbender and Philosophy </em>brings to the fore the Eastern, Western, and Indigenous philosophies that are implicit in the show. Following Uncle Iroh’s advice that it is important to draw wisdom from many traditions, this volume features contributions by experts on Buddhist, Daoist, Confucian, and Indigenous schools of thought, next to focusing on Western classical authors such as Plotinus, Kant, and Merleau-Ponty. The volume is also unique in drawing on less common traditions such as black abolitionism, anarchism, feminist care ethics, and the philosophy of martial arts. Intertwining experience and reflection, <em>Avatar: The Last Airbender and Philosophy</em> helps readers to deeply engage with today’s burning questions, such as how to deal with ecological destruction, the aftermath of colonialism and genocide, and wealth inequality, using the tools from a wide range of philosophical traditions.</p>
<p>This online book launch will feature several of the authors of contributions to the volume. Participants will be entered into a prize draw for three free copies of the book.</p>
<p><strong>Program</strong></p>
<p>(all times are given in CT)</p>
<p>2:30 Brief introduction on <em>Avatar: The Last Airbender</em><em> and Philosophy</em> by Helen De Cruz (co-editor)</p>
<p>Taster sessions of contributions to the volume</p>
<p><em>Water</em></p>
<p>* 2:37 Nicole Fice, “‘I will never, ever turn my back on people who need me’: Repairing the world through care”</p>
<p>* 2:44 Johnathan Flowers, “On the moral neutrality of bloodbending”</p>
<p>* 2:51 Isaac Wilhelm, “Mystical rationality”</p>
<p><em>Earth</em></p>
<p>* 2:58 Thomas Arnold, “The middle way and the many faces of earth”</p>
<p>* 3:05 Natalia Strok, “Time is an illusion: Time and space in the swamp”</p>
<p>* 3:13 Break with giveaway of free copies of <em>Avatar: The Last Airbender and Philosophy</em></p>
<p><em>Fire</em></p>
<p>* 3:23 Barrett Emerick and Audrey Yap, “Not giving up on Zuko: Relational identity and the stories we tell”</p>
<p>* 3:30 Eric Schwitzgebel and David Schwitzgebel, “Uncle Iroh, from fool to sage – or sage all along?”</p>
<p>* 3:37 Justin White “Being bad at being good: Zuko’s transformation and residual practical identities”</p>
<p><em>Air</em></p>
<p>*  3:44 Brett Patterson “The Avatar meets the Karmapa: Interconnections, friendship, and moral training”</p>
<p>*  3:51 James William Lincoln, “Ahimsa and Aang’s dilemma: ‘Everyone … [has] to be treated like they're worth giving a chance’”</p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 06:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1670135826763294</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>2023 National Endowment for the Humanities Summer Institute: Reconsidering Flannery O'Connor</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11912654/2023-national-endowment-humanities-summer-institute</link>
						<dc:creator>Nancy Davis-Bray</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Summer Program</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-01T00:00:00-04:00">June 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Georgia</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Graduate Studies, Humanities, Literature, Religious Studies and Theology, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The National Endowment for the Humanities is sponsoring a Summer Institute on Flannery O’Connor, June 1-29, 2023, “Reconsidering Flannery O’Connor.” Professor Robert Donahoo from Sam Houston State University and Dr, Bruce Gentry from Geeorgia College &amp; State University will be the co-directors of this Summer Institute at Georgia College in Milledgeville, GA.</p><p>For four weeks in June of 2023, Georgia College will host 25 teacher/scholars and numerous visiting scholars to learn about teaching and scholarship on Flannery O’Connor at the place where she wrote many of her works. </p><p>We welcome advanced graduate students, non-tenured or non-tenure track faculty, and tenured faculty who have a significant interest in Flannery O’Connor or topics associated with Flannery O’Connor and would gain from a four-week advanced immersion in Flannery O’Connor. In the past, individuals from a variety of fields and with a variety of interests have participated successfully in this Institute.</p><p><b>Interested? Explore the website at </b><a href="https://nam11.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Foconnorinstitute.gcsu.edu%2F&amp;data=05%7C01%7Cnancy.davisbray%40gcsu.edu%7C1af22020b4134ff2e51c08dad3bcc0f1%7Cbfd29cfa8e7142e69abc953a6d6f07d6%7C0%7C0%7C638055104889418262%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=qLAqS%2F5H%2Bj%2FRZrm3fdQ16QvUTDDctxED5qqWGUs2vhI%3D&amp;reserved=0" rel="nofollow"><b>https://oconnorinstitute.gcsu.edu/</b></a><b> to learn more about the opportunity and how to apply.</b></p><p><b>Questions? Contact us at </b><a href="mailto:oconnorinstitute2023@gcsu.edu"><b>oconnorinstitute2023@gcsu.edu</b></a><b> or check out our Facebook page (facebook.com/oconnorinstitute2023).</b></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>O'Connor Institute, Georgia College &amp; State University, Milledgeville, GA 31061</p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:oconnorinstitute2023@gcsu.edu">oconnorinstitute2023@gcsu.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://oconnorinstitute.gcsu.edu/" target="_blank">https://oconnorinstitute.gcsu.edu/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 18:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1670049426283310</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Master's Degree Funding (ca. $20,000CDN/pa) English Social History, Church History, or History of Magic 1350-1600 at ​​​​​​​University of Saskatchewan</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11912450/masters-degree-funding-ca-20000cdnpa-english-social-history</link>
						<dc:creator>Frank Klaassen</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Fellowship</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-12-01T00:00:00-05:00">December 1, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2024-02-27T00:00:00-05:00">February 27, 2024</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Canada</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Saskatchewan</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>British History / Studies, Early Modern History and Period Studies, Medieval and Byzantine History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Social History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span>The History Department at the University of Saskatchewan together with Dr. Sharon Wright and Dr. Frank Klaassen invite applications for three funded Master of Arts students interested in working with them on fifteenth- and sixteenth-century social, intellectual, or institutional history.</span></span></p><p><span><span>Klaassen and Wrights' SSHRC Insight Grant on Female Magic Practitioners will support three students (ca. $20,000 per year) through our two-year thesis-based MA program. Successful applicants will work as researchers on the court and visitation records of the Bishop of Hereford and/or continental records relating to the social history of magic 1350-1600. They will be provided with training in medieval Latin and palaeography but must have at least two years of undergraduate Latin prior to admission. Travel funds for research and conference presentations as well as additional support for foreign student tuition fees may be available.</span></span></p><p><span><span>Klaassen and Wright would be delighted to work with applicants to develop a research proposal (required for application). Students may wish to develop a project focused on Hereford ecclesiastical records which will allow them to collect data for their own thesis as they work as researchers on the SSHRC project. Potential topics include slander, fornication/adultery, irregular marriages, sexual license, bishop's visitations, disabilities, and the regulation of pastimes such as sports or drinking. </span></span></p><p><span><span>For more information contact Sharon Wright (<a href="mailto:sharon.wright@usask.ca">sharon.wright@usask.ca</a>) or Frank Klaassen (<a href="mailto:frank.klaassen@usask.ca">frank.klaassen@usask.ca</a>). For more information about the MA Program at the University of Saskatchewan see <a href="https://grad.usask.ca/programs/history.php#Program" rel="nofollow">https://grad.usask.ca/programs/history.php#Program</a></span></span></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:frank.klaassen@usask.ca">frank.klaassen@usask.ca</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 18:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1670049426283309</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rethinking Nature in ancient Judaism:  entanglement as a mode of vitality</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11911625/rethinking-nature-ancient-judaism-entanglement-mode-vitality</link>
						<dc:creator>Sara Ben-Isaac</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-12-13T00:00:00-05:00">December 13, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Ancient History, Jewish History / Studies, Languages, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Online UCL Institute of Jewish Studies lecture co-sponsored by the research network ‘Between Encyclopaedia and Epitome’  (U. Tübingen, UCL- London, FU Berlin)</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>While it has been said that there is no word for nature in Hebrew until the Tibbonite translation from the Arabic, this lecture will argue that we can already see signs of natural thinking in ancient Jewish texts. This is not an imposition of Greek thinking, but an integration and transformation of Greek thinking in a Jewish context.  By understanding the breadth and depth of the entanglement of cultures, we can open up pathways and see growth and development in a tradition that was said to be closed off from abstract thinking and fractured from its surrounding culture.  Professor Najman will argue that this was not the case.  Rather, that Judaism, Hebrew, and the growth of new textual traditions continue to exhibit vitality and creative innovation throughout the Hellenistic period and beyond.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Hindy Najman is the Oriel and Laing Professor of the Interpretation of Holy Scripture and the Director of the Oriel Centre for the Study of the Bible at the University of Oxford.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>She has written on the Hebrew Bible, the Dead Sea Scrolls, Rabbinic Literature and Pseudepigrapha.  Her publications include <i>Seconding Sinai: The Development of Mosaic Discourse in Second Temple Judaism </i>(2003), </span></span></span><span><span><span> <i>Past Renewals: Interpretive Authority, Renewed Revelation and the Quest for Perfection </i>(2010<i>) and  Losing the Temple and Recovering the Future: An Analysis of 4 Ezra</i></span></span></span><span><span><span> (2014).  She is currently completing a new book entitled: </span></span></span><i><span><span><span>Reading Practices and the Vitality of Scripture</span></span></span></i><span><span><span>.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>UCL INstitute of Jewish Studies</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ijs@ucl.ac.uk">ijs@ucl.ac.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/478135364747" target="_blank">https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/478135364747</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 18:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1669963029210346</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Max and Hilde Kochmann Summer School for PhD Students in European-Jewish History and Culture 2023</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11888646/max-and-hilde-kochmann-summer-school-phd-students-european</link>
						<dc:creator>Gideon Reuveni</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Workshop</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-04T00:00:00-04:00">June 4, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-07T00:00:00-04:00">June 7, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>European History / Studies, Holocaust, Genocide, and Memory Studies, Modern European History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Middle East History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The Sussex Weidenfeld Institute of Jewish Studies at the University of Sussex (</span></span><a href="https://www.sussex.ac.uk/research/centres/jewish-studies/" rel="nofollow"><span><span>https://www.sussex.ac.uk/research/centres/jewish-studies/</span></span></a><span><span>) in cooperation with the Center for Jewish Studies of the Karl-Franzens-Universität Graz invite PhD students to apply for the biennial Max and Hilde Kochmann Summer School for PhD students in European-Jewish History and Culture 2023.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The Summer School brings together </span></span><span><span>early career </span></span><span><span>researchers who are currently working on topics in Jewish history and culture, giving them the opportunity to present and discuss their projects in an informal and friendly atmosphere with leading scholars in the field. The Kochmann Summer School continues the tradition of previous events, creating an interdisciplinary network of </span></span><span><span>new </span></span><span><span>scholars engaged in areas of European-Jewish Studies, Thought and Culture from the early modern period to the present day. This year we particularly encourage </span></span><span><span>scholars exploring the intersection between</span></span><span><span> digital humanities and Holocaust commemoration to apply.  </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Applicants must be PhD students at the time the Summer School commences. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Candidates are invited to send, via email, a 500-word proposal outlining their PhD project, a short CV and one reference from their supervisor or relevant scholar in the field. Applications must be in English and sent as one PDF document to: </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Kate Marisson: </span></span><a href="mailto:K.Marrison@sussex.ac.uk"><span>K.Marrison@sussex.ac.uk</span></a></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>For enquiries please contact: </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Gideon Reuveni: </span><a href="mailto:g.reuveni@sussex.ac.uk"><span>g.reuveni@sussex.ac.uk</span></a></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Katrin Steffen: </span><a href="mailto:K.Steffen@sussex.ac.uk"><span><span>K.</span></span><span><span><span>Steffen</span></span></span><span><span>@sussex.ac.uk</span></span></a></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Victoria Walden: </span><a href="mailto:V.Walden@sussex.ac.uk"><span>V.Walden@sussex.ac.uk</span></a></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The Sussex Weidenfeld Institute will offer a travel allowance of up to £300 for candidates coming from Europe. Candidates from Israel, the United States and other non-European countries will be considered but may be asked to contribute towards their travel costs. Accommodation costs will be covered for all students.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>The Sussex Weidenfeld Institute of Jewish Studies</p><p>Univesity of Sussex</p><p>UK</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:K.Steffen@sussex.ac.uk">K.Steffen@sussex.ac.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.sussex.ac.uk/research/centres/jewish-studies/" target="_blank">https://www.sussex.ac.uk/research/centres/jewish-studies/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1669963029210345</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Bethlehem Conference on Moravian History &amp; Music</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11902243/bethlehem-conference-moravian-history-music</link>
						<dc:creator>Paul Peucker</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-01-01T00:00:00-05:00">January 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Pennsylvania</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology, Music and Music History, German History / Studies, Early Modern History and Period Studies, American History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>This conference explores Moravian history and music from the fifteenth to twenty-first centuries in Europe, the Americas, Asia, Africa, and Australia.</p><p><b>World • Heritage • Site</b></p><p>The Moravian communities of Bethlehem (USA), Gracehill (UK), and Herrnhut (Germany) are presently working together to join with Christiansfeld (Denmark) in becoming a multinational UNESCO <b>World Heritage Site.</b> These three words give us the theme for our 2023 conference. We especially welcome proposals for individual papers, panels, or lecture recitals addressing aspects of the relationships between Moravians and the <b>World</b> (natural, religious, socio-economic, political, etc.), Moravian <b>Heritage</b>, and Moravian <b>Sites</b> (<i>Sights</i> or <i>Cites</i>). Each of these perspectives offers a unique way of thinking about Moravians and their interactions with others.</p><p>We also welcome papers relating to the anniversaries of composers and instrument makers. These might include celebrating the birthday anniversaries of Jan Blahoslav (1523-1571), Christian Gregor (1723-1801), and Edward William Leinbach (1823-1901) or the 150th anniversary of the deaths of Peter Ricksecker (1791-1873), Jedediah Weiss (1796-1873), John Christian Malthaner (1810-1873), and C.F. Martin (1796-1873).  </p><p>Please submit a proposal of 300 words or less, accompanied by a one-page CV, by January 1, 2023, to: <a href="http://www.moravianconferences.org/submit-a-proposal" rel="nofollow">www.moravianconferences.org/submit-a-proposal</a>. We encourage submissions from undergraduate students for whom there may be special panels and poster sessions. </p><p>The program committee will notify accepted applicants by February 15, 2023. </p><p>Travel grants for research at the Moravian Archives are available. The Moravian Archives will be closed to researchers during the conference, but research is possible before and after the conference. More information on the research travel grants is available at: <a href="http://www.moravianchurcharchives.org/about%C2%A0" rel="nofollow">www.moravianchurcharchives.org/about </a>(tab: Research Grants). Application deadline for these Archives travel grants for research is February 28, 2023.</p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr. Hilde Binford, conference chair<br/>Moravian University</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:binfordh@moravian.edu">binfordh@moravian.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="http://www.moravianconferences.org/" target="_blank">http://www.moravianconferences.org</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 21:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1669876627907114</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – November 30, 2022</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-november-30-2022/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find job listings, a fellowship, Call for Papers, and a public scholar competition.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 36!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Open Rank Professor in Indigenous Studies (Tenure-Track, Tenured)</h4>



<p>University of California, Riverside, US</p>



<p>Deadline: January 3, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://naisa.org/job/open-rank-professor-tenure-track-or-tenured-indigenous-studies/">https://naisa.org/job/open-rank-professor-tenure-track-or-tenured-indigenous-studies/</a></p>



<h4>Research Assistant on Australian far-right (6-month appointment)</h4>



<p>More Information: Direct Message <a href="https://twitter.com/DrJoshuaRoose?s=20&amp;t=Zh88VyIYxUTmfW_9VtZ20Q">https://twitter.com/DrJoshuaRoose?s=20&amp;t=Zh88VyIYxUTmfW_9VtZ20Q</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor in Buddhism (Permanent)</h4>



<p>University of Cambridge, UK</p>



<p>Deadline: December 9<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.jobs.ac.uk/job/CUR720/university-assistant-professor-in-buddhism">https://www.jobs.ac.uk/job/CUR720/university-assistant-professor-in-buddhism</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor, Arab and Muslim Studies (Tenure-Track)</h4>



<p>San Francisco State University, US</p>



<p>Deadline: January 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.pageuppeople.com/873/sf/en-us/job/520558/assistant-professor-arab-and-muslim-studies?fbclid=IwAR1JnACzbK98YXHo_PZMjDxTATEDF80oC3_erjc1SFgmR5mVHmIg-0fkuL8">https://careers.pageuppeople.com/873/sf/en-us/job/520558/assistant-professor-arab-and-muslim-studies?fbclid=IwAR1JnACzbK98YXHo_PZMjDxTATEDF80oC3_erjc1SFgmR5mVHmIg-0fkuL8</a></p>



<h2>Fellowships:</h2>



<h4>Hilltop Short-Term Fellowships at Georgetown University</h4>



<p>Deadline: December 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/1cwwLDZy60">https://t.co/1cwwLDZy60</a></p>



<h2>Call For Papers:</h2>



<h4>American Academy of Religion – Eastern International Region</h4>



<p>Queens University, Canada</p>



<p>Deadline: February 1</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://eiraar.org/index.php/regional-news/2023-eir-cfp">2023 EIR Conference – Call for Papers (eiraar.org)</a></p>



<h4>200 Years of <em>Johnson v. M’Intosh</em>: Law, Religion, and Native American Lands</h4>



<p>Deadline: January 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://canopyforum.org/submit/">https://canopyforum.org/submit/</a></p>



<h2>Other:</h2>



<h4>ACLS Buddhism Public Scholars Competition</h4>



<p>Deadline: January 11, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/1cwwLDZy60">https://t.co/1cwwLDZy60</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1669876627907113</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Bloomsbury Essay Prize in Black British History &amp; Christianity</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11889479/bloomsbury-essay-prize-black-british-history-christianity</link>
						<dc:creator>Tommaso Milani</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Prize</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-02-28T00:00:00-05:00">February 28, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>British History / Studies, Race / Ethnic Studies, Race Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p> </p><p>Bloomsbury Central Baptist Church is delighted to announce the creation of the annual <strong>Bloomsbury Essay Prize in Black British History &amp; Christianity</strong>. The prize is awarded for the best essay in Black British History on a topic related to Christianity. The winner is awarded a prize of £300.</p><p><br/>Candidates must be BA or MA students or recently graduated students (the degree should have been awarded no more than 12 months before the submission deadline indicated below). Essays should be between 5,000 and 10,000 words. Footnotes count towards the word limit while the reference list / bibliography does not. Essays must be unpublished at the time of submission and show evidence of original historical research. Essays will be anonymised and examined by a panel of leading academic experts in Black British History and Black Theology.</p><p><br/>Essays must be sent in PDF format to <a href="mailto:essayprize@bloomsbury.org.uk">essayprize@bloomsbury.org.uk</a> together with a 100-word bio by <strong>February 28th, 2023</strong>. The winner will be announced in Spring 2023.</p><p><br/>For any queries, please contact: <a href="mailto:essayprize@bloomsbury.org.uk">essayprize@bloomsbury.org.uk</a>.</p><p> </p><p>More information on Bloomsbury Central Baptist Church, its history and commitment to racial justice can be found at the Church’s website: <a href="https://www.bloomsbury.org.uk/" rel="nofollow">https://www.bloomsbury.org.uk/</a>.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>For any queries, please contact: <strong><a href="mailto:essayprize@bloomsbury.org.uk">essayprize@bloomsbury.org.uk</a></strong>.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:essayprize@bloomsbury.org.uk">essayprize@bloomsbury.org.uk</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.bloomsbury.org.uk/bloomsbury-essay-prize-in-black-british-history-and-christianity/" target="_blank">https://www.bloomsbury.org.uk/bloomsbury-essay-prize-in-black-british-history-and-christianity/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 20:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1669876627907112</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Publication: Women in Judaism: A Multidisciplinary e-Journal New Issue</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/11882392/publication-women-judaism-multidisciplinary-e-journal-new</link>
						<dc:creator>Dina Ripsman Eylon</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Journal</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-12-31T00:00:00-05:00">December 31, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Canada</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Ontario</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><b><span>PRESS RELEASE</span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Toronto, November 28, 2022</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><i><span>Women in Judaism: A Multidisciplinary e-Journal</span></i></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>We are delighted to announce the electronic publication of the new issue of <i>Women in Judaism: A Multidisciplinary e-Journal</i>. The journal can be accessed at </span><a href="http://www.womeninjudaism.org/" rel="nofollow"><span>http://www.womeninjudaism.org</span></a> </span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Founded in 1997, the journal is the first multidisciplinary refereed e-journal solely dedicated to gender-related issues in Judaism.</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span>Vol. 18 No. 2 (2021): </span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span>Articles</span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span><a href="https://wjudaism.library.utoronto.ca/index.php/wjudaism/article/view/39679" rel="nofollow">Does a Male-Dominated Entity Represent the Jewish People? The Claims Conference and Advocacy for a Community</a></span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span>Rachel Blumenthal</span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span><a href="https://wjudaism.library.utoronto.ca/index.php/wjudaism/article/view/39680" rel="nofollow">Transformations and Emergent Themes in American Jewish Women’s History</a></span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span>Hana G. Green</span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span><a href="https://wjudaism.library.utoronto.ca/index.php/wjudaism/article/view/39677" rel="nofollow">The Singer Siblings: Different Views of Hassidic Life</a></span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span>Mara W. Cohen Ioannides</span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span>Ethnographic Interview</span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span><a href="https://wjudaism.library.utoronto.ca/index.php/wjudaism/article/view/39681" rel="nofollow">Inferiority with a Wink of the Eye: Jewish-Yemenite Women's “Feminist” Thesis</a></span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span>Tova Gamliel</span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span>Biographical Essays</span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span><a href="https://wjudaism.library.utoronto.ca/index.php/wjudaism/article/view/39682" rel="nofollow">“An Oasis in the Desert:” Dr. Garson Romalis and the Struggle to Maintain Access to Abortion in Canada</a></span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span>R. R. Broter</span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span>Book Reviews</span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span><a href="https://wjudaism.library.utoronto.ca/index.php/wjudaism/article/view/39683" rel="nofollow">Schwartz, Mimi. Good Neighbors, Bad Times Revisited: New Echoes of My Father’s German Village. New edition. Lincoln: University of Nebraska Press, 2021.</a></span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span>Reviewed by Anna Marie Anderson</span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span><a href="https://wjudaism.library.utoronto.ca/index.php/wjudaism/article/view/39688" rel="nofollow">Teller, Matthew. Nine Quarters of Jerusalem: A New Biography of the Old City. New York, NY: Other Press, 2022.</a></span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span>Reviewed by Elaine Margolin</span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span><a href="https://wjudaism.library.utoronto.ca/index.php/wjudaism/article/view/39684" rel="nofollow">Rothman-Zecher, Moriel. Before All the World: A Novel. New York: Farrar, Straus &amp; Giroux, 2022.</a></span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span>Reviewed by Elaine Margolin</span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Articles, essays, book and media reviews, short notes, and bibliographies from all disciplines in the Humanities and Social Sciences are welcome. Submissions are concurrently accepted and should be made by <b>e-mail</b> to: Dr. Dina Ripsman Eylon, Editor-in-Chief, <i>Women in Judaism: A Multidisciplinary Journal, </i>Email: <a href="mailto:dina.eylon@alum.utoronto.ca">dina.eylon@alum.utoronto.ca</a></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>The journal considers re-printing peer-reviewed papers or chapters from books that are not currently available in any digital format. We are also seeking book reviewers. A complete list of books is available on our Books Received section, which is updated periodically. </span></span></span></p><p> </p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr. Dina Ripsman Eylon, Editor-in-Chief, Women in Judaism: A Multidisciplinary e-Journal</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:dina.eylon@alum.utoronto.ca">dina.eylon@alum.utoronto.ca</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://wjudaism.library.utoronto.ca/index.php/wjudaism/index" target="_blank">https://wjudaism.library.utoronto.ca/index.php/wjudaism/index</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 20:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1669876627907111</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
