<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 12:21:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 12:21:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ May 19, 2023] Talk or similar: Desire and Its Configurations - a GCAS seminar with Prof. Bruce Fink</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/108161</link>
						<description>Venue: rue du Louvre<br/><br/>Speakers at this event: <br/>Creston Davis (GCAS College)<br/><br/><p>The seminar will examine Lacan’s notion of desire as developed in and around Seminar VI: Desire and Its Interpretation (Cambridge, UK: Polity Press, 2019). Various neurotic configurations of desire will be explored, and contrasted with what we find in psychosis.</p>
<p>The seminar will be in English.</p>
<p>For more information, visit GCAS' website: https://gcascollege.ie/bruce-fink-seminar</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 06:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676788629754873</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ May 19, 2023] Talk or similar: Desire and Its Configurations - a GCAS seminar with Prof. Bruce Fink</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/108157</link>
						<description>Venue: rue du Louvre<br/><br/>Speakers at this event: <br/>Creston Davis (GCAS College)<br/><br/><p>The seminar will examine Lacan’s notion of desire as developed in and around Seminar VI: Desire and Its Interpretation (Cambridge, UK: Polity Press, 2019). Various neurotic configurations of desire will be explored, and contrasted with what we find in psychosis.</p>
<p>The seminar will be in English.</p>
<p>For more information, visit GCAS' website: https://gcascollege.ie/bruce-fink-seminar</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 06:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676788629754872</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Women in religion: from spiritual leadership to female empowerment</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/02/16/women-in-religion-from-spiritual-leadership-to-female-empowerment</link>
						<dc:creator>icsah.eu@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, February 16, 2023 - 4:43pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>ICSAH</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:icsahcy1@gmail.com">icsahcy1@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/gender-studies-and-sexuality">gender studies and sexuality</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/medieval">medieval</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/modernist-studies">modernist studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>March 30, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>It is more than a cliché that gender plays a crucial role in religion, as most religious orders in the world were, and currently are, dominated by men. The role of women in cultic settings is, as a rule, secondary, as is also the authority of female ministers of religion, while the social benefits of those appointed with religious duties are also incomparable with the privileges received by men.  This year, we invite proposals that explore the female share in leadership roles related to religion (saints, prophetesses, priestesses, nuns, preachers, witches, shamans and more), and emphasize how their achievements are reflected in history and art. How prominent female figures have compromised men’s secured positions of power in socioreligious structures? What was their role in shaping gender-responsive societies? We encourage also papers that examine through gender lens the impact of religion on civic life by analysing the deeds of women of faith from a political perspective, or deal with cases of political power over religion, in cases of women who achieved to change traditional religious concepts, practices, customs or symbols. We welcome papers that deal with all religious systems from ancient to present times. </p>
<p> </p>
<p>To submit a proposal for a paper or a poster, please send an abstract of 350 words or less to <a href="mailto:icsahcy1@gmail.com" target="_blank">icsahcy1@gmail.com</a> by March 30th, 2023. </p>
<p>The proposed contributions should not have been previously published or accepted for publication elsewhere. Abstracts should include a title, a summary of the presentation, name of the author/s, institutional affiliation and email.  </p>
<p> </p>
<p>Accepted languages: English, French, Italian.  </p>
<p>Conference fee for participants: 50€  </p>
<p>For further information about the conference, please see our website <a href="http://www.icsah.eu/%C2%A0" target="_blank">www.icsah.eu/ </a></p>
<p>Please address any further enquiries to <a href="mailto:icsahcy1@gmail.com" target="_blank">icsahcy1@gmail.com</a></p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 20:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676615828227677</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hieros, Hierophania, Hieroglossia: Visions, Voices, Signs, Signification</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12359942/hieros-hierophania-hieroglossia-visions-voices-signs</link>
						<dc:creator>Fionn Bennett</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-09-14T00:00:00-04:00">September 14, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-09-15T00:00:00-04:00">September 15, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>France</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Indigenous Studies, Languages, Linguistics, Philosophy, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>Presentation</span></span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The organisers of the <i>HHH-</i>2023 conference invite paper proposals from their colleagues in the Human Sciences who can elucidate the hermeneutical and semiotic principles which were operative in the ideas that peoples in earlier times and in non-Western cultures entertained about the languages they spoke. We are particularly interested in proposals which investigate the belief that, in one guise or another, language is “a gift from the Gods to men”. What does this mean? Why was such a conceit taken seriously? What counted as “the Sacred”? What hermeneutic and semiotic ingenuity was utilised to interpret what it betokened and in forging these interpretations into signs, significance and language? </span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The interest of seeking answers to these questions isn’t limited to everything that is fascinating about these enigmas all unto themselves. It also creates an opportunity to gain as yet unsuspected insights into the meaning-affording potential of words and language. More than that, it offers us a framework and a perspective from which to identify and typify the limits and shortcoming of currently dominant ideas pertaining to the nature, vocation, applications and “apophantic” powers of language.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><b><span><span><span><span>Conference theme and objectives</span></span></span></span></b></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Ancient Egypt, Vedic India, China of the Shang dynasty, the Hellenes at the time of Homer, the Celts, the Aztecs and cultures the world over all believed that the language they spoke was masterminded and forged for them by some higher-than-mortal agency. Just how starkly this contrasts with “language science” in our religiously post‑religious modern age needs no explanation. For us it is simply absurd to maintain that language is anything but a tool devised by <i>homo symbolicus</i> to be able to interact purposively and productively with others of his kind. And yet this view is problematic. </span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>First because the “roots” of all the languages we use to discredit ancient lores about “glottogony” are themselves the products of precisely the kind of mythologies we wish to exorcise from any discussion about language. Second, the assumption that there is something “backward” or “superstitious” about these “exotic” examples of speculation pertaining to the origin of language is now, quite understandably, considered to be the scholarly corollary of a “colonialist” attitude towards “<i>la mentalité primitive</i>”. Third, many authoritative voices in cutting edge, game-changing thought in literary theory and semiotics regularly appeal to “supra‑rational” agencies and actants to supply their theorisation with what cannot be supplied by being “rational” about where language comes from, the nature of its signifying powers, and quite simply what it is. Finally, by thoughtlessly assuming that such myths are merely figments of an “unenlightened” mentality, we overlook the possibility that these “irrational” theories may rest upon rationales that a patient analysis of why they were adhered to would demonstrate to be credible in terms of the very criteria used to postulate their worthlessness. </span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Perplexed by all this, the organisers of the 2023 colloquium are looking for contributions from colleagues who can elucidate for their peers why so many communities believed that it made perfect sense to maintain that their speech was a “gift of the Gods to mortals”. </span><span>Why was such a conceit taken seriously? </span><span>What “d</span><span>ivinatory techniques” were involved in apprehending what counted as the Sacred? What hermeneutic and semiotic ingenuity was utilised to interpret what it betokened and in forging these interpretations into signs, significance and language? </span><span>What rationale is at work in the assumption one encounters so often that, in some sense or another, the Divine itself is a living, breathing, </span><i><span><span>pulsatingly resonant</span></span></i><span><span> property of </span></span><span>language and that its constituent words encode, mediate and reveal something “sublime” about their <i>denotata</i>? </span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>The point of raising these questions is not to celebrate or rehabilitate ‘traditional’ belief systems. Nor is it to be a recrimination of views on the nature, vocation and finality of words and language which repudiate the idea that anything mystical or supernatural should be involved in the analysis. What we really want is to enrich and vary the habitual acceptations and applications of linguistics, semiotics and the philosophy of language by exploring what could be significant or worthwhile about theories maintaining that language is an emanationist bye‑product of other-than-mortal agencies, for instance of <i>Gaia</i> or of one of her counterparts.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Obviously, the views of Indologists, Orientalists, Arabists and Indigenous Studies specialists on these points would be greatly appreciated. Idem for colleagues hailing from Ethnolinguistics, Ecosemiotics, Literary Theory, Comparative Poetics, Philology and sundry kindred fields.<br/>But that isn’t all. We also want to learn more about the way obsolete doxas about the divine origins of speech can be repurposed and undergo a rebirth in forms and in places one would least expect to find them. This would be particularly the case as concerns the theories of ostensibly ‘atheist’ <i>avant-garde</i> thinkers like Blanchot, Foucault, Derrida and Lacan as well as of pioneering artists like Hölderlin, Mallarmé, Baudelaire, Artaud, Ponge, Joyce, Eliot, etc.</span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>Suggested Topics</span></span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>We invite papers on topics that may include (but are not limited to):</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ol><li><span><span><span><span>Original research of a critical, comparativist or historical nature on Glottogonic theories, mythologies, folklores, traditions, </span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span>Studies which illuminate (<b><span>a</span></b>) the divinatory techniques involved in apprehending what counted as the Sacred, (<b><span>b</span></b>) the forms in which its effulgence manifested itself (<b><span>c</span></b>) the hermeneutic ingenuity utilised in interpreting what it was believed to mean and (<b><span>d</span></b>) the semiotic engineering mobilised to forge this meaning into signs, significance and language,</span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Critical assessments of the semiotic rationales that are operative in the conceit that language can encode, mediate and be “oversignified” by a higher order, “hieratic” content, significance or meaning, </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span>Contributions from specialists in Ecosemiotics and Ethnolinguistics which elucidate how “animist” cultures assumed that the natural environment had a voice and a language and how the meaning it communicated was translated into human speech,</span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Reflexions on the way that the properties of signs that are presumed to be “hieroglossic” differ from those that are deemed to be “demotic” or “profane”,</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Papers on “the Language of the Gods” <i>vs</i>. “the Language of Mortals”</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Insights into the dynamics of the dialogue which ensues when heterogeneous conceptions of the “Sacred” origin and character of speech encounter one another,</span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>Analyses of what happens to an established model of Sacred speech when it faces challenges to its authority in the name of “reason” or “science” or when facing pressure from societal, cultural, cultural or political changes, </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>The challenges and/or opportunities posed to literary artists when they are required to recognise, respect and celebrate the presumed Sacred character of their language while using it creatively, </span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span>The “deterritorialisation” of tradition-hallowed ideas on the Sacred origins and character of language and its “reterritorialisation” in the thought of contemporary literary theorists and in the works of avant-gardist literary artists. </span></span></span></span></span></span></li></ol><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>This list is only indicative. Anyone can approach the topic as they wish, provided that the subject matter dealt with, and the conclusions drawn from the analyses carried out provide fresh, evidence-based insights that are recognisably relevant to the conference theme.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>Scientific Committee</span></span></span></b></span></span></span></p>
<pre>
<span><span><span><span><span><strong>Ulrika </strong><span><strong>Mårtensson</strong> - </span>Norwe</span></span><span><span>gian University of Science &amp; Technology</span></span></span></span></span>

<span><span><span><span><strong>Ineke</strong><span><strong> Sluiter</strong> - </span>Universiteit Leiden, Holland</span></span></span></span>

<span><span><span><span><strong>Claude </strong><span><strong>Le Fustec </strong>-</span> Université de Rennes II</span></span></span></span>

<span><span><span><span><span><strong>James I. </strong><span><strong>Porter</strong> - U</span></span></span><span><span>niversity of California, Berkeley, U.S.A.</span></span></span></span></span>

<span><span><span><span><strong>Radcliffe G. <span>Edmonds</span> III </strong>- Bryn Mawr College, Pennsylvania, U.S.A.</span></span></span></span>

<span><span><span><span><strong>Giovanni </strong><span><strong>Manetti -</strong> </span>Università di Siena, Italy</span></span></span></span>

<span><span><span><span><strong>Alexis </strong><span><strong>Pinchard</strong> - </span>Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique</span></span></span></span>

<span><span><span><span><strong>Brian </strong><span><strong>Lowrey</strong> - </span>Université de Picardie</span></span></span></span></pre>

<p> </p>
<p><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>Contacting the Conference Organisers and Useful Dates</span></span></span></b></span></span></span></p>
<p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The conference is organised by Fionn <span>Bennett</span> (<span>Cirlep</span>) and Karin <span>Ueltschi</span> (<span>Crimel</span>) and will take place at the Université de Reims (France) on the <b>14<sup>th</sup> and 15<sup>th</sup> of September 2023</b>.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p>
<p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Please submit a proposal by the <b><span>1<sup>st</sup> of</span></b><span> <b>May 2023</b></span></span></span><b> </b><span><span>in English or French (up to 250 words), as well as a short bio-bibliography, to </span></span><a href="mailto:hieroglossia@univ-reims.fr"><b><span>hieroglossia@univ-reims.fr</span></b></a><span><span>. In the aftermath of the conference, a selection of peer reviewed papers will be included in a volume for publication. Feel free to contact us if any questions should arise before submitting your proposal. For additional information, go to our temporary website at: </span></span><a href="https://hieroglossia2023.blogspot.com/" rel="nofollow"><b><span>https://hieroglossia2023.blogspot.com/</span></b></a><span><span>. </span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Fionn Bennett and Karin Ueltschi-Courchinoux</p><p>Université de Reims - Champagne-Ardenne (France)</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:hieroglossia@univ.reims.fr">hieroglossia@univ.reims.fr</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://hieroglossia2023.blogspot.com/" target="_blank">https://hieroglossia2023.blogspot.com/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 18:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676615828227676</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Deadline Approaching: Short-term Research Fellowships at the MHS</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12366102/deadline-approaching-short-term-research-fellowships-mhs</link>
						<dc:creator>Cassie Cloutier</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Fellowship</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-01T00:00:00-05:00">March 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>African American History / Studies, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Military History, Environmental History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><b>MHS Short-Term Fellowships</b></p><p><strong>﻿Deadline: 1 March 2023</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.masshist.org/" rel="nofollow">The Massachusetts Historical Society</a> will offer  more than 15 short-term fellowships to support research using our extensive collections. Most grants will provide a stipend of $3,000 for four weeks of research at the MHS between 1 July 2023 and 30 June 2024. We offer both general awards and topic-specific fellowships, including histories of African Americans, religion, women, the environment, New England, the military, graphic materials, and more! See a complete list below. Applicants need only submit one application to be considered for all short-term opportunities. <a href="https://www.masshist.org/research/fellowships/short-term-research-fellowships" rel="nofollow">Learn more.</a></p><p>Short-term awards are open to advanced graduate students, faculty, and independent scholars. Applicants must be U.S. citizens, hold a green card, or hold a J-1 or F-1 visa that will allow them to accept the stipend.</p><p>Questions? See our <a href="https://www.masshist.org/research/fellowships/faq" rel="nofollow">FAQ</a> or e-mail <a href="mailto:fellowships@masshist.org">fellowships@masshist.org</a>.</p><p><strong><a href="https://masshistfellowships.slideroom.com/#/Login" rel="nofollow">Apply today!</a></strong></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Cassandra Cloutier, Research Coordinator, MHS </p><p><a href="mailto:fellowships@masshist.org">fellowships@masshist.org</a></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:fellowships@masshist.org">fellowships@masshist.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.masshist.org/research/fellowships/short-term-research-fellowships" target="_blank">https://www.masshist.org/research/fellowships/short-term-research-fellowships</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 18:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676615828227675</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Chapter proposals: A force of habit: Nuns in popular culture</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/02/12/call-for-chapter-proposals-a-force-of-habit-nuns-in-popular-culture</link>
						<dc:creator>marcus.harmes@usq.edu.au</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, February 16, 2023 - 9:18am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Marcus Harmes</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:marcus.harmes@usq.edu.au">marcus.harmes@usq.edu.au</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/film-and-television">film and television</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/gender-studies-and-sexuality">gender studies and sexuality</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/popular-culture">popular culture</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>March 31, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Nuns have a presence in cinema as longstanding as the medium itself, including the 1922 horror film <em>Haxan</em>. 2021’s <em>Benedetta</em>, a controversial but successful Paul Verhoeven film, is a recent restatement of the capacity for stories about women religious, or women in vocation normally called nuns, to be the source of powerful and successful works across all conceivable genres.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Statistics show the decline of religion in the western world but religion and its institutions maintain a prominent place in society and in creative outputs. Popular culture interprets, challenges and recreates religious practice and identity. At a time fewer people may be engaging with actual religious organisations or institutions, popular culture is more powerful than ever in shaping perceptions. Sexuality, agency, authority and leadership all register when popular culture turns attention to sisters in religious orders.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Nuns enable a rich array of story-telling types and genres, and character archetypes and stereotypes in both film and television. Nuns are central characters in some of the most popular and notable film and television productions of all time, among them <em>The Sound of Music, Black Narcissus, The Bells of St Mary</em>, and <em>Philomena </em>on the big screen and <em>Call the Midwife</em> and <em>Brides of Christ</em> on television. Alongside these major dramas lurk the disreputable works in the so-called ‘lost continent’ of exploitation and horror, from <em>Silent Night, Deadly Night</em> and <em>American Horror Story </em>to the many films in the ‘nunsploitation’ grindhouse films.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Despite their prevalence in popular culture and the strongly consistent visual aesthetic of cinematic and televisual nuns because of the (often anachronistically retained) habit, the presence and meaning of religious sisters in popular culture has been little interrogated in academic literature.  Rebecca Sullivan’s <em>Visual Habits: Nuns, Feminism and American Postwar Popular culture</em> from 2005 is an important survey but is limited to the United States. Colleen McDannell’s <em>Material Christianity: Religion and Popular Culture in America </em>(1995) is now nearly 30 years old and takes a far wider focus than women religious. This collection therefore will be a timely and exciting opportunity to explore this multitude of works.</p>
<p>While the type and number of popular culture works about nuns is expansive and growing, especially in the years since earlier works on religion in popular culture were written, the specific focus of this collection will be for chapters exploring the appropriation of the imagery and activity of nuns by popular culture in ways that have often, but not universally, created on-screen nuns as a strange, disturbing or even abusive presence. Central to this collection will be exploration of the tensions between actual and fictional nuns and the potential found in genres from drama to comedy and others to raise questions about the identity, actions, reputations and agency of women in religious orders. In actuality, in the western world at least, the number of women pursuing a vocation as a religious is terminally declining. The nuns who remain are often a visually inconspicuous presence as post-Vatican II and other modernising trends mean religious habits are either reduced or wholly abandoned. Alongside and contrary to this real-world decline and visual eclipse, fully habited remain a major element of popular culture.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Nuns and other religious do retain some prominence but because of the number of official commissions and investigations into historic abuse in convent run orphanages, missions, schools, and laundries and from Ireland to Canada to Australia, stories of actual abuse have emerged worse than any possible cinematic horror. Similarly, non-fictional and documentary film making, have opened up tensions in perceptions of nuns from the laudatory presentation of Sister Helen Prejean in first documentary then film about the abolition of the death penalty to the competing portrayals of Mother Teresa in terms of both her public and private personae.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>From these points about the actual and the fictional, there extends exploration of the inherent strangeness of nuns, their vocations and their enclosed lives that frequently registers in popular culture. In short, the institutions western religious orders, the numbers, their viability and their reputations are pursuing complex and challenging trajectories in the modern world. Analogous to these actual issues of identity and practice are the expansive, prominent, and still growing works on nuns in popular culture. In this popular culture, nuns have been many things from the wise and caring presence of Hollywood classics such as <em>The Sound of Music</em>, the sinister and even satanic of horror movies, then sources of female agency, leadership and identity that may be an affront to or challenged by masculine authority such as in <em>Doubt </em>to <em>Two Mules for Sister Sara </em>and <em>Lambs of God</em>, to agents of abuse and neglect seen in <em>The Magdalene Sisters </em>and <em>Philomena</em>. Perhaps most often they are simply a strange and even challenging presence, a stranger to wider society, but still essential to popular culture. It is also important to note that religion is not declining in the global south, and popular culture there may be presenting its own impressions of female religious life.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>There is a diversity of genres and works that could be considered as well as a rich number of themes including:</p>
<p>Comedy (<em>The Flying Nun</em>, <em>Nuns on the Run</em>, <em>Nasty Habits</em>, <em>The Blues Brothers</em>)</p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p>Horror(<em>The Conjuring</em>,<em> The Nun</em>, <em>The Devils</em>, <em>American Horror Story</em>)</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Musicals (<em>Sister Act</em>, <em>The Sound of Music</em>, <em>Nunsense</em>)</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Period drama (<em>Brides of Christ</em>, <em>Call the Midwife</em>, <em>Pillars of the Earth</em>, <em>Extramuros</em>, <em>The Innocents</em>)</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Science fiction (<em>Doctor Who</em>, <em>Warrior Nuns</em>, <em>Revelations</em>, <em>Sarah Jane Adventures</em>)</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Drama (<em>Black Narcissus</em>, <em>Bells of St Mary’s</em>, <em>Nun’s Story</em>, <em>Doubt</em>)</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Crime drama (<em>Father Dowling Mysteries</em>, <em>Sister Boniface Mysteries</em>, <em>Quiet as a Nun</em>)</p>
<p>The representation of nuns and their environments in period and modern settings</p>
<p>Iconography and the semiotics of religion</p>
<p>Feminism and religious authority</p>
<p>Confronting or perpetrating crime and evil</p>
<p>Documentary and non-fiction and the examination of religious histories</p>
<p>Controversies and past injustices</p>
<p>Celebrity nuns or notorious nuns</p>
<p>Nuns who singularise</p>
<p>Public and private lives and the spaces of religious vocation</p>
<p>Other enclosed communities in fictions (finishing schools, academies, sororities)</p>
<p> </p>
<p>We are assembling a special collection of essays that consider addressing the intersection of nuns with popular culture in light of the reflections offered above on fictional and non-fictional representations of nuns and the use and appropriation of their distinctive iconography.</p>
<p>Television and film from different national contexts will be welcome.</p>
<p><strong><em>Advice for contributors</em></strong></p>
<p>If you are interested in contributing to this collection, we ask that you submit an abstract of up to 250 words explaining the focus and approach your proposed essay.  The proposed volume is intended to be scholarly but accessible in tone and approach. Each contribution should be around 6000 words.  Abstracts should be emailed to <a href="mailto:marcus.harmes@usq.edu.au">marcus.harmes@usq.edu.au</a> by March 31st 2023 and contributors with successful abstracts will be notified in mid-April.</p>
<p>Full chapters would be expected by 29 September 2023.</p>
<p>An American publisher is interested in this proposal. Editors are Marcus K Harmes and Meredith Harmes, University of Southern Queensland.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 23:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676615828227674</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hieros, Hierophania, Hieroglossia: Visions, Voices, Signs, Signification</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/02/12/hieros-hierophania-hieroglossia-visions-voices-signs-signification</link>
						<dc:creator>Fionn Bennett</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Thursday, February 16, 2023 - 9:11am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Université de Reims (France)</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:hieroglossia@univ-reims.fr">hieroglossia@univ-reims.fr</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/poetry">poetry</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/theory">theory</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/world-literatures-and-indigenous-studies">world literatures and indigenous studies</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>May 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>Presentation</strong></p>
<p>The organisers of the <em>HHH-</em>2023 conference invite paper proposals from their colleagues in the Human Sciences who can elucidate the hermeneutical and semiotic principles which were operative in the ideas that peoples in earlier times and in non-Western cultures entertained about the languages they spoke. We are particularly interested in proposals which investigate the belief that, in one guise or another, language is “a gift from the Gods to men”. What does this mean? Why was such a conceit taken seriously? What counted as “the Sacred”? What hermeneutic and semiotic ingenuity was utilised to interpret what it betokened and in forging these interpretations into signs, significance and language? The interest of seeking answers to these questions isn’t limited to everything that is fascinating about these enigmas all unto themselves. It also creates an opportunity to gain as yet unsuspected insights into the meaning-affording potential of words and language. More than that, it offers us a framework and a perspective from which to identify and typify the limits and shortcoming of currently dominant ideas pertaining to the nature, vocation, applications and “apophantic” powers of language.</p>
<p><strong>Conference theme and objectives </strong></p>
<p>Ancient Egypt, Vedic India, China of the Shang dynasty, the Hellenes at the time of Homer, the Celts, the Aztecs and cultures the world over all believed that the language they spoke was masterminded and forged for them by some higher-than-mortal agency. Just how starkly this contrasts with “language science” in our religiously post‑religious modern age needs no explanation. For us it is simply absurd to maintain that language is anything but a tool devised by <em>homo symbolicus</em> to be able to interact purposively and productively with others of his kind. And yet this view is problematic.</p>
<p>First because the “roots” of all the languages we use to discredit ancient lores about “glottogony” are themselves the products of precisely the kind of mythologies we wish to exorcise from any discussion about language. Second, the assumption that there is something “backward” or “superstitious” about these “exotic” examples of speculation pertaining to the origin of language is now, quite understandably, considered to be the scholarly corollary of a “colonialist” attitude towards “<em>la mentalité primitive</em>”. Third, many authoritative voices in cutting edge, game-changing thought in literary theory and semiotics regularly appeal to “supra‑rational” agencies and actants to supply their theorisation with what cannot be supplied by being “rational” about where language comes from, the nature of its signifying powers, and quite simply what it is. Finally, by thoughtlessly assuming that such myths are merely figments of an “unenlightened” mentality, we overlook the possibility that these “irrational” theories may rest upon rationales that a patient analysis of why they were adhered to would demonstrate to be credible in terms of the very criteria used to postulate their worthlessness.</p>
<p>Perplexed by all this, the organisers of the 2023 colloquium are looking for contributions from colleagues who can elucidate for their peers why so many communities believed that it made perfect sense to maintain that their speech was a “gift of the Gods to mortals”. Why was such a conceit taken seriously? What “divinatory techniques” were involved in apprehending what counted as the Sacred? What hermeneutic and semiotic ingenuity was utilised to interpret what it betokened and in forging these interpretations into signs, significance and language? What rationale is at work in the assumption one encounters so often that, in some sense or another, the Divine itself is a living, breathing, <em>pulsatingly resonant</em> property of language and that its constituent words encode, mediate and reveal something “sublime” about their <em>denotata</em>?</p>
<p>The point of raising these questions is not to celebrate or rehabilitate ‘traditional’ belief systems. Nor is it to be a recrimination of views on the nature, vocation and finality of words and language which repudiate the idea that anything mystical or supernatural should be involved in the analysis. What we really want is to enrich and vary the habitual acceptations and applications of linguistics, semiotics and the philosophy of language by exploring what could be significant or worthwhile about theories maintaining that language is an emanationist bye‑product of other-than-mortal agencies, for instance of <em>Gaia</em> or of one of her counterparts.</p>
<p>Obviously, the views of Indologists, Orientalists, Arabists and Indigenous Studies specialists on these points would be greatly appreciated. Idem for colleagues hailing from Ethnolinguistics, Ecosemiotics, Literary Theory, Comparative Poetics, Philology and sundry kindred fields. <br/> But that isn’t all. We also want to learn more about the way obsolete doxas about the divine origins of speech can be repurposed and undergo a rebirth in forms and in places one would least expect to find them. This would be particularly the case as concerns the theories of ostensibly ‘atheist’ <em>avant-garde</em> thinkers like Blanchot, Foucault, Derrida and Lacan as well as of pioneering artists like Hölderlin, Mallarmé, Baudelaire, Artaud, Ponge, Joyce, Eliot, etc.</p>
<p><strong>Suggested Topics</strong></p>
<p>We invite papers on topics that may include (but are not limited to):</p>
<p>- Original research of a critical, comparativist or historical nature on Glottogonic theories, mythologies, folklores, traditions,</p>
<p>- Studies which illuminate (<strong>a</strong>) the divinatory techniques involved in apprehending what counted as the Sacred, (<strong>b</strong>) the forms in which its effulgence manifested itself (<strong>c</strong>) the hermeneutic ingenuity utilised in interpreting what it was believed to mean and (<strong>d</strong>) the semiotic engineering mobilised to forge this meaning into signs, significance and language,</p>
<p>- Critical assessments of the semiotic rationales that are operative in the conceit that language can encode, mediate and be “oversignified” by a higher order, “hieratic” content, significance or meaning,</p>
<p>- Contributions from specialists in Ecosemiotics and Ethnolinguistics which elucidate how “animist” cultures assumed that the natural environment had a voice and a language and how the meaning it communicated was translated into human speech,</p>
<p>- Reflexions on the way that the properties of signs that are presumed to be “hieroglossic” differ from those that are deemed to be “demotic” or “profane”,</p>
<p>- Papers on “the Language of the Gods” <em>vs</em>. “the Language of Mortals”</p>
<p>- Insights into the dynamics of the dialogue which ensues when heterogeneous conceptions of the “Sacred” origin and character of speech encounter one another,</p>
<p>- Analyses of what happens to an established model of Sacred speech when it faces challenges to its authority in the name of “reason” or “science” or when facing pressure from societal, cultural, cultural or political changes,</p>
<p>- The challenges and/or opportunities posed to literary artists when they are required to recognise, respect and celebrate the presumed Sacred character of their language while using it creatively,</p>
<p>- The “deterritorialisation” of tradition-hallowed ideas on the Sacred origins and character of language and its “reterritorialisation” in the thought of contemporary literary theorists and in the works of avant-gardist literary artists.</p>
<p>This list is only indicative. Anyone can approach the topic as they wish, provided that the subject matter dealt with, and the conclusions drawn from the analyses carried out provide fresh, evidence-based insights that are recognisably relevant to the conference theme.</p>
<p><strong>Details about the Conference Organisers and other useful Information</strong></p>
<p>The conference is organised by Fionn Bennett (Cirlep) and Karin Ueltschi (Crimel) and will take place at the Université de Reims (France) on the <strong>14th and 15th of September 2023</strong>.</p>
<p>Please submit a proposal by the <strong>1st of</strong> <strong>May 2023</strong>in English or French (up to 250 words), as well as a short bio-bibliography, to <a href="mailto:hieroglossia@univ-reims.fr"><strong>hieroglossia@univ-reims.fr</strong></a>. In the aftermath of the conference, a selection of peer reviewed papers will be included in a volume for publication. Feel free to contact us if any questions should arise before submitting your proposal. For additional information, go to our temporary website at: <a href="https://hieroglossia2023.blogspot.com/"><strong>https://hieroglossia2023.blogspot.com/</strong></a>.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 21:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676615828227673</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – February 14, 2023</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-february-14-2023/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find a new job opportunity, 2 fellowship programs, and 3 Call for Papers.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 32!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Visiting Assistant Professor of Religious Studies (1-year position, emphasis on Islamic studies)</h4>



<p>Bates College, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: March 8, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://apply.interfolio.com/121113?fbclid=IwAR22aphR2AvWJhvI4Y76AJRIeSJvbUJFSeoQ4rQARW8o_nXwgskB4JS1Flw">https://apply.interfolio.com/121113?fbclid=IwAR22aphR2AvWJhvI4Y76AJRIeSJvbUJFSeoQ4rQARW8o_nXwgskB4JS1Flw</a></p>



<h4>AAR/SBL Job Forum</h4>



<p><a href="https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search">https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search</a></p>



<h2>Fellowships:</h2>



<h4>Martin Marty Center Student Opportunities (Summer Internship Program, and Sacred Writes Workshop)</h4>



<p>Deadline: March 3, 2023 &amp; April 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://martycenter.org/knowledge-exchange/results?section=student-opportunities">https://martycenter.org/knowledge-exchange/results?section=student-opportunities</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>The Legacy and Limits of Vatican II in an Age of Crisis: Gender, Race, Abuse, and the Living Catholic Tradition.</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12333457/legacy-and-limits-vatican-ii-age-crisis-gender-race-abuse-and">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12333457/legacy-and-limits-vatican-ii-age-crisis-gender-race-abuse-and</a></p>



<h4>Symposium: Gender and Voice in Japanese Art</h4>



<p>Deadline: February 25, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12327512/symposium-gender-and-voice-japanese-art">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12327512/symposium-gender-and-voice-japanese-art</a></p>



<h4>Jerusalem – From the Umbilicus Mundi to the Four Corners of the Earth and Back</h4>



<p>Deadline: February 28, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12319365/cfp-jerusalem-umbilicus-mundi-four-corners-earth-and-back">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12319365/cfp-jerusalem-umbilicus-mundi-four-corners-earth-and-back</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676529424663441</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Interfaith Dialogue 2023 : Interfaith Dialogue What is a perfect human being?</title>
			<link>http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=171786&amp;copyownerid=179615</link>
						<description>Interfaith Dialogue What is a perfect human being? [Berlin, Online] [Mar 17, 2023 - Mar 17, 2023]</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 06:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676356629355917</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Interfaith Dialogue  2023 : Interfaith Dialogue What is a perfect human being?</title>
			<link>http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=171787&amp;copyownerid=179616</link>
						<description>Interfaith Dialogue What is a perfect human being? [Berlin, Online] [Mar 17, 2023 - Mar 17, 2023]</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 06:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676356629355916</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Political Theology and the State of Exce 2023 : NEW DEADLINE FOR SUBMISSIONS: CALL FOR PAPERS - Political Theology and the State of Exception: Critical readings on the centenary of Political Theology &amp; Roman Catholicism and Poli</title>
			<link>http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=171861&amp;copyownerid=173363</link>
						<description>NEW DEADLINE FOR SUBMISSIONS: CALL FOR PAPERS - Political Theology and the State of Exception: Critical readings on the centenary of Political Theology &amp; Roman Catholicism and Poli</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 06:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676356629355915</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ March 2, 2023] Conference or similar: Self-Narratives and Irony</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/107997</link>
						<description>Venue: Deakin Downtown, Level 12, 727 Collins Street<br/><br/><p>Over the last fourty years, the philosophical question surrounding the problem of personal identity has undergone two important and concomitant transformations. These transformations have durably affected theories of personal identity. Departing from the metaphysical ground of analysis of the modalities of identification and temporal synthesis of the Ego, a significant number of historical or systematic works devoted to the question of the Self have first sought to re-inscribe the problem a practical perspective. This allows the question of personal identity to be approached in narrower frameworks: those of moral philosophy or philosophy of action (Williams B. 1982, Frankfurt 1988, Ricœur 1990, Taylor 1992, Korsgaard 1996, Moran 2001, Larmore 2004, Descombes 2014). A second important displacement in the question of personal identity occurred in parallel to this first transformation with the rise of the narrative approaches of the self (MacIntyre 1981, Ricœur 1984, Bruner 1987 and 1991, Schechtman 1996, 73, Hutto 2007, Goldie 2012), engaging an in-depth reinterpretation of the question of individual identity and initiating the "narrative turn" of identity theories (Stokes 2015, 166).</p>

<p>These two lines of transformation have converged and come together over the last fifteen years through various works seeking to take advantage of the resources offered by narrative identity theories in order to propose a new model of "practical identity” (Williams S. 2004, Atkins 2008, Atkins and Mackenzie 2008, Korsgaard 2009, Mackenzie and Poltera 2010, Davenport 2012). However, this philosophical attempt to renew our understanding of personal identity highlight the practical dimension of the self and paid little attention to the various forms of self-detachment that narratives allow. The use of irony in the construction of narratives is paradigmatic of such forms of self-detachment, which enable the narrator to take a critical distance towards the characters of the story told.</p>

<p>The purpose of this workshop is to analyze the forms of self-detachment that ironical self-narratives involve, so as to highlight the role and philosophical significance of irony with regard to the constitution of one’s identity. </p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 06:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676356629355914</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Funding opportunities from the Friends Historical Association</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12364483/funding-opportunities-friends-historical-association</link>
						<dc:creator>Jordan Landes</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Grant</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-04-15T00:00:00-04:00">April 15, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The Friends Historical Association is pleased to offer funding to support contributions to the field of Quaker history. There are three grant opportunities: project support, publication subventions, and research funds. All opportunities run on the same cycle, and applications are due April 15, 2023. Details about each opportunity and application instruction are provided at <a href="https://www.quakerhistory.org/grants" rel="nofollow">https://www.quakerhistory.org/grants</a>.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Friends Historical Association<br/>c/o Haverford College Library<br/>370 Lancaster Ave. <br/>Haverford, PA 19041-1392</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:president@quakerhistory.org">president@quakerhistory.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.quakerhistory.org/grants" target="_blank">https://www.quakerhistory.org/grants</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 19:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676356629355913</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Symposium Understanding Judaism: New Approaches to Rabbinic Literature</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12346767/symposium-understanding-judaism-new-approaches-rabbinic</link>
						<dc:creator>Albertina Oegema</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Symposium</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-20T00:00:00-04:00">March 20, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-21T00:00:00-04:00">March 21, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Netherlands</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Ancient History, Classical Studies, Humanities, Jewish History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span>The board of the </span>Compendia Rerum Iudaicarum ad Novum Testamentum<span> is<span> thrilled to extend our invitation to you to join the two-day symposium ‘Understanding Judaism: New Approaches to Rabbinic Literature’, featuring honored Yale Professor Christine Hayes and other notable speakers such as Professors Peter Tomson, Martin Goodman, Lutz Doering, and Annette Merz. </span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>The symposium addresses the ways recent developments in the study of rabbinic literature affect long-standing modes of approaching culture, religion, and society in Late Antiquity. The seminar will take place at Utrecht University (Utrecht, the Netherlands) on March 20th and 21st, 2023, and celebrates the publication of Christine Hayes’ groundbreaking volume of </span></span><a href="https://brill.com/display/title/62292" rel="nofollow"><i><span><span><span><span>The Literature of the Sages: A Re-Visioning</span></span></span></span></i></a><a href="https://brill.com/display/title/62292" rel="nofollow"><span><span><span><span> (CRINT 16; Leiden: Brill, 2022)</span></span></span></span></a><span><span>. The symposium will include a masterclass featuring up-and-coming students and their work. For internationally based scholars, there are possibilities to attend the symposium virtually.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><b><span>Symposium Programme</span></b></span></span></p><p><span><span><u><span>Day 1</span></u></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span>09:30 Entrance</span></i></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>10:00 Eric Ottenheijm, Opening</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>10:10 Introduction by Peter J. Tomson </span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>10:45</span><i><span> Coffee/Tea Break</span></i></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>11:00 Christine Hayes, Introductory Lecture</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>11:45 Questions from the audience</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span>12:15 Lunch</span></i></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>13.30 Responses by three external specialists: Lutz Doering; Martin Goodman; Annette Merz.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span>15.00 Tea Break </span></i></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>15.30 Response of prof. Hayes</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Followed by a general discussion on the volume’s merits and final words by Eric Ottenheijm</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span>16.00 Reception</span></i></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span>18:00 Dinner (invited guests only)</span></i></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><u><span><span>Day 2</span></span></u></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span>09:30 Entrance</span></i></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>10:00 Eric Ottenheijm, Opening</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>10:15 Masterclass (part I)</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span>11:30 Coffee/Tea break</span></i></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>11:45 Masterclass (part II)</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><i><span>13:00 Lunch</span></i></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span>You can sign up with this sign-up link to register for the symposium or receive more information:</span><a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeqcJ4MQm2xbnH5mrHEvGW7YLW0JFPmS5kRr6yHe7nYshg-Kw/viewform?usp=sf_link" rel="nofollow"><span><span><span> <span><span><span>https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeqcJ4MQm2xbnH5mrHEvGW7YLW0JFPmS5kRr6yHe7nYshg-Kw/viewform?usp=sf_link</span></span></span></span></span></span></a> </span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Moreover, it would be most beneficial if you could spread the word about this exciting event. Please send this e-mail to anyone interested in the event in your network. Attached are both the poster and the social media post of the event. If you have channels to post about the event, please feel free to do so. Additionally, printing the poster and hanging it up in relevant areas near you would be beneficial to us. We have provided a caption for you to copy and paste into social media posts. </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>“On the 20th and 21st of March, 2023, CRINT presents the unique opportunity to learn from Yale Professor Christine Hayes through attending the Symposium on ‘Understanding Judaism’ in Utrecht. Sign up with this link to register for the symposium, receive more information, or view the program:</span><a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeqcJ4MQm2xbnH5mrHEvGW7YLW0JFPmS5kRr6yHe7nYshg-Kw/viewform?usp=sf_link" rel="nofollow"><span><span><span> <span><span><span>https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeqcJ4MQm2xbnH5mrHEvGW7YLW0JFPmS5kRr6yHe7nYshg-Kw/viewform?usp=sf_link</span></span></span></span></span></span></a><span><span>"</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Thank you for all your support. We hope to see you at the symposium soon and welcome all questions you may have. </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Kind regards, </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>On behalf of Dr. Eric Ottenheijm, Utrecht University, Chair of the CRINT Foundation.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Dr. Albertina Oegema, Radboud University Nijmegen / J. Gutenberg University Mainz, Secretary of the CRINT Foundation. </span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span>Perlei Toor (Student Assistant)</span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr. Albertina Oegema <br/><span><span><span><span><span><span>Radboud University Nijmegen / J. Gutenberg University Mainz, Secretary of the CRINT Foundation</span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:albertina.oegema@uni-mainz.de">albertina.oegema@uni-mainz.de</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 18:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676356629355912</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ July 1, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Philosophy and the Age of the Anthropocene</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/107937</link>
						<description><p>The term “Anthropocene” was coined by geologists in the latter half of the 20th century and popularized in the early 2000s to propose a new definition of the current geological era as one in which human activity has become the most dominant factor in the earth’s processes. The claim, proponents argue, is evidenced by phenomena such as anthropogenic climate change, loss of biodiversity, ocean acidification, and more. At the same time, philosophers have increasingly utilized the term to pursue related questions. What is the human? What is nature? Where does responsibility lie for the current ecological crisis? Would a category other than the human—such as capitalism, industrial technology, colonialism, or anthropocentric thinking itself—be more fruitful for these analyses? This work also dovetails with questions about the current relationship between philosophy and science more generally, such as questions about the legitimacy of using and expanding the meanings of scientific terms in extra-scientific contexts. Moreover, if we accept the term’s use, we are faced with practical and ethical questions: Can living in the Anthropocene be sustainable in the long term, or would moving beyond the Anthropocene even be possible? This conference aims to develop these and related questions.</p>
<p>We welcome abstract submissions from all academic disciplines, approaches, and traditions. Presentations will be 20 minutes long with a 15-20 minute Q&amp;A to follow each presentation. Potential paper topics include, but are not limited to, the following:</p>
<p>• The history of the term Anthropocene</p>
<p>• The dating of the Anthropocene</p>
<p>• Weighing the risks and urgency of various potential existential threats, including nuclear technology, superintelligence, artificial intelligence, climate change, nanotechnology, and gene editing technology</p>
<p>• Proposed definitions of the Anthropocene from different disciplinary perspectives</p>
<p>• Critical perspectives (including feminism, philosophy of race, decolonial thought, Marxism, deconstruction, and critical theory) on the Anthropocene</p>
<p>• Alternative proposed names for the Anthropocene, such as the Capitalocene (Moore), Chthulucene, Plantationocene (Haraway), Eurocene, and/or Entropocene (Stiegler)</p>
<p>• Philosophical approaches to humans, nature, and technology from figures in the history of philosophy</p>
<p>• Topics in philosophical anthropology related to the meaning of the human and the relation of the human to nature, non-human animals, and technology</p>
<p>• Topics in environmental philosophy related to the meaning of terms such as nature, ecosystem, environment, biodiversity, and sustainability</p>
<p>• Topics in the philosophy of science related to the use and expansion of meanings of scientific terms in extra-scientific contexts</p>
<p>• Practical, ethical, and political questions concerned with the possibility of living in or exiting the Anthropocene (such as Stiegler’s notion of the Neganthropocene)</p>
<p><strong>Please send 300-500 word abstracts prepared for anonymous review in PDF format to: depaulconference2023@gmail.com.</strong></p>
<p><strong>In the body of your email, please include 1) Name, 2) Institutional Affiliation, 3) Title of Paper, and 4) Contact Information (Email and phone number).</strong></p>
<p>While we are unable to provide any assistance with travel costs, the conference organizers will do our very best to find free accommodation for conference presenters who do not receive institutional funding for travel to conferences.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 06:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676270235358730</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ September 29, 2023 -  September 30, 2023] Conference or similar: Philosophy and the Age of the Anthropocene</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/107933</link>
						<description>Venue: 2350 N Kenmore Ave<br/><br/><p>The term “Anthropocene” was coined by geologists in the latter half of the 20th century and popularized in the early 2000s to propose a new definition of the current geological era as one in which human activity has become the most dominant factor in the earth’s processes. The claim, proponents argue, is evidenced by phenomena such as anthropogenic climate change, loss of biodiversity, ocean acidification, and more. At the same time, philosophers have increasingly utilized the term to pursue related questions. What is the human? What is nature? Where does responsibility lie for the current ecological crisis? Would a category other than the human—such as capitalism, industrial technology, colonialism, or anthropocentric thinking itself—be more fruitful for these analyses? This work also dovetails with questions about the current relationship between philosophy and science more generally, such as questions about the legitimacy of using and expanding the meanings of scientific terms in extra-scientific contexts. Moreover, if we accept the term’s use, we are faced with practical and ethical questions: Can living in the Anthropocene be sustainable in the long term, or would moving beyond the Anthropocene even be possible? This conference aims to develop these and related questions.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 06:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1676270235358729</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
