<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 12:20:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 12:20:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>Call for research and papers - Applications 2023 - Terrorism and counter-terrorism in Africa (from prevention to development, including strategy, doctrines, economic issues, etc.)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12666093/call-research-and-papers-applications-2023-terrorism-and</link>
						<dc:creator>Amel Larivière</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-05-07T00:00:00-04:00">May 7, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>African History / Studies, Political Science, Public Policy, Religious Studies and Theology, Social Sciences</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The Strategic Research Institute ("IRS") of the International Counter-Terrorism Academy ("AILCT"), located in Côte d'Ivoire, is launching its third call for research on issues related to terrorism and counter-terrorism in Africa (broad definitions, from prevention to development, including strategy, economic issues, etc.).</p><hr/><p><strong>Dealine : 7 May 2023</strong></p><p>The application must be sent by email to : <a href="mailto:candidature.bourse@ailct-irs.org">candidature.recherche@ailct-irs.org</a></p><p><strong>More information : <a href="https://issuu.com/ailct-irs/docs/2023-ailct-strategic_research_institute-call_for_r" rel="nofollow">Call for application 2023 - Call for resear - CT in Africa - AILCT</a></strong></p><p>Any question, contact : <a href="mailto:question.bourse@ailct-irs.org">question.recherche@ailct-irs.org</a></p><hr/><p><strong>Overview of the International Counter-terrorism Academy (AILCT) Research Programme</strong></p><p>The Strategic Research Institute (IRS) is a hybrid entity designed to be at the crossroads of a university research centre and a think tank. It is both anchored in its immediate environment - the International Counter-Terrorism Academy ( AILCT) - and fully open to the outside world.<br/>The actions and activities of the Institute are structured to meet three main objectives:</p><ul><li>Contributing to the academic debate.</li><li>Advocacy and policy influence.</li><li>Organising and contributing to dialogue between researchers, civil society and African state institutions.</li></ul><p><strong>Main themes</strong></p><ul><li>Drones and the fight against terrorism in Africa<ul><li>The use of drones by African armies in the fight against terrorism: strategic and ethical issues.</li><li>The resources and strategies employed by armed terrorist groups to counter the use of drones by state security forces</li></ul></li><li>Relations between security forces and various security actors in Africa: militias, vigilantes and auxiliary forces</li><li>A critical approach to African armies' counter-terrorism doctrines</li></ul><ul><li>Terrorism and Territoriality in Africa</li><li>Including the issue of governance</li><li>Terrorisms in Africa: doctrines and ideologies</li></ul><ul><li>Preventing terrorism in Africa: current situation, assessment, good practices and prospective<ul><li>Including :<ul><li>Prevention of radicalisation</li><li>Prevention of attacks</li><li>Prevention of political violence</li><li>Roles of government and civil society</li><li>Use of technology</li><li>Location-based approach, people-based approach, community-based approach</li></ul></li></ul></li></ul><ul><li>Relationships between security forces and civil society in the fight against terrorism in Africa</li><li>Financing of terrorism in Africa</li></ul><ul><li>Women and terrorism in Africa</li></ul><ul><li>Information landscapes and the treatment of terrorism in the African media</li><li>African victims of terrorism</li><li>African states, civil society and the refugees of terrorism</li></ul><p><em>Comparative approaches are welcomed.</em></p><p><strong>Eligility requirements</strong></p><ul><li>The researcher(s) must be affiliated to a recognised institution that can receive funds and sign an agreement;</li><li>The researcher(s) must hold a PhD;</li><li>A team may also include doctoral students. In this case, the scientific coordinator must hold a PhD and be an experienced researcher.</li><li>The researcher(s) must be able to demonstrate publications in peer reviewed journals;</li><li>The proposed research project must be in line with the research themes detailed above;</li><li>The researcher(s) must have an excellent command of French or English (level C1/C2).</li></ul><p><strong>The application </strong></p><p>Apllication (1 single file in PDF format) must include :</p><ul><li>A letter of motivation specifying the interest and relevance of the project (2 pages max)</li><li>The research project (12 pages max), including:<ul><li>The terms of reference of the project (bibliographical references required)</li><li>The context</li><li>The state of the Art</li><li>The general problematic and research axes</li><li>The objectives</li><li>The research programme's implementation conditions</li><li>The method and methodology</li><li>The duration of the research project</li><li>A chronogram or provisional timetable including the transmission of the deliverables detailed below</li><li>A detailed budget</li></ul></li><li>A presentation of the organisation that will receive the funds</li><li>The bank details of the organisation that will receive the funds</li><li>A biography of the scientific coordinator</li></ul><p>For each researcher :</p><ul><li>A CV (2 pages max)</li><li>A professional card or certificate mentioning the researcher home institution</li><li>A copy of the PhD diploma</li><li>A copy of an ID</li></ul><p><strong>Expectations and deliverables</strong></p><p>The final document must be an unpublished study:</p><ul><li>Of at least 45 pages, excluding footnotes, bibliography, illustrations and annexes</li><li>Combining methodological approaches</li><li>Richly referenced</li><li>Illustrated by at least one field study or interviews, the results of which are clearly outlined</li><li>Illustrated with graphs, maps and other data</li><li>Includes a bibliography and any other documents useful for understanding the study in annex</li><li>And meets international academic quality standards.</li></ul><p>In order to follow the progress of the commissioned study, the following deliverables are required:</p><ul><li>Deliverable 1: detailed plan, problem statement, bibliography and consolidated timeline</li><li>Deliverable 2: Intermediate report and progress review.</li><li>Deliverable 3: final study (submission for correction and validation by the AILCT)</li><li>Deliverable 4: final study (integration of eventual modifications requested by the AILCT and validation)</li></ul><p>These deliverables must be integrated in the research project (especially in the timeline).</p><hr/><p><strong>Dealine : 7 May 2023</strong></p><p>The application must be sent by email to : <a href="mailto:candidature.bourse@ailct-irs.org">candidature.recherche@ailct-irs.org</a></p><p><strong>More information : <a href="https://issuu.com/ailct-irs/docs/2023-ailct-strategic_research_institute-call_for_r" rel="nofollow">Call for application 2023 - Call for resear - CT in Africa - AILCT</a></strong></p><p>Any question, contact : <a href="mailto:question.bourse@ailct-irs.org">question.recherche@ailct-irs.org</a></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><div><div><div><div><div><div><div><p>Amel Larivière</p><p>Academic Coordinator, <strong>Académie Internationale de Lutte Contre le Terrorisme</strong></p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:question.recherche@ailct-irs.org">question.recherche@ailct-irs.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://issuu.com/ailct-irs/docs/2023-ailct-strategic_research_institute-call_for_r" target="_blank">https://issuu.com/ailct-irs/docs/2023-ailct-strategic_research_institute-call_for_r</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 17:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1681364232511087</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP for 15th Annual James A. Rawley Graduate Conference in the Humanities</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12709251/cfp-15th-annual-james-rawley-graduate-conference-humanities</link>
						<dc:creator>Joslyn Edmond</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-16T00:00:00-04:00">June 16, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Nebraska</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Cultural History / Studies, European History / Studies, Race / Ethnic Studies, Women's &amp; Gender History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><strong>15th Annual James A. Rawley Graduate Conference in the Humanities</strong></p><p>University of Nebraska-Lincoln | October 5-6, 2023</p><p>Call for Papers</p><p>Submission Deadline: June 16, 2023</p><p><strong>Keynote Speaker</strong>: Dr. Cathleen Cahill, Pennsylvania State University.</p><p>Author of <em>Recasting the Vote: How Women of Color Transformed the Suffrage Movement </em>(2020)</p><p>The History Graduate Student Association at the University of Nebraska –Lincoln invites all graduate students to the James A. Rawley Graduate Conference in the Humanities, <strong>October 5-6, 2023</strong>. The two-day conference will be held on UNL’s City Campus in downtown Lincoln (a hybrid option will be available toensure greater accessibility). The Rawley Graduate Conference strives to serve the larger humanities community and looks forward to submissions from those of the humanities and other related fields, including but not limited to: History, Classical/Modern Languages, Religious Studies, English, Philosophy, Anthropology, Sociology, Environmental Studies, Ethnic Studies, Medieval/Renaissance Studies, Women and Gender Studies, and Digital Humanities. While all proposals are invited, preference will be given to those which address the 2023 theme of:</p><p><strong>‘In Between the Lines: Race, Class, Gender and the IntersectionsBetween’</strong></p><p>This conference is intended to interpret the concept of ‘In Between the Lines’ broadly. Therefore, submissions are encouraged which address this conceptin any way. Potential projects might explore any of the above categories as they pertain to society, cultures, politics, economies, and religions across the world over time. Projects may connect to this year’s theme through traditional academia, digital humanities work, alternative academic avenues,or other methodologies and perspectives. Please do not find these suggestions to be limiting-submissions are encouraged to push the concept of ‘In Between the Lines’ as it fits the applicant's research.</p><p><strong>Submission Guidelines:</strong></p><p>Individual papers, panels, posters, roundtables, and digital projects are all equally and highly encouraged. Submissions for individual papers/projects should include a one-paragraph abstract (300-word max) which includes the topic, core argument and methodology of the project. Applicants should also provide a current one-page CV. For full panels, submissions should include a session title, one-page session abstract and brief explanation as to how each project fits the theme of the panel. For relevant papers/projects, please include a one-paragraph abstract (300-word max) of each paper/project in the panel, as well as a one-page CV for all participants. Panel submissions should also specify the name and contact information for the panel chair. <em>Please also list any AV and/or accessibility concerns with all submissions.</em></p><p>The James A. Rawley Graduate Conference will be offering a <strong>Research Lightning Round</strong>. Presenters will be given <strong>5 minutes </strong>to pitch their research before a panel of commentators from various specializations and receive feedback on their research. Interested participants should follow Individual Submission guidelines and specify in their email to the Rawley Planning Committee that they seek application to the lightning round.<strong>Seats are limited, but projects do not need to fit conference theme.</strong></p><p><strong>Questions?</strong> If you have any questions or concerns about the upcoming conference or about proposals, please do not hesitate to ask the planning committee.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>All materials should be emailed to the 2023 Rawley Planning Committee at <strong><a href="mailto:rawleyunl@gmail.com">rawleyunl@gmail.com</a> </strong>no later than Friday, June 16th, 2023, with the subject line “Rawley 2023 Submission –[Last Name, First Name].”</p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:rawleyunl@gmail.com">rawleyunl@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://history.unl.edu/2023-Rawley" target="_blank">https://history.unl.edu/2023-Rawley</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1681364232511086</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – April 12, 2023</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-april-12-2023/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find 5 new job opportunities, 2 Fellowships, 9 Calls for Papers, 6 upcoming conference/speakers, and 4 other events.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 33!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>University of Michigan Press Marketing Associate</h4>



<p>USA</p>



<p>Deadline: April 24, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.umich.edu/job_detail/232929/marketing-associate">https://careers.umich.edu/job_detail/232929/marketing-associate</a></p>



<h4>Marketing &amp; Operations Coordinator for Longleaf Services (affiliate of UNC Press)</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://uncpress.org/now-hiring-marketing-operations-coordinator/">https://uncpress.org/now-hiring-marketing-operations-coordinator/</a></p>



<h4>Minerva Recruitment Job Listings Cite (with areas specifically tailored for Ph.D.)</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://minerva-recruitment.com/">Minerva Recruitment – Higher Education Graduate Jobs, UK &amp; Worldwide (minerva-recruitment.com)</a></p>



<h4>Postdoctoral Fellow – Social Survey (1 year, possibility of renewal)</h4>



<p>Purdue University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: Until filled</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.purdue.edu/job/West-Lafayette-Post-Doctoral-Research-Associate-IN-47906/855274200/">https://careers.purdue.edu/job/West-Lafayette-Post-Doctoral-Research-Associate-IN-47906/855274200/</a></p>



<h4>Postdoctoral Fellow – GIS and Spatial Studies (1 year, possibility of renewal)</h4>



<p>Purdue University, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: Until filled</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://careers.purdue.edu/job/West-Lafayette-Post-Doctoral-Research-Associtae-IN-47906/855274600/">https://careers.purdue.edu/job/West-Lafayette-Post-Doctoral-Research-Associtae-IN-47906/855274600/</a></p>



<h4>AAR/SBL Job Forum</h4>



<p><a href="https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search">https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search</a></p>



<h2>Fellowships:</h2>



<h4>Holstein Dissertation Fellowships</h4>



<p>UC Riverside, USA</p>



<p>Deadline: May 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://religiousstudies.ucr.edu/holstein-chair/holstein-dissertation-fellowship">https://religiousstudies.ucr.edu/holstein-chair/holstein-dissertation-fellowship</a></p>



<h4>American Society of Learned Societies</h4>



<p>Deadline: Varies depending on fellowship </p>



<p>More Information: https://www.acls.org/competitions-and-deadlines/</p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>Early Career Workshop on Islamic Thought and Anglophone Philosophy</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 24<sup>th</sup>, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/110221">https://philevents.org/event/show/110221</a></p>



<h4>Political Theology Network</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 2, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://twitter.com/lukasik_c/status/1645429777266884612?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw">https://twitter.com/lukasik_c/status/1645429777266884612?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw</a></p>



<h4>Religious Symbolism and Symbolic Logic (4<sup>th</sup> World Congress on Logic and Religion)</h4>



<p>Date: May 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/110137">CFP: Religious Symbolism and Symbolic Logic – PhilEvents</a></p>



<h4>Global China in a Religious World</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 20, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12680637/global-china-religious-world">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12680637/global-china-religious-world</a></p>



<h4>Senses, Emotions, and Experience in the History of Education</h4>



<p>Deadline: June 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/1PcGC7TDy7">https://t.co/1PcGC7TDy7</a></p>



<h4>“Life is War”: Social Militarization and the Culture of Prayers in Africa</h4>



<p>Deadline: June 24, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12675996/%E2%80%9Clife-war%E2%80%9D-social-militarization-and-culture-prayers-africa">“Life is War”: Social Militarization and the Culture of Prayers in Africa | H-Announce | H-Net</a></p>



<h4>The Esoteric Theology of Philip K. Dick</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/04/03/the-esoteric-theology-of-philip-k-dick">https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/04/03/the-esoteric-theology-of-philip-k-dick</a></p>



<h4>Rethinking Racism Through Embodiment and Place (A thematic stream for the 47<sup>th</sup> Annual Meeting of the International Merleau-Ponty Circle)</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/109945">https://philevents.org/event/show/109945</a></p>



<h4>Religion and Spirituality in Everyday Life</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: https://www.degruyter.com/journal/key/opth/html</p>



<h2>Conferences:</h2>



<h4>Preserving and Analyzing Digital Texts</h4>



<p>Zoom</p>



<p>Date: April 21, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://rarebookschool.org/all-programs/events/preserving-and-analyzing-digital-texts/">https://rarebookschool.org/all-programs/events/preserving-and-analyzing-digital-texts/</a></p>



<h4>Religious Symbolism and Symbolic Logic (4<sup>th</sup> World Congress on Logic and Religion)</h4>



<p>Sinaia Romania</p>



<p>Date: September 3-8, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/110133">https://philevents.org/event/show/110133</a></p>



<h4>Gender and Sexuality in Greek Mythology</h4>



<p>Online</p>



<p>Date: May 2-16, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12676109/2nd-online-conference-cycle-gender-and-sexuality-greek">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12676109/2nd-online-conference-cycle-gender-and-sexuality-greek</a></p>



<h4>Religion &amp; Drugs</h4>



<p>Online</p>



<p>Date: April 20, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://twitter.com/csraac/status/1644011131311194114?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw">https://twitter.com/csraac/status/1644011131311194114?s=12&amp;t=1bnDmUb5FfsZQqiXR0lnJw</a></p>



<h4>American Academy of Religion – Eastern International Region Conference</h4>



<p>Canada</p>



<p>Date: May 5-7, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/Uw6x3zncsr">https://t.co/Uw6x3zncsr</a></p>



<h4>Newberry Scholarly Seminars </h4>



<p>Date: Varies depending on the seminar</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.newberry.org/research/scholarly-seminars?category=religion-culture&amp;start=&amp;end=">Scholarly Seminars | Newberry Library</a></p>



<h2>Miscellaneous:</h2>



<h4>Teacher Advisory Council 2023-2024</h4>



<p>National Humanities Center</p>



<p>Deadline: May 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://nationalhumanitiescenter.org/education-programs/teacher-advisory-council/application/">https://nationalhumanitiescenter.org/education-programs/teacher-advisory-council/application/</a></p>



<h4>Training for Ph.D.’s Looking for Jobs Outside the Academy</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://fromphdtolife.com/phd-job-search-help/?utm_source=Twitter&amp;utm_medium=tweet&amp;utm_campaign=daily&amp;utm_id=tw">https://fromphdtolife.com/phd-job-search-help/?utm_source=Twitter&amp;utm_medium=tweet&amp;utm_campaign=daily&amp;utm_id=tw</a></p>



<h4>Graduate Student Institute – Islam in the Contemporary World</h4>



<p>Virginia, USA</p>



<p>Date: May 30 – June 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12686832/graduate-student-institute-islam-contemporary-world">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12686832/graduate-student-institute-islam-contemporary-world</a></p>



<h4>Beyond the Professoriate: Transforming CV into Resume</h4>



<p>Date: April 19, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: https://institutions.beyondprof.com/webinar-why-you-cant-convert-a-cv-into-a-resume/</p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1681364232511085</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ June 16, 2023] Conference or similar: Author-meets-critics workshop with  Michael Rosen, Senator Joseph S. Clark Professor of Ethics in Politics and Government at Harvard University</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/110229</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p>Author-meets-critics workshop with</p>
<p><strong>Michael Rosen</strong></p>
<p>Senator Joseph S. Clark Professor of Ethics in Politics and Government at Harvard University</p>
<p><strong>Distinguished Fellow at the Klassik Stiftung Weimar 2023</strong></p>
<p><strong>The Shadow of God. <br/></strong><strong>Kant, Hegel, and the Passage from Heaven to History</strong></p>
<p><strong>in Weimar, 16th June 2023</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Once in the West, our lives were bounded by religion. Then we were guided out of the darkness of faith, we are often told, by the cold light of science and reason. To be modern was to reject the religious for the secular and rational. In a bold retelling of philosophical history, Michael Rosen explains the limits of this story, showing that many modern and apparently secular ways of seeing the world were in fact profoundly shaped by religion. The key thinkers, Rosen argues, were the German Idealists, as they sought to reconcile reason and religion. It was central to Kant’s philosophy that, if God is both just and assigns us to heaven or hell for eternity, we must know what is required of us and be able to choose freely. In trying to live moral lives, Kant argued, we are engaged in a collective enterprise as members of a “Church invisible” working together to achieve justice in history. As later Idealists moved away from Kant’s ideas about personal immortality, this idea of “historical immortality” took center stage. Through social projects that outlive us we maintain a kind of presence after death. Conceptions of historical immortality moved not just into the universalistic ideologies of liberalism and revolutionary socialism but into nationalist and racist doctrines that opposed them. But how, after global wars and genocide, can we retain faith in any conception of shared moral progress and, if not, what is to become of the idea of historical immortality? That is our present predicament. A seamless blend of philosophy and intellectual history, <em>The Shadow of God</em> is a profound exploration of secular modernity’s theistic inheritance.</p>
<p><strong>Organizers: </strong></p>
<p>Prof. Dr. Helmut Heit (Weimar): Helmut.Heit@klassik-stiftung.de</p>
<p>Dr. Kai-Uwe Hoffmann (Jena): kai-uwe.hoffmann@uni-jena.de</p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 05:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1681277827624968</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ May 20, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Author-meets-critics workshop with  Michael Rosen, Senator Joseph S. Clark Professor of Ethics in Politics and Government at Harvard University</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/110233</link>
						<description><p>The Klassik Stiftung Weimar invites applications for an author-meets-critics workshop with</p>

<p><strong>Michael Rosen</strong></p>
<p>Senator Joseph S. Clark Professor of Ethics in Politics and Government at Harvard University</p>
<p><strong>Distinguished Fellow at the Klassik Stiftung Weimar 2023</strong></p>

<p><strong>The Shadow of God. <br/></strong><strong>Kant, Hegel, and the Passage from Heaven to History</strong></p>
<p><strong>in Weimar, 16th June 2023</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Once in the West, our lives were bounded by religion. Then we were guided out of the darkness of faith, we are often told, by the cold light of science and reason. To be modern was to reject the religious for the secular and rational. In a bold retelling of philosophical history, Michael Rosen explains the limits of this story, showing that many modern and apparently secular ways of seeing the world were in fact profoundly shaped by religion. The key thinkers, Rosen argues, were the German Idealists, as they sought to reconcile reason and religion. It was central to Kant’s philosophy that, if God is both just and assigns us to heaven or hell for eternity, we must know what is required of us and be able to choose freely. In trying to live moral lives, Kant argued, we are engaged in a collective enterprise as members of a “Church invisible” working together to achieve justice in history. As later Idealists moved away from Kant’s ideas about personal immortality, this idea of “historical immortality” took center stage. Through social projects that outlive us we maintain a kind of presence after death. Conceptions of historical immortality moved not just into the universalistic ideologies of liberalism and revolutionary socialism but into nationalist and racist doctrines that opposed them. But how, after global wars and genocide, can we retain faith in any conception of shared moral progress and, if not, what is to become of the idea of historical immortality? That is our present predicament. A seamless blend of philosophy and intellectual history, <em>The Shadow of God</em> is a profound exploration of secular modernity’s theistic inheritance.</p>
<p>Interested researchers working in all areas of philosophy are encouraged to submit abstracts for 30-minute presentations devoted to critical discussion of any of the themes of the book. To have a presentation considered for the workshop, please send an abstract of no more than 300 words to the organizers by Thursday 20 May. We aim to make decisions by 1 June. </p>
<p><strong>Dates and Deadines</strong></p>
<p>Deadline for submissions: May 20, 2023 | Notification: June 1, 2023 | Workshop: June 16, 2023</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Organizers: </strong></p>
<p>Prof. Dr. Helmut Heit (Weimar): Helmut.Heit@klassik-stiftung.de</p>
<p>Dr. Kai-Uwe Hoffmann (Jena): kai-uwe.hoffmann@uni-jena.de</p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 05:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1681277827624967</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ June 16, 2023] Conference or similar: Author-meets-critics workshop with  Michael Rosen, Senator Joseph S. Clark Professor of Ethics in Politics and Government at Harvard University</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/110229</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p>Author-meets-critics workshop with</p>
<p><strong>Michael Rosen</strong></p>
<p>Senator Joseph S. Clark Professor of Ethics in Politics and Government at Harvard University</p>
<p><strong>Distinguished Fellow at the Klassik Stiftung Weimar 2023</strong></p>
<p><strong>The Shadow of God. <br/></strong><strong>Kant, Hegel, and the Passage from Heaven to History</strong></p>
<p><strong>in Weimar, 16th June 2023</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Once in the West, our lives were bounded by religion. Then we were guided out of the darkness of faith, we are often told, by the cold light of science and reason. To be modern was to reject the religious for the secular and rational. In a bold retelling of philosophical history, Michael Rosen explains the limits of this story, showing that many modern and apparently secular ways of seeing the world were in fact profoundly shaped by religion. The key thinkers, Rosen argues, were the German Idealists, as they sought to reconcile reason and religion. It was central to Kant’s philosophy that, if God is both just and assigns us to heaven or hell for eternity, we must know what is required of us and be able to choose freely. In trying to live moral lives, Kant argued, we are engaged in a collective enterprise as members of a “Church invisible” working together to achieve justice in history. As later Idealists moved away from Kant’s ideas about personal immortality, this idea of “historical immortality” took center stage. Through social projects that outlive us we maintain a kind of presence after death. Conceptions of historical immortality moved not just into the universalistic ideologies of liberalism and revolutionary socialism but into nationalist and racist doctrines that opposed them. But how, after global wars and genocide, can we retain faith in any conception of shared moral progress and, if not, what is to become of the idea of historical immortality? That is our present predicament. A seamless blend of philosophy and intellectual history, <em>The Shadow of God</em> is a profound exploration of secular modernity’s theistic inheritance.</p>
<p><strong>Organizers: </strong></p>
<p>Prof. Dr. Helmut Heit (Weimar): Helmut.Heit@klassik-stiftung.de</p>
<p>Dr. Kai-Uwe Hoffmann (Jena): kai-uwe.hoffmann@uni-jena.de</p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 05:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1681277827624966</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[Today] Talk or similar: THE LOGICAL PROBLEM OF EVIL FROM A PARACONSISTENT PERSPECTIVE</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/110289</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/>Speakers at this event: <br/>Itala Maria Loffredo D'Ottaviano (University of Campinas)<br/>Itala Maria Loffredo D'Ottaviano (Universidade Estadual de Campinas)<br/><br/><p>Dear Colleague,<br/><br/>You are invited to participate in the next session of the Logic and Religion Webinar Series which will be held on <strong>April 13 (Thursday), 2023</strong>, at <strong>4pm CET</strong> with the topic:</p>
<p><strong>THE LOGICAL PROBLEM OF EVIL FROM A PARACONSISTENT PERSPECTIVE</strong></p>
<p><strong>Speaker:</strong> Itala Maria Loffredo D'Ottaviano (University of Campinas, Brazil).<strong><br/>Chair:</strong> Evandro Gomes (State University of Maringá, Brazil).</p>
<p>Please, register in advance to access the zoom link:<br/>https://www.logicandreligion.com/webinars</p>
<p> <br/>Abstract: After a brief discussion on the presence of <u>paraconsistent approaches in the history of Western thought</u>, in special in ancient and medieval times, we will characterize paraconsistent logic, created only during the 20th century. Recently, <u>Bertato (2021)</u> presented a proposal for a Formal Natural Theology through a first-order logical theory, by formally introducing fundamental concepts such as divine, necessary, and supreme. In this presentation, based on Bertato’s system, we will propose a paraconsistent underlying approach to deal with the Logical Problem of Evil, such that the presence of contradictions does not lead to logical triviality.</p>
<p>Join us 5 minutes prior to the beginning of the session!<br/> <br/>With best wishes,</p>
<p>-- </p>
<p>Francisco de Assis Mariano <br/>The University of Missouri-Columbia<br/>LARA Secretary</p></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 05:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1681277827624965</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ May 20, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Author-meets-critics workshop with  Michael Rosen, Senator Joseph S. Clark Professor of Ethics in Politics and Government at Harvard University</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/110233</link>
						<description><p>The Klassik Stiftung Weimar invites applications for an author-meets-critics workshop with</p>

<p><strong>Michael Rosen</strong></p>
<p>Senator Joseph S. Clark Professor of Ethics in Politics and Government at Harvard University</p>
<p><strong>Distinguished Fellow at the Klassik Stiftung Weimar 2023</strong></p>

<p><strong>The Shadow of God. <br/></strong><strong>Kant, Hegel, and the Passage from Heaven to History</strong></p>
<p><strong>in Weimar, 16th June 2023</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Once in the West, our lives were bounded by religion. Then we were guided out of the darkness of faith, we are often told, by the cold light of science and reason. To be modern was to reject the religious for the secular and rational. In a bold retelling of philosophical history, Michael Rosen explains the limits of this story, showing that many modern and apparently secular ways of seeing the world were in fact profoundly shaped by religion. The key thinkers, Rosen argues, were the German Idealists, as they sought to reconcile reason and religion. It was central to Kant’s philosophy that, if God is both just and assigns us to heaven or hell for eternity, we must know what is required of us and be able to choose freely. In trying to live moral lives, Kant argued, we are engaged in a collective enterprise as members of a “Church invisible” working together to achieve justice in history. As later Idealists moved away from Kant’s ideas about personal immortality, this idea of “historical immortality” took center stage. Through social projects that outlive us we maintain a kind of presence after death. Conceptions of historical immortality moved not just into the universalistic ideologies of liberalism and revolutionary socialism but into nationalist and racist doctrines that opposed them. But how, after global wars and genocide, can we retain faith in any conception of shared moral progress and, if not, what is to become of the idea of historical immortality? That is our present predicament. A seamless blend of philosophy and intellectual history, <em>The Shadow of God</em> is a profound exploration of secular modernity’s theistic inheritance.</p>
<p>Interested researchers working in all areas of philosophy are encouraged to submit abstracts for 30-minute presentations devoted to critical discussion of any of the themes of the book. To have a presentation considered for the workshop, please send an abstract of no more than 300 words to the organizers by Thursday 20 May. We aim to make decisions by 1 June. </p>
<p><strong>Dates and Deadines</strong></p>
<p>Deadline for submissions: May 20, 2023 | Notification: June 1, 2023 | Workshop: June 16, 2023</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Organizers: </strong></p>
<p>Prof. Dr. Helmut Heit (Weimar): Helmut.Heit@klassik-stiftung.de</p>
<p>Dr. Kai-Uwe Hoffmann (Jena): kai-uwe.hoffmann@uni-jena.de</p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 05:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1681277827624964</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>2023 call for applications - PhD grants (fellowships)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12665886/2023-call-applications-phd-grants-fellowships</link>
						<dc:creator>Amel Larivière</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Grant</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-05-07T00:00:00-04:00">May 7, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>African History / Studies, Social Sciences, Religious Studies and Theology, Political Science, Public Policy</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><strong>Dealine : 7 May 2023</strong></p><p>The application must be sent by email to : <a href="mailto:candidature.bourse@ailct-irs.org">candidature.bourse@ailct-irs.org</a></p><p><strong>More information : <a href="https://issuu.com/ailct-irs/docs/2023-ailct-strategic_research_institute-call_for_a" rel="nofollow">Call for application 2023 - Grant-Fellowship programme - PhD - AILCT</a></strong></p><p>Any question, contact : <a href="mailto:question.bourse@ailct-irs.org">question.bourse@ailct-irs.org</a></p><hr/><p><strong>Purpose of the programme</strong></p><p>This programme aims to foster the development of doctoral theses on terrorism and counterterrorism issues (in their broadest definition).</p><p>In addition to an annual financial support, the programme aims to :</p><ul><li>Accompany the recipient doctoral students in the development of their research projects, through the organisation of seminars on methods and methodologies;</li><li>Give PhD students the opportunity to discover the work of recognised researchers and discuss with them via the organisation of conferences and workshops;</li><li>Provide awardees with the opportunity to broaden their scope of analysis by connecting them with practitioners trained at the Academy ;</li><li>Support PhD candidates throughout their professional integration into the academic world, by offering professional development seminars ;</li><li>Support awardees in the development of a professional network and reputation in their field of research, through the promotion of their work at events organised by the Académie</li><li>Internationale de Lutte Contre le Terrorisme (AILCT) or through the publications issued by its Strategic Research Institute (IRS).</li></ul><p><em>The programme offers one-year renewable grants. For PhD candidates in the final stages of their thesis, support is available for a shorter time frame.</em></p><p><strong>Eligility requirements</strong></p><ul><li>The applicant has been registered in a full-time PhD programme for at least six months;</li><li>The thesis project must be related to the research themes developed within the Strategic Research Institute ( IRS) of the AILCT;</li><li>The applicant must have an excellent command of either French or English (level C1/C2), and an intermediate level (level B1/B2 minimum) in the other language.</li></ul><p><strong>Money</strong></p><ul><li>The grant amounts to 7 500€ per year (from June 2023 to May 2024).</li><li>For PhD students in the final stages of their degree, a pro rata will be applied.</li></ul><p><strong>Main themes</strong></p><ul><li>Drones and the fight against terrorism in Africa<ul><li>The use of drones by African armies in the fight against terrorism: strategic and ethical issues.</li><li>The resources and strategies employed by armed terrorist groups to counter the use of drones by state security forces</li></ul></li><li>Relations between security forces and various security actors in Africa: militias, vigilantes and auxiliary forces</li><li>A critical approach to African armies' counter-terrorism doctrines</li></ul><ul><li>Terrorism and Territoriality in Africa</li><li>Including the issue of governance</li><li>Terrorisms in Africa: doctrines and ideologies</li></ul><ul><li>Preventing terrorism in Africa: current situation, assessment, good practices and prospective<ul><li>Including :<ul><li>Prevention of radicalisation</li><li>Prevention of attacks</li><li>Prevention of political violence</li><li>Roles of government and civil society</li><li>Use of technology</li><li>Location-based approach, people-based approach, community-based approach</li></ul></li></ul></li></ul><ul><li>Relationships between security forces and civil society in the fight against terrorism in Africa</li><li>Financing of terrorism in Africa</li></ul><ul><li>Women and terrorism in Africa</li></ul><ul><li>Information landscapes and the treatment of terrorism in the African media</li><li>African victims of terrorism</li><li>African states, civil society and the refugees of terrorism</li></ul><p><em>Comparative approaches are welcomed.</em></p><p><strong>The application </strong></p><p>Submit an apllication (1 single file in PDF format) including :</p><ul><li>A cover letter specifying the interest and relevance of the project and of the applicant's project in relation to the research themes prioritised by the Academy (2 pages max);</li><li>A presentation of the thesis (5 pages max), including :<ul><li>Context and state of the Art</li><li>The aim of the project</li><li>Method and methodology</li><li>Duration and planning of the thesis</li><li>Steps already taken and goals already achieved</li><li>Communication and promotion strategy</li><li>Chronogram or timetable</li><li>Grants already secured (if applicable)</li></ul></li><li>An example of academic writing (article, dissertation, research paper);</li><li>A transcript of grades earned in the current programme;</li><li>Un CV (2 pages max) ;</li><li>A certificate of enrolment in a PhD programme;</li><li>A letter of support from a researcher;</li><li>A letter of support from the thesis supervisor;</li><li>A copy of your ID.</li></ul><hr/><p><strong>Dealine : 7 May 2023</strong></p><p>The application must be sent by email to : <a href="mailto:candidature.bourse@ailct-irs.org">candidature.bourse@ailct-irs.org</a></p><p><strong>More information : <a href="https://issuu.com/ailct-irs/docs/2023-ailct-strategic_research_institute-call_for_a" rel="nofollow">Call for application 2023 - Grant-Fellowship programme - PhD - AILCT</a></strong></p><p>Any question, contact : <a href="mailto:question.bourse@ailct-irs.org">question.bourse@ailct-irs.org</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><div><div><div><div><div><p>Amel Larivière</p><p>Academic Coordinator, <strong>Académie Internationale de Lutte Contre le Terrorisme</strong></p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:question.bourse@ailct-irs.org">question.bourse@ailct-irs.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://issuu.com/ailct-irs/docs/2023-ailct-strategic_research_institute-call_for_a" target="_blank">https://issuu.com/ailct-irs/docs/2023-ailct-strategic_research_institute-call_for_a</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 19:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1681277827624963</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A Constitutional Culture: New England and the Struggle Against Arbitrary Rule in the Restoration Empire</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12706040/constitutional-culture-new-england-and-struggle-against</link>
						<dc:creator>Lauren Lemley</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-05-10T00:00:00-04:00">May 10, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>American History / Studies, British History / Studies, Colonial and Post-Colonial History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span>Join us for a virtual discussion with author Adrian Chastain Weimer to celebrate the release of <a href="https://www.pennpress.org/9781512823974/a-constitutional-culture/" rel="nofollow"><em>A Constitutional Culture: New England and the Struggle Against Arbitrary Rule in the Restoration Empire</em></a>.</span></p><p><span>In <em>A Constitutional Culture</em>, Weimer uncovers the story of how, more than a hundred years before the American Revolution, colonists pledged their lives and livelihoods to the defense of local political institutions against arbitrary rule.</span></p><p><span>With the return of Charles II to the English throne in 1660, the puritan-led colonies faced enormous pressure to conform to the crown’s priorities. Charles demanded that puritans change voting practices, baptismal policies, and laws, and he also cast an eye on local resources such as forests, a valuable source of masts for the English navy. In the face of this threat to local rule, colonists had to decide whether they would submit to the commissioners’ authority, which they viewed as arbitrary because it was not accountable to the people, or whether they would mobilize to defy the crown.</span></p><p><span>Those resisting the crown included not just freemen (voters) but also people often seen as excluded or marginalized such as non-freemen, indentured servants, and women. Together they crafted a potent regional constitutional culture in defiance of Charles II that was characterized by a skepticism of metropolitan ambition, a defense of civil and religious liberties, and a conviction that self-government was divinely sanctioned.</span></p><p><span>The event is free to all, but registration is required via this link: </span><a href="https://us06web.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_FXyxEovIRASqkdZXmkR5Mg" rel="nofollow"><span>https://us06web.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_FXyxEovIRASqkdZXmkR5Mg</span></a></p><p><span>After registering, you will receive a confirmation email containing information about joining the webinar.</span></p><p><span>For more information, please email <a href="mailto:info@14beacon.org?subject=A%20Constitutional%20Culture">info@14beacon.org</a>.</span></p><p><br/><span><strong>SPEAKER BIO</strong></span></p><p><strong>Adrian Chastain Weimer</strong> is Professor of History at Providence College. Her first book, <a href="https://academic.oup.com/book/8688" rel="nofollow"><em>Martyrs' Mirror: Persecution and Holiness in Early New England</em></a> (Oxford, 2011) explores how puritans, Baptists, and Quakers imagined themselves within historical narratives of persecution, especially the stories in John Foxe’s “Book of Martyrs.” Weimer's work has been honored with the Jane Dempsey Douglass Prize and the Michael Kennedy Prize, and has been supported by the American Council of Learned Societies, the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation, the Folger Shakespeare Library, the Young Scholars in American Religion program, and through National Endowment for the Humanities Long-term Research Fellowships at the Massachusetts Historical Society and the American Antiquarian Society.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Lauren Lemley<br/>Communications Manager<br/>Congregational Library &amp; Archives</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:info@14beacon.org">info@14beacon.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.congregationallibrary.org/events/constitutionalculture" target="_blank">https://www.congregationallibrary.org/events/constitutionalculture</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 19:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1681277827624962</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP: Princeton University Early Career Workshop in Islamic Thought and Anglophone Philosophy – May 17-19</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12702158/cfp-princeton-university-early-career-workshop-islamic-thought</link>
						<dc:creator>Kamal Ahmed</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-04-24T00:00:00-04:00">April 24, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>New Jersey</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Islamic History / Studies, Philosophy, Religious Studies and Theology, Humanities</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><b><span>CALL FOR PAPERS</span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span>Princeton University Early Career Workshop on Islamic Thought and Anglophone Philosophy – May 17-19</span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>New Deadline: <b><u>April 24th, 2023</u></b></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span>Description</span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>The Princeton Project in Philosophy and Religion invites abstracts for an early career workshop in Islamic thought and Anglophone philosophy to be held from <b><u>May 17-19</u></b>.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>The workshop seeks to foster research that places Islamic thought in conversation with Anglophone philosophy. Islamic thought is widely conceived to include classical philosophy (<i>falsafah</i>), post-classical philosophy (<i>ḥikmah</i>), philosophical theology (<i>kalām</i>), logic (<i>mantiq</i>), legal philosophy (<i>ʾuṣūl al-fiqh</i>), spiritual philosophy (<i>taṣawwuf</i>), rhetoric (<i>balaghaḥ</i>), and the philosophy of language (<i>lughah</i>). All areas of contemporary Anglophone philosophy will be considered and submissions in epistemology and philosophy of religion are especially encouraged.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>We invite abstracts from many disciplines including Philosophy, Near Eastern and Islamic studies, Religion and Theology, and History that are intellectually rigorous and focus on theoretical analysis of philosophical arguments while remaining conscious of historical context. </span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Submissions are open to advanced graduate students (ABD or equivalent) and early career recent PhD recipients (within three years of receiving their PhD who have not secured a tenure-track position). Applicants should be able to demonstrate interdisciplinary knowledge and training appropriate to their research proposal.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Each successful applicant will be allocated two faculty respondents, one from Philosophy and one from Islamic studies, who will provide comments on their paper and serve as a commentator at the workshop. Andrew Chignell (Princeton), Lara Buchak (Princeton), and John Pittard (Yale) will be the faculty respondents from Philosophy. Frank Griffel (Yale) and two other faculty members will be the faculty respondents from Islamic thought and intellectual history.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>Travel, lodging, and meal expenses of participants will be covered by the project.</span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><b><span>Stage I:</span></b><span> Applicants complete the application form and submit a cv and abstract of <b>500-750 words</b>, not including references and bibliography, by <b><u>April 24<sup>th</sup>, 2023.</u></b> You should have a draft research paper in progress by the time of submission.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span>Stage II: </span></b><span>If accepted, participants will be required to submit a final paper of <b>4000 – 6000 words</b> by <b><u>May 10th, 2023</u>.</b></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span>To apply and submit an abstract</span></b><span>, please fill in the form on the following link: <a href="https://forms.gle/jF2qbZ2EkUoPBN8c8" rel="nofollow">https://forms.gle/jF2qbZ2EkUoPBN8c8</a></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span>For questions, please contact <a href="mailto:philosophy.islamicworld@gmail.com">philosophy.islamicworld@gmail.com</a>.</span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span>The Early Career Workshop on Islamic Thought and Anglophone Philosophy is hosted by “Building Collaborative Research Networks Across the Islamic Scholarly Tradition and Western Philosophy,” a project funded by a grant from the John Templeton Foundation.</span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Kamal Ahmed, <a href="http://www.pppr.princeton.edu/" rel="nofollow">www.pppr.princeton.edu</a>, <a href="mailto:krahmed@princeton.edu">krahmed@princeton.edu</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:philosophy.islamicworld@gmail.com">philosophy.islamicworld@gmail.com</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 19:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1681277827624961</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ April 24, 2023] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/110221</link>
						<description>Publication Name: Early Career Workshop on Islamic Thought and Anglophone Philosophy<br/><br/><p><strong>CFP: Princeton University Early Career Workshop in Islamic Thought and Anglophone Philosophy</strong></p>
<p><strong>CALL FOR PAPERS</strong></p>
<p><strong>Early Career Workshop on Islamic Thought and Anglophone Philosophy – May 17-19</strong></p>
<p>New Deadline: <strong><u>April 24th, 2023</u></strong></p>
<p><strong>Description</strong></p>
<p>The Princeton Project in Philosophy and Religion invites abstracts for an early career workshop in Islamic thought and Anglophone philosophy to be held from <strong><u>May 17-19</u></strong>.</p>
<p>The workshop seeks to foster research that places Islamic thought in conversation with Anglophone philosophy. Islamic thought is widely conceived to include classical philosophy (<em>falsafah</em>), post-classical philosophy (<em>ḥikmah</em>), philosophical theology (<em>kalām</em>), logic (<em>mantiq</em>), legal philosophy (<em>ʾuṣūl al-fiqh</em>), spiritual philosophy (<em>taṣawwuf</em>), rhetoric (<em>balaghaḥ</em>), and the philosophy of language (<em>lughah</em>). All areas of contemporary Anglophone philosophy will be considered and submissions in epistemology and philosophy of religion are especially encouraged.</p>
<p>We invite abstracts from many disciplines including Philosophy, Near Eastern and Islamic studies, Religion and Theology, and History that are intellectually rigorous and focus on theoretical analysis of philosophical arguments while remaining conscious of historical context.</p>
<p>Submissions are open to advanced graduate students (ABD or equivalent) and early career recent PhD recipients (within three years of receiving their PhD who have not secured a tenure-track position). Applicants should be able to demonstrate interdisciplinary knowledge and training appropriate to their research proposal.</p>
<p>Each successful applicant will be allocated two faculty respondents, one from Philosophy and one from Islamic studies, who will provide comments on their paper and serve as a commentator at the workshop. Andrew Chignell (Princeton), Lara Buchak (Princeton), and John Pittard (Yale) will be the faculty respondents from Philosophy. Frank Griffel (Yale) and two other faculty members will be the faculty respondents from Islamic thought and intellectual history.</p>
<p>Travel, lodging, and meal expenses of participants will be covered by the project.</p>
<p><strong>Stage I:</strong> Applicants complete the application form and submit a cv and abstract of <strong>500-750 words</strong>, not including references and bibliography, by <strong><u>April 24th, 2023.</u></strong> You should have a draft research paper in progress by the time of submission.</p>
<p><strong>Stage II: </strong>If accepted, participants will be required to submit a final paper of <strong>4000 – 6000 words</strong> by <strong><u>May 10th, 2023</u>.</strong></p>
<p><strong>To apply and submit an abstract</strong>, please fill in the form on the following link: <a href="https://forms.gle/jF2qbZ2EkUoPBN8c8">https://forms.gle/jF2qbZ2EkUoPBN8c8</a></p>
<p>For questions, please contact <a href="mailto:philosophy.islamicworld@gmail.com">philosophy.islamicworld@gmail.com</a>.</p>
<p>The Early Career Workshop on Islamic Thought and Anglophone Philosophy is hosted by “Building Collaborative Research Networks Across the Islamic Scholarly Tradition and Western Philosophy,” a project funded by a grant from the John Templeton Foundation.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1681191424158960</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ May 1, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: Religious Symbolism and Symbolic Logic</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/110137</link>
						<description><p>On the one hand symbolism is important in most religions, on the other hand modern logic is often  characterized as symbolic.  This workshop, part of the 4th World Congress on Logic and Religion, explores the relation bewteen these two symbolic approaches. Suggested topics include - but are not limited to - the following:</p>
<p>- Boole's symbolic mathematical notation in logic and abstract religious notions  </p>
<p>- Zoroastrianism's dualism, Pythagoras's table of oppositions, Trinity Christian triangle, Islamic geometrical objects and the theory of oppositions</p>
<p>- Yin/Yang and the notion of complementary contradiction</p>
<p>- the symbolism of the cross, crucification, negation and abnegation </p>
<p>- Venn symbolic logic, Venn diagrams and their application to understanding of religious phenomena</p>
<p>- the universal quantifier and <em>catho</em>licism as a religion for all </p>
<p>-  is the existential quantifier really symbolizing existence? </p>
<p>- Cabala symbolism and logic in <em>Alice's Adventures in Wonderland</em> by Charles Dodgson, aka Lewis Carroll, deacon in the Church of England and symbolic logician</p>
<p>- logical "interpretation" of Gödel's proof of the existence of God in symbolic logic</p>
<p>Submit a one page abstract by May 1st to jyb.logos@gmail.com</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 05:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680932232851034</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ September 3, 2023 -  September 8, 2023] Conference or similar: Religious Symbolism and Symbolic Logic</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/110133</link>
						<description>Venue: Octavian Goga Street, 4<br/><br/><p>On the one hand symbolism is important in most religions, on the other hand modern logic is often  characterized as symbolic.  This workshop, part of the 4th World Congress on Logic and Religion, explores the relation bewteen these two symbolic approaches. Suggested topics include - but are not limited to - the following:</p>
<p>- Boole's symbolic mathematical notation in logic and abstract religious notions  </p>
<p>- Zoroastrianism's dualism, Pythagoras's table of oppositions, Trinity Christian triangle, Islamic geometrical objects and the theory of oppositions</p>
<p>- Yin/Yang and the notion of complementary contradiction</p>
<p>- the symbolism of the cross, crucification, negation and abnegation </p>
<p>- Venn symbolic logic, Venn diagrams and their application to understanding of religious phenomena</p>
<p>- the universal quantifier and <em>catho</em>licism as a religion for all </p>
<p>-  is the existential quantifier really symbolizing existence? </p>
<p>- Cabala symbolism and logic in <em>Alice's Adventures in Wonderland</em> by Charles Dodgson, aka Lewis Carroll, deacon in the Church of England and symbolic logician</p>
<p>- logical "interpretation" of Gödel's proof of the existence of God in symbolic logic</p>
<p>Submit a one page abstract by May 1st to jyb.logos@gmail.com</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 05:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680932232851033</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Graduate Student Institute - Islam in the Contemporary World</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12686832/graduate-student-institute-islam-contemporary-world</link>
						<dc:creator>Ermin  Sinanovic</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Summer Program</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-05-30T00:00:00-04:00">May 30, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-13T00:00:00-04:00">June 13, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Virginia</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Islamic History / Studies, Middle East History / Studies, Political Science, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><div> </div><div>Center for Islam in the Contemporary World</div><div>at Shenandoah University (CICW)</div><div> </div><div><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Graduate Student Institute</span><br/><span>“Islam in the Contemporary World”</span><br/><span>May 30 – June 13, 2023</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></div><div> </div><div>Venue: George Mason University</div><div>Fairfax, VA</div><div> </div><div><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The CICW’s summer student program, “Islam in the Contemporary World,” is a graduate students’ institute whose objective is twofold: (1) to provide graduate students with foundational instructions in Islamic studies with a focus on contemporary issues and (2) to have discussions about the lived experiences of Muslim graduate students, especially as they pertain to issues of wellness, equity, and belonging. By combining academic and mentoring sessions, we aim to provide a rounded approach to Islam in the contemporary world.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></div><div> </div><div><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>More info at this link<span><span><span>: </span></span></span><a href="https://www.contemporaryislam.org/graduate-student-institute-2023.html" rel="nofollow">https://www.contemporaryislam.org/graduate-student-institute-2023.html</a></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></div><div> </div><div><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Please address any questions to Marjan Popal, Program Manager, at <a href="mailto:mpopal@contemporaryislam.org">mpopal@contemporaryislam.org</a></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></div></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Marjan Popal, <a href="mailto:mpopal@contemporaryislam.org">mpopal@contemporaryislam.org</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:mpopal@contemporaryislam.org">mpopal@contemporaryislam.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.contemporaryislam.org/graduate-student-institute-2023.html" target="_blank">https://www.contemporaryislam.org/graduate-student-institute-2023.html</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 17:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680932232851032</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Global China in a Religious World</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12680637/global-china-religious-world</link>
						<dc:creator>Valerie  Yeo</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-08-17T00:00:00-04:00">August 17, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-08-23T00:00:00-04:00">August 23, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Singapore</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><div> </div><div> </div><div><span><strong>Global China in a Religious World<br/>17-18 Aug | University of Hong Kong (in-person) &amp;<br/>22-23 Aug | via Zoom (Online)</strong></span></div><p><strong>CALL FOR PAPERS DEADLINE | 20 April 2023</strong></p><p>Discussions on the rise of Global China, through the Belt and Road Initiative (BRI) and beyond, have focused on physical infrastructures, financial investments, commerce, and geopolitics. What about the religious dimension of China’s deepening entanglements with the world? Religion is central to the culture and national identity of most BRI and adjacent countries, and, often, their political system and ideology as well. These religions include Islam, Buddhism, Hinduism, and Protestant, Catholic and Orthodox Christianity, among others. What are the religious implications and consequences of these circulations and frictions? The growing presence of China in countries of the Global South may increase the importance of China in the imagination, strategies, or missionizing goals of religious organizations, movements, political parties and ideologies in those countries. These imaginations, strategies and identity formations may be inflected by a resurfacing of historical imaginations and networks. At the same time, growing links offer opportunities for the international expansion of Chinese religious and spiritual networks and organizations. This increased circulation may impact on China’s religious ecology and complicate China’s internal religious policy as well as its management of religious exchanges in the service of diplomacy and soft power.</p><p>This international conference will bring together scholars working on different regions and disciplines, to map out the contours of the religious dimensions and implications of Global China, through discussion of empirical studies and testing of different analytical frameworks.</p><p>Scholars are invited to submit paper proposals on empirical studies touching on one or more of the following topics:</p><ul><li>The circulation and penetration of religious networks, personnel and practices between China and other countries, including countries of the BRI and beyond, including through migration, trade or missionary movements;</li><li>Religious entanglements and responses to Chinese-invested infrastructure projects;</li><li>Evolving religious and civilizational discourses, identities and imaginaries as a consequence of intensified relationships between China and other nations;</li><li>State management and control, whether by China or other countries, of increased religious flows in a context of securitization and geopolitical tensions;</li><li>Religious factors in national politics or geopolitics involving China.</li></ul><p>The conference will be held both in-person, at the University of Hong Kong on 17-18 August, and online, hosted by the Asia Research Institute on 22-23 August.</p><p><strong>The conference is generously supported by the project <a href="https://asiar.hku.hk/brinfaith/home/" rel="nofollow"><em>Infrastructures of Faith: Religious Mobilities on the Belt and Road</em> (BRINFAITH)</a> at the Asian Religious Connections research cluster of the Hong Kong Institute for the Humanities and Social Sciences (HKIHSS), University of Hong Kong, and jointly organized by HKIHSS; Asia Research Institute, National University of Singapore; and Center for Global Asia, New York University Shanghai.</strong></p><p><br/><strong>SUBMISSION OF PROPOSALS</strong></p><p>Paper proposals should include a title, an abstract (250 words maximum) and a brief personal biography of 100 words for submission. Please use the <a href="https://ari.nus.edu.sg/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/CFP-Proposal-Form_Global-China-Religious-World.docx" rel="nofollow">paper proposal form</a> and send it as a word document file to <a href="mailto:asiar@hku.hk">asiar@hku.hk</a> by <strong>20 April 2023</strong>. Successful applicants will be notified by <strong>early May</strong>.</p><p>Applicants may indicate a preference for in-person and/or online participation. Conference participants selected for in-person participation will be provided with return economy airfare to Hong Kong and three nights of accommodation at the conference hotel (one author per paper), and will also be provided with an honorarium of 5000 HKD. Online participants will be provided with a modest honorarium.</p><p>Please also include a statement confirming that your paper has not been published previously. Conference papers may potentially be invited for inclusion in an edited volume or special issue, in collaboration with the conference organizers and/or other participants. Paper presenters will be required to submit paper drafts by <strong>12 Aug. 2023</strong>. These drafts will be circulated to fellow panelists and discussants in advance. Drafts need not be fully polished as we expect that presenters will wish to incorporate feedback from fellow participants.</p><p><br/><strong>CONFERENCE CONVENOR</strong></p><p><strong>Prof David A. Palmer</strong><br/>Hong Kong Institute for the Humanities and Social Sciences, The University of Hong Kong</p><p><br/><strong>CONFERENCE CO-CONVENORS</strong></p><p><strong>Prof Tansen Sen</strong><br/>Center on Global Asia, New York University Shanghai</p><p><strong>Dr Michel Chambon</strong><br/>Initiative for the Study of Asian Catholics, Asia Research Institute, National University of Singapore</p><p><strong>Dr Emily Hertzman</strong><br/>Asia Research Institute, National University of Singapore</p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Valerie Yeo<br/>Asia Research Institute,<br/>National University of Singapore</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:valerie.yeo@nus.edu.sg">valerie.yeo@nus.edu.sg</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://ari.nus.edu.sg/events/global-china-religious-world/" target="_blank">https://ari.nus.edu.sg/events/global-china-religious-world/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 17:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680845830571879</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Journal of Social Encounters  special issue on Extractive Politics, Conflict and Peacebuilding</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12643265/journal-social-encounters-special-issue-extractive-politics</link>
						<dc:creator>Ron Pagnucco</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Journal</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-30T00:00:00-04:00">March 30, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-08-16T00:00:00-04:00">August 16, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Minnesota</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Area Studies, Colonial and Post-Colonial History / Studies, Environmental History / Studies, Peace History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The March 2023 issue of the Journal of Social Encounters (JSE), a special issue on Extractive Politics, Conflict and Peacebuilding, includes case studies from Mozambique, Myanmar, Democratic Republic of Congo, Serbia, Mexico, the United States. Colombia and Kenya. The issue also includes a section of essays on religious leaders and peacebuilding. The JSE is an online, peer-reviewed, open access journal; the March special issue can be found at this link:<br/>Journal of Social Encounters   Volume 7, Issue 1 (March 2023) Extractive Politics, Conflict and Peacebuilding<br/><a href="https://digitalcommons.csbsju.edu/social_encounters/" rel="nofollow">https://digitalcommons.csbsju.edu/social_encounters/</a><br/><br/>For more information, please contact:<br/>Dr. Ron Pagnucco<br/>Coordinating Editor<br/>Journal of Social Encounters<br/><a href="mailto:rpagnucco@csbsju.edu">rpagnucco@csbsju.edu</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr. Ron Pagnucco<br/>Coordinating Editor<br/>Journal of Social Encounters</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:rpagnucco@csbsju.edu">rpagnucco@csbsju.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 17:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1680845830571878</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
