<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 17:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 17:43:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>Call for Papers: The Role of Religion in Asian American Civil Rights Discourses</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10878287/call-papers-role-religion-asian-american-civil-rights</link>
						<dc:creator>shannon toribio</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-24T00:00:00-04:00">March 24, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-03-26T00:00:00-04:00">March 26, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>California</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Asian American History / Studies, Asian History / Studies, Humanities, Race / Ethnic Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><strong>American Academy of Religion - Western Region Annual Meeting 2023</strong></p><p>University of California, Davis March 24-26, 2023</p><p><strong>Call for Papers: The Role of Religion in Asian American Civil Rights Discourses</strong></p><p>Panel: Asian American Religious Studies Unit</p><p> </p><p>In recent years, we have seen how Asian Americans’ civil rights continue to be threatened. Such events include the resurgence of Asian American hate since the pandemic, as well as the ongoing court case against affirmative action: “Students for Fair Admissions v. Harvard.” It is a mistake to assume, however, that Asians have been passive agents in these events. Many Asian Americans have taken part in activism—but have their voices been loud enough to be heard or have they been muffled amidst the magnitude of Asian American hate that renders racism against them invisible? Adding more layers to these issues is the way that the civil rights struggle creates solidarity within the Asian American community and other minoritized communities, but at the same time it has also fostered divisiveness both within Asian American communities and outside. How have ideas about immigration, stereotypes, and boundaries been both embraced and challenged by Asian Americans?</p><p>Needless to say, the problem of defending the civil rights of Asian Americans is a complex matter, one in which religion struggles to find its place. For this year’s conference, we ask what role religion holds in communicating and addressing these social and political issues? How do religious discourses, rituals, doctrines, and teachings serve Asian Americans in terms of defending their civil rights, as well as fostering group solidarity amidst the plurality of Asian American religious traditions? As scholars of Asian American religion, what is our role in this political discourse? How do we see Asian American civil rights movements and scholarship moving forward?</p><p>Scholars of all levels are invited to participate in this dialogue. Interested parties may send abstracts (250 words) to Shannon Toribio(<a href="mailto:shannon_toribio@ucsb.edu">shannon_toribio@ucsb.edu</a>) or Laura Snell (<a href="mailto:laurasnell@ucsb.edu">laurasnell@ucsb.edu</a>). The <strong>deadline</strong> for submission is<strong> October 14, 2022. </strong>All participants must submit a Program Participant Form (attached and also available on the AAR/WR website). Participants at AARWR must be members of the AAR. The AAR membership information is found at aarweb.org.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>shannon toribio</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:shannon_toribio@ucsb.edu">shannon_toribio@ucsb.edu</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 17:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663133834568877</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Book Reviewers Needed</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/09/12/book-reviewers-needed</link>
						<dc:creator>elyce.helford@mtsu.edu</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Monday, September 12, 2022 - 9:27pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Jewish Film and New Media</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:elyce.helford@mtsu.edu">elyce.helford@mtsu.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/film-and-television">film and television</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/popular-culture">popular culture</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>November 1, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>International journal <em>Jewish Film and New Media</em> seeks book reviewers for new and recently published scholarly volumes. Reviewers may propose books on which to write or our Reviews Editor will assign them based on interest and experience. Advanced graduate students to full professor and experienced independent scholars welcome to apply. Graduate students or those with limited publication experience should be prepared to share a relevant writing sample. There is no pay for reviewers, but we will obtain a copy of the book for you to keep. (Note: Some publishers provide only ebooks; we have no control over this practice.)</p>
<p>Any questions? Please email Book Reviews Editor Dr. Elyce Rae Helford at <a href="mailto:elyce.helford@mtsu.edu">elyce.helford@mtsu.edu</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 19:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663047433356609</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FEATURED JOB: Assistant Professor, Modern Islam, and Race- University of Pittsburgh</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10849390/featured-job-assistant-professor-modern-islam-and-race</link>
						<dc:creator>Kendra Fuller</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Home Office Notices (Jobs, Reviews)</div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>Pennsylvania</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology, Islamic History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The Department of Religious Studies at the University of Pittsburgh seeks to appoint a tenure-track assistant professor in Modern Islam and Race, pending budgetary approval.  The renewable, three-year appointment runs from September 1, 2023, through April 30, 2026, and Fall term classes begin August 28, 2023. Geographic specialization(s) open.  We welcome applicants from all disciplinary backgrounds with a demonstrated commitment to the study of religion. The teaching requirement is two courses per semester, and teaching includes introductory and upper-level courses on Islam and courses in the area of specialization of the successful candidate. We offer new colleagues considerable scope for designing new courses and integrating them into our curriculum.</p><p>Minimum Qualifications:</p><ul><li>Ph.D. in Religious Studies or an allied discipline is expected by the time of appointment. ABD candidates must be scheduled to defend their dissertations by August 1, 2023.</li><li>Research focuses on Islamic Studies in the modern world.</li><li>A research and teaching agenda are featuring dynamic and innovative approaches to the intersections of Islam in the modern world with issues of race, ethnicity, and other forms of identity including gender and sexuality; diaspora, colonialism, and post-colonialism; and minoritized perspectives.</li><li>Ability to teach courses in Religious Studies to a diverse student body in a public research university setting.</li></ul><p>Preference will be given to candidates whose work complements or expands existing areas of strength and thematic clusters in the department and in other departments, programs, centers, and schools at the university.</p><p>The Dietrich School of Arts and Sciences and the University of Pittsburgh are also engaged in cluster-hiring in “Race, Representation, and Anti-Black and Systemic Racism” and “Race and Social Determinants of Equity and Wellbeing.” This position is not formally part of the cluster hire initiative, but we actively encourage applications from candidates whose interests relate to this area. The University of Pittsburgh has embarked on significant initiatives to diversify its faculty, student body, and curriculum. We encourage applications from scholars eager to contribute to this mission.</p><p>To apply, please submit the following materials</p><ol><li>A letter of application describing current and future teaching and research directions.  This letter should also discuss how your work engages existing areas of teaching and research in the department and in the Dietrich School. </li><li>A statement discussing how your past, planned, or potential contributions or experiences relating to diversity, equity, and inclusion will advance the University of Pittsburgh’s commitment to inclusive excellence;</li><li>A full C.V.;</li><li>An article-length scholarly writing sample (a journal article or a dissertation or book chapter);</li><li>Two sample syllabi for courses;  </li><li> Names and email addresses of at least three individuals who can provide recommendations;</li><li> Finalists will be asked to submit evidence of teaching effectiveness, such as student or peer evaluations.</li></ol><p>In order to ensure full consideration, applications should be received by October 24, 2022. <a href="https://cfopitt.taleo.net/careersection/pitt_faculty_external/jobsearch.ftl?lang=en&amp;portal=12100023232" rel="nofollow">Apply at Talent Center: Work at Pitt</a>, requisition # 22007545.</p><p>For administrative questions, contact Allison Thompson at <a href="mailto:allisonthompson@pitt.edu">allisonthompson@pitt.edu</a>; for questions about the position, contact Adam Shear at <a href="mailto:ashear@pitt.edu">ashear@pitt.edu</a>.</p><p>The University of Pittsburgh requires all Pitt constituents (employees and students) on all campuses to be vaccinated against COVID-19 or have an approved exemption. Visit coronavirus.pitt.edu to learn more about this requirement. </p><hr/><p>To submit YOUR job posting, please visit the H-Net Job Guide:<a href="https://www.h-net.org/jobs" rel="nofollow"> https://www.h-net.org/jobs</a></p><p>Featured jobs receive an added boost on H-Announce and H-Net’s social media channels.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>For administrative questions, contact Allison Thompson at <a href="mailto:allisonthompson@pitt.edu">allisonthompson@pitt.edu</a>; for questions about the position, contact Adam Shear at <a href="mailto:ashear@pitt.edu">ashear@pitt.edu</a>.</p></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php" target="_blank">https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php?id=63916</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 19:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663047433356608</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Special Issue &quot;Mobilization of Art and Religion in the Hispanic World: The Intersections of Race, Religion, Gender, and Objects c. 1500–1800&quot;</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/09/11/special-issue-mobilization-of-art-and-religion-in-the-hispanic-world-the</link>
						<dc:creator>ira.kazi@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Monday, September 12, 2022 - 9:29pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Religions</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:ikazi3@uwo.ca">ikazi3@uwo.ca</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/gender-studies-and-sexuality">gender studies and sexuality</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/postcolonial">postcolonial</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/world-literatures-and-indigenous-studies">world literatures and indigenous studies</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>September 16, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>**Deadline Extended**</p>
<p>**Since these are electronic publications, we have been offered the opportunity to expand our content. Likewise, we recognize that the lessening of covid restrictions has allowed for more research travel. The expected deadlines for delivery of final papers remains the same [1 February 2023], but all abstracts should be submitted by September 16th, 2022. Please note for both journals: all abstracts we select and papers put forward for peer review will have their submission fees waived.** </p>
<p>Special Issue Information:</p>
<p>Dear Colleagues,</p>
<p>In recent years, academic interest in the movement of people, objects, and ideas has risen significantly, driven by the desire to develop a fuller understanding of history and our current globalized world (Beaudry and Paron 2013, Corcoran-Tadd, Hung et. al. 2021). These interests have forced us to reconsider knowledge, art, spatial, religious, and historical formations, prior to, during, and after the colonial era, as we have recognized for several decades now that colonialism was formalized and transgressed by virtually all peoples involved (Hofman and Keehnen 2018). Further, objects, styles, concepts, and other material artifacts traversed oceans and continents (Callligaro, Chiappero et. al. 2019, Hamann 2010, Hyman 2017). We look to consider the intersections of Hispanic cultural traditions with European (whether Jewish, Islamic, Catholic, or Protestant), Indigenous/First Nations, Afro-Latin American/Afro-Caribbean, and Asian-Latin American in a developing global world. By considering the mobility of peoples, objects, themes, and other social constructs throughout the global Spanish territories, we explore the intersection of disparate religious traditions to consider the formation of new cultural knowledges and practices through the appropriation, assimilation, commodification, fetishization, marginalization, and hybridization of objects and practices.</p>
<p>We invite contributors to submit their research in English for consideration. Please note that there is a two-stage submission procedure. We will first collect a title and short abstract (maximum 250 words), 5 keywords, and a short bio (150 words), by 16 September 2022, via email to Dr. Cody Barteet (<a href="mailto:cbarteet@uwo.ca">cbarteet@uwo.ca</a>), Iraboty Kazi (<a href="mailto:ikazi3@uwo.ca">ikazi3@uwo.ca</a>), and Dr. Alena Robin (<a href="mailto:arobin82@uwo.ca">arobin82@uwo.ca</a>). Before 30 May 2022, we will invite selected abstracts to be submitted as 7000- to 9000-word papers for peer review by 1 February 2023. Journal publication is expected in mid- to late 2023, depending on the revision time needed after peer review. Each article will be published open access on a rolling basis after successfully passing peer review.</p>
<p>Keywords<br/>mobility<br/>religious art<br/>cultural artifacts<br/>Hispanic world<br/>transatlantic<br/>transpacific<br/>transcontinental<br/>race<br/>gender<br/> </p>
<p>Dr. C. Cody Barteet<br/>Guest Editor<br/>Iraboty Kazi<br/>Guest Editor Assistant<br/>Dr. Alena Robin<br/>Guest Editor</p>
<p> </p>
<p>For more information: <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/si/101901">https://www.mdpi.com/si/101901</a></p>
<p> </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 13:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663047433356607</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FreshRSS 1.20.0</title>
			<link>https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/releases/tag/1.20.0</link>
						<dc:creator>Alkarex</dc:creator>
			<description><ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/milestones/1.20.0">Milestone</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/discussions/4517" data-hovercard-type="discussion" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/discussions/4517/hovercard">Discussion</a></li>
</ul>
<p>A few highlights <g-emoji alias="sparkles" fallback-src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/2728.png">✨</g-emoji>:</p>
<ul>
<li>New Web scraping feature <em>HTML+XPath</em> for Web pages without any RSS/ATOM feed <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4220" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4220/hovercard">#4220</a></li>
<li>Add support for <em>Dynamic OPML</em> <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4407" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4407/hovercard">#4407</a></li>
<li>New search engine supporting (nested) parentheses, also with negation <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4378" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4378/hovercard">#4378</a></li>
<li>Allow many (50k+) feeds <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4347" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4347/hovercard">#4347</a> and other performance improvements</li>
<li>New option to exclude some DOM elements with a CSS Selector when retrieving an article full content <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4501" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4501/hovercard">#4501</a></li>
<li>New option to automatically mark as read gone articles <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4426" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4426/hovercard">#4426</a></li>
<li>2 new themes and plenty of UI improvements</li>
<li>Supported by <a href="https://hyliu.me/fluent-reader-lite/" rel="nofollow">Fluent Reader Lite</a> client on Android and iOS <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4595" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4595/hovercard">#4595</a></li>
<li>Several bug fixes</li>
<li>1.20.x will be the last release(s) to support PHP 7.0 before requiring PHP 7.2+</li>
</ul>
<p>Detailed <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/compare/1.19.2...1.20.0">tracked changes</a>.</p>
<p>Full <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/blob/1.20.0/CHANGELOG.md">changelog</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Features
<ul>
<li>New Web scraping feature <em>HTML+XPath</em> for Web pages without any RSS/ATOM feed <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4220" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4220/hovercard">#4220</a></li>
<li>Add support for <em>Dynamic OPML</em> <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4407" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4407/hovercard">#4407</a>
<ul>
<li>Subscriber: Ability for a category to be dynamically populated with a list of feeds provided by a remote OPML</li>
<li>Publisher: Ability to dynamically export a FreshRSS view (all, feed, category) into a dynamic OPML</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>New search engine supporting (nested) parentheses <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4378" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4378/hovercard">#4378</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4503" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4503/hovercard">#4503</a>
<ul>
<li><code>(author:Alice OR intitle:hello) (author:Bob OR intitle:world)</code></li>
<li>also with negation: <code>!((author:Alice intitle:hello) OR (author:Bob intitle:world))</code></li>
<li>and supporting calling user queries from the search field by name: <code>search:"My query"</code> or <code>search:QueryA</code>, or by ID: <code>S:3</code></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Allow many (50k+) feeds <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4347" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4347/hovercard">#4347</a>
<ul>
<li>Note: only for new users or after an export/import or a manual database update</li>
<li>See also <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4357" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4357/hovercard">#4357</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4353" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4353/hovercard">#4353</a>,<br/>
<a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4417" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4417/hovercard">#4417</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4502" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4502/hovercard">#4502</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>New option to exclude some DOM elements with a CSS Selector when retrieving an article full content <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4501" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4501/hovercard">#4501</a></li>
<li>New option to automatically mark as read gone articles <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4426" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4426/hovercard">#4426</a></li>
<li>New OPML export/import of some proprietary FreshRSS attributes <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4342" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4342/hovercard">#4342</a></li>
<li>Tolerate the import of some invalid OPML files <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4591" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4591/hovercard">#4591</a></li>
<li>New feed settings to allow cookies and HTTP redirects <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4470" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4470/hovercard">#4470</a></li>
<li>Performance: Easier <a href="https://freshrss.github.io/FreshRSS/en/admins/DatabaseConfig.html" rel="nofollow">text search indexes</a> for fast searches with PostgreSQL <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4505" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4505/hovercard">#4505</a>
<ul>
<li>The indexes must be manually added for now. Using GIN <code>pg_trgm</code></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Easier definition of default user queries for new users in <code>data/config-user.custom.php</code> <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4360" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4360/hovercard">#4360</a></li>
<li>New sharing through standard <a href="https://www.w3.org/TR/web-share/" rel="nofollow">Web Share API</a> <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4271" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4271/hovercard">#4271</a></li>
<li>New sharing with Xing, Reddit, Pinterest, WhatsApp <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4270" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4270/hovercard">#4270</a></li>
<li>New sharing with <a href="https://archive.ph/" rel="nofollow"><code>archive.today</code></a> <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4530" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4530/hovercard">#4530</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>SimplePie
<ul>
<li>New method <code>rename_attribute()</code> instead of removing attributes to better be able to style/hide content of articles <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4175" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4175/hovercard">#4175</a>,<br/>
<a href="https://github.com/simplepie/simplepie/pull/717" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/simplepie/simplepie/pull/717/hovercard">simplepie#717</a></li>
<li>Fix parsing of HTTP Links <a href="https://github.com/simplepie/simplepie/pull/729" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/simplepie/simplepie/pull/729/hovercard">simplepie#729</a></li>
<li>Fix <code>status_code</code> type for PHP 8.1+ <a href="https://github.com/simplepie/simplepie/pull/728" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/simplepie/simplepie/pull/728/hovercard">simplepie#728</a></li>
<li>Fix relative URLs <a href="https://github.com/simplepie/simplepie/pull/744" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/simplepie/simplepie/pull/744/hovercard">simplepie#744</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Bug fixing
<ul>
<li>Fix last update &amp; archive logic (especially for very long feeds, for which some old items were marked as unread) <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4422" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4422/hovercard">#4422</a></li>
<li>Fix regression with Fever API on 32-bit platforms <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4201" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4201/hovercard">#4201</a></li>
<li>Fix read-when-same-title bug <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4206" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4206/hovercard">#4206</a></li>
<li>Fix some search expressions such as <code>"ab cd"</code> and <code>ab-cd</code> <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4277" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4277/hovercard">#4277</a></li>
<li>Fix auto-load of more articles when using shortcuts <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4532" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4532/hovercard">#4532</a></li>
<li>Fix <kbd>space</kbd> shortcut <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4581" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4581/hovercard">#4581</a></li>
<li>WebSub: Use hash instead of base64 to handle long URLs <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4282" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4282/hovercard">#4282</a></li>
<li>Fix handling of authors with ampersand <code>&amp;</code> <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4287" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4287/hovercard">#4287</a></li>
<li>Fix lazy loading images containing a quote <code>'</code> in the address <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4330" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4330/hovercard">#4330</a></li>
<li>Fix database size calculation for PostgreSQL <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4249" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4249/hovercard">#4249</a></li>
<li>Fix HTTP root redirection in some cases (trailing slash with a proxy) <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4167" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4167/hovercard">#4167</a></li>
<li>Fix <code>htmlspecialchars()</code> warnings with PHP 8.1+ <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4411" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4411/hovercard">#4411</a></li>
<li>Fix OPML category encoding <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4427" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4427/hovercard">#4427</a></li>
<li>Fix one category of favicon update problem <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4358" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4358/hovercard">#4358</a></li>
<li>Fix rare mark-as-read bug <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4456" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4456/hovercard">#4456</a></li>
<li>Add missing extension hook <code>freshrss_user_maintenance</code> in CLI <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4495" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4495/hovercard">#4495</a></li>
<li>Rename conflicting function <code>errorMessage()</code> which exists on some platforms <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4289" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4289/hovercard">#4289</a></li>
<li>Fix remain of bookmarklet <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4240" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4240/hovercard">#4240</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>UI
<ul>
<li>Performance: Automatic simplification of layout for 1000+ feeds <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4357" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4357/hovercard">#4357</a></li>
<li>Performance: New option <em>icons-as-emojis</em> <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4353" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4353/hovercard">#4353</a></li>
<li>Manage feed configuration using a dynamic slider view <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4226" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4226/hovercard">#4226</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4297" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4297/hovercard">#4297</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4394" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4394/hovercard">#4394</a></li>
<li>New option for custom HTML logo/title in the main Web UI view <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4369" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4369/hovercard">#4369</a></li>
<li>Show errored, empty, muted feeds in statistics <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4276" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4276/hovercard">#4276</a></li>
<li>Improve configuration of registration form <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/3932" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/3932/hovercard">#3932</a></li>
<li>Improve subscription list drag &amp; drop <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/3953" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/3953/hovercard">#3953</a></li>
<li>Improve extension manager <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4181" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4181/hovercard">#4181</a></li>
<li>Improve idle feeds list <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4192" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4192/hovercard">#4192</a></li>
<li>Improve feed link in normal view <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4006" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4006/hovercard">#4006</a></li>
<li>Improve browser notification for unread message <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4193" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4193/hovercard">#4193</a></li>
<li>Improve notification banner <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4023" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4023/hovercard">#4023</a></li>
<li>Improve new article banner <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4037" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4037/hovercard">#4037</a></li>
<li>Improve pagination + <em>load more</em> button <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4125" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4125/hovercard">#4125</a></li>
<li>Improve log view <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4204" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4204/hovercard">#4204</a></li>
<li>Improve unread articles counter in normal view <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4166" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4166/hovercard">#4166</a></li>
<li>Automatically set the category when adding a feed from an existing category <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4333" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4333/hovercard">#4333</a></li>
<li>Better PWA colours for mobile <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4254" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4254/hovercard">#4254</a></li>
<li>Improve article footer <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4306" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4306/hovercard">#4306</a></li>
<li>Various UI and style improvements <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4205" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4205/hovercard">#4205</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4212" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4212/hovercard">#4212</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4218" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4218/hovercard">#4218</a>,<br/>
<a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4238" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4238/hovercard">#4238</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4455" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4455/hovercard">#4455</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4298" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4298/hovercard">#4298</a>,<br/>
<a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4383" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4383/hovercard">#4383</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4452" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4452/hovercard">#4452</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4455" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4455/hovercard">#4455</a>,<br/>
<a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4466" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4466/hovercard">#4466</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4471" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4471/hovercard">#4471</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4472" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4472/hovercard">#4472</a>,<br/>
<a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4474" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4474/hovercard">#4474</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4498" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4498/hovercard">#4498</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4502" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4502/hovercard">#4502</a>,<br/>
<a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4504" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4504/hovercard">#4504</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4558" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4558/hovercard">#4558</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4546" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4546/hovercard">#4546</a>,<br/>
<a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4541" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4541/hovercard">#4541</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Themes
<ul>
<li>New theme <em>Dark pink</em> <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4311" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4311/hovercard">#4311</a></li>
<li>New theme <em>Nord</em> <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4400" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4400/hovercard">#4400</a></li>
<li>Improve themes <em>Alternative Dark</em> <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4587" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4587/hovercard">#4587</a>;<br/>
<em>Ansum</em> <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4538" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4538/hovercard">#4538</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4549" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4549/hovercard">#4549</a>;<br/>
<em>Flat</em> <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4575" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4575/hovercard">#4575</a>;<br/>
<em>Mapco</em> <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4491" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4491/hovercard">#4491</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4491" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4491/hovercard">#4491</a>;<br/>
<em>Swage</em> <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4493" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4493/hovercard">#4493</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4512" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4512/hovercard">#4512</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4566" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4566/hovercard">#4566</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Extensions
<ul>
<li>Allow extensions using <code>entry_before_insert</code> to change <code>entry-&gt;isRead()</code> <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4331" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4331/hovercard">#4331</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>i18n
<ul>
<li>Improve i18n CLI <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4197" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4197/hovercard">#4197</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4199" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4199/hovercard">#4199</a></li>
<li>Add Chinese (Traditional) <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4578" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4578/hovercard">#4578</a></li>
<li>Improve Chinese (Simplified) <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4332" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4332/hovercard">#4332</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4337" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4337/hovercard">#4337</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4379" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4379/hovercard">#4379</a>,<br/>
<a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4509" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4509/hovercard">#4509</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4577" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4577/hovercard">#4577</a></li>
<li>Improve English <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4450" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4450/hovercard">#4450</a></li>
<li>Improve German <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4525" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4525/hovercard">#4525</a></li>
<li>Improve Korean <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4572" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4572/hovercard">#4572</a></li>
<li>Improve Occitan <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4548" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4548/hovercard">#4548</a></li>
<li>Improve Polish <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4363" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4363/hovercard">#4363</a></li>
<li>Improve Russian <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4385" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4385/hovercard">#4385</a></li>
<li>Improve Slovak <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4524" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4524/hovercard">#4524</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>API
<ul>
<li>Restrict maximum length of item content length for clients compatibility <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4583" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4583/hovercard">#4583</a></li>
<li>Supported by <a href="https://hyliu.me/fluent-reader-lite/" rel="nofollow">Fluent Reader Lite</a> <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4595" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4595/hovercard">#4595</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Deployment
<ul>
<li>Docker: Performance: entrypoint fix buffering, problematic when importing large OPMLs during install <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4417" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4417/hovercard">#4417</a></li>
<li>Docker default image (Debian 11 Bullseye) updated to PHP 7.4.30 and Apache 2.4.54</li>
<li>Docker: alternative image updated to Alpine 3.16 with PHP 8.0.22 and Apache 2.4.54 <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4391" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4391/hovercard">#4391</a>
<ul>
<li>Add PHP extensions <code>php-openssl</code> (used by PHPMailer) and <code>php-xml</code> (used by SimplePie) <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4420" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4420/hovercard">#4420</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Docker: Upgraded dev image <code>freshrss/freshrss:newest</code> to PHP 8.2 <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4420" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4420/hovercard">#4420</a></li>
<li>Include PHP extensions in Composer for easier automated deployment <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4497" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4497/hovercard">#4497</a></li>
<li>Improved trimming of <code>base_url</code> to avoid some common configuration bugs, especially via Docker / CLI <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4423" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4423/hovercard">#4423</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>CLI
<ul>
<li>Allow empty DB prefix <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4488" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4488/hovercard">#4488</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Compatibility
<ul>
<li>Initial support for PHP 8.2+ <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4420" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4420/hovercard">#4420</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4421" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4421/hovercard">#4421</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Security
<ul>
<li>Improved error page, properly returning HTTP 500 and CSP <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4465" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4465/hovercard">#4465</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Misc.
<ul>
<li>Replace <code>lib_phpQuery</code> by <a href="https://github.com/PhpGt/CssXPath"><code>PhpGt/CssXPath</code></a> library for full content retrieval <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4261" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4261/hovercard">#4261</a>
<ul>
<li>Add support for star CSS Selectors such as <code>a[href*="example"]</code> <a href="https://github.com/PhpGt/CssXPath/pull/181" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/PhpGt/CssXPath/pull/181/hovercard">CssXPath#181</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Performance: Do not render irrelevant HTML for Ajax calls <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4310" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4310/hovercard">#4310</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4366" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4366/hovercard">#4366</a></li>
<li>Performance: New limit option when reloading a feed <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4370" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4370/hovercard">#4370</a></li>
<li>Optional possibility to use Composer to update some libraries <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4329" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4329/hovercard">#4329</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4368" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4368/hovercard">#4368</a>
<ul>
<li>Update to PHPMailer 6.6.0 <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4329" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4329/hovercard">#4329</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Use <code>.gitattributes</code> <code>export-ignore</code> <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4415" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4415/hovercard">#4415</a></li>
<li>Remove HTTP Referer for HTML download <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4372" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4372/hovercard">#4372</a></li>
<li>Add database field <code>attributes</code> (JSON) for entries <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4444" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4444/hovercard">#4444</a></li>
<li>Improve dev automated checks <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4209" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4209/hovercard">#4209</a></li>
<li>Update dev dependencies <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4173" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4173/hovercard">#4173</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4203" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4203/hovercard">#4203</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4241" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4241/hovercard">#4241</a>,<br/>
<a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4419" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4419/hovercard">#4419</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4424" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4424/hovercard">#4424</a></li>
<li>Fix extension list warning when offline<a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4571" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4571/hovercard">#4571</a></li>
<li>Code improvements <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4130" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4130/hovercard">#4130</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4194" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4194/hovercard">#4194</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4201" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4201/hovercard">#4201</a>,<br/>
<a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4202" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4202/hovercard">#4202</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4258" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4258/hovercard">#4258</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4263" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4263/hovercard">#4263</a>,<br/>
<a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4356" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4356/hovercard">#4356</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4436" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4436/hovercard">#4436</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4489" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4489/hovercard">#4489</a>,<br/>
<a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4490" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4490/hovercard">#4490</a>, <a href="https://github.com/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4496" data-hovercard-type="pull_request" data-hovercard-url="/FreshRSS/FreshRSS/pull/4496/hovercard">#4496</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 15:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1662874623017072</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Christianity's American Fate: How Religion Became More Conservative and Society More Secular</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10838372/christianitys-american-fate-how-religion-became-more</link>
						<dc:creator>Tahera Tajbhai</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Lecture</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-09-28T00:00:00-04:00">September 28, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>New York</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>American History / Studies, Contemporary History, Cultural History / Studies, Political History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>The Department of<a href="https://www.newschool.edu/nssr/historical-studies/" rel="nofollow"> <b>Historical Studies</b></a> at the <b><a href="https://www.newschool.edu/" rel="nofollow">New School</a></b> in New York City is proud to announce our the start of our 2022 - 2023 lecture series: <b>CRITICAL HISTORY TODAY</b>, featuring guest speaker Professor David Hollinger.</p><p>In this lecture, Professor Hollinger (UC Berkeley) discusses how and why Christianity — a variegated and often progressive force in the United States — has largely been captured by the most politically, culturally, and theologically reactionary Americans. </p><hr/><p><a href="https://history.berkeley.edu/people/faculty/emeriti/david-hollinger" rel="nofollow">David A. Hollinger</a> is the Preston Hotchkis Professor of History Emeritus at the University of California. He is a former President of the Organization of American Historians and the author of many books, including <em>Postethnic America (1995, 2000, and 2006), Science, Jews, and Secular Culture (1996), After Cloven Tongues of Fire (2013),</em> and <em>Protestants Abroad (2017)</em>.</p><hr/><p>This event is part of the <em><a href="http://event.newschool.edu/criticalhistorytoday" rel="nofollow">Critical History Today</a></em> lecture series. The themes of which build upon our shared commitment to developing modes of historical analysis that speak to the urgent concerns of the present and that promote rigorous engagement between history and other branches of the humanities and social sciences.</p><p>Presented by the <a href="https://www.newschool.edu/lang/history/" rel="nofollow">Historical Studies</a> department at <a href="http://www.newschool.edu/lang" rel="nofollow">Eugene Lang College of Liberal Arts</a> and <a href="https://www.newschool.edu/nssr/" rel="nofollow">The New School for Social Research</a> at The New School.</p><hr/><p><u><strong>Cost and Location</strong></u></p><p>This event is free with registration. Located at 65 West 11th Street - Wollman Hall, 5th Floor.</p><p><u><strong>COVID REQUIREMENTS</strong></u></p><p>Event guests and visitors must provide proof of up-to-date vaccination, including a booster when <strong><a href="https://covid19vaccine.health.ny.gov/booster-doses-frequently-asked-questions" rel="nofollow">eligible</a></strong>. The following protocols will be in place to ensure a safe and healthy experience for everyone:</p><ul><li>Masks must be worn in concert and lecture venues where events are held. Masks are encouraged and optional elsewhere indoors.</li><li>The New School has partnered with CLEAR to utilize <strong><a href="https://clear.app.link/TheNewSchool" rel="nofollow">Health Pass</a></strong>, an online tool that safely and simply verifies proof of COVID-19 vaccination. For detailed instructions on downloading and using CLEAR, visit the “<strong><a href="https://www.newschool.edu/covid-19/campus-access/?open=gatherings" rel="nofollow">Events and Gatherings</a></strong>” section on our Access to Campus page. Specific questions about using the CLEAR Health Pass to attend an on-campus event can be directed to the event organizer.</li></ul><p>To ensure expedited event check-in, event guests should set up a CLEAR Health Pass account with proof of vaccination prior to the event.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Tahera Tajbhai, Senior Secretary</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:history@newschool.edu">history@newschool.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://event.newschool.edu/davidhollinger" target="_blank">https://event.newschool.edu/davidhollinger</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 17:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1662788229029239</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Short-Term Research Fellowship in Special Collections, Georgetown University</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10846764/short-term-research-fellowship-special-collections-georgetown</link>
						<dc:creator>David Collins， S.J.</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Fellowship</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-12-15T00:00:00-05:00">December 15, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>District Of Columbia</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>American History / Studies, Humanities, Local History, Religious Studies and Theology, Slavery</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span> </span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The Hilltop Short-term Fellowships for Individual Research in Catholic Studies at Georgetown University</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The Hilltop Short-Term Fellowships provide opportunities for individuals who have a specific need for </span></span></span><span><span><span>the Special Collections at Georgetown University’s Lauinger Library</span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span> to advance a significant scholarly project </span></span></span><span><span><span>in disciplines associated with Catholic Studies</span></span></span><span><span><span>, broadly conceived.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>PhD candidates and scholars with advanced degrees</span></span></span><span><span><span> who live and work outside of the Washington metropolitan area are eligible to apply. The fellowships are available for </span></span></span><span><span><span>one month </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>with a stipend of </span></span></span><span><span><span>$3,000.</span></span></span><span><span><span> </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The library’s collections are especially suitable for studies of </span></span></span><span><span><span>Catholicism in the U.S. colonial and early national periods</span></span></span><span><span><span>, as well as of Jesuit activity from the colonial period to the present in North America. Projects that focus on American Indian, African American, and women's histories are especially welcome. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Major components of the university’s Special Collections (the first two of which constitute the heart of the </span></span></span><span><span><span>Jesuit/Georgetown “slavery archives”</span></span></span><span><span><span>) include:</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Georgetown University Archives (eighteenth century to the present)</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Maryland Province (Jesuit) Archives (seventeenth century to the present)</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Woodstock (Jesuit) Theological Library Collection</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span> Among the other collections: </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>America</span></span><span><span> magazine archives</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>John Gilmary Shea library and papers</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>And there are numerous collected papers, including those of </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Jesuits from John </span></span></span><span><span><span>Carroll </span></span></span><span><span><span>to John </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>LaFarge</span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>, from John Courtney </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Murray </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>and Gustave </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Weigel </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>to Edmund </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Walsh </span></span></span><span><span><span>and Horace </span></span></span><span><span><span>McKenna</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Leading figures in 20th-century Catholic scholarship and  public life including, journalist and photographer Anna </span></span></span><span><span><span>Brady</span></span></span><span><span><span>, theologian Monika K. </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Hellwig</span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>, novelist Sr. </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Alma Regina</span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>, and navigator Michael </span></span></span><span><span><span>Richey</span></span></span><span><span><span>. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Literary figures, including the </span></span></span><span><span><span>Kilmer </span></span></span><span><span><span>Family, Seumas </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>MacManus</span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>, Theodore </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Maynard</span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>, </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Sister Miriam </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>RSM, Evelyn </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Waugh</span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>, Graham </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Greene</span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>, Christopher </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Sykes</span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>, Catherine </span></span></span><span><span><span>Walston</span></span></span><span><span><span>, et al.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li></ul><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>This list is not exhaustive. Applicants are directed to the website of the </span></span></span><span><span><span>Booth Family Center for Special Collections</span></span></span><span><span><span>, which includes multiple finders’ guides; and to the </span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span>fellowship webpage</span></span></span><span><span><span> for more information: </span></span></span><span><span><span><a href="https://catholicstudies.georgetown.edu/fellowship/" rel="nofollow">https://catholicstudies.georgetown.edu/fellowship/</a></span></span></span><span><span><span>. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span><span> </span><span> </span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Prof. David J. Collins, S.J., Ph.D.</p><p>Haub Director of Catholic Studies</p><p>Georgetown University</p><p>Washington, DC 20057</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:catholicstudies@georgetown.edu">catholicstudies@georgetown.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://catholicstudies.georgetown.edu/fellowship/" target="_blank">https://catholicstudies.georgetown.edu/fellowship/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 17:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1662788229029238</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How To Do No Harm: Reflections on Ethics and Methods in Shii Studies (panel)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10844636/how-do-no-harm-reflections-ethics-and-methods-shii-studies</link>
						<dc:creator>Fouad Gehad Marei</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-09-13T00:00:00-04:00">September 13, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Germany</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Area Studies, Islamic History / Studies, Middle East History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Research and Methodology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><div> </div><div> </div><div><span><span><span><span><span><b><span><span><span>How To Do No Harm:</span></span></span></b><b> </b><b><span><span><span>Reflections on Ethics and Methods in Shii Studies</span></span></span></b></span></span></span></span></span></div><p><span><span><span>a discussion with <a href="https://www.religion.utoronto.ca/people/directories/all-faculty/karen-ruffle" rel="nofollow"><b>Prof. Karen Ruffle</b></a> (University of Toronto)<br/>and <a href="https://www.soas.ac.uk/staff/staff105767.php" rel="nofollow"><b>Prof. Alison Scott-Baumann</b></a> (SOAS, London)</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>organized by<span> <a href="https://www.ctr.lu.se/en/person/FouadMarei/" rel="nofollow"><b>Fouad Gehad Marei</b></a> (Lund University) and</span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><a href="https://www.fscire.it/lang/eng/equipe/ricercatori/card-1619190558" rel="nofollow"><b>Minoo Mirshahvalad</b></a></span><span> (</span>Fondazione per le Scienze Religiose Giovanni XXIII<span>)</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>at the Deutscher Orientalistentag (DOT). Berlin, Germany</span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>_____________________________________________________</span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><b><span>When: </span></b><span>Tuesday, 13 September 2022 at 09:30–11:00 and 11:30–13:00<br/><b>Where: </b>Free University of Berlin (<a href="https://goo.gl/maps/nndfpdKymdpBkFFo9" rel="nofollow">Habelschwerdter Allee 45, 14195 Berlin</a>) . <b>Room:</b> “Rabat” (K25/11)</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><u>Description of roundtable</u></b><b>:</b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>In this two-part roundtable, we examine some of the ethical and methodological issues pertaining to the scholarly study of Shiism and arising from the intellectual trajectories of Shii Studies as a specialized subfield. <span>The roundtable brings together a group of scholars with an interest in the study of Shii Islam, Shii political groups and piety movements, Shii religious scholarship and scholarly networks, armed resistance groups, and Shiism in the diaspora. We present insights based on our experiences as scholars and academicians working in, on, and from diverse sociopolitical and geographical contexts, including Germany, Iraq, Iran, Italy, Lebanon, Syria, and the United Kingdom. While we focus on ethics and methods in Shii Studies, we draw on and engage with questions relevant to other disciplinary fields, including Islamic Studies, Middle Eastern and Area Studies, sociology, anthropology, and political science.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span>We organize our interventions around a set of guiding questions categorized in four themes:</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><b><span>Part I – Shii Studies</span></b></span></span></span></span></p><ol><li><span><span><span><span><b><span>Why Shii Studies? </span></b><span>What motivates the separation of Islamic and Shii Studies and the emergence of the specialization field of Shii Studies? What are the methodological and intellectual gains and challenges that result from the specialized study of Shiism? And, in what ways can processes of sectarianization and the specialization of Shii Studies impact one another, and to what effect?</span></span></span></span></span><br/> </li><li><span><span><span><b><span>Shii Studies and the scrutinizing gaze: </span></b><span>How can scholars navigate the politicization and securitization of Islamic and Shii studies in Western and Middle Eastern scholarly circles? How can scholars circumvent social stigmas and the political and legal designations of Shii religious groups, congregations and movements as, for example, ’terrorist’, ‘extremist’, 'homophobic’, ‘anti-Semitic’? What challenges do these designations pose for researchers and research subjects? And, (how) should scholars of Shiism engage with governmental and nongovernmental policy research?</span></span></span></span></li></ol><p> </p><p><span><span><span><b><span>Part II – Ethics and methods</span></b></span></span></span></p><ol><li><span><span><span><b><span>Ethics and methods in social and ethnographic research: </span></b><span>How can scholars of Shii Studies conduct <i>longue durée</i> ethnographic research methodically and how can they account for it? Should they disclose their identities/intentions as researchers and seek permissions when researching congregations to which they ‘belong’ or which they also frequent for non-research (social, devotional, personal) purposes?</span></span></span></span><br/> </li><li><span><span><span><b><span>Ethics and methods in digital research: </span></b><span>How can social researchers ensure methodological rigor while also accounting for contextual nuances when conducting online, digital and distance research? And, how can we distinguish between open-source and public material when conducting digital and social media research?</span></span></span></span></li></ol><p><span><span><span><span><span>The roundtable discussion will be moderated by </span><a href="https://www.religion.utoronto.ca/people/directories/all-faculty/karen-ruffle" rel="nofollow"><b>Karen Ruffle</b></a><span>, Professor of History of Religions at the University of Toronto, and </span><a href="https://www.soas.ac.uk/staff/staff105767.php" rel="nofollow"><b>Alison Scott-Baumann</b></a><span>, Professor of Society and Belief at the School of Oriental and African Studies (SOAS), University of London. Karen Ruffle specializes in the study of South Asian Shiʿism and is the convenor of the Working Group Sensing Shiʿism, which brings together scholars engaged in ethnographic, theoretical, and empirical research on material culture, the sensorium, and ritual practice. Alison Scott-Baumann has conducted research on Islam and Islamic studies in British higher education. Her work has addressed the impact of the U.K. Government’s counter-terrorism strategy, PREVENT, on Islamic Studies and representations of Islam on campus. She has been consulted by the U.K. government and co-authored the Siddiqui Report (2007) and the Review of Imam Training reports in 2008–2010.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><u><span>Background</span></u></b><b><span>:</span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span>An interest in the specialized study of Shiism gained momentum in the 1980s following the Islamic Revolution in Iran in 1979 and the emergence of Shii Islamist movements with a strong presence in the Middle East and activist agendas spanning the globe. This interest motivated academicians, foreign policy researchers and practitioners, and security study specialists, eventually giving rise to an interdisciplinary subfield now commonly referred to as Shii Studies. This nascent field gained new relevance in the twenty-first century as Shii Muslims became increasingly visible among Middle Eastern diasporas in Europe, North America and Australia. This corresponded to mass migrations and forced displacements resulting from violent conflict and economic inopportunity in countries of the Middle East with significant Shii populations since the 1980s as well as sectarianized violence targeting Shiis regionwide since the 2000s.</span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span>Scholars and policy researchers have often (over) emphasized Shii Islamists’ enmity to Israel and opposition to U.S.-led global politics of hegemony as part of a political worldview that has been interwoven in activist interpretations of Shii hagiography, eschatology and ritual cultures since the mid-twentieth century. Moreover, as Shii Muslims born in the global North ‘come of age’ and diasporic Shiis organize the affairs of their communities independently of the more established, Sunni diasporic Muslim organizations, Shiis have found themselves subjected to the scrutinizing gaze of academic researchers and policymakers as well as the disenfranchising policing practices of state and society in the global North.</span></span></span></p><div><span> </span></div><p> </p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><b><u>Roundtable participants</u></b><b>:</b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b>Part I – Shii Studies</b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b>Chair:</b> Fouad Gehad Marei (Lund University)<br/><b>Discussant:</b> Karen Ruffle (University of Toronto)<br/><b>Panelists:</b></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span><span>Edith Szanto (Assistant Professor of Religious Studies, University of Alabama)</span></span></span></span><ul><li><span><span><span><i><span>“Fabricating Shiism”: Analyzing Shii Studies in Light of the Work of Russell McCutcheon</span></i></span></span></span></li></ul></li><li><span><span><span>Zeina Kamal Taha (PhD candidate, American University of Beirut)</span></span></span><ul><li><span><span><span><i>Shii Studies in Ayatollah Ali Khamenai’s Discourse</i></span></span></span></li></ul></li><li><span><span><span>Peyman Eshaghi (PhD Candidate, BGSMCS, Freie Universität Berlin) and Jabbar Rahmani (Assistant Professor of Anthropology, Institute for Social and Cultural Studies, Tehran)</span></span></span><ul><li><span><span><span><i>Considering the Past via the Present: Chances and Challenges of Historical Studies of Shii Rituals</i></span></span></span></li></ul></li><li><span><span><span>Minoo Mishahvalad (Research Fellow, Fondazione per le Scienze Religiose Giovanni XXIII, Palermo)</span></span></span><ul><li><span><span><span><i>How Ethical Can One Study Oneself?</i></span></span></span></li></ul></li></ul><p> </p><p><span><span><span><b>Part II – Ethics and methods</b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b>Chair: </b>Minoo Mirshahvalad (Fondazione per le Scienze Religiose Giovanni XXIII)<br/><b>Discussant:</b> Alison Scott-Baumann (SOAS, University of London)<br/><b>Panelists:</b></span></span></span></p><ul><li><span><span><span>Fouad Gehad Marei (Research Fellow, Lund University)</span></span></span><ul><li><span><span><span><i>Reflections on Ethics and Methods in Digital and Ethnographic Research</i></span></span></span></li></ul></li><li><span><span><span>Jean-Michel Landry (Professor of Anthropology, Carleton University)</span></span></span><ul><li><span><span><span><i>Suspicious Subjects: The Ethics and Politics of Ethnographic Trust in Shii Contexts</i></span></span></span></li></ul></li><li><span><span><span>Hutan Hejazi (Assistant Professor of Social Science, Universidad Europea de Madrid)</span></span></span><ul><li><span><span><span><i><span>Towards an Ethnography of the Oppressed: On How to Do Fieldwork with Your Enemies, and Why</span></i></span></span></span></li></ul></li><li><span><span><span>Oliver Scharbrodt (Professor of Islamic Studies, Lund University)</span></span></span><ul><li><span><span><span><i>S</i><i>patial Methodology in the Study of Diasporic Religions: The Example of Transnational Twelver Shia Islam in Europe</i></span></span></span></li></ul></li></ul><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:fouad.marei@ctr.lu.se">fouad.marei@ctr.lu.se</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 17:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1662788229029237</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The World of Printed Prayers</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/09/09/the-world-of-printed-prayers</link>
						<dc:creator>katherinemtycz@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Friday, September 9, 2022 - 7:07pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>University of Galway</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:printedprayersproject@gmail.com">printedprayersproject@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/bibliography-and-history-of-the-book">bibliography and history of the book</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/eighteenth-century">eighteenth century</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/renaissance">renaissance</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>October 17, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>CALL FOR PAPERS</strong></p>
<p><strong>The World of Printed Prayers</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>2-day Virtual Conference</strong></p>
<p><strong>The University of Galway</strong></p>
<p><strong>26-27 January 2023</strong></p>
<p><strong>Thursday and Friday, 12:45-5:30 (Irish Standard Time)</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Since it’s invention, print has been harnessed to promote piety, to proselytize, and to spread both orthodox and unorthodox beliefs. This conference will explore the multifaceted use of printed devotional objects from the earliest days of replicating text and image using printing techniques through the end of the nineteenth century. This conference is particularly concerned with the production, dissemination, and engagement with cheap printed prayers from all faiths, denominations, and religious traditions around the world. In particular, speakers are asked to explore relatively brief prayer texts that appear in in the form of short-printed pamphlets, chapbooks, micro-chapbooks, broadsides, flyers, posters, images with captions, saint cards (such as <em>santini</em>), etc. Such texts may include: short prayers, longer prayer texts, intercessory prayers, legends and litanies of saints, virtual pilgrimages, songs, catechisms, etc. Whether they were sold in bookshops, peddled by street-sellers, presented by a mountebank as part of a religious cure, sold as pilgrimage souvenirs, passed out on holy days, or distributed by official authorities, these printed objects had the potential to reach wide audiences. With texts often accompanied by images, these objects also appeal to a range of devotees of different ages, socio-economic classes, and literacy levels.</p>
<p>We invite papers that explore the use of print in the dissemination of prayer texts from any time, place, and faith up until 1900. Please submit <strong>150-word bios</strong> and abstracts for <strong>traditional 20-minute conference papers (200 word abstract)</strong> or <strong>10-minute case studies (100 word abstract)</strong> that engage with, but are not limited to, any of the following themes:</p>
<p> <strong>Production</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Authorship</li>
<li>Printing &amp; Printers</li>
<li>Methods of printing</li>
<li>Official vs. clandestine production</li>
<li>Illustrations (woodcuts, engravings, etchings, lithographs, etc.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Content</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Links to oral and manuscript traditions</li>
<li>Poetry or prose</li>
<li>Popular prayer texts</li>
<li>Figures</li>
<li>Themes</li>
<li>The use of the vernacular</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Dissemination</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>How were they distributed? By whom?</li>
<li>Spreading of orthodox or unorthodox beliefs</li>
<li>Policing of printed prayers</li>
<li>Translation and transmission</li>
<li>Intended vs. actual audience</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Engagement</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Multimodal and sensory engagement with printed prayers</li>
<li>Agency of the printed object</li>
<li>The role of literacy</li>
<li>Text &amp; Image Interactions</li>
<li>Role in devotional practices</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Legacy</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Ephemerality</li>
<li>Collection history</li>
<li>Bibliographic analysis</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Please submit your brief bios, paper titles, and abstracts to Dr Katherine Tycz (University of Galway) at </strong><a href="mailto:printedprayersproject@gmail.com"><strong>printedprayersproject@gmail.com</strong></a><strong> by midnight (Irish Standard Time) October 17, 2022.</strong></p>
<p><strong>The World of Printed Prayers</strong> conference is hosted by Dr. Katherine Tycz, Irish Research Council Postdoctoral Fellow in Italian Studies. Dr. Tycz is based at the Moore Institute for Research in the Humanities and Social Studies and is affiliated with the Centre for the Study of Religion (CSR) at the University of Galway.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>                    </p>
<p> </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 16:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1662788229029236</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hinduism Against Hindutva</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/09/07/hinduism-against-hindutva</link>
						<dc:creator>mukti.lakhi@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Friday, September 9, 2022 - 7:01pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Mukti Lakhi Mangharam</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:mukti.l.m@rutgers.edu">mukti.l.m@rutgers.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/ethnicity-and-national-identity">ethnicity and national identity</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/gender-studies-and-sexuality">gender studies and sexuality</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/world-literatures-and-indigenous-studies">world literatures and indigenous studies</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>November 1, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p> </p>
<p>Hinduism Against Hindutva</p>
<p> </p>
<p>In the summer of 2021, speakers at the Dismantling Global Hindutva conference stated: "In our advocacy, we state clearly that Hindutva ideology is not the same as the Hinduism that we aspire to, but we cannot deny that proponents of Hindutva are doing so as Hindus, in the name of a monolithic Hinduism. As Shana Sippy put it, not all Hinduism is Hindutva, but Hindutva is clearly one manifestation of Hinduism.”  </p>
<p> </p>
<p>To contest the kind of monolithic Hinduism that has lent itself to Hindutva and that is becoming increasingly dominant, we are compiling an edited collection that seeks to center ethical, inclusive, anti-caste, feminist and anti-patriarchal strands of thought in Hindu mythology, philosophy and culture. This collection will not be a defense of Hinduism. Rather, it will acknowledge the hierarchical and oppressive forms that Hinduism has taken and seek to mount critiques of them from within the tradition itself, highlighting a centuries old process of radical dissent and interpretation within a vast and differentiated cultural system of thought and practice. The collection would critique the strands that lend themselves so easily to/are Hindutva and seek to understand and lend force to the more complex strands within Hinduism that can be interpreted in ways that are anti-hierarchical and inclusive.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>We invite 300 word abstracts from interested contributors.Please email <a href="mailto:mukti.l.m@rutgers.edu">mukti.l.m@rutgers.edu</a></p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 13:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1662788229029235</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Papers: 'The Natures of the Beast: Medieval Animal Entanglements' (IMC Leeds 2023)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10830793/call-papers-natures-beast-medieval-animal-entanglements-imc</link>
						<dc:creator>Sven Gins</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-09-14T00:00:00-04:00">September 14, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Animal Studies, Art, Art History &amp; Visual Studies, Cultural History / Studies, Medieval and Byzantine History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Medieval history teems with animals, creatures both mundane and fantastic. Much as our historiography would suggest humankind’s solitary ascent from simian to sovereign of the world, the reality is that human life and imagination are often intrinsically entangled with nonhuman creatures. As medievalists, we know that our history is not just our own: it is inextricably bound, stitched, and glued together with nonhumans.</p><p>The ongoing ‘Animal Turn’ in the humanities generates a growing body of research about these commonly overlooked historical actors. Recent studies raise ethical implications about how humans have treated other animals, past and present, by interrogating the apparent self-evidence of the human/animal binary and highlighting animal entanglement, agency, and coevolution. In response to the Leeds International Medieval Congress 2023’s ‘Networks and Entanglements’ theme, we welcome proposals for 20-minute papers on any aspect of (human-)animal entanglement.</p><p><strong>Potential themes include (but are not limited to):</strong></p><ul><li>Animal entanglements in medieval art, literature, socio-political or religious discourse, or material culture;</li><li>Animals that problematise the medieval hierarchy of creation; </li><li>Hybrids/monsters that transcend elemental, humoral, or other categories;</li><li>Medieval animals that oscillate between pain and pleasure;</li><li>Animals that complicate medieval notions of linear and nonlinear time;</li><li>Animals as vectors for medieval ethnic/racial discourse; </li><li>Medieval animal entanglements in post-medieval media;</li><li>Medieval animal entanglements as (in)tangible heritage;</li><li>Human-nonhuman animal entanglements in any of the above;</li></ul><p>We invite papers that explore any of the above-mentioned themes from a variety of disciplines. All scholars are welcome, including virtual delegates. <strong>Please send a title and abstract of your paper (250-300 words) as well as a short biography to Sven Gins (<u><a href="mailto:s.gins@rug.nl">s.gins@rug.nl</a></u>) by Wednesday, September 14th, 2022, at the latest. </strong>The session(s) will be sponsored by the Dutch Research Council (NWO) as part of the <em>Homo Imperfectus </em>project (PGW.21.029) and by the Centre for Religion and Heritage at the University of Groningen. The Leeds IMC will take place from from July 3rd to 6th, 2023. </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:s.gins@rug.nl">s.gins@rug.nl</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 17:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1662701832775083</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP - South Central Renaissance Conference</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/09/06/cfp-south-central-renaissance-conference</link>
						<dc:creator>sdunnhensley@yahoo.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Wednesday, September 7, 2022 - 10:31pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Susan Dunn-Hensley (program chair) / South Central Renaissance Conference </div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:susan.dunnhensley@wheaton.edu">susan.dunnhensley@wheaton.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/international-conferences">international conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/renaissance">renaissance</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/theatre">theatre</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>December 30, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><strong>Call for Papers </strong></p>
<p><strong>The South Central Renaissance Conference</strong></p>
<p>Exploring the Renaissance 2023: An International Conference</p>
<p> </p>
<p>April 27-29, 2023 — University of California, Berkeley</p>
<p> </p>
<p>SCRC welcomes 15- to 20-minute papers on all aspects of Renaissance studies. Submit 300-to 500-word abstracts at southcentralrenaissanceconference.org </p>
<p> </p>
<p>Deadline: December 30, 2022</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Full conference CFP and Submission Information: <a href="https://southcentralrenaissanceconference.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/SCRC-2023-Call-for-Papers.pdf">SCRC-2023-Call-for-Papers.pdf (southcentralrenaissanceconference.org)</a><a href="https://southcentralrenaissanceconference.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/SCRC-2023-Call-for-Papers.pdf"><br/></a></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Program Chair: Susan Dunn-Hensley</p>
<p>contact information: <a href="mailto:susan.dunnhensley@wheaton.edu">susan.dunnhensley@wheaton.edu</a> </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 19:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1662701832775082</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Interdisciplinary Qur'anic Studies 2022 : Call for paper: International Journal of Interdisciplinary Qur'anic Studies</title>
			<link>http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=168599&amp;copyownerid=176853</link>
						<description>Call for paper: International Journal of Interdisciplinary Qur'anic Studies</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 05:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1662615430402755</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>UK Association for Buddhist Studies Conference 2023 - Call for Papers</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10829024/uk-association-buddhist-studies-conference-2023-call-papers</link>
						<dc:creator>Nick Swann</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-01-05T00:00:00-05:00">January 5, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United Kingdom</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Anthropology, Area Studies, Asian History / Studies, Humanities, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><pre>



 </pre>

<p>Details of the cfp for UKABS 2023 are below. They can also be found on the UKABS website (see link above). As stated below we are keen to attract academic papers from people whose work is influenced by Buddhist thought, practice, or similar who would not typically think of submitting a paper to a Buddhist Studies conference, so please feel free to circulate this cfp widely and imaginatively. </p>
<p>Many thanks,</p>
<p>Nick Swann, Secretary, UKABS.</p>
<p>*****</p>
<p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The UK Association for Buddhist Studies is pleased to announce that our annual conference for 2023 will take place at the University of St Andrews, Scotland, <b>21-23 June 2023</b>. The conference is supported by the St Andrews Encyclopaedia of Theology.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p>
<p><span><span><span><span><b><span><span>Negotiating Boundaries in Buddhism and Buddhist Studies</span></span></b></span></span></span></span></p>
<p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Constructed boundaries divide one religion from another, one ethnic group from another, and define gender identities. Further, boundaries exist within many arenas of secular, social and professional life. Within academia, such firm boundaries exist between academics in different disciplines that two people working in the same field at the same institution can be completely unaware of one another. To a casual or uninvested observer, such boundaries can appear clear and solid; on closer inspection they are revealed as porous, complex, contested. For instance, there appears to be a clear boundary between lay and ordained Buddhists across different Buddhist traditions, but temporary ordination is common in some cultures, as is the taking of extra precepts by laity during retreat or on certain days of the month, and Vajrayāna <i>yogi</i>s and <i>yoginī</i>s blur this distinction further. As well, cultural practices such as festivals can cut across boundaries between Buddhist and non-Buddhist groups in a society, and plural and hybrid identities problematise the very category of ‘Buddhist’. Converts to Buddhism face negotiating their new identity and adapting habits and behaviours. Theoretically, the concept of <i>anatta</i> challenges gender or sexuality as fixed categories, but inclusivity might not be played out in the lived experience of Buddhists. From student to professor, scholar-practitioners in Buddhist Studies continually hop across a boundary between critically distant academic and sympathetic insider. Furthermore, Buddhist Studies itself is not a limited good existing solely for its own sake, but has come to inform and be informed by a range of academic disciplines including law, business studies, neuroscience, peace studies, politics, and philosophy amongst others. In fact, Buddhist studies has previously imposed its own boundaries on various aspects of Buddhist tradition by the habit of taxonomy in its critical study: for example, the perceived divides between meditation and text, or text and ritual, and those imagined between artefact and embodied presence. Methodological and categorical insights from various disciplines may well contribute to the construction of new lines of demarcation, or facilitate the disruption of others.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p>
<p><span><span><span><span><span><span>For the conference, our aim is to explore a variety of boundaries including, but not limited to:</span></span></span></span></span></span></p>
<ul><li><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Perceived boundaries between religious ‘insider’ and ‘outsider’</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Constructed boundaries between academic disciplines</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Contested boundaries between one religion and another</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Erected boundaries between those inside the academy and those outside</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li></ul>
<p><span><span><span><span><span><span>This conference welcomes papers that explore these boundaries. We would particularly welcome papers from academics who do not affiliate to Buddhist Studies but whose work is informed by Buddhist Studies.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p>
<p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The call for panels and proposals opens on <b>6 September </b>and closes on <b>5 January 2023</b>. </span></span></span></span></span></span></p>
<p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Types of submission: </span></span></span></span></span></span></p>
<ol><li><span><span><span><span><span><b><span><span>Short panel</span></span></b><span><span>: Panel organisers are asked to submit a title and 300-word abstract on the panel and a list of potential panellists. Short panels are one hour long and should consist of three panellists who will each present 15 minute papers. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><b><span><span>Long panel</span></span></b><span><span>: Panel organisers are asked to submit a title and 300-word abstract on the panel and a list of potential panellists. Long panels are two hours long and should consist of four panellists who will each present 20 minute papers.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span><span><span><b><span><span>Paper submission</span></span></b><span><span>: Individuals are invited to submit a title and 300-word abstract on a research paper. If accepted, the conference committee will organise these into panels. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></li></ol>
<p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Please send your submissions to: <a href="mailto:negotiatingboundaries@gmail.com"><span>negotiatingboundaries@gmail.com</span></a></span></span></span></span></span></span></p>
<p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The call for panels and proposals is open to all academics, students and interested parties. The UK Association for Buddhist Studies also has a proud tradition of showcasing the work of up-and-coming research students, and a separate call for postgraduate panels will be advertised in due course.  </span></span></span></span></span></span></p>
<p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Conference registration will open on <b>31 October 2022</b> and be available via the University of St Andrews website. </span></span></span></span></span></span></p>
<p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The conference will take place in <a href="https://news.st-andrews.ac.uk/long-reads/the-quad/" rel="nofollow"><span>St Salvator’s</span></a>, one of the oldest remaining parts of the university, which is situated a few minutes walk from our well-known <a href="https://fifecoastandcountrysidetrust.co.uk/walks/fife-beaches/st-andrews-west-sands/" rel="nofollow"><span>West Sands</span></a> beach. </span></span></span></span></span></span></p>
<p><span><span><span><span><b><span><span>Conference events</span></span></b></span></span></span></span></p>
<p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The conference begins on Wednesday with registration throughout the day and the first event at 3.15pm. For those travelling the day before there is a Ceilidh and Whiskey-tasting event the night before, that can be booked when you register for the conference. A <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xPDwO-M-VUE" rel="nofollow"><span>Ceilidh</span></a>, for those who do not know, is an evening of Scottish dancing (kilts optional!) Also, on the Wednesday the university will be opening its collection of religious manuscripts for viewing. Over the whole course of the conference, Tibetan Tashi Lhunpo monks will be visiting and creating a <a href="https://www.tashi-lhunpo.org.uk/sand-mandala-making" rel="nofollow"><span>sand mandala</span></a>. This can be viewed any time by any delegate, and we will have the sand mandala closing ritual to conclude the conference. On Thursday evening, after the conference dinner, the Tashi Lhunpo monks will also offer us a <a href="https://www.tashi-lhunpo.org.uk/masked-dance" rel="nofollow"><span>cham</span></a> performance.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p>
<p><span><span><span><span><span><span>The conference organising committee is: Dr Elizabeth Harris (University of Birmingham), President of UKABS, Dr Nick Swann (University of South Wales), UKABS Secretary, Prof. Alice Collett (University of St Andrews) and Dr Nic Newton.  </span></span></span></span></span></span></p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Please use the contact email address for correspondence. </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:negotiatingboundaries@gmail.com">negotiatingboundaries@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://ukabs.org.uk/2023-conference/" target="_blank">https://ukabs.org.uk/2023-conference/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 17:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1662615430402754</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Opportunites Digest – September 5, 2022</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-opportunites-digest-september-5-2022/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find several job postings, one application for research funding, and one call for papers. </p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 37!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Post-Doctoral Research Associate for Project on Abuse in Religious Contexts</h4>



<p>University of Kent, UK</p>



<p>Deadline: September 19, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://jobs.kent.ac.uk/vacancy.aspx?ref=AHUM-189-22">AHUM-189-22 Post-Doctoral Research Associate – Jobs at the University of Kent</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Religion</h4>



<p>Trinity University, US</p>



<p>Deadline: October 3, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.trinity.edu/human-resources/employment-opportunities/faculty/40861">https://www.trinity.edu/human-resources/employment-opportunities/faculty/40861</a></p>



<h4>Post-Doctoral Position in Buddhism and Waste</h4>



<p>University of Copenhagen, DK</p>



<p>Deadline: November 25, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://eur01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Femployment.ku.dk%2Ffaculty%2F%3Fshow%3D157235&amp;data=05%7C01%7Cb.schmidt%40uwtsd.ac.uk%7Cc532662fb2b5461b25a708da86609ce9%7C4e0f11f9046e45059cb8db2152311e21%7C0%7C0%7C637970046745365872%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=HsL2ZGygakCpefknxWS8vRmH7PSy2XJ%2F8cc1ZHrIQlM%3D&amp;reserved=0">https://eur01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Femployment.ku.dk%2Ffaculty%2F%3Fshow%3D157235&amp;data=05%7C01%7Cb.schmidt%40uwtsd.ac.uk%7Cc532662fb2b5461b25a708da86609ce9%7C4e0f11f9046e45059cb8db2152311e21%7C0%7C0%7C637970046745365872%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=HsL2ZGygakCpefknxWS8vRmH7PSy2XJ%2F8cc1ZHrIQlM%3D&amp;reserved=0</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor – Religions of Africa and/or Its Diaspora</h4>



<p>University of Tennessee, US</p>



<p>Deadline: October 15, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://apply.interfolio.com/111195?fbclid=IwAR0Lt0bCl4AfUyWj_CygX37JZpdu5iUFmU0wYZXpwpu9Mf4pbAgFkwVh4_I">https://apply.interfolio.com/111195?fbclid=IwAR0Lt0bCl4AfUyWj_CygX37JZpdu5iUFmU0wYZXpwpu9Mf4pbAgFkwVh4_I</a></p>



<h2>Research Funding:</h2>



<h4>Apply for Funding to Analyze and Write About Data from the National Survey of Religious Leaders</h4>



<p>Through Duke University, US</p>



<p>Deadline: October 3, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://nam10.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fsites.duke.edu%2Fnsrl%2Faward-details&amp;data=05%7C01%7Cngibson%40templeton.org%7C3e9e117791894b440db208da89df8833%7Cd8048558225c4dd4b685805de9f9489a%7C0%7C0%7C637973890433772320%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=gHl0wFHdw7GGJavu67pHKygf9NGz9bx5FTIo3C6R6pQ%3D&amp;reserved=0">https://nam10.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fsites.duke.edu%2Fnsrl%2Faward-details&amp;data=05%7C01%7Cngibson%40templeton.org%7C3e9e117791894b440db208da89df8833%7Cd8048558225c4dd4b685805de9f9489a%7C0%7C0%7C637973890433772320%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=gHl0wFHdw7GGJavu67pHKygf9NGz9bx5FTIo3C6R6pQ%3D&amp;reserved=0</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>New Scholarship in the Study of African American Religious History</h4>



<p>Deadline: October 31, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://crossroads.princeton.edu/cfp-edited-volume-african-american-religious-history">https://crossroads.princeton.edu/cfp-edited-volume-african-american-religious-history</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1662615430402753</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Arc - Extended Call for Book Reviews</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/09/05/arc-extended-call-for-book-reviews</link>
						<dc:creator>Daniel.fishley@mcgill.ca</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Wednesday, September 7, 2022 - 9:55pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Arc: Journal of the School of Religious Studies</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:arc.relgstud@mcgill.ca">arc.relgstud@mcgill.ca</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/theory">theory</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>October 31, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Call for Book Reviews: “Looking Backward – Looking Forward”</p>
<p>The editors of Arc: Journal of the School of Religious Studies are pleased to announce an extended call for book reviews for our forthcoming volume (Vol. 50). As the 50th anniversary of the journal presents a unique opportunity to think both retrospectively and prospectively, Arc is asking for submissions that engage with the theme of looking backward – looking forward.</p>
<p>The theme of looking forward – looking backward resonates across diverse and interdisciplinary interactions with religion. Submissions are welcome from any area within the study of religion, including: Theology; Comparative Religions; Theory and Method; Philosophy of Religion; History of Religions; Sociology of Religion; Anthropology of Religion; Psychology of Religion; Religious Ethics; Critical Race Theory; Religion and Literature; Religion and Art; Religion and Linguistics; Religion and Health; Textual Studies. Submissions may focus on traditions from any time period or geographic area. General book reviews that do not engage with the theme are also accepted.</p>
<p>The submission deadline for Vol. 50 is 31 October, 2022. Book reviews should not exceed 1,500 words. For detailed submission guidelines, please consult the Guidelines for Contributors on our website (<a href="https://www.mcgill.ca/religiousstudies/research/publications">https://www.mcgill.ca/religiousstudies/research/publications</a>). All electronic correspondence should be sent to the editors at the following email address: <a href="mailto:arc.relgstud@mcgill.ca">arc.relgstud@mcgill.ca</a></p>
<p>Arc is an interdisciplinary, refereed journal published annually by the School of Religious Studies, McGill University. The journal combines the talents of professors and graduate students in offering space for scholarly discussions on various aspects of the academic study of religion.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 13:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1662615430402752</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Dissenting Beliefs Edited Collection: Heresy and Heterodoxy in Fantasy</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/09/05/dissenting-beliefs-edited-collection-heresy-and-heterodoxy-in-fantasy</link>
						<dc:creator>lucinda.holdsworth@glasgow.ac.uk</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Wednesday, September 7, 2022 - 9:52pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Centre for Fantasy and the Fantastic</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:Dissenting.Beliefs@gmail.com">Dissenting.Beliefs@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/film-and-television">film and television</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/popular-culture">popular culture</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>October 3, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Religious fantasy, for a great many readers, is synonymous with Christian fantasy; more specifically, it is understood as literature overtly reproducing biblical narratives within a fantasy world, such as C. S. Lewis’ The Chronicles of Narnia. Concurrently, fantasy texts engaging with theology through non-allegorical means that challenge mainstream Christian doctrine are all too often dismissed as disingenuous, offensive or deliberately antagonistic. While this is sometimes the case, such a narrow view of religious fantasy excludes all but the least innovative texts from the genre and leaves little room for authors of other faiths. Furthermore, the dominance of texts affirming orthodoxy in religious fantasy discourse threatens to blind us to another side of belief: that radical, sometimes even heretical, literary reconfigurations of religion can also be acts of devotion.</p>
<p>If religious fantasy is instead allowed to encompass heterodoxy and heresy, theological subversions and expressions of misotheism, then the affordances of religious fantasy expand far beyond the didacticism popularly attributed to it. Understood in these terms, religious fantasy can be used: to affirm one’s identity and spiritual worth in opposition to official doctrines which may deny it, as a tool of protest against unjust systems of power, to explore complex spiritual responses to historical instances of religious complicity in atrocities, or to express lived spiritual experiences which do not conform to orthodox teachings.</p>
<p>Following on from the ‘Dissenting Beliefs’ conference sponsored by the Centre for Fantasy and the Fantastic at the University of Glasgow in December 2021, this edited volume aims to encompass the depth and breadth of new scholarship on the affordances of heresy and heterodoxy in fantasy across a wide range of faiths. We welcome proposals for eventual peer-reviewed chapters of 5,000-7,000 words, and we especially welcome submissions from postgraduate students and early-career researchers. Chapters might address, but are not limited to, the following topics:</p>
<p>Queer, feminist and womanist theology in fantasy <br/>Non-Western, post-colonial or anti-colonial heresies and fantasy <br/>Misotheism, ‘New’ Atheism and Death of God theology in fantasy <br/>Fantasy and interreligious dialogue <br/>The affordances of fantasy in theologies of protest <br/>New Media’s interactions with fantasy and theology, and how this might differ from traditional media</p>
<p>Please submit a 300-word abstract and a short bio (maximum 150 words) to <a href="mailto:Dissenting.Beliefs@gmail.com">Dissenting.Beliefs@gmail.com</a> with the subject line ‘Abstract Submission’ by 3 October 2022. We are particularly keen to highlight the contributions of authors who are underrepresented in scholarship on religion and theology in fantasy; therefore we will not be accepting submissions on the works of J.R.R. Tolkien, C.S. Lewis, J.K. Rowling or Philip Pullman.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1662615430402751</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
