<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 03:36:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 03:36:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ March 31, 2023 -  April 1, 2023] Conference or similar: Philosophy of religion in Asia</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103290</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p>The Veritas Research Center (at UIC, Yonsei University) is hosting a workshop on the philosophy of religion, which will be held in a hybrid format in Seoul/online on March 31 (Friday)/April 1 (Saturday) 2023.</p>
<p>The aim of this workshop is to diversify and globalize philosophy of religion. As it stands, philosophy of religion has traditionally tended to pay particular attention to philosophical questions arising within and about Christianity. Moreover, leading English philosophy of religion journals tend to receive far more submissions from English-speaking parts of the world. At the same time, philosophy of religion is a broad field that encompasses philosophically relevant questions arising within and about any religious tradition and about religion(s) in general. Relatedly, journals such as the <em>Journal of Analytic Theology</em>, <em>Religious Studies</em>, and the <em>International Journal for Philosophy of Religion</em> are seeking more submissions from non-English-speaking parts of the world. Thus, the field has much potential to continue its ongoing efforts to globalize and diversify.</p>
<p>In addition to talks on any topic of the philosophy of religion, the workshop will include a <strong>Publication Seminar</strong> held by Prof. Helen De Cruz, Executive Editor of the <em>Journal of Analytic Theology. </em>This seminar is aimed at early career researchers and doctoral students across Asia who are interested in publishing in leading English philosophy of religion journals. The seminar will offer practical advice on how to make a paper ready for submission (e.g., cover letter, formatting), where and how to submit, how to increase the odds that your paper survives the desk review stage, when to query an editor, etc.</p>
<p>We invite abstracts of between 150 and 300 words on any topic in philosophy of religion(s), broadly construed. We particularly encourage early career researchers working in Asia to apply.</p>
<p>Please send your abstract as an email attachment, with the subject line ‘Philosophy of Religion in Asia’ to <a href="mailto:nataljadeng@yonsei.ac.kr">nataljadeng at yonsei.ac.kr</a> by 23:59 (KST) on November 30 2022. Papers should be suitable for a 20-30 minute presentation. In the body of the email, please indicate (a) your current affiliation, and (b) whether you would prefer to present in person or online. (Please note that we cannot offer travel funding, so that you should only indicate that you prefer to present in person if you have travel funding or are based in Seoul or its surroundings.)</p>
<p>In case of questions, please feel free to contact <a href="mailto:nataljadeng@yonsei.ac.kr">nataljadeng at yonsei.ac.kr</a></p>
<p>The event is jointly sponsored by Prof. <strong>Yujin Nagasawa</strong>’s Global Philosophy of Religion Project at the University of Birmingham (<a href="https://urldefense.com/v3/__https:/www.global-philosophy.org/__;!!K543PA!OpbVpEmmnkasi-MEbQtSTI1olToT2CclUhFgqSHti4M3f_vpPjP-_WLmPgSEHQVeiF2I1NPlJ9DDCfsS%24">https://www.global-philosophy.org/</a>) and the Veritas Research Center, Underwood International College (UIC), Yonsei University.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663997827801221</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ November 30, 2022] CFP for conference or similar: Philosophy of religion in Asia</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103294</link>
						<description><p>The Veritas Research Center (at UIC, Yonsei University) is hosting a workshop on the philosophy of religion, which will be held in a hybrid format in Seoul/online on March 31 (Friday)/April 1 (Saturday) 2023.</p>
<p>The aim of this workshop is to diversify and globalize philosophy of religion. As it stands, philosophy of religion has traditionally tended to pay particular attention to philosophical questions arising within and about Christianity. Moreover, leading English philosophy of religion journals tend to receive far more submissions from English-speaking parts of the world. At the same time, philosophy of religion is a broad field that encompasses philosophically relevant questions arising within and about any religious tradition and about religion(s) in general. Relatedly, journals such as the <em>Journal of Analytic Theology</em>, <em>Religious Studies</em>, and the <em>International Journal for Philosophy of Religion</em> are seeking more submissions from non-English-speaking parts of the world. Thus, the field has much potential to continue its ongoing efforts to globalize and diversify.</p>
<p>In addition to talks on any topic of the philosophy of religion, the workshop will include a <strong>Publication Seminar</strong> held by Prof. Helen De Cruz, Executive Editor of the <em>Journal of Analytic Theology. </em>This seminar is aimed at early career researchers and doctoral students across Asia who are interested in publishing in leading English philosophy of religion journals. The seminar will offer practical advice on how to make a paper ready for submission (e.g., cover letter, formatting), where and how to submit, how to increase the odds that your paper survives the desk review stage, when to query an editor, etc.</p>
<p>We invite abstracts of between 150 and 300 words on any topic in philosophy of religion(s), broadly construed. We particularly encourage early career researchers working in Asia to apply.</p>
<p>Please send your abstract as an email attachment, with the subject line ‘Philosophy of Religion in Asia’ to <a href="mailto:nataljadeng@yonsei.ac.kr">nataljadeng at yonsei.ac.kr</a> by 23:59 (KST) on November 30 2022. Papers should be suitable for a 20-30 minute presentation. In the body of the email, please indicate (a) your current affiliation, and (b) whether you would prefer to present in person or online. (Please note that we cannot offer travel funding, so that you should only indicate that you prefer to present in person if you have travel funding or are based in Seoul or its surroundings.)</p>
<p>In case of questions, please feel free to contact <a href="mailto:nataljadeng@yonsei.ac.kr">nataljadeng at yonsei.ac.kr</a></p>
<p>The event is jointly sponsored by Prof. <strong>Yujin Nagasawa</strong>’s Global Philosophy of Religion Project at the University of Birmingham (<a href="https://urldefense.com/v3/__https:/www.global-philosophy.org/__;!!K543PA!OpbVpEmmnkasi-MEbQtSTI1olToT2CclUhFgqSHti4M3f_vpPjP-_WLmPgSEHQVeiF2I1NPlJ9DDCfsS%24">https://www.global-philosophy.org/</a>) and the Veritas Research Center, Underwood International College (UIC), Yonsei University.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663997827801220</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CQHA Online: Interpretive Approaches Sessions: October 2022</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10979999/cqha-online-interpretive-approaches-sessions-october-2022</link>
						<dc:creator>Susan Garfinkel</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Symposium</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-12T00:00:00-04:00">October 12, 2022</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-10-26T00:00:00-04:00">October 26, 2022</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>American History / Studies, Art, Art History &amp; Visual Studies, Atlantic History / Studies, Colonial and Post-Colonial History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><h3>CQHA ONLINE: INTERPRETATIVE APPROACHES SESSIONS: OCTOBER 2022&amp;</h3><p>Please join the Conference of Quaker Historians and Archivists (CQHA) on<strong> three days in October</strong> for a set of virtual sessions foregrounding expanded approaches to the study of Quaker history and culture. </p><p><strong>Our <a href="https://library.guilford.edu/cqha/june2022" rel="nofollow">October sessions</a> have been chosen with a focus on interpretive approaches in mind.</strong> In each, we are delighted to welcome both emerging and established practitioners in their areas of Quaker scholarship. We will also hold short CQHA informational briefings and our biennial CQHA business meeting as part of these sessions. We will meet over Zoom and there is no cost to attend. <a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/cqha-online-interpretative-approaches-sessions-october-2022-tickets-422164544517" rel="nofollow">Registration is via Eventbrite</a>. </p><p>The sessions are scheduled for<strong> October 12, 19, and 26, beginning at 12:30 pm EDT</strong>. They are: </p><p> </p><p><strong>♦ Graphic Novels: Quakers in Pictures and Print</strong><br/>   Wednesday, October 12, 2022 </p><p>12:30-2:00 pm EDT | Session<br/>  2:00-2:30 pm EDT | CQHA Briefing</p><p><em>Presenters:</em></p><ul><li><strong>Marcus Rediker</strong>, Distinguished Professor, University of Pittsburgh</li><li><strong>David Lester</strong>, Artist and musician (Mecca Normal) in Vancouver, Canada, and graphic novelist of Prophet against Slavery</li><li><strong>Will Fenton</strong>, Associate Director, Center for Spatial and Textual Analysis, Stanford University</li><li><strong>Katelyn L. Lucas</strong>, Tribal Historic Preservation Assistant for Delaware Nation and PhD Candidate, Temple University</li><li><strong>Dash Shaw</strong>, American comic book writer/artist and animator, and cartoonist of Discipline (2021) published by the New York Review Comics</li></ul><p><em>Description:</em></p><p>This session focuses on three historical graphic novels to consider issues of interpretation in presenting the Quaker past through the lens of graphic or visual presentation. <strong>David Lester </strong>and <strong>Marcus Rediker</strong> will discuss the collaboration of artist and historian in the making of Prophet against Slavery: Benjamin Lay, A Graphic Novel (Beacon Press, 2021), a graphic adaptation of Rediker’s biography of Benjamin Lay. <strong>Katelyn Lucas</strong> and <strong>Will Fenton</strong> will share insights from Ghost River: The Fall and Rise of the Conestoga (Library Company of Philadelphia, 2019), which reimagines the Paxton massacres of 1763 as an educational graphic novel, introducing new interpreters and new bodies of evidence to highlight Indigenous victims and their kin. <strong>Dash Shaw’s</strong> presentation will detail his process and the historical materials and references for Discipline (New York Review Comics, 2021), a graphic novel about a Quaker soldier in the American Civil War, which incorporates Civil War-era Quaker letters and diary entries. Together these presentations will give insights into innovative ways of engaging and imagining the Quaker past. </p><p><em>CQHA</em>: A short <strong>briefing on CQHA and upcoming business</strong> will follow the presentation. </p><p> </p><p><strong>♦ Thought and Action in Decolonizing Practices: A Conversation</strong><br/>   Wednesday, October 19, 2022 </p><p>12:30-1:00 pm EDT | CQHA Briefing<br/>  1:00-2:30 pm EDT | Session </p><p><em>Presenters</em>:</p><ul><li><strong>Sa’ed Atshan</strong>, Director of Undergraduate Studies and Professor of Anthropology, Emory University</li><li><strong>Paula Palmer</strong>, Director of Toward Right Relationship, a project of the Indigenous Peoples Concerns committee of the Boulder Friends Meeting</li><li><strong>Tanya Maus</strong> (moderator), Director, Peace Resource Center and Director, Quaker Heritage Center, Wilmington College</li></ul><p><em>Description</em>: </p><p>Focusing on academic practice and activism, this panel is devoted to a dialogue between <strong>Sa’ed Atshan</strong> and <strong>Paula Palmer</strong> regarding their interventions into upholding and uplifting the rights of first peoples and colonized peoples. <strong>Tanya Maus</strong> will moderate. <strong>Atshan’s</strong> scholarship has brought into focus the trauma of Palestinian identities including Queer and Quaker Palestinians as well as the potential for intersectional activism and solidarity among various constituents. <strong>Palmer’s</strong> lifework and activism have focused on the rights of Indigenous peoples. She witnesses the roles Quakers played in colonization and the forced assimilation of native children by means of the Quaker industrial boarding schools. Through dialogue, both participants will focus on the relationship between thought and practice, the various meanings of decolonization within the context of their work, and the necessity of restorative justice. </p><p><em>CQHA</em>: A short <strong>briefing on CQHA and upcoming business </strong>will precede the presentation. </p><p> </p><p><strong>♦ Quakers and Networks</strong><br/>   Wednesday, October 26, 2022 </p><p>12:30-2:00 pm EDT | Session<br/>  2:15-3:15 pm EDT | CQHA Business Meeting </p><p><em>Presenters:</em></p><ul><li><strong>Esther Sahle</strong>, Research Associate in Global History, Freie Universität Berlin</li><li><strong>Michael F. Suarez</strong>, S.J., Professor of English and Director of Rare Book School at the University of Virginia</li><li><strong>James Truitt</strong>, Senior Archives Technician, Friends Historical Library of Swarthmore College</li></ul><p><em>Description: </em></p><p>New attention to network analysis in the humanities has invited new opportunities to explore the dense set of religious, economic, and social interconnections that characterize historical Quakerism. In this session, <strong>Esther Sahle</strong> will revisit what we know on the development and significance of Quaker business networks, contextualizing them within broader social and economic developments of the long eighteenth century. <strong>Michael Suarez</strong> will discuss the essential role played by Transatlantic Quaker networks in the campaign to abolish the slave trade, c.1787–1807. <strong>James Truitt</strong> will introduce participants to Friendly Networks, an online project that maps social networks within archival sources using the journals of eighteenth-century New Jersey minister John Hunt together with EAC-CPF and TEI, widely-used standards for authority control and text encoding.</p><p><em>CQHA</em>: The biennial<strong> CQHA Business Meeting</strong> will follow the presentation. </p><p> </p><p><strong>Questions? </strong>Please see our website for full information, and don't hesitate to contact the session organizers by email. </p><ul><li>CQHA Website: <a href="http://libguides.guilford.edu/cqha" rel="nofollow">http://libguides.guilford.edu/cqha</a> </li><li>CQHA June Methodology Sessions: <a href="https://library.guilford.edu/cqha/june2022" rel="nofollow">https://library.guilford.edu/cqha/june2022</a></li><li>Facebook: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/quakerhistoriansandarchivists" rel="nofollow">https://www.facebook.com/quakerhistoriansandarchivists</a></li><li>Contact Us: <a href="mailto:quakerhistoriansandarchivists@gmail.com">quakerhistoriansandarchivists@gmail.com</a></li></ul></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Quaker Historians And Archivists<br/><a href="mailto:quakerhistoriansandarchivists@gmail.com">quakerhistoriansandarchivists@gmail.com</a><br/><a href="https://library.guilford.edu/cqha/june2022" rel="nofollow">https://library.guilford.edu/cqha/june2022</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:quakerhistoriansandarchivists@gmail.com">quakerhistoriansandarchivists@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://library.guilford.edu/cqha/june2022" target="_blank">https://library.guilford.edu/cqha/june2022</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 17:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663997827801219</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Special Topic:Confluence-- Thomas Merton (CEA 3/30/23-4/1/23</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/09/23/special-topicconfluence-thomas-merton-cea-33023-4123</link>
						<dc:creator>mweis9@naz.edu</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Friday, September 23, 2022 - 1:50pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>College English Association + International Thomas Merton Society</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:mweis9@naz.edu">mweis9@naz.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/ecocriticism-and-environmental-studies">ecocriticism and environmental studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/rhetoric-and-composition">rhetoric and composition</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>November 1, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p align="center"><strong>I</strong><strong>nternational </strong><strong>T</strong><strong>homas </strong><strong>M</strong><strong>erton </strong><strong>S</strong><strong>ociety</strong><strong> </strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>at the</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>C</strong><strong>ollege </strong><strong>E</strong><strong>nglish </strong><strong>A</strong><strong>ssociation</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>52nd ANNUAL CONFERENCE</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong> </strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>San Antonio, TX - Sheraton Gunter Hotel</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>March 30-April 1, 2023</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>Call for Papers</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>An allied organization of the College English Association (CEA), the International Thomas Merton Society (ITMS) will be sponsoring one or more panels at the annual CEA Conference next <strong>March 30-Apr. 1</strong>, as well as recommending individual proposals for other concurrent sessions<strong>.  Overarching theme of the Conference: CONFLUENCE.</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Suggested lines of inquiry about Merton's thinking and writing (but only suggested):</em></strong></p>
<p><strong>        </strong><strong>• Merging contemplation and action</strong></p>
<p><strong>         • Prophetic power of confluence: waves of justice, waves of peace</strong></p>
<p><strong>         • Uniting the personal and the public</strong></p>
<p><strong>         • Convergence of commitment: Merton and Dorothy Day; Merton and Heschel; Merton and ?</strong></p>
<p><strong>         • Blending mysticisms: East and West</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>You are invited to submit a title and proposal (200-500 words) for a 6-8 page paper (15 minute presentation time) and encouraged to contact Monica Weis SSJ (<a href="mailto:mweis9@naz.edu">mweis9@naz.edu</a>) for directions on how to submit your proposal to the CEA data base and how to negotiate your CEA membership ($50) by January 2023</p>
<p><strong>Deadline for electronic proposals is November 1, 2022</strong></p>
<p><strong>Online submission site: <a href="http://cea-web.org/">http://cea-web.org</a>   (site opens August 15)</strong></p>
<p>                                         <a href="https://www.conftool.pro/cea2020/" target="_blank">https://www.conftool.pro/cea2023/</a></p>
<p> </p>
<p>The annual CEA Conference is a wonderfully congenial gathering of 500+ scholar-teachers committed to literature, writing, college teaching, and related fields.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 16:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663997827801218</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Marilynne Robinson Society</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/09/22/marilynne-robinson-society</link>
						<dc:creator>hapark1@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Friday, September 23, 2022 - 3:25pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>American Literature Association Conference (ALA); Boston, MA</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:haein.park@biola.edu">haein.park@biola.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/african-american">african-american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>November 15, 2021</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>The Marilynne Robinson Society will be hosting a panel on a wide variety of topics connected to Robinson’s essays and novels at the annual conference of the American Literature Association.</p>
<p>The annual American Literature Association (ALA) conference will take place in Boston, MA, May 25-28, 2023. </p>
<p>Please submit a 350-word proposal and short bio to <a href="mailto:haein.park@biola.edu">haein.park@biola.edu</a> by November 15, 2020.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663997827801217</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Marilynne Robinson, Jesus and John Wayne, and the American Evangelical Tradition</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/09/22/marilynne-robinson-jesus-and-john-wayne-and-the-american-evangelical-tradition</link>
						<dc:creator>hapark1@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Friday, September 23, 2022 - 3:25pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>American Literature Association Conference (ALA); Boston, MA; May 25-28, 2023</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:haein.park@biola.edu">haein.park@biola.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/african-american">african-american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>November 15, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Marilynne Robinson, <em>Jesus and John Wayne</em>, and the American Evangelical Tradition</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The Marilynne Robinson Society at the ALA is seeking papers that examine the author’s relationship to American evangelicalism.  Robinson’s spiritual vision has been shaped by the writings of Jonathan Edwards, who is considered to be the founding father of American evangelicalism.  How does Robinson’s body of work lead us to think critically about the evangelical tradition in the United States?  How do her essays and novels, particularly <em>Gilead</em>, provide a counter-narrative to the discourses found in modern and contemporary American evangelicalism?  In what ways can they respond to the incisive diagnosis presented by Kristen Du Mez’s recent book, <em>Jesus and John Wayne</em>, a text that examines the connection between American evangelicalism, Christian nationalism, rugged masculinity, and political power? How might Robinson’s novels and essays in conversation with Du Mez’s <em>Jesus and John Wayne</em> illuminate our understanding of the evangelical tradition in the United States?  These are some of the questions that the panel seeks to address.</p>
<p>The annual American Literature Association (ALA) conference will take place in Boston, MA, May 25-28, 2023.  </p>
<p>Please submit a 350-word paper proposal and short bio to <a href="mailto:haein.park@biola.edu">haein.park@biola.edu</a> by November 15, 2022. </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 23:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663997827801216</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ November 30, 2022] CFP for conference or similar: 2023 Uehiro Graduate Philosophy Conference - What Dreams May Come?: Philosophical Explorations in Dreaming, Suffering, and Death</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/101438</link>
						<description><p>Call For Papers - Spring 2023 Uehiro Philosophy Graduate Student Conference</p>
<p>Title/Topic: What Dreams May Come?: Philosophical Explorations in Dreaming, Suffering, and Death</p>
<p>Date: Thursday, March 2nd &amp; Friday, March 3rd, 2023</p>
<p>Location: University of Hawaii-Manoa, Honolulu, Hawaii</p>
<p>The University of Hawaii at Manoa Philosophy Department is calling for papers for its annual Uehiro Graduate Student Conference “What Dreams May Come?: Philosophical Explorations in Dreaming, Suffering, and Death”. We invite graduate students working in all areas of philosophy to submit papers on the conference theme. We welcome interdisciplinary submissions, and we strongly encourage submissions from members of underrepresented groups. The conference will take place in person. Travel costs will be subsidized for a small number of student presenters who submit full papers. Affordable lodging will be available for all presenters.</p>
<p>We are honored to have Dr. Michael Brady (University of Glasgow), Dr. Melanie Rosen (Trent University) and Dr. Arindam Chakrabarti (University of Hawaii-Manoa) as our keynote speakers.</p>
<p>This year’s conference title is inspired by the famous lines in Hamlet:</p>
<p>“To be, or not to be, that is the question:</p>
<p>Whether 'tis nobler in the mind to suffer</p>
<p>The slings and arrows of outrageous fortune,</p>
<p>Or to take Arms against a Sea of troubles,</p>
<p>And by opposing end them: to die, to sleep</p>
<p>No more; and by a sleep, to say we end</p>
<p>The heart-ache, and the thousand natural shocks</p>
<p>That Flesh is heir to? 'Tis a consummation</p>
<p>Devoutly to be wished. To die, to sleep,</p>
<p>To sleep, perchance to Dream; aye, there's the rub,</p>
<p>For in that sleep of death, what dreams may come,</p>
<p>When we have shuffled off this mortal coil, </p>
<p>Must give us pause. ”</p>
<p>Papers should explore dreaming, suffering, and death, and grapple with questions that arise out of these facets of life. These topics may also be broadly construed. For example, we welcome papers on "dreaming" as both a phenomena in philosophy of mind and as an "ideal" or "aspiration" in other areas of philosophy. Likewise, "suffering" can include the philosophy of pain, or "duḥkha" in Buddhist philosophy. As such, we invite papers from all philosophical fields and traditions.</p>
<p>Presentations should not exceed twenty (20) minutes in length, and another five (5) minutes for questions. Paper submissions should not exceed 4000 words. Abstracts are also welcome and should not exceed 250 words, but preference for travel funds will be given to completed papers. Submissions should be prepared for blind review. The deadline for submissions is November 30, 2022, and presenters will be notified of our decision by early January.</p>
<p>Send papers as a PDF file and prepared for blind review to uehriogradpc@gmail.com - In the body of the e-mail please include: 1) Your name, 2) Title of the paper, 3) Institutional affiliation, 4) Contact information (e-mail, phone, or mailing address)</p>
<p>The conference is free and open to the public.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663825028249979</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – September 21, 2022</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-september-21-2022/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find four tenure-track job openings.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 37!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Job</h2>



<h4>Assistant Professor of Contemporary Islam in the Americas (tenure-track)</h4>



<p>DePaul University, US</p>



<p>Deadline: October 15<sup>th</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://mesana.org/resources-and-opportunities/2022/09/19/contemporary-islam-in-the-americas">https://mesana.org/resources-and-opportunities/2022/09/19/contemporary-islam-in-the-americas</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor in Religious Studies (tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Colby College, US</p>



<p>Deadline: October 21<sup>st</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://apply.interfolio.com/112793">https://apply.interfolio.com/112793</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor, Religion &amp; Politics in the Department for the Study of Religions (tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Wake Forest University, US</p>



<p>Deadline: October 21<sup>st</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://wfu.wd1.myworkdayjobs.com/en-US/Faculty_Career_Website_live/job/Assistant-Professor--Religion---Politics-in-the-Department-for-the-Study-of-Religions_R0004859?fbclid=IwAR31s5dUIHADeoFTdi6lRQXyy4Vd9qWpfHLl5XsJvZIIBMmh0G7MYBrE65o">Assistant Professor, Religion &amp; Politics in the Department for the Study of Religions (myworkdayjobs.com)</a></p>



<h4>Assistant Professor, East Asian Buddhism in the Department for the Study of Religions (tenure-track)</h4>



<p>Wake Forest, US</p>



<p>Deadline: October 21<sup>st</sup>, 2022</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://wfu.wd1.myworkdayjobs.com/en-US/Faculty_Career_Website_live/job/Assistant-Professor--East-Asian-Buddhism-in-the-Department-for-the-Study-of-Religions_R0004860?fbclid=IwAR3IEeK0FqtG4pcYdwH5tIXob6uixzykWddQ_1ftoDAVt1Acle1EOOfAbKw">Assistant Professor, East Asian Buddhism in the Department for the Study of Religions (myworkdayjobs.com)</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663825028249978</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CfP &quot;“Catholic Abolitionisms&quot;, Trier (Germany), June 15-16, 2023</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10953455/cfp-%E2%80%9Ccatholic-abolitionisms-trier-germany-june-15-16-2023</link>
						<dc:creator>Miriam  Franchina</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-15T00:00:00-04:00">June 15, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-16T00:00:00-04:00">June 16, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Germany</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Atlantic History / Studies, Latin American and Caribbean History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology, Slavery, Spanish and Portuguese History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><div><span><span>Damien Tricoire (Universität Trier), Miriam Franchina (Universität Trier), and Jeremy Popkin (Univ. of Kentucky) are organizing a conference entitled “</span><span><b>Catholic Abolitionisms</b></span><span>.” The conference will be held in </span><span><b>Trier (Germany) on June 15-16, 2023</b></span><span>. </span></span></div><div><span><span>We invite interested scholars to send a <strong>250-word proposal for a 20 minutes presentation </strong>to Miriam Franchina  (</span><a href="mailto:franchina@uni-trier.de"><span>franchina@uni-trier.de</span></a><span>) <strong>by September 30, 2022. </strong></span></span></div><p><span><span>If accepted, speakers will be asked to circulate a draft of their talk shortly before the conference.</span> </span></p><div><span><span>Usually, historiography tends to associate abolitionist movements with Protestant and anglophone movements. Our central question is whether or not, and to what extent, Catholicism inspired abolitionist ideas and movements in the Atlantic world during the early modern era. We use “abolitionisms” in the plural to include instances that may not be connected because of their chronological or geographical distance and to suggest a comparative dimension. We think that a variety of actors (clergymen, indigenous populations, enslaved Africans and Afro-Creoles, members of the Roman Curia, intellectuals in Europe and the Americas, both in colonial times and after independence) may have resorted to Catholic ideas as an argument to criticize the slave trade and colonial slavery fundamentally; and to Catholic networks to concretely reform and possibly abolish the slave trade. </span></span></div><div><span> </span></div><div><span><span>Topics for the conference include (but are not limited to):</span></span></div><ol><li><span><span>The attitude and actions of specific groups of clergy (notably religious orders) to the question of slavery and slave trade, for example, how the Dominicans with Las Casas (16th c.), or the Capuchins with De Jaca and Moirans (17th c.) substantially contested slavery and the slave trade.</span></span></li><li><span><span>The attitude and ensuing actions taken by the Roman Curia based on reports and requests coming from missionaries across the world, both before and after officially condemning slavery in 1839 (for example, the 11 articles issued in 1686 on the enslavement of Africans; or the ad-hoc deliberations on specific “cases of conscience” submitted by missionaries from the Americas).</span></span></li><li><span><span>Catholic-inspired movements of protest and rebellion by indigenous people in the Americas, for example, the rebellion led by the messianic leader Juan Santos Atahualpa in Peru (second half of the 18th c.).</span></span></li><li><span><span>Catholic-inspired movements of protest and rebellion by enslaved Africans and Afro-Creoles in the Americas and West and Central Africa, for example, the messianic and reform Catholicism movement led by the Beatriz Kimpa Vita in the Kingdom of Kongo (early 18th c. ).</span></span></li><li><span><span>Catholic-inspired intellectual circles and networks in Europe and the Americas in the age of abolition, for example, the Abbé Gregoire’s political action and treatises during the French Revolution.</span></span></li><li><span><span>The influence of Catholic-inspired arguments against slavery on intellectuals and politicians who acted in a secular sphere or were personally Protestant, for example, Brissot’s abolitionism.</span></span></li><li><span><span>Trans-confessional networks that debated abolitionism with religious arguments, for example, King Christophe of Haiti and the English abolitionist Thomas Clarkson</span></span></li></ol><div><span><span>Please note that we do not have a precise overview of the funding available at this stage. It would be helpful if you could kindly let us know whether you had any traveling funds available. Online attendance can also be arranged. To learn more about the venue, check out </span><a href="https://nam04.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fmy.matterport.com%2Fshow%2F%3Fm%3D3MiYmELXfpw&amp;data=05%7C01%7Cpopkin%40uky.edu%7Cf5dd6d041403468b9ec008da93ff1e21%7C2b30530b69b64457b818481cb53d42ae%7C0%7C0%7C637985021188587918%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=r131DAEp1Rf3JkOPt4K4KrqOXOPOhBeimRLCBehFovk%3D&amp;reserved=0" rel="nofollow"><span>this virtual tour of the Schatzkammer</span></a><span> of the City Library of Trier.</span></span></div><div><span> </span></div><div><span><span>I am looking forward to hearing from you.</span></span></div><div><span> </span></div><div><span><span>Do not hesitate to contact me for any further queries.</span></span></div><div> </div><div><span><span>Miriam Franchina</span></span></div><p><span><span><a href="mailto:franchina@uni-trier.de">franchina@uni-trier.de</a></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Miriam Franchina</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:franchina@uni-trier.de">franchina@uni-trier.de</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 20:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663738629996306</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FEATURED JOB: Postdoctoral Fellow in Humanities (Andrew W. Mellon Fellows)- Asian University for Women</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10948597/featured-job-postdoctoral-fellow-humanities-andrew-w-mellon</link>
						<dc:creator>Kendra Fuller</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Home Office Notices (Jobs, Reviews)</div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Bangladesh</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Humanities, History Education, Literature, Philosophy, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><strong>Postdoctoral Fellow in Humanities (Andrew W. Mellon Fellows)</strong></p><p>The Andrew W. Mellon Foundation has announced a major grant to the Asian University for Women in Chittagong (Bangladesh) to create and support a new Humanities major that will combine Literature, History, Philosophy and Comparative Religion, supported by extracurricular activities in music, dance, photography and the visual arts.</p><p>AUW is seeking applications from candidates who have recently acquired PhDs from reputable universities in the fields of History, Literature, Philosophy, or Comparative Religious Studies for appointment as Andrew W. Mellon Fellows at AUW. The appointments, based in Chittagong, will be for two years on completion of which the Fellows may be considered for appointment as Assistant Professors.</p><p>We seek candidates who are rooted in their disciplines and at the same time passionate about the potential of interdisciplinary work; who can inspire students with an understanding of the relationship of theory and practice in understanding the world; who can engage creatively with the students to understand multiple forms of oppression and resistance, whether through written texts or through religious practices. Past courses taught at AUW <strong>include Literature of Social Reflection; Banned Books; Shakespeare; Literature as Resistance to Oppression; Poetry of Faiz, Darwish, and Neruda; Greek Tragedies</strong>; History of Empires; South Asian History; South East Asian History; Women’s History; History of Those Without History; Labor Movement History; History of Industrialization; Socially Engaged Buddhism; Asexuality in Contemporary Global Fiction; and Islam and Gender.</p><p>Fellows in History will most likely have interests in topics that relate to hegemony and resistance; in  Literature in postcolonial and comparative literature; in Comparative Religion in people’s lived religious experience, for example sufism, rather than textual analysis; in Philosophy in moral philosophy, philosophy of science and critical theory.</p><p>The Andrew W. Mellon Fellows will work as a team with the Dean of Humanities and colleagues in Bangladesh and internationally to develop a Humanities major at AUW.</p><p><strong>Vacancies: </strong>Nine</p><p><strong>Areas of interest</strong>: History, Literature, Philosophy and Comparative Religious Studies</p><p><strong>Employment Status: </strong>Full-time contractual</p><p><strong>Job Location: </strong>Chittagong, Bangladesh</p><p><strong>Job Context:</strong> Developing AUW’s capacity to teach the humanities from an Asian perspective and to generate fresh and exciting ideas</p><p><strong>Core Responsibilities</strong>:</p><ul><li>Research and publication in the applicant’s area of specialization</li><li>Teaching two courses per term (four per year).</li><li>Program development</li><li>Other duties as assigned by Dean of Humanities</li></ul><p><strong>Qualifications and Experience Required:</strong></p><ul><li>Doctorate from recognized university in relevant field</li><li>Demonstrated ability to think and work outside disciplinary boundaries</li><li>Experience of working in a liberal arts environment in a well-established university or college</li><li>Excellent command of spoken and written English</li><li>Experience of working in a multicultural environment with excellent communication skills</li><li>Appropriate IT skills</li><li>Excellent interpersonal skills and capacity to work collaboratively, build constructive partnerships and to engage in effective teamwork</li><li>Ability to represent the University in a professional manner and to communicate effectively and persuasively</li></ul><p>Female candidates are strongly encouraged to apply.</p><p>Andrew W. Mellon Fellowships will come with funds for research and travel. Each Andrew W. Mellon Fellow will have the opportunity to continue his or her research and to identify a mentor to work with them. Selected candidates will receive a salary of $30,000 per annum, tax-free in Bangladesh (except for Bangladeshi citizens) plus free housing and access to meals at the AUW dining halls at no cost. Local transportation between the residential accommodation and the campus runs on a regular schedule.</p><p><strong>Candidates with spouses who have similar intellectual pedigrees and interests are encouraged to apply. Similarly, candidates with particular connections or interests in the region are emphatically encouraged to apply.</strong></p><p><strong>Start Date:</strong> 1 July 2023. Earlier or later start dates are negotiable.</p><p><strong>Application Deadline:</strong> Applications should be submitted by January 15, 2023.</p><p><strong>To Apply:</strong></p><p>Interested applicants should send their CVs along with a Cover Letter detailing how their qualifications, skills, abilities and experience meet the specific requirements of the role, as outlined in the job description; teaching and research statements; and three references (Name &amp; Contact Information), addressing to <strong><a href="mailto:jobs@auw.edu.bd">jobs@auw.edu.bd</a></strong>. In addition to the other documents, applicants should also send an illustrative course description and syllabus. <strong>Please mention the position applied for in the subject line.</strong> The review of applications will begin immediately. Only short-listed candidates will be contacted.</p><hr/><p>To submit YOUR job posting, please visit the H-Net Job Guide:<a href="https://www.h-net.org/jobs" rel="nofollow"> https://www.h-net.org/jobs</a></p><p>Featured jobs receive an added boost on H-Announce and H-Net’s social media channels.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><a href="mailto:jobs@auw.edu.bd">jobs@auw.edu.bd</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php" target="_blank">https://www.h-net.org/jobs/job_display.php?id=64023</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 17:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663738629996305</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Art of Ruling: Ancient Conceptions of Leadership in a Global Context</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/09/19/the-art-of-ruling-ancient-conceptions-of-leadership-in-a-global-context</link>
						<dc:creator>gkaravitis</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, September 20, 2022 - 9:34pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Gerasimos Karavitis</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:gk59@nyu.edu">gk59@nyu.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/classical-studies">classical studies</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/theory">theory</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>September 19, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Call for Papers
</p><p>Comparative Political Theory Conference</p>
<p>Title: “The Art of Ruling: Ancient Conceptions of Leadership in a Global Context”</p>
<p>Date: December 3, 2022</p>
<p>Location: New York University, Liberal Studies (726 Broadway, 6th Floor)</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Description:</strong></p>
<p>The conference invites submissions on ancient conceptions of political leadership. It intends to be global in scope, bringing together perspectives that emerged in multiple ancient civilizations. Examples of such civilizations include the Babylonian, Chinese, Egyptian, Greek, Judean, Indian, Mayan, Nubian, Persian, and Roman civilizations. How did thinkers in ancient times understand the qualities of a good leader? How did they conceptualize the relationship between rulers and ruled? What challenges did they think leadership entails? From what lived experiences did their conceptions emerge? Did a conception of leaderless politics appear anywhere in the ancient world? How do ancient conceptions of leadership differ from those of the modern era? And how might ancient conceptions of leadership continue to inform our views of leadership today? We invite direct commentaries on the works of ancient thinkers (e.g., Confucius, Plato) as well as papers on later thinkers who interpreted the ancients (e.g., Arendt, Foucault). While the conference relates to a central theme in political theory, we welcome papers that explore ancient conceptions of leadership from multiple disciplinary standpoints (e.g., history, biography, literature, mythology).</p>
<p><strong>Format:</strong></p>
<p>The conference will take place in person. Presentations should be no longer than twenty-five minutes in length.  </p>
<p><strong>Abstracts:</strong></p>
<p>Please submit a two hundred fifty word abstract for papers here <a href="https://www.cptls.org/" target="_blank" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.cptls.org/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1663684409698000&amp;usg=AOvVaw2zzYvkyETcpOxpI-1w5meq">https://www.cptls.org</a>   </p>
<p>The deadline for submitting abstracts is October 15, 2022. Please include the proposed title of your paper along with the abstract.</p>
<p><strong>Correspondence:</strong></p>
<p>Notification of acceptance will be sent no later than November 1.</p>
<p><strong>Inquiries:</strong></p>
<p>Please direct all inquiries to <a href="mailto:cptlsinfo@gmail.com" target="_blank">cptlsinfo@gmail.com</a></p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 15:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663738629996304</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Special Issue &quot;Religion and the Working Class in Film&quot;</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/09/19/special-issue-religion-and-the-working-class-in-film</link>
						<dc:creator>sdiasbranco@fl.uc.pt</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, September 20, 2022 - 9:24pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Religions</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:sdiasbranco@fl.uc.pt">sdiasbranco@fl.uc.pt</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/film-and-television">film and television</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/journals-and-collections-of-essays">journals and collections of essays</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/popular-culture">popular culture</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>March 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Special Issue "Religion and the Working Class in Film"</p>
<p>edited by Sérgio Dias Branco (University of Coimbra)</p>
<p> </p>
<p>This Special Issue, entitled “Religion and the Working Class in Film”, aims to combine the latest developments in the study of religion and film with new approaches in working-class studies. Recently, research within the study of religion and film has produced more concrete studies regarding precise topics and works. At the same time, new working-class studies have given special importance to the cultural expressions that emerge from working-class people and evoke their complex, multifaceted, and intersectional experiences. The main purpose of this Special Issue is to publish contributions that investigate the links between religion and the working class in film grounded in these current discussions.</p>
<p>Scholarship on religion and film—from philosophical, theological, and cultural perspectives—has increased in quantity and quality in recent years. Publications by Inge Kirsner (Komm und sieh: Religion im Film, 2020), Stefanie Knauss (Religion and Film: Representation, Experience, Meaning, 2020), S. Brent Plate (Religion and Film: Cinema and the Re-Creation of the World, 2nd ed., 2017), as well as those by M. Gail Hamner, Terry Lindvall, Gerard Loughlin, John C. Lyden, Joel W. Martin, and Melanie Wright, among others, have promoted and advanced discussions regarding the complex relations between film and religion. Additionally, some researchers have concentrated on specific religious traditions—e.g., Nathan Abrams (The New Jew in Film: Exploring Jewishness and Judaism in Contemporary Cinema, 2012), Francisca Cho (“Imagining Nothing and Imaging Otherness in Buddhist Film”, 1999), Christopher Deacy (Screen Christologies: Redemption and the Medium of Film, 2002), and Kristian Petersen (edited, New Approaches to Islam in Film, 2021)—and others have focused on filmmakers—e.g., Christopher B. Barnett and Clark J. Elliston (edited, Theology and the Films of Terrence Malick, 2018) or Joel Mayward (The Dardenne Brothers’ Cinematic Parables: Integrating Theology, 2022). This effort to limit the scope of research within the study of religion and film has produced more concrete studies regarding precise topics and works.</p>
<p>A topic that may be fruitfully paired with religion in the study of film is the representation of the working class. Recently, researchers such as John Russo and Sherry Lee Linkon (edited, New Working-Class Studies, 2005) have identified and sought to define new trends in working-class studies. A feature of these tendencies is the way they place the working class at the center of inquiry, rather than as a subsequent topic that surfaces from research into social and economic history. The working class works differently in the workplace, in the household, and in communities, and it is shaped by race, gender, sexuality, ethnicity, and place, but also religion. These new studies have given special importance to the cultural expressions that emerge from working-class people and evoke their experiences.</p>
<p>This Special Issue seeks research that considers the developments in the study of religion and film and the new methodological approaches in the working-class studies outlined above. Authors should investigate the links between religion and the working class in film grounded in these current discussions.</p>
<p>Research topics may include (but are not limited to) the following, articulated with specific or comparative analyses of films, individually or in a group:</p>
<ul>
<li>Religion and labor activism;</li>
<li>Religion and the migration and displacement of workers;</li>
<li>Religion and colonialism;</li>
<li>Religion and working-class environments and backgrounds;</li>
<li>Class conflicts in religious settings and contexts;</li>
<li>Cooperation and antagonism between working-class people from different religions;</li>
<li>Cultural politics of the working class as shaped by religion;</li>
<li>Labor unions and progressive politics linked with religious doctrine and organizations;</li>
<li>Intersectional readings that relate religion and class with race, gender, sexuality, ethnicity, and place;</li>
<li>Religions and their connections with disadvantaged social strata.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p>More information here: <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/journal/religions/special_issues/ELT133384M">https://www.mdpi.com/journal/religions/special_issues/ELT133384M</a></p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 10:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663738629996303</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Call for Applications: Thriving in Diverse Contexts</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10943788/call-applications-thriving-diverse-contexts</link>
						<dc:creator>Clifford Anderson</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Fellowship</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-01T00:00:00-04:00">June 1, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2025-05-31T00:00:00-04:00">May 31, 2025</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>State/Province: </div><div><div>New Jersey</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>“What makes for human thriving?” If you are a researcher in the field of Christian theology working on the question of human thriving in the contemporary era, we invite you to apply for this exciting program at the Center of Theological Inquiry in Princeton, NJ (USA).</p><p>This question about the concept and conditions of human flourishing around the world is at the core of the Center’s new cross-training program in the psychological sciences for researchers in any branch of Christian theology, including systematic, philosophical, moral, practical, biblical, and postcolonial theologies. CTI invites theologians who are conducting research on human thriving in their context, or on related themes, to apply for a two-year study program on psychological science and its critical evaluation and application in theologies of thriving.</p><p>Successful applicants will join one of the two peer groups of six theologians in the study and research phases of this cross-training program in psychology, June 2023 - May 2025.</p><p>Applicants should hold an advanced degree in Christian theology or equivalent and a full-time faculty position at an accredited Higher Education Institution. Applications Portal open: October 1, 2022 – January 15, 2023. For more information and to apply, go to <a href="https://www.ctinquiry.org/apply" rel="nofollow">ctinquiry.org/apply</a>.</p><p>This program is made possible by a grant from the John Templeton Foundation.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Clifford B. Anderson, PhD</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Director of Digital Research</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Center of Theological Inquiry</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><br/>50 Stockton Street<br/><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Princeton, NJ 08540</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:clifford.anderson@ctinquiry.org">clifford.anderson@ctinquiry.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.ctinquiry.org/" target="_blank">https://www.ctinquiry.org/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 20:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663652228945949</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Newcombe Fellowships--Deadline 11/15</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10943346/newcombe-fellowships-deadline-1115</link>
						<dc:creator>Lindsay Smith</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Fellowship</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-11-15T00:00:00-05:00">November 15, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>United States</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Social Sciences, Graduate Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Newcombe Fellows are late-stage Ph.D. students in the humanities and social sciences whose research in some way attends to those commitments and ideals and seeks to understand the communities, social practices, and political arrangements that embody them</p><h2>The Fellowship Award</h2><p>Newcombe Fellows receive $30,000 for 12 months of full-time dissertation writing. (No half-year or partial awards are allowed.)</p><ul><li>20 non-renewable fellowships of $30,000 will be awarded in the spring of 2023.</li><li>Fellows’ graduate schools will be asked to waive tuition and fees while maintaining health insurance for Newcombe Fellows.</li><li>Fellows become part of a network of more than 1,300 Newcombe Fellows leading the way in their various fields.</li></ul><p> </p><h2>Eligibility</h2><p>Eligible applicants for the 2023 Charlotte W. Newcombe Doctoral Dissertation Fellowship must:</p><ul><li>be candidates for Ph.D. degrees in any field of study in the humanities and social sciences at accredited graduate schools in the United States. Candidates working on D.Min., law, Psy.D., Ed.D. and other professional degrees are not eligible.</li><li>have completed all pre-dissertation requirements fulfilled by the application deadline November 15, 2022, including approval of the dissertation proposal.</li><li>be in the writing stage of the dissertation. Usually, this means that fieldwork or other research is complete and writing has begun by the time of the award.</li><li>must expect to complete the dissertation between April 1, 2024 and August 31, 2025.</li><li>have never held a similar national award for the final year of dissertation writing. Applicants who have won such awards as the AAUW, Ford, NAEd/Spencer, Mellon/ACLS, or Mellon-CES fellowship are not eligible.</li><li>be in a humanities or social science department, writing on topics where ethical or religious values are a central concern.</li><li>Prior applicants who did not receive the award when they first applied may reapply if their revised timeline meets Newcombe Fellowship guidelines for completion and defense.</li></ul></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Jere Hogans, Program Officer</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:newcombe@citizensandscholars.org">newcombe@citizensandscholars.org</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://citizensandscholars.org/fellowships/for-scholars-education-leaders/charlotte-w-newcombe-fellowship/" target="_blank">https://citizensandscholars.org/fellowships/for-scholars-education-leaders/charlotte-w-newcombe-fellowship/</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 20:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663652228945948</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Temple Cultures and Traditions of India</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/10918385/temple-cultures-and-traditions-india</link>
						<dc:creator>SWATI  GOEL</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2022-09-30T00:00:00-04:00">September 30, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>India</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Art, Art History &amp; Visual Studies, Intellectual History, Literature, Religious Studies and Theology, South Asian History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Braj Sanskriti Shodh Sansthan (A Research Academy for History, Archaeology, Art, Literature and Folk Culture of Braj)</p><p>Mandir Shri Dham Goda Vihar Premises, Vrindavan, Mathura-281121</p><p><u><strong>Invites</strong></u></p><p>Abstracts for Three Day National Conference: <em><strong>Temple Cultures and Traditions of India</strong></em></p><p>25th to 27th November 2022</p><p><strong>Call For Papers: </strong>Braj Sanskriti Shodh Sansthan, Vrindavan, invites proposals for an interdisciplinary conference.</p><p>The papers and subsequent presentations should connect broadly with our aim to understand the temple culture and traditions of India from multiple standpoints. Please send in your Abstracts of about 500 words by <strong>30th of September, 2022</strong> to <strong><em><a href="mailto:Bsssseminar@gmail.com">Bsssseminar@gmail.com</a></em></strong> The selected participants would be informed by the 15th of October, 2022 and will be required to submit their full papers by the 15th of November, 2022. The conference is scheduled to be held on<strong> 25th, 26th and 27th of November 2022.</strong> The institute will also organise a Heritage Walk on the Historical temples of Vrindavan (detailed schedule of the conference to be released later) .</p><p><strong>Format </strong> The language of the Abstract and respective papers can be either Hindi or English.  They should be typed in Times New Roman font in case of English and Kruti Dev 10 font for Hindi and must be thoroughly proofread.  The Abstracts must include the Name of the Scholars and their professional affiliation. </p><p><strong>Concept Note</strong></p><p>Temples have been an inextricable part of Indian society; within the diversity of the cultures, they have often served the society in multiple faceted ways. In the textual traditions, temples have been perceived as Purush and Prakriti, both immutably depicting the cosmos. The connection with the divine, whether as an individual, group or community, is as personal as it is shared. Temples encapsulate this spirit by acting as sites of sacred space where the revered is the supreme and the devotee a participant in its grandeur. Historically temples have always had a central role to play in the normal functioning of society. Within the several hierarchies of temples being dedicated from Gram devta, Kul devta, Tirtha sthal to Dham, temples have served as public spaces with a binding factor. Therefore, it also gives rise to the material and non-material cultures around themselves.</p><p>The Indian Temple has been hailed as a ‘Monument of Manifestation’ by the eminent art historian Stella Kramrisch. This statement has not even a modicum of fiction in it. Hinduism certainly has a hoary history, and its antiquity could be traced back at least to the Rig Vedic Period. Yajña or the institution of sacrifice, was the core of the Vedic Religion. The Yajur Veda and the Brāhmaṇa texts contain mantras or sacrificial formulae and elaborate injunctions pertaining to the performance of Yajñas. These Vedic Yajñas would be conducted in specially constructed Vedic altars known as chitis. The construction of these chitis was an architectural science, and in their simplest forms, the chitis were a pile of bricks. As time advanced, there was marked shift from Yajñas to worship images in specially built enclosures or temples. However, despite the Yajña rituals gradually waning into the background, the structures of temples owe their origins to the Vedic chitis. The act of temple construction was considered equivalent to a Yajña and was to be initiated in strict confirmation of the prescribed set of rituals. The emergence and dissemination of Bhakti and the ever-growing prominence of sects like Bhāgavata and Śaiva added to the functional and spiritual relevance of temples. The Dharmaśāstra texts incorporated the building of temples in the category of Pūrta Dharmas, and a person belonging to any varṇa could undertake the tasks which were included in the Pūrta Dharma.</p><p>The Epics and Purāṇas comprise many references to temples, and those like the Agni and Matsya Purāṇas provide detailed instructions about the creation of temples and consecration of images in them. Moreover, texts specially dedicated to the science of temple building were written and widely used by the sthapatis. Speaking from an 3 archaeological perspective, the history of temples goes back to the Mauryan Period. We find a depiction of small shrines in the reliefs from the Buddhist Stupa sites of Bharhut and Sanchi in Madhya Pradesh and Mathurā. Epigraphical evidences from the Śuṅga Period onward also provide testimony to the construction of shrines which archaeological evidences have to a great extent corroborated. The structures of temples became more elaborate and codified from the Gupta Period onward. Apart from the Guptas, dynasties like the Vākāṭakas in central India and the Badami Cālukyas and Pallavas in Karnataka and Tamil Nadu respectively pioneered the creation of temples- both rock-cut and structural. During the Gupta period we find a systematic categorization of temples based on their shapes and dimensions. Around the same time, temple architecture manifested itself in three principal idioms- Nāgara, Draviḍa, and Vesara. Apart from these three major architectural styles, several regional styles of temple building originated and matured in various parts of India. From simple shrine like structures, temples now assumed colossal forms equipped with a garbhagṛha (sanctum sanctorum), a line of maṇḍapas or halls, massive śikharas, and shrines of parivāra devatas.</p><p>By the early medieval period, individual temples metamorphosed into temple complexes, and these temple complexes grew into the cultural hubs of contemporary society. It was mainly through the institution of temples that performing arts like music and dance, fine arts like sculpture and paintings, and culinary traditions of bhoga were inextricably connected. Temples no longer remained purely religious establishments- they took on multi-dimensional roles as educational, economic, social, and political epicentres shaping the aesthetic expression of the then societies. Many dynasties, merchants, and common people contributed munificently towards the construction of temples. Hinduism came to be almost completely identified with temples, and art historian George Michell has opined that the Hinduism that developed around the start of the 1st millennium CE is, to a great extent, ‘Temple Hinduism’. This statement aptly summarizes the vital position of temples in the gamut of Hinduism. The temples of India not merely evoke a profound veneration towards a deity through various ritual enactments and festivals but also have been subjected to a magnificent oeuvre of cultures when devotees throng its premises from parts of the country. They facilitate intercultural dialogue and circulate the idea of multiplicity of cultures with deeply rooted human values of shared experiences, respect, and togetherness.</p><p>The conference therefore, aims to bring together researchers from all disciplines to deliberate upon the philosophical, religious, social, economic, technical, artistic, ethnographic, traditional, landscape, material, and non-material aspects of temples.</p><p><strong>Broad Themes of the conference:</strong> The topics may include, but are not restricted to:  Art and Architecture of the temples</p><p> Temples as centres of learning: Textual Traditions of the temples</p><p> Economic and political patronage of the temples</p><p> Temple Pilgrimage, Ecology and the Environment</p><p> Urbanism and the Temples</p><p> Temples as Economic spaces</p><p> Temple Food culture: Bhoga &amp; Śṛṅgāra Paramparā</p><p> Rāga Paramparā : Musical traditions associated with the temples</p><p> Folklore and Oral narratives shaping the temple cultures</p><p> Conservation and Preservation of the temples</p><p> Mobility of the temples</p><p> Social justice: Caste, Untouchability, and access to temples</p><p> House temples and the idea of service</p><p> Temple without deities</p><p> Sampradāyas and the temples</p><p> Temple Festivals and feasts</p><p> Temples and the colonial state</p><p> Performative temple arts</p><p>A nominal amount of Rs. 800/- can be paid online or on arrival. The institute will provide accommodation and food facilities; however, the travel expenses will solely be the responsibility of the participants. Selected Scholars will have to get themselves registered through Emails.</p><p>Please feel free to contact conference organizers for any queries on the above-given Email Id </p><p>Braj Sanskriti Shodh Sansthan Shri Dham Goda Vihar Temple Premises, Gopeshwar Marg,Vrindavan -281121, Mathura, U.P, India</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p><a href="mailto:Bsssseminar@gmail.com">Bsssseminar@gmail.com</a>, <a href="mailto:swativenki90@gmail.com">swativenki90@gmail.com</a></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:Bsssseminar@gmail.com">Bsssseminar@gmail.com</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 19:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663652228945947</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ October 28, 2022 -  October 29, 2022] Conference or similar: Ipoteze religioase în studiul naturii umane</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/103106</link>
						<description>Venue: Bulevardul Vasile Pârvan 4<br/><br/><p><strong>Ipoteze Religioase în Studiul Naturii Umane</strong></p>

<p>Universitatea de Vest din Timișoara, 28-29 octombrie 2022</p>

<p>Amfiteatrul A01, Bd. Vasile Pârvan Nr. 4, Timișoara</p>

<p><a href="https://religioushypotheses.com/conference">https://religioushypotheses.com/conference</a></p>


<p>Această conferință face parte din proiectul de cercetare „Religious Hypotheses and the Study of Human Nature” și este realizată în colaborare cu Universitatea de Vest din Timișoara (UVT), programul de masterat „Practica Asistenței Sociale Centrate pe Valori” și Centrul Areopagus din Timișoara. Conferința se concentrează pe întrebarea dacă Scripturile și tradițiile religioase (în special cea creștină) pot furniza ipoteze testabile și care anume sunt rezultatele testării acestor ipoteze. Conferința reunește cercetători dintr-o gamă largă de discipline, inclusiv teologie, filosofie, medicină, lingvistică, informatică, psihologie, istorie și studii literare. Printre vorbitorii confirmați se numără:</p>


<p><strong>Alexandru Neagoe (Universitatea de Vest, Timișoara)</strong></p>

<p><strong>Charles White (Spring Arbor University, SUA)</strong></p>

<p><strong>Emanuel Țundrea (Universitatea Emanuel, Oradea)</strong></p>

<p><strong>Dan Aurel Botică (Universitatea Emanuel, Oradea)</strong></p>

<p><strong>Marius Clim (Academia Română, Filiala Iași)</strong></p>

<p><strong>Ovidiu Hanc (Universitatea Emanuel, Oradea)</strong></p>

<p><strong>Ioan Chirilă (Institutul Național de Sănătate Publică, Iași)</strong></p>

<p><strong>Denise (Daniela) Vasiliu (Universitatea Alexandru Ioan Cuza, Iași)</strong></p>

<p><strong>Ștefan Frenț (Universitatea de Medicină și Farmacie Victor Babeș, Timișoara)</strong></p>

<p><strong>Filip Popovici (Universitatea din București)</strong></p>

<p><strong>Iulia-Teodora Drișcu (Universitatea Alexandru Ioan Cuza, Iași)</strong></p>

<p><strong>Alin Christoph Cucu (Universitatea din Lausanne, Elveția)</strong></p>
<p><strong><br/></strong></p>


<p><strong>Conferința se va desfășura aproape exclusiv în limba română.</strong></p>


<p>Participarea este gratuită, nu este necesară înregistrarea.</p>


<p><strong>Burse pentru studenți</strong>: Oferim până la 6 burse de 250 USD pentru studenți români (cu excepția UVT, inclusiv doctoranzi) pentru călătorie și cazare. Pentru a aplica, vă rugăm să trimiteți următoarele documente la adresa <a href="mailto:info@religioushypotheses.com">info@religioushypotheses.com</a><strong> până la data de 30 septembrie 2022:</strong></p>

<p>·      Un CV actualizat</p>

<p>·      O scurtă scrisoare motivațională (max. 1 pagină A4)</p>

<p>Câștigătorii vor fi anunțați la câteva zile după termenul limită. De asemenea, beneficiarii burselor sunt invitați să participe la dineurile de conferință de vineri și sâmbătă seara.</p>


<p>Informații actualizate, precum și programul conferinței vor fi disponibile la:</p>

<p><a href="https://religioushypotheses.com/conference">https://religioushypotheses.com/conference</a>.  </p>


<p>„Religious Hypotheses and the Study of Human Nature” este un subproiect din cadrul programului mai amplu „<a href="https://cee.ianramseycentre.ox.ac.uk/">New Horizons for Science and Religion in Central and Eastern Europe</a>”, finanțat de Fundația John Templeton. Partenerii noștri locali sunt Fundația Agora Christi din Iași (organizare) și Academia Română din Iași (auspicii academice). </p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 05:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1663479426076763</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
