<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 12:18:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 12:18:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=6304038b62d7d&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=b5142b8a9c4208e145af4be2c86d4ad4&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ May 15, 2023 -  May 16, 2023] Conference or similar: Politiques de la traduction - Politiken der Übersetzung</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/110729</link>
						<description>Venue: Friedrichstraße 191<br/><br/><p>We are pleased to share with you the program of the Franco-German conference "Politiques de la traduction: appropriation, critique, hospitalité -  Politiken der Übersetzung: Aneignung, Kritik, Gastfreundschaft" (link: https://cmb.hu-berlin.de/fileadmin/user_upload/Politiken_der_Uebersetzung_Programm_def.pdf). The event will begin on Monday, May 15 at 9:30 am at the Centre Marc Bloch (Berlin) and end on Tuesday, May 16 at 1:00 pm. Admission to the entire colloquium is free.<br/>There will also be the opportunity to take part to the conference online. Please contact us at uebersetzungsseminar@gmail.com if you would like to receive the link to log in.  <br/><br/>Best regards,<br/><br/>The organizers,<br/>Alessandro Colleoni<br/>Elise Huchet<br/>Silvia Pieroni<br/>Lilja Walliser</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 05:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1682228225468455</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ May 1, 2023] CFP for conference or similar: 2023 Annual Meeting Canadian Society of Christian Philosophers</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/110689</link>
						<description><p>The Canadian Society of Christian Philosophers will hold its annual meeting the morning of <strong>June 1, 2023</strong> as part of the Annual Congress of the Canadian Philosophical Association. This year’s conference is in-person and will be held at York University. We invite submissions in any field of philosophy, that, by virtue of its topic, may be of particular interest to Christian philosophers. <strong>Please submit an abstract (prepared for blind review) of no more than 500 words.</strong> Please use a Word, pdf, or rtf document and send abstracts to Paul Franks (pfranks@tyndale.ca). </p>
<p><strong>Deadline: May 1st, 2023.   </strong></p>
<p>Our main event will be a keynote lecture by Professor Klaas Kraay from Toronto Metropolitan University. For updates and for information on the society, visit our website: www.cscp-scpc.ca.   Please note that current membership in the CSCP is required to present. Details regarding membership can be found here: https://cscp-scpc.ca/?page_id=13. </p></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 05:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1682141829031981</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>4th  Graduate Colloquium in Middle Eastern and Ottoman Studies</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12747560/4th-graduate-colloquium-middle-eastern-and-ottoman-studies</link>
						<dc:creator>Didar Ayşe Akbulut</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Papers</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-08-11T00:00:00-04:00">August 11, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-08-12T00:00:00-04:00">August 12, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Country: </div><div><div>Turkey</div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Arabic History / Studies, Immigration &amp; Migration History / Studies, Islamic History / Studies, Middle East History / Studies, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><hr/><hr/><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><b><span><span>4<sup>th</sup>  Graduate Colloquium in Middle Eastern and Ottoman Studies</span></span></b></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The Institute of Middle East and Islamic Countries Studies at Marmara University, in collaboration with the AbuSulayman Center for Global Islamic Studies at George Mason University, invites proposals for the third meeting of the Annual Graduate Colloquium in Middle Eastern and Ottoman Studies to be held on August 11-12, 2023 in Istanbul. The Colloquium welcomes papers related to the Middle East Islamic Studies in historical and contemporary contexts, including Ottoman Studies. The Colloquium is open to all disciplines as well as multidisciplinary and cross-disciplinary fields, including, but not limited to history, history of arts and architecture, <span><span>literature</span></span>, <span><span>religious studies</span></span>, cultural studies, political science, sociology, and anthropology. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Middle Eastern, Islamic, and Ottoman studies have been rapidly expanding in recent decades, in theme, scope, specialty, and researcher demographics. Expansion and specialization at once make it increasingly more difficult to have broad-based conversations on common themes. The Colloquium will bring together advanced Ph.D. students </span></span><span><span><span>who have already passed their doctoral examinations at the time of application and scholars whose expertise closely aligns with topics of accepted papers. </span></span></span><span><span>The Colloquium will host graduate students to present their ongoing research to a peer audience with diverse specialties and disciplinary expertise, exchange views and perspectives, and engage in constructive discussion in a multidisciplinary intellectual setting. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Please submit proposals that include approx. 250-word abstract with a tentative title, short CV, and the name of the proposed discussant. Proposals may be submitted for individual papers or pre-organized panels. All submissions will be evaluated by a blind peer review process. The organizing committee will make an effort to match presenters of accepted papers with the most suitable discussants. It is advised, therefore, that presenters contact their preferred discussants in advance. Papers on ongoing research are welcome. Papers in the form of thesis proposals alone will not be considered. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p>For further information please visit<u> istanbulcolloquium.com</u></p><p> </p><p> </p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><b><span><span>Timeline</span></span></b></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Application Deadline: May 20, 2023</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Notification of acceptance: June 3, 2023</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Full Paper Submission: August 3, 2023</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Colloquium date: August 11-12, 2023</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:istanbulcolloquium@gmail.com">istanbulcolloquium@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://istanbulcolloquium.com/" target="_blank">https://istanbulcolloquium.com</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 17:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1682141829031980</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Shifting Perspectives on Muslimness and Islam in Contemporary Fiction - Special Session - PAMLA 2023 (Oct 26-29, 2023, Portland, OR)</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12746280/shifting-perspectives-muslimness-and-islam-contemporary</link>
						<dc:creator>Maria Mothes</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-05-31T00:00:00-04:00">May 31, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Islamic History / Studies, Languages, Literature, Religious Studies and Theology, American History / Studies</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Abstract:</p><p>The panel invites papers discussing texts that shape the perception and representation of Muslimness and/or Islam in contemporary literature. Global, transnational, and comparative perspectives are welcome.</p><p>Description:</p><p>This panel seeks to contextualize the current position of Muslims in Western societies as either marginalized or made hypervisible. More often than not, portrayals of Muslims in the media or popular culture focus on the adherents of the imagined category of ‘Islam,’ rendering the people behind this category invisible. In light of the all-to-common binary distinctions (secular/religious, moderns/traditional, etc.), this panel seeks to contemplate ways toward “a religious literacy that does not overdetermine the role of religion” (Rashid 61). Instead of the either/or trap, an epistemological approach allowing us to trace ‘both/and’ is sought out “since the most common Muslim life is lived amidst a congeries of various laws and norms” (Reinhart 8). The panel seeks to create a space for dialogue about how contemporary literature negotiates holistic but also nuanced identities and how Muslimness is depicted as part of the spectrum of the human experience. Moreover, the panel invites papers investigating the role of literature in shaping the perception and representation of religion and how literature thus contributes to shifting perspectives on Islam and Muslimness.</p><p>You will be able to submit abstract proposals using the online submission form (you will have to go to <a href="https://pamla.ballastacademic.com/" rel="nofollow">https://pamla.ballastacademic.com</a> to login or create an account first). <strong>The deadline to submit presentation proposals is May 31, 2023. </strong>If you have any questions, please contact the panel chair (Maria Mothes) at <a href="mailto:mmothes@uni-koblenz.de">mmothes@uni-koblenz.de</a>.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>PAMLA</p><p>Special Session Chair: Maria Mothes, University of Koblenz, Germany</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:mmothes@uni-koblenz.de">mmothes@uni-koblenz.de</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://pamla.ballastacademic.com/Home/S/18844" target="_blank">https://pamla.ballastacademic.com/Home/S/18844</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 17:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1682055428197657</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Special Issue of Religions: Whither Spirituality?</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12741975/special-issue-religions-whither-spirituality</link>
						<dc:creator>Morgan Shipley</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Call for Publications</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-08-01T00:00:00-04:00">August 1, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Cultural History / Studies, Humanities, Intellectual History, Philosophy, Religious Studies and Theology</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>In the 21st century, amidst a global world still emerging from a shared pandemic, continually contending with increased reliance on technology, and persistently responding to a series of human-made catastrophes, what is meant by spirituality?</p><p>For many, spirituality remains a word wed contingently to religion, often emerging to describe experiential aspects of faith, belief, and practice within an established system of religion. In this usage, spirituality often connects to one’s relationship to the sacred, whether this be a transcendent truth or something more immanent, such as nature.</p><p>However, for a growing chorus of voices, spirituality increasingly speaks to secular realities—it is more and more a placeholder to describe the ongoing pursuit of meaning, the longing for purpose, and the hope for belongingness both within and beyond religious membership. Once the domain of religion, spirituality now emerges in relation to concerns regarding individual wellness and collective well-being, and in connection to areas ranging from medical care, professional development, and leadership skills to various cultural expressions, including the arts, sport, and technology. For individuals who now prefer the moniker spiritual but not religious, spirituality might signify an enduring commitment to belief but without the “baggage” of religious affiliation; for others, spirituality denotes a specifically secular ideal, one that demonstrates how humans continue to seek answers to the major challenges of life without the guiding hand of religious doctrine or authority.</p><p>This Special Issue of <em>Religions</em> seeks contributions that add to, challenge, and seek to complicate the ways in which spirituality emerges, is described, and is applied across both religious and secular landscapes. Is spirituality the experiential or cultural manifestation of religion? What are the results, implications, losses, and values of separating spirituality from religion? What becomes of spirituality within secularity? How do Western notions of spirituality impact global cultural knowledge? What occurs when spirituality and spiritual practices are appropriated in the name of wellness? How do digital spaces connect to spiritual practices and understandings? And what might all this tell us about both spirituality and the continued place of religion in our contemporary moment?</p><p>Potential topics include, but are not limited to:</p><ul><li>Spirituality and Religion</li><li>Spirituality or Religion</li><li>Global Spirituality</li><li>Spirituality or Spiritualities?</li><li>Spiritual vs. Spirituality</li><li>Spirituality and Nature</li><li>Spirituality and Environmentalism</li><li>Spirituality and Justice</li><li>Spirituality and Culture</li><li>Spirituality and Digital Culture</li><li>Spirituality and Technology</li><li>Spiritual But Not Religious</li><li>The Nones</li><li>Spirituality and Wellness</li><li>Secular Spirituality</li><li>Problems/Limits of Definition(s)</li><li>Religion, Spirituality, Theology, and Processes of Classification</li><li>Spirituality and Philosophy</li><li>Spirituality and Public Life</li><li>Spirituality, Politics, and Economics</li><li>Spirituality and Appropriation</li><li>Spiritual Tourism</li><li>Spirituality and the New Age</li><li>Indigeneity and Spirituality</li></ul><p>Dr. Morgan Shipley<br/><em>Guest Editor</em></p><p><strong>Manuscript Submission Information</strong></p><p>Manuscripts should be submitted online at <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/" rel="nofollow">www.mdpi.com</a> by <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/user/register/" rel="nofollow">registering</a> and <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/user/login/" rel="nofollow">logging in to this website</a>. Once you are registered, <a href="https://susy.mdpi.com/user/manuscripts/upload/?journal=religions" rel="nofollow">click here to go to the submission form</a>. Manuscripts can be submitted until the deadline. All submissions that pass pre-check are peer-reviewed. Accepted papers will be published continuously in the journal (as soon as accepted) and will be listed together on the special issue website. Research articles, review articles as well as short communications are invited. For planned papers, a title and short abstract (about 100 words) can be sent to the Editorial Office for announcement on this website.</p><p>Submitted manuscripts should not have been published previously, nor be under consideration for publication elsewhere (except conference proceedings papers). All manuscripts are thoroughly refereed through a double-blind peer-review process. A guide for authors and other relevant information for submission of manuscripts is available on the <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/journal/religions/instructions" rel="nofollow">Instructions for Authors</a> page. <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/journal/religions/" rel="nofollow"><em>Religions</em></a> is an international peer-reviewed open access monthly journal published by MDPI.</p><p>Please visit the <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/journal/religions/instructions" rel="nofollow">Instructions for Authors</a> page before submitting a manuscript. The <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/about/apc/" rel="nofollow">Article Processing Charge (APC)</a> for publication in this <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/about/openaccess/" rel="nofollow">open access</a> journal is typically 1400 CHF (Swiss Francs). <strong>However, this fee will be waived if accepted for publication.</strong></p><p>Submitted papers should be well formatted and use good English. Authors may use MDPI's <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/authors/english" rel="nofollow">English editing service</a> prior to publication or during author revisions.</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr. Morgan Shipley</p><p>Department of Religious Studies, Michigan State University</p><p> </p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:shiple18@msu.edu">shiple18@msu.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>URL: </div><div><div><a href="https://www.mdpi.com/journal/religions/special_issues/65SUOHA8B1" target="_blank">https://www.mdpi.com/journal/religions/special_issues/65SUOHA8B1</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 17:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1681969031040448</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Religious Studies Project Digest – April 19, 2023</title>
			<link>https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/opportunities/religious-studies-project-digest-april-19-2023/</link>
						<dc:creator>Trevor Linn</dc:creator>
			<category>Opportunities</category>
			<description><p>Welcome to the Religious Studies Opportunities Digest! This week you will find 1 new job opportunity, 2 Fellowships, 1 grant, 1 award, 8 Calls for Papers, 5 upcoming conferences/speakers, and 1 new MA program in Religion in the Public Sphere.</p>



<p>Everyone at RSP says<em> thank you </em>to all who have generously supported the RSP through our Patreon and PayPal donation options! Our goal is to have <strong>100 patrons</strong> (currently at 33!) to support all of our upcoming developments. Please visit our <a href="https://www.religiousstudiesproject.com/donations/">donations page</a> for information on how you can sign up for a regular subscription, leave a one-off donation, advertise with us, or use our Amazon links.</p>



<h2>Jobs:</h2>



<h4>Senior Lecturer in Environmental Humanities (Education and Research) Full-time</h4>



<p>University of Exeter, UK</p>



<p>Deadline: April 26, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://jobs.exeter.ac.uk/hrpr_webrecruitment/wrd/run/ETREC107GF.open?VACANCY_ID=858635duTT&amp;WVID=3817591jNg&amp;LANG=USA&amp;fbclid=IwAR31HDfhnsyr_8uC1-uM0wXWuMBwM-FM0xOo6HrJp04UPytd45tb13UjWgs">https://jobs.exeter.ac.uk/hrpr_webrecruitment/wrd/run/ETREC107GF.open?VACANCY_ID=858635duTT&amp;WVID=3817591jNg&amp;LANG=USA&amp;fbclid=IwAR31HDfhnsyr_8uC1-uM0wXWuMBwM-FM0xOo6HrJp04UPytd45tb13UjWgs</a></p>



<h4>Minerva Recruitment Job Listings Cite (with areas specifically tailored for Ph.D.)</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://minerva-recruitment.com/">Minerva Recruitment – Higher Education Graduate Jobs, UK &amp; Worldwide (minerva-recruitment.com)</a></p>



<h4>AAR/SBL Job Forum</h4>



<p><a href="https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search">https://www.aarsbl.org/job-listings-search</a></p>



<h2>Fellowships:</h2>



<h4>3 full-time, 4-year paid Ph.D. positions</h4>



<p>University of Tartu, Estonia</p>



<p>Deadline: May 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://usuteaduskond.ut.ee/en/content/open-call-three-full-time-paid-phd-positions-theology-and-religious-studies">https://usuteaduskond.ut.ee/en/content/open-call-three-full-time-paid-phd-positions-theology-and-religious-studies</a></p>



<h4>Ph.D. Grant-Fellowship Program for International Counter-terrorism Academy</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 7, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12665886/2023-call-applications-phd-grants-fellowships">2023 call for applications – PhD grants (fellowships) | H-Announce | H-Net</a></p>



<h2>Grants:</h2>



<h4>European Association for the Study of Religion Bursaries</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.easr2023.org/bursaries/">https://www.easr2023.org/bursaries/</a></p>



<h2>Awards:</h2>



<h4>Manfred Lautenschlaeger Award for Theological Promise 2024</h4>



<p>Deadline: June 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/FaStissR6K">https://t.co/FaStissR6K</a></p>



<h2>Call for Papers:</h2>



<h4>Phenomenological Workshop on Love and Sexuality</h4>



<p>Deadline: June 30, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/110325">https://philevents.org/event/show/110325</a></p>



<h4>International Counter-terrorism Academy Research Program</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 7, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12666093/call-research-and-papers-applications-2023-terrorism-and">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12666093/call-research-and-papers-applications-2023-terrorism-and</a></p>



<h4>15<sup>th</sup> Annual James A. Rawley Graduate Conference in the Humanities</h4>



<p>Deadline: June 16, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12709251/cfp-15th-annual-james-rawley-graduate-conference-humanities">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12709251/cfp-15th-annual-james-rawley-graduate-conference-humanities</a></p>



<h4>Bloomsbury Handbook on Religion, Space, and Place</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 15, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.isa-sociology.org/uploads/imgen/1496-cfp-the-bloomsbury-handbook-on-religion-space-and-place-2023.pdf?1681208650">https://www.isa-sociology.org/uploads/imgen/1496-cfp-the-bloomsbury-handbook-on-religion-space-and-place-2023.pdf?1681208650</a></p>



<h4>Princeton University Early Career Workshop in Islamic Thought and Anglophone Philosophy</h4>



<p>Deadline: April 24, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12702158/cfp-princeton-university-early-career-workshop-islamic-thought">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12702158/cfp-princeton-university-early-career-workshop-islamic-thought</a></p>



<h4>Author-meets-critics workshop with Michael Rosen, Senator Joseph S. Clark Professor of Ethics in Politics and Government at Harvard University</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 20, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://philevents.org/event/show/110233">https://philevents.org/event/show/110233</a></p>



<h4>Theology, Religion, and the Last of Us</h4>



<p>Deadline: May 26, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://popularcultureandtheology.com/2023/04/10/call-for-paper-theology-religion-and-the-last-of-us/">https://popularcultureandtheology.com/2023/04/10/call-for-paper-theology-religion-and-the-last-of-us/</a></p>



<h4>LATINX Talk</h4>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://latinxtalk.org/call-for-papers/">https://latinxtalk.org/call-for-papers/</a></p>



<h2>Conferences:</h2>



<h4>Carpe Diem: Saturnalia in Rabbinic Literature</h4>



<p>Online</p>



<p>Date: April 24, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/6rYbstjRCB">https://t.co/6rYbstjRCB</a></p>



<h4>Freedom of Choice</h4>



<p>Online</p>



<p>Date: April 21, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/44wGrPpBVE">https://t.co/44wGrPpBVE</a></p>



<h4>2023 Nonreligion and Secularity Research Network</h4>



<p>University of Ottawa, Canada</p>



<p>Date: June 7-9, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdHEE7dAGYT-7uRLmEYZ2zZgzRBVi1p8jlO9MmQDpgJfDTb0w/viewform">https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdHEE7dAGYT-7uRLmEYZ2zZgzRBVi1p8jlO9MmQDpgJfDTb0w/viewform</a></p>



<h4>A Constitutional Culture: New England and the Struggle Against Arbitrary Rule in the Restoration Empire</h4>



<p>Online</p>



<p>Date: May 10, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12706040/constitutional-culture-new-england-and-struggle-against">https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12706040/constitutional-culture-new-england-and-struggle-against</a></p>



<h4>A Roman World? Imperial Power and Provincial Communities</h4>



<p>Columbia University</p>



<p>Date: April 28, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://t.co/iYsKtxOF0J">https://t.co/iYsKtxOF0J</a></p>



<h2>Other:</h2>



<h4>International MA in Religion in the Public Sphere</h4>



<p>Leibniz University Hannover, Germany</p>



<p>Deadline: June 1, 2023</p>



<p>More Information: <a href="https://www.irw.uni-hannover.de/en/studium/studiengaenge-und-studienfaecher/international-master-programme-religion-in-the-public-sphere">https://www.irw.uni-hannover.de/en/studium/studiengaenge-und-studienfaecher/international-master-programme-religion-in-the-public-sphere</a></p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1681969031040447</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>DEADLINE EXTENDED: Esotericism, Occultism, and Magic at SWPACA online conference June 8-9</title>
			<link>https://networks.h-net.org/node/73374/announcements/12735180/deadline-extended-esotericism-occultism-and-magic-swpaca</link>
						<dc:creator>George Sieg</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>Type: </div><div><div>Conference</div></div></div><div><div>Date: </div><div><div><span><span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-08T00:00:00-04:00">June 8, 2023</span> to <span property="dc:date" datatype="xsd:dateTime" content="2023-06-09T00:00:00-04:00">June 9, 2023</span></span></div></div></div><div><div>Subject Fields: </div><div><div>Popular Culture Studies, American History / Studies, Humanities, Religious Studies and Theology, Intellectual History</div></div></div><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>DEADLINE EXTENDED!</span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>Call for Papers</span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>ESOTERICISM, OCCULTISM, AND MAGIC</span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>Southwest Popular / American Culture Association (SWPACA)</span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span> SWPACA Summer Salon </span></span></b></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>June 8 &amp; 9, 2023</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Virtual Conference</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><a href="http://www.southwestpca.org/" rel="nofollow"><span><span>http://www.southwestpca.org</span></span></a></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Submissions open on <b>March 18, 2023</b></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Proposal submission deadline: <b>EXTENDED to April 22, 2023 </b></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Proposals for papers are now being accepted for the SWPACA Summer Salon. SWPACA offers nearly 70 subject areas in a variety of categories encompassing the following: Film, Television, Music, &amp; Visual Media; Historic &amp; Contemporary Cultures; Identities &amp; Cultures; Language &amp; Literature; Science Fiction &amp; Fantasy; and Pedagogy &amp; Popular Culture. For a full list of subject areas, area descriptions, and Area Chairs, please visit </span></span><a href="http://southwestpca.org/conference/call-for-papers/" rel="nofollow"><span><span>http://southwestpca.org/conference/call-for-papers/</span></span></a> </span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><strong>Esotericism, Occultism, and Magic</strong> invites proposals relating to magical worldviews, practices, and representations, as well as consciousness transformation, hidden meanings, the power of transmutation, and related phenomena. Characteristic beliefs and practices include: arcane symbolism, imagery, and aesthetics; unseen forces and spiritual intermediaries; synchronous patterns, non-ordinary causation, and anomalous processes. Examples of ideas and systems include Theosophy, Freemasonry, Rosicrucianism, Hermeticism, Gnosticism, Sufism, Satanism, Tantra, witchcraft, sorcery, demonology, astrology, alchemy, shamanism, yoga, parapsychology, and psychic and paranormal phenomena, along with beliefs and practices relating to altered states of consciousness, overlapping with the study of mysticism as well as New Age spirituality, channeling, positive thinking, manifest intention, guardian angels, and Ascended Masters. Esoteric, occult, and magical concepts, beliefs, and practices appear in every culture and civilization; contemporary media and popular culture have embraced them enthusiastically, yet at times have reacted against them. The impact of esotericism, occultism, and magic on genre formation/content and popular cultural perceptions has been profound. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span> </span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Special themes for the Summer Salon may include the following, but all proposals suitable to the Area will be considered: the construction and representation of EOM traditions and traditionalisms; the role of narratives and counter-narratives in the formation of EOM worldviews; metafiction and metatextuality; symbolic representations of conspiracy; misidentification, confusion, and conflation of identity among and between EOM systems and traditions, both emically and etically; EOM and transgression; EOM as a vector of conflicts concerning identity, ethnicity, race, class, gender, sexuality, and sociocultural tensions; EOM and the counterculture; EOM and New Age thought; cryptohistory; intersections of EOM systems and traditions with demonization and/or diabolization; historical interactions and mutual influences between EOM worldviews and/or practitioners and the realms of cryptography and espionage; EOM and the monstrous, inhuman, unhuman, abhuman, transhuman, and post-human; EOM and augmented reality, virtual reality, metacognition, metanarrative, artifice, and the uncanny (valley); conception, creation, conjuration, and animation of artificial life, unlife, the undead, spirits, servitors, familiars, elementals, homunculi, and constructs; EOM and the paranormal; EOM representations in alternative media; the mainstreaming of EOM; the intersection of EOM with popular spirituality, including popular numerology and astrology, angel beliefs, self-help, popular witchcraft and spellcasting; EOM across, within, between, and <i>as </i>genre; archives, archaicism, and nostalgia; canonicity in representations and transmissions; fantasy and escapism in worldview, practice, and representation; scrying, divination, surveillance, the “seer” and conceptions/representations of the “watchers”; eroticism, love, romance, and romanticism; EOM and aesthetics; EOM as transdisciplinary</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Sample Ideas for topics categorized by media:</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Literature: Fiction by practitioners, such as Philip K. Dick, William S. Burroughs, C. S. Friedman. Books by practitioners (for example, Evola, Gurdjieff, Crowley, Anton LaVey, Gerald Gardner, Peter Carroll, Edgar Cayce). Influences and themes in magical realism, speculative fiction, gothic fiction, weird fiction, historical fiction, urban fantasy, paranormal romance and adventure. Fiction influential on practitioners, such as <i>Zanoni</i>, Goethe’s <i>Faust</i>, The <i>Illuminatus! </i>Trilogy. Historical representations of magicians, witches, and wizards, including stylized and mythic figures (Merlin, Morgan La Fey, Circe, Medea, Kostchie the Deathless, etc.), in genre fiction (contemporary Arthurian adaptations) or modernizations (Neil Gaiman, Tim Powers, Jim Butcher), indigenous futurism and fantasy (Octavia Butler, Rebecca Roanhorse).  New Age and/or popular manifestation guides, such as <i>The Secret</i>. Conspiracist and/or extra-terrestrial cosmologies related to esoteric concepts (David Icke, the Seth transmissions to Jane Roberts, the Michael channelings, etc.).</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Visual Art: Examples: Hilma af Klint, Wassily Kandinsky, Austin Spare, Rosaleen Norton, Michael Bertiaux.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Film: Content as in <i>Hellraiser, The Color Out of Space, </i></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><i>The Witch</i>, <em>H</em><i>ereditary</i>, <i>Midsommar</i>, <i>Apostle, The Endless, A Dark Song, Kill List, Drag Me To Hell, The Skeleton Key</i>, <i>The Serpent and the Rainbow</i>, <i>The Ninth Gate</i>, <i>The Conjuring </i>series, <i>The Wicker Man</i>; Gnostic allegories such as <i>The Matrix</i>, <i>Dark City</i>, <i>The Truman Show</i>; explorations of consciousness such as <i>eXistenZ</i>, <i>Altered States</i>, <i>2001 Space Odyssey, Dune</i>; representations of occult aesthetic, such as <i>Eyes Wide Shut</i>, occult conspiracy, such as <i>Starry Eyes, </i>or traumatic initiation, such as the <i>Saw</i> series; stylized depictions of magicians, wizards, and witches (<i>Dr. Strange, Shazam, Maleficent, Oz, Warlock, Thulsa Doom </i>of<i> Conan, Jafar</i> of <i>Aladdin</i>) ; esoteric/occult films such those by Kenneth Anger and Alejandro Jodorowsky; pseudo- and crypto-history in fiction (<i>Tomb Raider, National Treasure</i>); New Age documentaries, such as <i>The Secret</i>; conspiracist receptions of esoteric and occult history, such as <i>Zeitgeist</i>.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Television: Theme and/or content examples <i>Mayfair Witches, Westworld, Stranger Things, Brand New Cherry Flavor, Yellowjackets, Sandman, Wandavision, Game of Thrones/House of the Dragon, The Witcher, The Magicians, A Discovery of Witches, Midnight Mass, The Devil In Ohio, The Order, Dark, Shadowhunters, The Man in the High Castle, The Chilling Adventures of Sabrina, Twin Peaks, Penny Dreadful, DaVinci’s Demons, American Horror Story, American Gods, Lucifer, True Detective</i> (season one), <i>Strange Angel</i> (fictionalized biography of occultist/magician Jack Parsons.) Significant protagonists and anti-heroes; fourth-wall-breaking or uncanny figures, presented with esoteric, occult, or quasi-ritualistic aesthetics (Dr. Hannibal Lecter, Frank Underwood of <i>House of Cards</i>). </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Comics / Graphic Novels: Contain esoteric, occult, and magical motifs and tropes. Some are actively esoteric; Grant Morrison claims <i>The Invisibles </i>and <i>Promethea </i>as personal magical workings; the graphic novels of Neil Gaiman embrace esoteric, occult, magical themes and characters.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Music: Specific artists (e.g. Genesis P-Orridge, David Bowie, Coil, Marilyn Manson, Ghost, Watain, Dissection, Behemoth, Wardruna, Tori Amos, Loreena McKennitt, Gustav Holst), genres (dark ambient, dungeon synth, black metal, viking/Nordic ambient, apocalyptic folk, military industrial, witch house).</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Video Games: Theme and content, e.g., <i>Astrologaster, The Council, Goetia, Hell Is Others, Cyberpunk 2077, Saturnalia, Solium Infernum, A Plague Tale, Cult of the Lamb, Hunt: Showdown, Medium, Potion Craft: Alchemist Simulator, Dead Synchronicity, The Witcher, Silent Hill, Darkest Dungeon, Cultist  Simulator, The Shadow Government Simulator, Secret Government, Secret World, Xenogears, Devil May Cry, Murdered: Soul Suspect, Arcana, Arcanum: Of Steamworks and Magick Obscura, Shadow Hearts, Arx Fatalis, Eternal Darkness</i>; pseudo-history <i>Assassin’s Creed, Tomb Raider, Broken Sword</i>; historical worldviews, <i>Civilization VI </i>(secret societies), <i>Crusader Kings </i>(cults, witchcraft, demonolatry), <i>Curious Expedition </i>(historical occultists as playable characters, occult revival + pulp aesthetic); <i>Deus Ex, SOMA, State of Mind </i>(transhumanism); methodology (<i>Nevermind</i>, when utilizing biofeedback)</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Tabletop Roleplaying Games: <i>The Esoterrorists </i>and <i>Yellow King </i>(Pelgrane Press)<i>, Esoterica </i>(Fire Ruby Designs), <i>Kult: Divinity Lost </i>(rebooted by Modiphius Games), <i>Liminal </i>(Modiphius),<i> Sigil &amp; Shadow </i>(Osprey Games), <i>Esoteric Enterprises </i>(Dying Stylishly Games), White Wolf’s <i>Mage</i> (classic <i>World of Darkness</i>) and <i>Demon: The Descent </i>(<i>Chronicles of Darkness</i>), <i>World of Darkness </i>generally, Atlas Games <i>Unknown Armies</i>, Monte Cook’s <i>Invisible Sun, </i>Kevin Crawford's <i>Silent Legions.</i> RPGs have influenced the conception of magic in popular culture across media, and present extensive representation of magical figures.  Esoteric and gnostic themes intersect with transhumanism in examples such as <i>Eclipse Phase</i>.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Other possible topics:</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Influence of esoteric/occult/magical/New Age beliefs, practices, symbols on popular culture and aesthetics (e.g., memes, clothing, tattoos, jewelry).</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Influence of popular culture on esoteric/occult/magical beliefs, practices, and practitioners (e.g., Lovecraft mythos as actual magical practice, fictional gods of chaos in Chaos Magic, and real vampire communities using concepts from <i>Vampire:The Masquerade</i>).</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>Popular beliefs about esotericism/occultism/magic: fads, trends, moral panics, witch-hunts, witch-crazes, conspiracy theories (e.g., anti-occult-conspiracism in QAnon; Illuminati paranoia, bloodline of the Holy Grail beliefs, Satanic Ritual Abuse scandals).</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>Reactions and polemics against esoteric/occult/magical beliefs and practices</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><b><span><span>All proposals must be submitted through the conference’s database at </span></span></b><a href="http://register.southwestpca.org/southwestpca" rel="nofollow"><b><span><span>http://register.southwestpca.org/southwestpca</span></span></b></a></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>For details on using the submission database and on the application process in general, please see the Proposal Submission FAQs and Tips page at </span></span><a href="http://southwestpca.org/conference/faqs-and-tips/" rel="nofollow"><span><span>http://southwestpca.org/conference/faqs-and-tips/</span></span></a> <span><span>Registration information for the conference will be available at </span></span><a href="http://southwestpca.org/conference/conference-registration-information/" rel="nofollow"><span><span><span>http://southwestpca.org/conference/conference-registration-information/</span></span></span></a></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>Individual proposals for 15-minute papers must include an abstract of approximately 200-500 words. Including a brief bio in the body of the proposal form is encouraged, but not required.   </span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>If you have any questions about the Esotericism, Occultism, and Magic area, please contact its Area Chair, Dr. George J. Sieg, Southwestern Indian Polytechnic Institute, <a href="mailto:georgejsieg@gmail.com">georgejsieg@gmail.com</a>. </span></span><span><span>If you have general questions about the conference, please contact us at </span></span><a href="mailto:support@southwestpca.org"><span><span>support@southwestpca.org</span></span></a><span><span>, and a member of the executive team will get back to you.</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span><span><span><span><span>We look forward to receiving your submissions!</span></span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Info: </div><div><div><p>Dr. George J. Sieg </p><p><a href="mailto:georgejsieg@gmail.com">georgejsieg@gmail.com</a></p><p>Southwest Popular/American Culture Association: Esotericism, Occultism, and Magic (Area Chair)</p><p>Southwestern Indian Polytechnic Institute: Philosophy (Liberal Arts)</p><p>Albquerque, New Mexico</p><p>(505) 440-2105</p></div></div></div><div><div>Contact Email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:georgejsieg@gmail.com">georgejsieg@gmail.com</a></div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 19:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1681882632184708</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>DEADLINE EXTENDED Esotericism, Occultism, and Magic online at SWPACA conference June 8-9, 2023</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2023/03/19/deadline-extended-esotericism-occultism-and-magic-online-at-swpaca-conference-june-8</link>
						<dc:creator>georgejsieg@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Monday, April 17, 2023 - 6:49pm</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Southwest Popular/American Culture Association</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:Georgejsieg@gmail.com">Georgejsieg@gmail.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/american">american</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/online-conferences">online conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/popular-culture">popular culture</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>April 22, 2023</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p align="center"><strong>DEADLINE EXTENDED!</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>Call for Papers</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>ESOTERICISM, OCCULTISM, AND MAGIC</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>Southwest Popular / American Culture Association (SWPACA)</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong> SWPACA Summer Salon </strong> </p>
<p align="center">June 8 &amp; 9, 2023</p>
<p align="center">Virtual Conference</p>
<p align="center"><a href="http://www.southwestpca.org/">http://www.southwestpca.org</a></p>
<p align="center">Submissions open on <strong>March 18, 2023</strong></p>
<p align="center">Proposal submission deadline: <strong>EXTENDED to April 22, 2023</strong></p>
<p>Proposals for papers are now being accepted for the SWPACA Summer Salon. SWPACA offers nearly 70 subject areas in a variety of categories encompassing the following: Film, Television, Music, &amp; Visual Media; Historic &amp; Contemporary Cultures; Identities &amp; Cultures; Language &amp; Literature; Science Fiction &amp; Fantasy; and Pedagogy &amp; Popular Culture. For a full list of subject areas, area descriptions, and Area Chairs, please visit <a href="http://southwestpca.org/conference/call-for-papers/">http://southwestpca.org/conference/call-for-papers/</a></p>
<p><strong>Esotericism, Occultism, and Magic</strong> invites proposals relating to magical worldviews, practices, and representations, as well as consciousness transformation, hidden meanings, the power of transmutation, and related phenomena. Characteristic beliefs and practices include: arcane symbolism, imagery, and aesthetics; unseen forces and spiritual intermediaries; synchronous patterns, non-ordinary causation, and anomalous processes. Examples of ideas and systems include Theosophy, Freemasonry, Rosicrucianism, Hermeticism, Gnosticism, Sufism, Satanism, Tantra, witchcraft, sorcery, demonology, astrology, alchemy, shamanism, yoga, parapsychology, and psychic and paranormal phenomena, along with beliefs and practices relating to altered states of consciousness, overlapping with the study of mysticism as well as New Age spirituality, channeling, positive thinking, manifest intention, guardian angels, and Ascended Masters. Esoteric, occult, and magical concepts, beliefs, and practices appear in every culture and civilization; contemporary media and popular culture have embraced them enthusiastically, yet at times have reacted against them. The impact of esotericism, occultism, and magic on genre formation/content and popular cultural perceptions has been profound.</p>
<p>Special themes for the Summer Salon may include the following, but all proposals suitable to the Area will be considered: the construction and representation of EOM traditions and traditionalisms; the role of narratives and counter-narratives in the formation of EOM worldviews; metafiction and metatextuality; symbolic representations of conspiracy; misidentification, confusion, and conflation of identity among and between EOM systems and traditions, both emically and etically; EOM and transgression; EOM as a vector of conflicts concerning identity, ethnicity, race, class, gender, sexuality, and sociocultural tensions; EOM and the counterculture; EOM and New Age thought; cryptohistory; intersections of EOM systems and traditions with demonization and/or diabolization; historical interactions and mutual influences between EOM worldviews and/or practitioners and the realms of cryptography and espionage; EOM and the monstrous, inhuman, unhuman, abhuman, transhuman, and post-human; EOM and augmented reality, virtual reality, metacognition, metanarrative, artifice, and the uncanny (valley); conception, creation, conjuration, and animation of artificial life, unlife, the undead, spirits, servitors, familiars, elementals, homunculi, and constructs; EOM and the paranormal; EOM representations in alternative media; the mainstreaming of EOM; the intersection of EOM with popular spirituality, including popular numerology and astrology, angel beliefs, self-help, popular witchcraft and spellcasting; EOM across, within, between, and <em>as </em>genre; archives, archaicism, and nostalgia; canonicity in representations and transmissions; fantasy and escapism in worldview, practice, and representation; scrying, divination, surveillance, the “seer” and conceptions/representations of the “watchers”; eroticism, love, romance, and romanticism; EOM and aesthetics; EOM as transdisciplinary</p>
<p>Sample Ideas for topics categorized by media:</p>
<p>Literature: Fiction by practitioners, such as Philip K. Dick, William S. Burroughs, C. S. Friedman. Books by practitioners (for example, Evola, Gurdjieff, Crowley, Anton LaVey, Gerald Gardner, Peter Carroll, Edgar Cayce). Influences and themes in magical realism, speculative fiction, gothic fiction, weird fiction, historical fiction, urban fantasy, paranormal romance and adventure. Fiction influential on practitioners, such as <em>Zanoni</em>, Goethe’s <em>Faust</em>, The <em>Illuminatus! </em>Trilogy. Historical representations of magicians, witches, and wizards, including stylized and mythic figures (Merlin, Morgan La Fey, Circe, Medea, Kostchie the Deathless, etc.), in genre fiction (contemporary Arthurian adaptations) or modernizations (Neil Gaiman, Tim Powers, Jim Butcher), indigenous futurism and fantasy (Octavia Butler, Rebecca Roanhorse).  New Age and/or popular manifestation guides, such as <em>The Secret</em>. Conspiracist and/or extra-terrestrial cosmologies related to esoteric concepts (David Icke, the Seth transmissions to Jane Roberts, the Michael channelings, etc.).</p>
<p>Visual Art: Examples: Hilma af Klint, Wassily Kandinsky, Austin Spare, Rosaleen Norton, Michael Bertiaux.</p>
<p>Film: Content as in <em>Hellraiser, The Color Out of Space, The Witch</em>, <em>Hereditary</em>, <em>Midsommar</em>, <em>Apostle, The Endless, A Dark Song, Kill List, Drag Me To Hell, The Skeleton Key</em>, <em>The Serpent and the Rainbow</em>, <em>The Ninth Gate</em>, <em>The Conjuring </em>series, <em>The Wicker Man</em>; Gnostic allegories such as <em>The Matrix</em>, <em>Dark City</em>, <em>The Truman Show</em>; explorations of consciousness such as <em>eXistenZ</em>, <em>Altered States</em>, <em>2001 Space Odyssey, Dune</em>; representations of occult aesthetic, such as <em>Eyes Wide Shut</em>, occult conspiracy, such as <em>Starry Eyes, </em>or traumatic initiation, such as the <em>Saw</em> series; stylized depictions of magicians, wizards, and witches (<em>Dr. Strange, Shazam, Maleficent, Oz, Warlock, Thulsa Doom </em>of<em> Conan, Jafar</em> of <em>Aladdin</em>) ; esoteric/occult films such those by Kenneth Anger and Alejandro Jodorowsky; pseudo- and crypto-history in fiction (<em>Tomb Raider, National Treasure</em>); New Age documentaries, such as <em>The Secret</em>; conspiracist receptions of esoteric and occult history, such as <em>Zeitgeist</em>.</p>
<p>Television: Theme and/or content examples <em>Mayfair Witches, Westworld, Stranger Things, Brand New Cherry Flavor, Yellowjackets, Sandman, Wandavision, Game of Thrones/House of the Dragon, The Witcher, The Magicians, A Discovery of Witches, Midnight Mass, The Devil In Ohio, The Order, Dark, Shadowhunters, The Man in the High Castle, The Chilling Adventures of Sabrina, Twin Peaks, Penny Dreadful, DaVinci’s Demons, American Horror Story, American Gods, Lucifer, True Detective</em> (season one), <em>Strange Angel</em> (fictionalized biography of occultist/magician Jack Parsons.) Significant protagonists and anti-heroes; fourth-wall-breaking or uncanny figures, presented with esoteric, occult, or quasi-ritualistic aesthetics (Dr. Hannibal Lecter, Frank Underwood of <em>House of Cards</em>). </p>
<p>Comics / Graphic Novels: Contain esoteric, occult, and magical motifs and tropes. Some are actively esoteric; Grant Morrison claims <em>The Invisibles </em>and <em>Promethea </em>as personal magical workings; the graphic novels of Neil Gaiman embrace esoteric, occult, magical themes and characters.</p>
<p>Music: Specific artists (e.g. Genesis P-Orridge, David Bowie, Coil, Marilyn Manson, Ghost, Watain, Dissection, Behemoth, Wardruna, Tori Amos, Loreena McKennitt, Gustav Holst), genres (dark ambient, dungeon synth, black metal, viking/Nordic ambient, apocalyptic folk, military industrial, witch house).</p>
<p>Video Games: Theme and content, e.g., <em>Astrologaster, The Council, Goetia, Hell Is Others, Cyberpunk 2077, Saturnalia, Solium Infernum, A Plague Tale, Cult of the Lamb, Hunt: Showdown, Medium, Potion Craft: Alchemist Simulator, Dead Synchronicity, The Witcher, Silent Hill, Darkest Dungeon, Cultist  Simulator, The Shadow Government Simulator, Secret Government, Secret World, Xenogears, Devil May Cry, Murdered: Soul Suspect, Arcana, Arcanum: Of Steamworks and Magick Obscura, Shadow Hearts, Arx Fatalis, Eternal Darkness</em>; pseudo-history <em>Assassin’s Creed, Tomb Raider, Broken Sword</em>; historical worldviews, <em>Civilization VI </em>(secret societies), <em>Crusader Kings </em>(cults, witchcraft, demonolatry), <em>Curious Expedition </em>(historical occultists as playable characters, occult revival + pulp aesthetic); <em>Deus Ex, SOMA, State of Mind </em>(transhumanism); methodology (<em>Nevermind</em>, when utilizing biofeedback)</p>
<p>Tabletop Roleplaying Games: <em>The Esoterrorists </em>and <em>Yellow King </em>(Pelgrane Press)<em>, Esoterica </em>(Fire Ruby Designs), <em>Kult: Divinity Lost </em>(rebooted by Modiphius Games), <em>Liminal </em>(Modiphius),<em> Sigil &amp; Shadow </em>(Osprey Games), <em>Esoteric Enterprises </em>(Dying Stylishly Games), White Wolf’s <em>Mage</em> (classic <em>World of Darkness</em>) and <em>Demon: The Descent </em>(<em>Chronicles of Darkness</em>), <em>World of Darkness </em>generally, Atlas Games <em>Unknown Armies</em>, Monte Cook’s <em>Invisible Sun, </em>Kevin Crawford's <em>Silent Legions.</em> RPGs have influenced the conception of magic in popular culture across media, and present extensive representation of magical figures.  Esoteric and gnostic themes intersect with transhumanism in examples such as <em>Eclipse Phase</em>.</p>
<p>Other possible topics:</p>
<p>Influence of esoteric/occult/magical/New Age beliefs, practices, symbols on popular culture and aesthetics (e.g., memes, clothing, tattoos, jewelry).</p>
<p>Influence of popular culture on esoteric/occult/magical beliefs, practices, and practitioners (e.g., Lovecraft mythos as actual magical practice, fictional gods of chaos in Chaos Magic, and real vampire communities using concepts from <em>Vampire:The Masquerade</em>).</p>
<p>Popular beliefs about esotericism/occultism/magic: fads, trends, moral panics, witch-hunts, witch-crazes, conspiracy theories (e.g., anti-occult-conspiracism in QAnon; Illuminati paranoia, bloodline of the Holy Grail beliefs, Satanic Ritual Abuse scandals).</p>
<p>Reactions and polemics against esoteric/occult/magical beliefs and practices</p>
<p><strong>All proposals must be submitted through the conference’s database at </strong><a href="http://register.southwestpca.org/southwestpca"><strong>http://register.southwestpca.org/southwestpca</strong></a></p>
<p>For details on using the submission database and on the application process in general, please see the Proposal Submission FAQs and Tips page at <a href="http://southwestpca.org/conference/faqs-and-tips/">http://southwestpca.org/conference/faqs-and-tips/</a> Registration information for the conference will be available at <a href="http://southwestpca.org/conference/conference-registration-information/">http://southwestpca.org/conference/conference-registration-information/</a></p>
<p>Individual proposals for 15-minute papers must include an abstract of approximately 200-500 words. Including a brief bio in the body of the proposal form is encouraged, but not required.  </p>
<p>If you have any questions about the Esotericism, Occultism, and Magic area, please contact its Area Chair, Dr. George J. Sieg, Southwestern Indian Polytechnic Institute, <a href="mailto:georgejsieg@gmail.com">georgejsieg@gmail.com</a>. If you have general questions about the conference, please contact us at <a href="mailto:support@southwestpca.org">support@southwestpca.org</a>, and a member of the executive team will get back to you.</p>
<p>We look forward to receiving your submissions!</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 01:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1681796223309114</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
