<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type = "text/xsl" href = "feed.xsl" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel> 
		<title>Main stream | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>https://input.relcfp.com/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of Main stream | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 20:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 20:00:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://input.relcfp.com/p/i/?a=rss&amp;rid=62e967f6bc0f0&amp;user=wyattphd-admin&amp;token=batman&amp;hours=168" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>[ August 13, 2022] Talk or similar: Edith Stein Fest 2022</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/101950</link>
						<description>Venue: Silbergasse 35<br/><br/>Speakers at this event: <br/>Waltraud Holzer-Mitterhof<br/><br/><p>16.30h "Was aber blieb vom Menschensinn"<br/>durch die Autorin<br/>Waltraud Holzer-Mitterhof<br/>Musik f?r Bratsche: Christina Hecher</p>
<p>18.00h Festmesse</p>
<p>um Anmeldung wird gebeten</p>
<p>Online und vor Ort</p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 05:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1659505029671910</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ August 15, 2022] CFP for conference or similar:  Hinduism, Buddhism, Jainism and Logic</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/101962</link>
						<description>
							<p>The aim of this workshop is to explore the philosophical and logical aspects pertaining to religion coming from the Hindu, Buddhist, and Jain perspectives. The participants will inquire into how the relations between logic and religion are supported by rational inquiry on religious matters. They will scrupulously examine a wide range of arguments postulated by Indian philosophers, logicians, and theologians. The main themes will center around: the doctrine of karma and the related concepts of suffering, accumulation of merits, and detachment, the belief in an afterlife, rebirth, and/or liberation, the main arguments for the existence and non-existence of a permanent self, and the disputes between the theists and atheists over the existence of the divine realm(s) and God.</p>
<p>We invite submissions of contributed papers on topics related to these questions, including but not restricted to:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Philosophico-logical arguments for the possibility of liberation and reincarnation.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Retributive dimension of the doctrine of karma.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Logic and the concept of God, especially the arguments for and against the existence of God.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Theism and Atheism in the Indian religious-philosophical traditions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Arguments for the existence and persistence of a self</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Ethical implications of religious beliefs</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Paper proposals drawing upon original sources written in classical Indian languages (Sanskrit, Pali, Prakrit) and papers with comparative and/or cross-cultural components are particularly welcome.</p>
<p>Abstracts must have a maximum of 600 words and be written in English according to our template; they must be submitted via Easychair (note that prior registration with EasyChair is required). In the submission, one of the keywords must be <strong>"Hinduism, Buddhism, Jainism and Logic"</strong>. At least one author of each accepted paper must register for the congress.</p>
<p>Accepted abstracts will be published in the congress proceedings, which will be available during the congress. After the meeting authors will be invited to submit a complete version of their works, which will be peer-reviewed and published in a book and/or special issues of journals with publishers of international recognition. Peer-reviewed papers of previous WoCoLoR’s appeared as special issues of Logica Universalis (Springer), Sophia (Springer) and the Journal of Applied Logics (College Publications).</p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 05:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1659505029671909</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ November 4, 2022 -  November 8, 2022] Conference or similar:  Hinduism, Buddhism, Jainism and Logic</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/101954</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p>The aim of this workshop is to explore the philosophical and logical aspects pertaining to religion coming from the Hindu, Buddhist, and Jain perspectives. The participants will inquire into how the relations between logic and religion are supported by rational inquiry on religious matters. They will scrupulously examine a wide range of arguments postulated by Indian philosophers, logicians, and theologians. The main themes will center around: the doctrine of karma and the related concepts of suffering, accumulation of merits, and detachment, the belief in an afterlife, rebirth, and/or liberation, the main arguments for the existence and non-existence of a permanent self, and the disputes between the theists and atheists over the existence of the divine realm(s) and God.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 05:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1659505029671908</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ November 4, 2022 -  November 8, 2022] Conference or similar:  Hinduism, Buddhism, Jainism and Logic</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/101958</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p>The aim of this workshop is to explore the philosophical and logical aspects pertaining to religion coming from the Hindu, Buddhist, and Jain perspectives. The participants will inquire into how the relations between logic and religion are supported by rational inquiry on religious matters. They will scrupulously examine a wide range of arguments postulated by Indian philosophers, logicians, and theologians. The main themes will center around: the doctrine of karma and the related concepts of suffering, accumulation of merits, and detachment, the belief in an afterlife, rebirth, and/or liberation, the main arguments for the existence and non-existence of a permanent self, and the disputes between the theists and atheists over the existence of the divine realm(s) and God.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 05:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1659505029671907</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Symposium on the Third Anniversary of the Canonization of Saint John Henry Newman</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/08/01/symposium-on-the-third-anniversary-of-the-canonization-of-saint-john-henry-newman</link>
						<dc:creator>kathryn.edney@regiscollege.edu</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Tuesday, August 2, 2022 - 10:33am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Joseph Draper, Regis College</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:joseph.draper@regiscollege.edu">joseph.draper@regiscollege.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/cultural-studies-and-historical-approaches">cultural studies and historical approaches</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/general-announcements">general announcements</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/online-conferences">online conferences</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>August 15, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Regis College, Department of Interdisciplinary Studies in the Humanities is pleased to Announce a Symposium on the Third Anniversary of the Canonization of Saint John Henry Newman and 77th Anniversary of the first Newman Symposium at Regis College. Friday, October 21, 2022.</p>
<p>Conference Theme: How to be a 21st-century saint. In October 2019, the Church canonized five new saints, including Cardinal Newman. An analysis of Newman’s work and persona offers important insights into the practices and patterns of behavior that define the contemporary Catholic Church, since, in the words of Peter Burke, saints “reflect the values of the culture which sees them in a heroic light.”</p>
<p>The Symposium is currently planned as a hybrid event, with the possibility of both in-person and virtual participation.</p>
<p>Keynote Speaker: Richard Lennan “On Consulting”: Newman and Pope Francis in a Synodal Church”</p>
<p>Richard Lennan is a priest of the diocese of Maitland-Newcastle (Australia) and Professor of Systematic Theology and chair of the Ecclesiastical Faculty in the School of Theology and Ministry at Boston College. He holds a Master of Philosophy from the University of Oxford and a doctorate in theology from the University of Innsbruck (Austria). His research and teaching focus on ecclesiology, ministry, and the theology of Karl Rahner. His most recent books are Tilling the Church: Theology for an Unfinished Project (Liturgical, 2022) and, as co-editor, Priestly Ministry and the People of God: Hope and Horizons (Orbis, 2022).</p>
<p>We invite proposals for presentations from any field in the Humanities directly or indirectly related to the work and life of Saint John Henry Newman, including academic and independent scholars (papers), graduate students (papers or posters), and undergraduate students (poster session). We especially encourage undergraduate students to consider participating in this symposium. Undergraduate presenters will be eligible to receive the Regis College Saint John Henry Newman Symposium Award of $500. Areas of interest include:</p>
<p>1. Newman’s preaching – the content, character, and influence of his sermons<br/>2. Newman as historian, theologian, and Cardinal<br/>3. Canonization – the path to sainthood <br/>4. Miracles – the relationship between faith and reason, science and religion <br/>5. Cultural values – as determined by the Church in various eras and identified in prospects for canonization<br/>6. Devotion to the saints – how individuals are celebrated in particular communities <br/>7. Other themes in Newman’s published works or life</p>
<p>Paper presentations are 20 – 25 minutes. Proposals: Please include your name, institution, presentation title, and a 150 – 250 word abstract. Email proposals to <a href="mailto:joseph.draper@regiscollege.edu">joseph.draper@regiscollege.edu</a> in MS Word or PDF format.</p>
<p>Dates: Paper proposal review begins July 15. Notification by August 15. Undergraduate poster proposals due by October 3.</p>
<p>Presenters must register for membership in the Newman Symposium; registration information will be made available in August. Presentations will be considered for publication in the 2022 Symposium proceedings.</p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1659505029671906</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Routledge Handbook of Trans Literature</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/07/30/the-routledge-handbook-of-trans-literature</link>
						<dc:creator>dvakoch@meti.org</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Wednesday, August 3, 2022 - 10:06am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Routledge Literature Handbooks</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:dvakoch@ciis.edu">dvakoch@ciis.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/gender-studies-and-sexuality">gender studies and sexuality</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/postcolonial">postcolonial</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/twentieth-century-and-beyond">twentieth century and beyond</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>September 1, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Chapter proposals are invited for <strong><em>The Routledge Handbook of Trans Literature</em></strong> (hereafter simply<em> The Handbook</em>), to be published within the series <a href="https://www.routledge.com/Routledge-Literature-Handbooks/book-series/RLHB" target="_blank">Routledge Literature Handbooks</a> in 2023. Interested authors should submit a 300-word abstract, a 200-word biography, and a sample of a previously published chapter or article to the Dropbox folder at <a href="https://bit.ly/Routledge_Handbook_of_Trans_Literature">https://bit.ly/Routledge_Handbook_of_Trans_Literature</a> no later than September 1, 2022. Abstracts and biographies should be submitted as Word documents, and previously published chapters or articles should be submitted as PDFs. Both Word files and PDFs should contain the author’s name in the file names. Please include your email address in your biography file.</p>
<p>Each chapter will provide a comprehensive survey and analysis of a clearly defined subject at the interface of transgender studies and literature, with chapters grouped into two parts. Part I examines core topics that inform contemporary trans literary theory and criticism, while Part II explores diverse literary genres, movements, and periods through a trans lens. <strong>High-priority topics for which we especially welcome proposals are listed below.</strong></p>
<p>Confirmed contributors include:</p>
<p><strong>Part I. Core Topics</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Activism and Trans Literature, Sunaina Jain, PhD, Department of English, Mehr Chand Mahajan DAV College for Women, India</li>
<li>Culture and Trans Literature, Nicole Anae, PhD, Department of Literary and Cultural Studies, Central Queensland University, Australia</li>
<li>Discourse Analysis and Trans Literature, Katja Plemenita?, PhD, Department of English and American Studies, University of Maribor, Slovenia</li>
<li>Nondualist Philosophies and Trans Literature, Peter I-min Huang, PhD, Department of English, Tamkang University, Taiwan</li>
<li>Paradox and Trans Literature, Libe Garc?a Zarranz, PhD, Department of Teacher Education, Norwegian University of Science and Technology, Norway</li>
<li>Settler Hegemony and Trans Literature, Nicholas Birns, PhD, School of Professional Studies, New York University, USA</li>
<li>Space and Trans Literature, Jackson Jesse Nash, PhD, Arts and Humanities Department, The Open University, England</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Part II. Genres, Movements, and Periods</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Creative Writing as Trans Literature, Nicole Anae, PhD, Department of Literary and Cultural Studies, Central Queensland University, Australia</li>
<li>Medieval Literature as Trans Literature, Kristen Carella, PhD, Department of English, Assumption University, USA</li>
<li>Minor Literature as Trans Literature, Aaron Hammes, PhD, Department of Sociology, John Jay College of Criminal Justice, USA</li>
<li>Modernist Literature as Trans Literature, Rebekah Taylor-Wiseman, PhD, Department of English, Brenau University, USA</li>
<li>Mystery and Detective Fiction as Trans Literature, Casey A. Cothran, PhD, Department of English, Winthrop University, USA</li>
<li>Picture Books as Trans Literature, Joshua Hill, PhD, Department of Early Childhood Education, University of Maine Farmington, USA</li>
<li>Poetry as Trans Literature, Trace Peterson, PhD, The Fox Center for Humanistic Inquiry, Emory University, USA</li>
<li>Renaissance Literature as Trans Literature, Katarzyna Burzy?ska, PhD, Faculty of English, Adam Mickiewicz University, Poland</li>
<li>Travel Writing as Trans Literature, Lenka Filipova, PhD, English Department, Free University Berlin, Germany</li>
<li>Young Adult Literature as Trans Literature, Michelle Deininger, PhD, Humanities Department, Continuing and Professional Education, Cardiff University, Wales</li>
</ul>
<p>Authors will be notified whether their proposals are accepted by October 1, 2022. Solid first drafts of full chapters are due by February 1, 2023, and final versions that cross-reference other chapters extensively are due April 1, 2023. All authors must have already completed their doctorates. In your 200-word biography, please note the year and university where you earned your doctorate. Only previously unpublished works will be considered. <strong>We seek a broadly international group of scholarly contributors.</strong></p>
<p>The senior editor of <em>The Handbook</em>, Douglas Vakoch, has edited over twenty books, including <a href="https://www.routledge.com/Transecology-Transgender-Perspectives-on-Environment-and-Nature/Vakoch/p/book/9780367086510"><em>Transecology: Transgender Perspectives on Environment and Nature</em></a> (2020), <a href="https://link.springer.com/book/9783030963859"><em>Transgender India: Understanding Third Gender Identities and Experiences</em></a> (2022), and <a href="https://www.routledge.com/The-Routledge-Handbook-of-Ecofeminism-and-Literature/Vakoch/p/book/9781032050119"><em>The Routledge Handbook of Ecofeminism and Literature</em></a> (2023), which will appear in <a href="https://www.routledge.com/Routledge-Literature-Handbooks/book-series/RLHB">Routledge Literature Handbooks</a>—the same series will that include <em>The Routledge Handbook of Trans Literature</em>.</p>
<p><strong>We welcome proposals for the following high-priority topics.</strong></p>
<p><strong>High-priority topics for Part I include:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Abjection and Trans Literature</li>
<li>Disability and Trans Literature</li>
<li>Dysphoria and Trans Literature</li>
<li>Ecology and Trans Literature</li>
<li>Female Masculinities and Trans Literature</li>
<li>Impurity and Trans Literature</li>
<li>Indigeneity and Trans Literature </li>
<li>Intersectionality and Trans Literature</li>
<li>Intimacy and Trans Literature</li>
<li>Monstrosity and Trans Literature</li>
<li>Otherness and Trans Literature</li>
<li>Performativity and Trans Literature</li>
<li>Race and Trans Literature</li>
<li>Religion and Trans Literature</li>
<li>Politics and Trans Literature</li>
<li>The Senses and Trans Literature</li>
<li>Temporality and Trans Literature</li>
<li>Transcorporeality and Trans Literature</li>
<li>Transhumanism and Trans Literature</li>
<li>Translation and Trans Literature</li>
<li>Visual Culture and Trans Literature</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>High-priority genres, movements, and periods for Part II include:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Autobiography as Trans Literature</li>
<li>Biography as Trans Literature</li>
<li>Children's Fiction as Trans Literature</li>
<li>Climate Fiction as Trans Literature</li>
<li>Drama as Trans Literature</li>
<li>Dystopian Literature as Trans Literature</li>
<li>Historical Fiction as Trans Literature</li>
<li>Horror as Trans Literature</li>
<li>Postcolonial Literature as Trans Literature</li>
<li>Posthuman Literature as Trans Literature</li>
<li>Postmodern Literature as Trans Literature</li>
<li>Romantic Literature as Trans Literature</li>
<li>Science Fiction as Trans Literature </li>
<li>Utopian Literature as Trans Literature</li>
<li>Victorian Literature as Trans Literature</li>
</ul>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 18:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1659505029671905</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ May 27, 2023 -  June 2, 2023] Conference or similar: CFP: Back to the Things Themselves! 2023 – CRISIS</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/101930</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/><p><em>BTTTT!</em> is solely interested in the phenomenological practice of carefully and attentively describing the appearances of things in their concrete, lived givenness, without drawing on metaphysical, scientific, or other explanatory preconceptions. We ascribe to no single “orthodox” phenomenological method. Indeed, we embrace diverse approaches to “the things themselves,” so long as these approaches are focused on encounters with experience untainted by conceptual impositions. The goal should be to live behind one’s own eyes, to heed the call of things, and to attempt to give things their own voice as purely as possible, so as to reveal their sense and significance within their larger matrices of lived meaning.</p>
<p><em>The theme for our 2023 panel is <strong>CRISIS</strong></em>. In his own time Husserl wrote of the crisis of the European sciences; our present historical moment finds us surrounded by a multitude of crises worthy of careful phenomenological analysis. In the teeth of a once-in-a-century pandemic that has decimated the global population, we are confronted with crises of social antagonism, political polarization, and looming environmental catastrophe, as well as crises of information, evidence, epistemology, and truth. <em>BTTTT!</em> 2023 invites those engaged in phenomenological practice to delve into these and other instances of crisis that have unsettled the intersubjective, disrupted the horizonal structure of experience, and undermined our shared sense of world. We seek original descriptions of various dimensions of the life-world in <em>crisis</em>.</p></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 05:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1659418631381175</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Dealing with Trauma in Early Modern France</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/07/31/dealing-with-trauma-in-early-modern-france</link>
						<dc:creator>lguihard@sas.upenn.edu</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Monday, August 1, 2022 - 9:16am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Lauriane Guihard / University of Pennsylvania</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:lguihard@sas.upenn.edu">lguihard@sas.upenn.edu</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/gender-studies-and-sexuality">gender studies and sexuality</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/renaissance">renaissance</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/travel-writing">travel writing</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>September 30, 2021</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>From ancient Greek ?????? (meaning “wound, damage”), the term <em>trauma </em>refers to a physical or psychological injury provoked by a violent event, and the very event causing this great distress. Traumatic events abound in early modern France, whether be caused by natural catastrophes (floods, storms, fires, harsh winter, plagues) or by human activity (warfare, sexual violence, religious persecution). As Erin Peters and Cynthia Richards note in the introduction of the volume they edited, <em>Early Modern Trauma: Europe and the Atlantic World</em>, the application of trauma studies to the early modern world offer an interesting lens to apprehend major changes in early modern society, such as the development of new devices (weaponry, printing), the Reformation and the Wars of Religion, the expeditions led in the Americas and the origins of colonialism and slavery. Studying French sixteenth-century writings in that perspective allows us to decipher the individual and/or collective challenges authors have witnessed, or even had to overcome and live through themselves. In his - now famous - essai “De l’amiti?,” Montaigne, for example, opens up about the trauma of losing his dear friend, La Bo?tie, who died suddenly from illness at 32 years old. In his <em>Histoire m?morable du si?ge et de la famine de Sancerre</em>, Jean de L?ry recounts the drastic and horrifying measures that survivors of Sancerre’s siege had to undertake, including cannibalism. In Marguerite de Navarre’s <em>Heptam?ron</em>, the <em>devisants</em>, who seek shelter in the abbey of Notre Dame de Sarrance after a natural disaster, often share tales dealing with sexual violence. These writings, while informing us about the historical <em>traumata </em>that early modern France was confronted with, also expose the strategies of resilience that sixteenth-century authors - and more generally, people from that time - were setting up to cope with the trauma. We welcome any papers in French or in English that reflect on personal, cultural, or historical trauma encountered in sixteenth-century French literature, in an effort to (re)define the meaning of trauma for early modern studies.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>This panel will examine the role(s) played by sixteenth-century literature in recounting and facing trauma in early modern France.</p>
<p> Please submit abstract online on : <a href="https://www.cfplist.com/nemla/Home/S/19879">https://www.cfplist.com/nemla/Home/S/19879</a></p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 02:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1659418631381174</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ May 31, 2030] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/101922</link>
						<description>Publication Name: Phenomenologies of Religious Experience<br/><br/><p>This series invites proposals in classical phenomenology, French phenomenology, pre- and post-phenomenologies, and in methodologies that bridge phenomenology and analytic philosophy. The relation between phenomenology and religious experience can be considered in a variety of modes: epistemic (phenomenology as a "rigorous science" of religious experience in Husserl's sense); ontic (phenomenology as a way to access the core motive, or regulative ideal, of religion); analogical (phenomenological experience as a secular version of religious experience); generalizing (religious experience turning into phenomenological experience when stripped from its dogmatic frame), etc. Proposals can take critical, descriptive, theoretical, comparative, historical, or other approaches, and they can focus on the interplay between religious or spiritual experience and assorted theoretical approaches, or proceed from such experience towards building a new theory. In accord with Husserl’s original intent, the series welcomes attempts to locate spiritual or religious experience within a broader theory of the sciences (Wissenschaftslehre) and to expand phenomenology towards transcendental philosophy and metaphysics.<br/><br/>The series covers five areas:<br/>1) Clarifications of religious and spiritual experience, its formal phenomenological research, and its relationships to art, textuality, culture, anthropology, politics, and comparative religion;<br/>2) Metaphysical extensions of the phenomenology of religious and spiritual experience;<br/>3) Existential and psychological analyses, in different traditions, of religious and spiritual experience;<br/>4) Theologies of religious experience, with or beyond a specific focus on ritual and liturgy, including liberation theologies, feminist theologies, theologies at the intersection of religious experience and race, social status, etc.;<br/>5) The phenomenology of religious and spiritual experience as applied to and/ or examined within medicine, nursing, and the health sciences and the natural and social sciences.<br/><br/>The series is published in cooperation with the Society for the Phenomenology of Religious Experience, www.sophere.org.<br/><br/><br/>Editors: Michael Barber (michael.barber@slu.edu), Peter Costello (PCOSTELL@providence.edu), Olga Louchakova-Schwartz (founding editor, olouch@ucdavis.edu), and Martin Nitsche (nitsche@flu.cas.cz)</p>

<p><br/>Advisory Board: Jason Alvis (University of Vienna), Angela Ales Bello (Pontifical Lateran University), Michel Bitbol (The French National Center for Scientific Research), Carla Canullo (University of Macerata), David Ciavatta (Ryerson University), Crina Gschwandtner (Fordham University), Neal DeRoo (The King’s University), Thomas Fuchs (University of Heidelberg), James G. Hart (University of Indiana), Richard Kearney (Boston College), Jeff McCurry (Duquesne University), Felix O’Murchadha (National University of Ireland, Galway), Dermot Moran (Boston College), Tom Nenon (The University of Memphis), Ry?suke ?hashi (Universities of Kyoto and Osaka), Vincent Pastro (Jesuit School of Theology of Santa Clara University and Aquinas Institute of Theology, St Louis), Hans Rainer Sepp (Charles University), Michel Staudigl (University of Vienna), Claudia Welz (Aarhus University)<br/>Staff editorial contact: Jana Hodges-Kluck (jhodges-kluck@rowman.com) </p></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 05:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1659332228439915</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ May 31, 2030] CFP for publication or other deadline: null</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/101922</link>
						<description>Publication Name: Phenomenologies of Religious Experience<br/><br/><p>This series invites proposals in classical phenomenology, French phenomenology, pre- and post-phenomenologies, and in methodologies that bridge phenomenology and analytic philosophy. The relation between phenomenology and religious experience can be considered in a variety of modes: epistemic (phenomenology as a "rigorous science" of religious experience in Husserl's sense); ontic (phenomenology as a way to access the core motive, or regulative ideal, of religion); analogical (phenomenological experience as a secular version of religious experience); generalizing (religious experience turning into phenomenological experience when stripped from its dogmatic frame), etc. Proposals can take critical, descriptive, theoretical, comparative, historical, or other approaches, and they can focus on the interplay between religious or spiritual experience and assorted theoretical approaches, or proceed from such experience towards building a new theory. In accord with Husserl’s original intent, the series welcomes attempts to locate spiritual or religious experience within a broader theory of the sciences (Wissenschaftslehre) and to expand phenomenology towards transcendental philosophy and metaphysics.<br/><br/>The series covers five areas:<br/>1) Clarifications of religious and spiritual experience, its formal phenomenological research, and its relationships to art, textuality, culture, anthropology, politics, and comparative religion;<br/>2) Metaphysical extensions of the phenomenology of religious and spiritual experience;<br/>3) Existential and psychological analyses, in different traditions, of religious and spiritual experience;<br/>4) Theologies of religious experience, with or beyond a specific focus on ritual and liturgy, including liberation theologies, feminist theologies, theologies at the intersection of religious experience and race, social status, etc.;<br/>5) The phenomenology of religious and spiritual experience as applied to and/ or examined within medicine, nursing, and the health sciences and the natural and social sciences.<br/><br/>The series is published in cooperation with the Society for the Phenomenology of Religious Experience, www.sophere.org.<br/><br/><br/>Editors: Michael Barber (michael.barber@slu.edu), Peter Costello (PCOSTELL@providence.edu), Olga Louchakova-Schwartz (founding editor, olouch@ucdavis.edu), and Martin Nitsche (nitsche@flu.cas.cz)</p>

<p><br/>Advisory Board: Jason Alvis (University of Vienna), Angela Ales Bello (Pontifical Lateran University), Michel Bitbol (The French National Center for Scientific Research), Carla Canullo (University of Macerata), David Ciavatta (Ryerson University), Crina Gschwandtner (Fordham University), Neal DeRoo (The King’s University), Thomas Fuchs (University of Heidelberg), James G. Hart (University of Indiana), Richard Kearney (Boston College), Jeff McCurry (Duquesne University), Felix O’Murchadha (National University of Ireland, Galway), Dermot Moran (Boston College), Tom Nenon (The University of Memphis), Ry?suke ?hashi (Universities of Kyoto and Osaka), Vincent Pastro (Jesuit School of Theology of Santa Clara University and Aquinas Institute of Theology, St Louis), Hans Rainer Sepp (Charles University), Michel Staudigl (University of Vienna), Claudia Welz (Aarhus University)<br/>Staff editorial contact: Jana Hodges-Kluck (jhodges-kluck@rowman.com) </p></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 05:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1659332228439914</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Handbook of Trans Literature 2023 : The Routledge Handbook of Trans Literature</title>
			<link>http://www.wikicfp.com/cfp/servlet/event.showcfp?eventid=166514&amp;copyownerid=73684</link>
						<description>The Routledge Handbook of Trans Literature</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 05:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1659245832461669</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[ November 4, 2022] Conference talk or similar: Paradise as a mental and psychological model</title>
			<link>https://philevents.org/event/show/101906</link>
						<description>Venue: Unknown<br/><br/>Speakers at this event: <br/>Andre Martins (Universidade Federal do Rio de Janeiro)<br/><br/><p>The religious notion of paradise is approached in our research as an imaginary creation that – like all imaginary creation – responds to human desires, based on their affective experiences and idealizations of happiness and pleasure, which includes artificial paradises, and the absence of suffering. In the same way, hell indicates, on the one hand, human suffering, and on the other, moral punishment to their behaviors that differ from that established by religious dictates. Spinoza particularly studied the affections of hope and fear present in religious superstition. Based on the philosophy of mind proposed by Spinoza, we will seek to identify the mental structure of religion on the one hand, as well as, on the other hand, false gurus and false prophets, differentiating them from the true, but indicating why what separates them is a fine line between the first, second and third genres of knowledge.</p>
<p>Keywords: paradise, pleasure, suffering, religion, moral, Spinoza</p></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 05:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1659245832461668</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CFP- Chapter abstracts for the edited collection “Depicting the afterlife: morality and religion in contemporary film and media</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/07/29/cfp-chapter-abstracts-for-the-edited-collection-%E2%80%9Cdepicting-the-afterlife-morality-and</link>
						<dc:creator>angelique.nairn@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Friday, July 29, 2022 - 9:24am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>Angelique Nairn (Auckland University of Technology)</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:angelique.nairn@aut.ac.nz">angelique.nairn@aut.ac.nz</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/film-and-television">film and television</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/interdisciplinary">interdisciplinary</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/popular-culture">popular culture</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>November 17, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>(For possible inclusion as part of the Routledge Advances in Popular Culture Studies series)</p>
<p> </p>
<p>As Garrett (2015) contends, popular cultural representations of the afterlife are a means of imaginatively and creatively grappling with the unknown. These representations can offer explanations about life after death or the in-between, to rationalize the existential, support and challenge religious doctrines, and entertain and educate so that society might live life to the fullest or feel assured that there is something more. </p>
<p>According to O’Neil (2022), at their crux, these representations hinge on hope and the prospect of happiness, permeable boundaries that see a blurring of ‘here’ and ‘there,’ self-determination as key to understanding the afterlife, and acts of sacrifice and love that forge the conditions of eternal happiness. These ideas about the afterlife construct perceptions of morality and religion: what one must do now to reap the benefits once one has passed over.</p>
<p>These popular cultural representations, then, present “a range of narratives, consumer choices, moral dispositions and selected rituals of conduct” (Saenz, 1992, p. 43), which people “may adopt, adapt, criticize or reject as components in our implicit knowledge” (Dant, 2012, p. 24). With media such as <em>The Good Place, Upload, The Inbetween, Afterlife of the Party, Coco, Soul, Reaper, Elsewhere, If I Stay, and Boo Bitch </em>(to name but a few), focused on the afterlife, it seems timely to explore the messages promulgated in such texts about morality and/or religion. This is especially given media can prompt questioning and reasoning that aids self-reflection (Hawkins, 2001) and integrates people into an established order offering models of appropriate ways of being (Krijen &amp; Verboord, 2016).</p>
<p>Therefore, this collection aims to explore representations of morality and/or religion in 21st-century popular cultural texts that feature and emphasize the afterlife. It asks how the afterlife is understood but moreover, how are people encouraged to live their lives? Such aims will inevitably consider what place (if any) religion has in shaping popular cultural texts and understandings of the beyond, and what perceptions of morality are favoured and guide character story arcs. Ultimately this edited collection will contribute to a continued and growing discussion on the representations of morality, religion, and the afterlife in contemporary society.</p>
<p>Please send 300- word abstracts, including a title and short biography to Angelique Nairn <a href="mailto:angelique.nairn@aut.ac.nz">angelique.nairn@aut.ac.nz</a> by November 17th 2022.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Please note that the edited collection will not be published before 2024.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Possible topics might include, but are not limited to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Moral motivation/reasoning and life after death</li>
<li>Dichotomies of Heaven and Hell</li>
<li>Representations of the ‘soul’</li>
<li>Cultural differences in constructions of the afterlife</li>
<li>Depictions/constructions of the spiritual realm</li>
<li>Ghosts, the paranormal, and the afterlife</li>
<li>Religious motifs in texts that feature the afterlife</li>
<li>Representations of Supreme Being(s)</li>
<li>Notions of suffering and reward in the afterlife</li>
</ul>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 09:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1659159423763184</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>International Journal of Humanities, Art and Social Studies (IJHAS)</title>
			<link>https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/cfp/2022/07/13/international-journal-of-humanities-art-and-social-studies-ijhas-1</link>
						<dc:creator>jaksondevil@outlook.com</dc:creator>
			<description><div><div>updated: </div><div><div><span>Saturday, July 30, 2022 - 7:21am</span></div></div></div><div><div>full name / name of organization: </div><div><div>USA</div></div></div><div><div>contact email: </div><div><div><a href="mailto:Ijhas.publishing@yahoo.com">Ijhas.publishing@yahoo.com</a></div></div></div><div><div>categories (up to 5): </div><div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/postcolonial">postcolonial</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/professional-topics">professional topics</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/religion">religion</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/renaissance">renaissance</a></div><div><a href="https://call-for-papers.sas.upenn.edu/category/rhetoric-and-composition">rhetoric and composition</a></div></div></div><div><div>deadline for submissions: </div><div><div><span>July 30, 2022</span></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>International Journal of Humanities, Art and Social Studies (IJHAS)<br/>
</p><p align="center"><strong>***</strong><strong> July Issue *** </strong></p>
<p align="center"><a href="https://flyccs.com/papers/"><strong>Submission System</strong></a></p>
<p align="center"><a href="https://flyccs.com/jounals/IJHASS/Home.html">https://flyccs.com/jounals/IJHASS/Home.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Scope</strong></p>
<p><strong>International Journal of Humanities, Art and Social Studies (IJHAS) </strong>is an open access peer-reviewed journal that publishes articles which contribute new results in all areas of humanities, art and social science. The journal focuses aims to promote interdisciplinary studies in humanities and social science and become the leading journal in humanities and social science in the world. The goal of this journal is to bring together researchers and practitioners from academia and industry to focus on areas of literary and social studies for a cross cultural exploration and subsequent innovation of subjects concerned and establishing new collaborations in these areas. Authors are solicited to contribute to this journal by submitting articles for the development of humanities and social science fields.</p>
<p><strong>Topics of interest include, but are not limited to, the following</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Humanities and social science such as anthropology</li>
<li>Visual Arts</li>
<li>Anthropology, Area Studies, Archaeology</li>
<li>Culture and Ethics Studies</li>
<li>Economics, Ethics, Geography, History</li>
<li>Business studies</li>
<li>Communication studies</li>
<li>Corporate governance</li>
<li>Criminology, Cross-cultural studies</li>
<li>Demography, Development studies</li>
<li>Economics</li>
<li>Education</li>
<li>Language and Linguistics</li>
<li>History</li>
<li>Literature</li>
<li>Performing Art</li>
<li>Philosophy</li>
<li>Religion</li>
<li>Media studies, Methodology</li>
<li>Paralegal, Performing arts (music, theatre &amp; dance)</li>
<li>Gender and Sexuality Studies, Geography</li>
<li>Industrial relations, Information Science, International relations</li>
<li>Law, Linguistics, Library science, Linguistics Literature</li>
<li>Political science, Philosophy</li>
<li>Psychology, Population Studies</li>
<li>Public administration</li>
<li>Religious studies</li>
<li>Social welfare, Sociology</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Paper Submission</strong></p>
<p>Authors are invited to submit papers for this journal through <a href="https://flyccs.com/papers/"><strong>Submission System</strong></a><strong>.</strong> Submissions must be original and should not have been published previously or be under consideration for publication while being evaluated for this Journal.</p>
<p><strong>Important Dates</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Submission Deadline : July 28, 2022</strong></li>
<li><strong>Notification :August 27, 2022</strong></li>
<li><strong>Final Manuscript Due : August 30, 2022</strong></li>
<li><strong>·         </strong><strong>Publication Date : Determined by the Editor-in-Chief</strong></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Contacts </strong></p>
<p><strong>Here's where you can reach us  : </strong><a href="mailto:ijhasjournal@yahoo.com">ijhasjournal@yahoo.com</a></p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
</div></div></div></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 04:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1659159423763183</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>